<filme>
 <id>
  802
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0107076
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Alvo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A woman hires a drifter as her guide through New Orleans in search of her father, who has gone missing. They discover a deadly game of cat and mouse behind his disappearance in the process.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Natasha Binder comes to New Orleans looking for her father, who has gone missing. In doing so, she meets a very hard man called Chance. He helps her find out that her father was killed by an organisation who sell the opportunity to hunt human prey. They are taking advantage of a police strike in New Orleans. Will the Muscles from Brussels win through?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   money
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   louisiana
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new orleans louisiana
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   missing person
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   union
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Woo
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Chuck Pfarrer
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jean-Claude Van Damme
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lance Henriksen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Yancy Butler
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How can something so bad be this good?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put Hard Target is a terrible movie. It is a testament to how big Jean Claude Van Damme really was in the early nineties. He was a master of the action/Martial Arts film. Nearly every scene in this film feels like a spoof...a joke and yet its not at all. I am actually surprised Van Damme would do something like this given his ego because couldn't he see just how ridiculous it was. Its like the ultimate spoof of the 80's action genre. Who better to do it than John Woo? I constantly hear how legendary this director is but I often wonder if this opinion too is a joke. The guy almost killed the Mission Impossible franchise with ridiculous hair, constant slow motion camera tricks, and ridiculous "hero" analogies. And here we have Hard Target with the exact same MO. Hair, slow-mo, hero analogies all over again. Some day I might have someone watch this film and tell me how many times he goes into slow motion which is not dramatic in this case or even remotely "cool" but instead looks ridiculous, hokey and dumb. Especially when your hero is sporting a greasy, stringy mullet. Now all this being said, I'll be darned if this isn't some sort of bizarre cheeky entertainment. Maybe because its laughable or just how incredibly outlandish the action scenes are. The scene with Van Damme standing on the seat of a dirt bike, shooting bad guys and then rolling over the top of their car...is just too ridiculously legendary to not be cool. This is the stuff Chuck Norris wishes he had under his belt. Jean Claude Van Damme is not a great actor, never was. But there is no arguing his chemistry in the 90's. There is just something slick and cool about that enormous ego that he has. His character in Hard Target is just about portrayed as God-like. He has this untouchable, swoon at his feet persona that it so ridiculous that its fun to watch. Yancy Butler is the stereotypical required female partner to Van Damme. She does alright and certainly has the "deer in the headlights" look down pat. She literally looks 90% of the time like she is on an infomercial that is selling Jean Claude Van Damme and she wants it! Her longing looks and open mouthed gaping is hilarious. Their chemistry is okay but really sort of unnecessary. Lance Henriksen is actually the perfect action hero villain. He has the look down and he a cold blooded horrifying killer. He probably has the best role in the entire film. He is a very worthy action film villain. Not to be outdone Arnold Vosloo is a brilliant right hand man to Henriksen. He could have easily been the lead villain in his own right. He is equally as cold and calculating and you get two great final battles when Van Damme takes them on. Wilford Brimley makes a cameo as the obligatory old man that the hero cares about. John Woo gets constant praise from fans for being a "brilliant" action director but his style is always the same and is so awkward at times. He has to be the king of overusing slow motion and when you pair it together with Van Damme and this story it just makes it even more cheesy. Now all this being said Hard Target has found its niche. Twenty years later and it can sit comfortably in action classic status. You can laugh at it and marvel at the action scenes. Plenty of explosions and gun fights and non-stop action especially towards the end of the movie. I can give them kudos for actually creating a solid story even if its a little cookie cutter and predictable. Ultimately Hard Target is nothing but sheer entertainment no matter how you take it or look at it. Nothing wrong with that but it certainly makes a lot of grievous errors in film making and they should just be lucky that it will likely continue to achieve cult status amongst action fans and Van Damme junkies. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot going for it...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phillipfawcett
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but Claude Van Damme is not it! Not a fan, here, of a guy who has more wood in him than the Bastoin forest. Maybe I'm just not a karate fan: it always seems to me that by the time you've finishing spinning and getting your leg up, any adversary could have laid you out, end of. The slow-motion sequences just make me want to give the guy a Coors Light, so he can take his pay check and get out of there. Seagal is a much more engaging actor for me, and his Aikido seems more credible. However, I find this movie an enjoyable ride! Firstly, the premise is powerful and interesting. Sick gun-loving sons- of-bitches run a business which stages real-life hunts of some poor wretch who 'will not be missed'. They always take care to choose somebody with a fighting background, like a Nam Vet, just to give them a bit of a challenge. The script makes an effort to lend this credibility by explaining that 'trouble spots' in the world are always chosen for this, and they move on from country to country after each 'hunt' to evade fallout. Secondly, some of the characters are extremely strong, particularly the villains. Lance Henriksen is always good value, and here puts in a wonderfully hard-assed and droll portrayal of the 'Director' (for want of a better title). Legendary movie quote #33: "Now you know why we insist on payment up front." LOL His side-kick, 'Pik', is a superbly sadistic piece of work by Arnold Vosloo. He doesn't overplay it, yet leaves the viewer in no doubt as to his nature. He has a quiet and chilling business-like manner most of the time, but when time comes for an execution you see what a hobby it is for him, with the twinkle in his eye. The two lead females are sympathetic and credible characters, especially policewoman Kasi Lemmons. Unfortunately the same cannot be said for the 'lovable' but ridiculous Uncle Douvee. I guess he was injected into the final phase of the movie to lend a sprinkling of humour, but imo it did not need it. We already have the two main good characters to engage with, and the movie should have been allowed to stand on its gritty and punchy violence and the quite disturbing aspects of human nature. We really care if some of these characters live or die, even the psychos! In a downtown New Orleans scene, one of the 'hunted' is totally unable to get anybody to help him, which made me really angry. All too believable, and really lent credibility to how the company gets away with it. Uncle Douvee... jeez. If you can get past the image of this old fool playing the hero, then fair play to you (maybe I need to 'lighten up'). If you can get past the attempts at a French (or Belgian, whatever) accent by the very American bit-part actor Wilfred Brimley, then you were not getitng properly into the movie in the first place. Sorry to pick on him, but for me it really grated. It's all the more sad when you remember him in his straight-up role as a mafia henchman in 'The Firm': believable and exactly the tone called for here. Bit-part is what it was, though, and the strengths of the movie outweigh the weaknesses. I would have loved to see Harrison Ford or even Bruce Willis in the Van Damme role - with the every-guy credibility and minus the slow motion, please!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's like a drug isn't it, to bring a man down?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hard Target is directed by John Woo and written by Chuck Pfarrer. It stars Jean-Claude Van Damme, Lance Henriksen, Yancy Butler, Arnold Vosloo and Wilford Brimley. Music is by Graeme Revell and cinematography by Russell Carpenter. New Orleans and ex-merchant marine Chance Boudreaux (Damme) is struggling to gain employment on account of some muscular indiscretions. However, after saving Natasha Binder (Butler) from the hands of robbers, he is offered some work by her that pays handsomely. The task is to find out where her father is, a homeless ex-forces man who has mysteriously disappeared. It's a search that leads them to a sick urban safari being run by Emil Fouchon (Henriksen), the prey? Man! After pushing the boundaries of action cinema in Hong Kong, it was only a matter of time before John Woo got lured to America to dabble in the dollar. Hard Target was his first American movie, which in spite of the studio being nervous about his hiring (Sam Raimi was on standby should it implode) and cuts being made on demand for a certificate rating to open it up to a wider audience, it worked out well. It was a financial success, even though there was the inevitable mixed reviews from critics and today it rightly is held in high regard amongst action movie die- hards. OK! Nobody could seriously claim it's a titan of cinema, it's an absurd story derived from The Most Dangerous Game, the acting is of the usual Van Damme kick assery standard (JC pouts and mumbles, Butler is terrible, Brimley is miscast, Henriksen so over the top we almost lose him from our vision) and preposterousness reaches new levels. Yes it's a dumb fun action movie where leaving the brain at the door is a requisite. But what action delights await the faithful, what grace and style does Woo bring to the mayhem, it's a visceral thriller that once it gets the plot initiations out of the way, unleashes beautiful carnage that thunders the chest royally. Can violence be lyrical? In Woo's hands yes, certainly. The action film is one of the most maligned in cinema, but there is great artistry to many of them, to that end Hard Target scores incredibly high. The stunt work is amazing, the choreography of the fight scenes, with Van Damme showing his wonderful skills, are exquisite sights for the action film fan. Woo's tricks involving slow-mo, freeze frames and juddering close ups all get worked out here, quite often forming part of another ballet of bloodshed. Woo and Van Damme were a good fit, the film rocks for those so inclined for such kinetic malarkey, and not even The Muscles from Brussels' mullet can spoil the enjoyment. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What made you want to complicate my life like this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS*** Even for a Jean-Claude Van Damme action movie "Hard Target" is just a bit too hard to take despite all its action scenes as well as Mr. Van Damme's kick boxing & martial art talents. At first the film starts off like the 1932 classic "The Most Dangerous Game" but quickly deteriorates into a mindless and disjointed free for all. With Van Damme as merchant marine Chance Boudreaux taking on an entire army of bikers in the Louisiana bayous lead by the villainous Emil Fouchon played by Lance Henriksen. Totally unbelievable fight & action scenes even for Van Damme to preform with or without a stunt double that has him have more lives in the movie then a dozen cats. There's also Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's love interest in the film Nat Binder, Nancy Butler, who despite being a damsel in distress seems to have trouble keeping a straight face in many of the action as well as love scenes she's in the movie. It was Nat's missing dad, Douglas Pfarrer,who was later found to be murdered that had Van Damme, who was hired by Net to find him, get involved in this holy mess in the first place. And who can forget Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's moon shine drinking uncle Douvee played by William Brimley who about the best, after Lance Henriksen, actor in the film. Who no matter how much booze he drinks is still able to ride his horse without falling off as well as shoot arrows as accurately as Robin Hood. And as things turned out it was the booze, or the flask that he stored it in, that ended up saving his life! The final showdown in the film between Van Damme-Chance Boudreaux-and Emil Fouchon-Lance Henriksen-just went on and on to the point where all the fighting shooting and exploding lost their effect since for a time it didn't effect the two at all. And when it finally ended you couldn't care less who ended up winning but was happy as hell to know the movie, and all the suffering you went through in watching it, was thank God finally over!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good plot, entertaining, but nowhere near a Woo classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a far cry from Woo's masterpeices in Hong Kong. It was his first American movie and one must say that in a lot of ways it is a disappointment. I am not saying that it is a bad movie, but it seems that the creative genius that is John Woo is seriously hindered by the capital focus of the American market. Us Westerners like movies with happy endings and movies that do not challenge us to think. This movie is action but its action is not beautifully crafted within a movie with real characters struggling in a real world. Hard Target is set in New Orleans during a police strike, though this does not seem evident. A group has set itself up where they hire vagrants to run 10 kilometers with $10 000 while they are being chased by hunters. These vagrants are not supposed to have any ties, but unfortunately they chose somebody who does. When his daughter comes to New Orleans to find him dead, she starts asking questions, and brings Van Damme in to help her. The plot is good, but the thing with Woo's movies from Hong Kong is that it is about the characters struggling with themselves and the bad guys were simply around to make their life even harder. No such struggle occurs within this movie. Van Damme, who is simply a sailor that happens to be good at martial arts, is not able to play a character with any depth. Personally I do not think much of his acting ability, and people really only watch his movies to see his moves - and they are not even martial arts. The only reason Van Damme can do these moves is because he is a dancer. The movie plasters John Woo as being the director and attempts to attract people to the movie on this fact. The action is good, and the imagery used is typical of John Woo. He is a brilliant director, but is even better when he is not restrained. I feel that this film is let down in the fact that there is no character struggle in this movie. The characters are not anti-heroes, which is one of the aspects that elevates Woo movies above the others. It is not until Face Off that John Woo's American movies began to stand out. There are two things that seem to form a part of Woo movies. The main characters either begin as friends but slowly drift apart until they are fighting each other at the end, or they are apart and through the struggles that they face, they are drawn together and realise that they need to help each other. Face Off is a completely different idea where the good guy suddenly finds that he is the bad guy and cannot do anything about it. A Bullet in the Head, Too Catch a Thief, and Broken Arrow are examples of the first type, while The Killer and Hard Boiled are examples of the second type. Hard Target doesn't fall into either category. The characters do not entertain me as their struggles are purely action orientated and as such it doesn't grab me as Woo's other movies do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Competent action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DaRick89
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As with many action movies, Hard to Kill's strengths and weaknesses are fairly simple to analyse. It's a competent action thriller, notable for some stylish action scenes that have John Woo's touch; one particularly memorable example is when Chance Boudreaux (Jean-Claude Van Damme) quite literally blasts a bikie thug out a window with a shotgun and a petrol can! These moments pretty much make the film worth seeing by themselves, despite the usual weaknesses in the plotting and JCVD's ever wooden countenance. As JCVD himself noted however, viewers paid the money to see him waste bad guys and he does plenty of this - sometimes in more inventive ways than expected (using snake traps). It very much makes the film worth seeing for action buffs, even though I'm reluctant to give a really high rating based on this alone. The plot is not too extraordinary: a homeless veteran gets murdered by a team of mercenaries led by Emil Fouchoud (Henriksen) and Van Cleaf (Vosloo), after which his daughter Nat (Butler) comes looking for him and commissions Boudreaux, a homeless Cajun merchant marine (!) to help her out after he rescues her from marauding thugs, raising the ire of the mercenary team. A few plot holes are obvious (shouldn't this mercenary team have been dealt with a while ago, police strike or not? Why is JCVD made a CAJUN?), but it works well as a vehicle for blowing stuff up and killing people. The dialogue is pretty standard stuff: some profanity, some hilariously cringeworthy lines ("don't worry about Randall; he's all ears!) and some macho stuff. As for the acting, the villains are better than the heroes. Of course, when JCVD is your hero, that's bound to be the case, with his unconvincing delivery. He has recently shown that he is capable of acting, but he was a long off that in 1993. Still, English is probably his third language (after French and Dutch); Yancy Butler has no such excuses, being quite wooden in a role that doesn't demand that much. Vosloo and Henriksen are much better though. Vosloo has that quiet menace that always makes him a good villain, while Henriksen goes from menacing and purposeful to merrily nuts as Boudreaux causes him more difficulties than expected. Even Wilford Brimley is amusing as Chance's crazy uncle, reeling off some zany lines. In the end, Hard Target is not a great movie, but it's a competent action thriller with some nice stylistic touches from John Woo during the action scenes. Henriksen, Vosloo and Brimley compensate somewhat for JCVD and Butler, but you still shouldn't watch this film for the acting and especially not for the plotting. Action fans generally don't really look for either that much though, so that's alright. Movie-goers looking for a bit more will probably like some of the style, but won't find that much else. 3/5 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Lance Henriksen show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies starring Jean-Claude Van Damme can't be labeled as anything else than "so bad it's good" material. This one makes no exception. Lance Henriksen however, transcends the genre with a grandiose over-the-top performance that's great fun to watch. As to Van Damme, this actor is not merely campy. His lack of charisma, not to mention linguistic competence, is simply astonishing. Butler is a perfect match  she's fake as a Latino soap-opera, although her English is better than Van Damme's. The film's plot is ridiculous and it gets over- violent to the point of being unpleasant, but it's all worth watching for Lance Henriksen's gleefully villainous show-off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    HK Neo Reviews: Hard Target
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (webmaster@thehkneo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director John Woo's first venture into Hollywood was not without its obstacles. With Van Damme being one of Hollywood's bright action stars back in the early 90s, it is pretty much certain that Woo lacked what he received in his later works  control. The film for most of it, seems uneven, especially when there are scenes you can clearly see as Woo's footprints all over it and there are others that are just plain awful. Still, if you ignore the bad acting from Van Damme, poor pacing, poor editing, there is still fun to be had. Namely the majority of the shooting sequences, a wonderful villainous turn by future "The Mummy" star  Lance Henriksen and a few pigeons to boost, Hard Target is really not that bad Neo rates it 6/10. - www.thehkneo.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best Van Damme movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chris1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First saw this movie when i was buying a video of Maximum Risk,which is a decent Van Damme film.So i watched this film and was not disappointed,i was entertained throughout the whole movie.The action was practically non-stop.The storyline is decent enough with ruthless business men hunting homeless war veterans,and the street-wise Chance Boudreaux was going to find out sooner or later,to bad for the bad guys.The action scenes are spot on.When Van Damme first appears,you just know the s**t is going down.In roughly the first half hour of the film sees a fight at a caf&eacute; in which Van Damme breaks a guys arm it is brutal.As the film rolls on,we discover Chance's background and how he himself has experienced the streets.Lance Henrickson is great as the Emil Fouchon chief bad guy,you just love to hate.And Arnold Vosloo as his sidekick Pick Van Cleef was great and funny at times.You just know when he utters the words "Randall,Randall,Randall" that Randall was in for a very bad day.Wilford Brimley as the enjoyable and funny uncle Douvee.The tag-line for this movie is "Don't Hunt What You Cant Kill" and the bad guys should have realised this.This is a decent and enjoyable Van Damme film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High-quality Van Damme at his absolute best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance Boudreaux (Van Damme) is a New Orleans longshoreman who is down on his luck and struggling to find work. Opportunity comes his way when Nat (Butler) hires him to help her find her missing father. As it turns out, her father isn't missing, necessarily, he was a victim of a malevolent gang of "human hunters". Led by Fouchon (Henriksen), and with his second in command Pik Van Cleef (Vosloo), they get their kicks (and get rich) letting weekend warriors pay them to go on the ultimate hunting expedition: for man! But they meet their match with the fearless Chance, a man they cannot kill. Along for the ride is Chance's uncle Douvee (Brimley). Will Chance get his chance at glory? Or, to the human hunters, is he just another HARD TARGET? Hard Target is hands-down one of Van Damme's best. It's explosively entertaining and lives up to the promise of a Van Damme and John Woo team-up. It's everything a combination of those two men could be and should be, and doesn't let the audience down. Once again, this is classic 90's action fun from the golden time when Van Damme movies went to the theater. Back then, we remember joking with our friends that because there's so much slow motion in this movie, if it was all played at regular speed, the film would be about 20 minutes. And it's true, there is a lot of dramatic slo-mo, but it's all for the best. And Van Damme and others get a lot of unnecessarily portentous entrances and exits, which just adds to the style of Hard Target, which is just a tad bit off-kilter. But that's far from a bad thing. It separates itself from its many competitors that way. Besides Van Damme and his absurd hair, the cast assembled for this is just killer: Lance Henriksen is great as the baddie who's so bad, even his piano-playing is evil. Vosloo is also adept at being bad, and his quasi-Scottish (?) accent, well, accentuates his sinister glares. Yancy Butler gives a bug-eyed performance who always seems surprised at the proceedings. But top marks must go to the great Wilford Brimley. In a strange role for him, the barely-intelligible, bow-and-arrow toting, horseback riding uncle is truly lovable and you root for him, even though he doesn't appear until late in the film. That's a tribute to Brimley that the audience can grow to love him so quickly. This movie puts a twist on the time-honored Most Dangerous Game (1932) idea. The formula's been tried before, with varying degrees of success, in everything from Death Ring (1992) to Avenging Force (1986). But Hard Target has plenty of awesome moments, including the extended climax in (what else) an abandoned warehouse. Never one to be afraid of wasting bullets, Woo pulls out all the stops in an extended feast of overkill. It's over-the-top fun everyone should see. On a technical note, the British DVD is longer than the American cut, including more violence. So try to track that down if you can, for the complete picture. Go down to the bayou tonight for some high-octane, high-quality Van Damme at his absolute best. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How can something so bad be this good?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put Hard Target is a terrible movie. It is a testament to how big Jean Claude Van Damme really was in the early nineties. He was a master of the action/Martial Arts film. Nearly every scene in this film feels like a spoof...a joke and yet its not at all. I am actually surprised Van Damme would do something like this given his ego because couldn't he see just how ridiculous it was. Its like the ultimate spoof of the 80's action genre. Who better to do it than John Woo? I constantly hear how legendary this director is but I often wonder if this opinion too is a joke. The guy almost killed the Mission Impossible franchise with ridiculous hair, constant slow motion camera tricks, and ridiculous "hero" analogies. And here we have Hard Target with the exact same MO. Hair, slow-mo, hero analogies all over again. Some day I might have someone watch this film and tell me how many times he goes into slow motion which is not dramatic in this case or even remotely "cool" but instead looks ridiculous, hokey and dumb. Especially when your hero is sporting a greasy, stringy mullet. Now all this being said, I'll be darned if this isn't some sort of bizarre cheeky entertainment. Maybe because its laughable or just how incredibly outlandish the action scenes are. The scene with Van Damme standing on the seat of a dirt bike, shooting bad guys and then rolling over the top of their car...is just too ridiculously legendary to not be cool. This is the stuff Chuck Norris wishes he had under his belt. Jean Claude Van Damme is not a great actor, never was. But there is no arguing his chemistry in the 90's. There is just something slick and cool about that enormous ego that he has. His character in Hard Target is just about portrayed as God-like. He has this untouchable, swoon at his feet persona that it so ridiculous that its fun to watch. Yancy Butler is the stereotypical required female partner to Van Damme. She does alright and certainly has the "deer in the headlights" look down pat. She literally looks 90% of the time like she is on an infomercial that is selling Jean Claude Van Damme and she wants it! Her longing looks and open mouthed gaping is hilarious. Their chemistry is okay but really sort of unnecessary. Lance Henriksen is actually the perfect action hero villain. He has the look down and he a cold blooded horrifying killer. He probably has the best role in the entire film. He is a very worthy action film villain. Not to be outdone Arnold Vosloo is a brilliant right hand man to Henriksen. He could have easily been the lead villain in his own right. He is equally as cold and calculating and you get two great final battles when Van Damme takes them on. Wilford Brimley makes a cameo as the obligatory old man that the hero cares about. John Woo gets constant praise from fans for being a "brilliant" action director but his style is always the same and is so awkward at times. He has to be the king of overusing slow motion and when you pair it together with Van Damme and this story it just makes it even more cheesy. Now all this being said Hard Target has found its niche. Twenty years later and it can sit comfortably in action classic status. You can laugh at it and marvel at the action scenes. Plenty of explosions and gun fights and non-stop action especially towards the end of the movie. I can give them kudos for actually creating a solid story even if its a little cookie cutter and predictable. Ultimately Hard Target is nothing but sheer entertainment no matter how you take it or look at it. Nothing wrong with that but it certainly makes a lot of grievous errors in film making and they should just be lucky that it will likely continue to achieve cult status amongst action fans and Van Damme junkies. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot going for it...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phillipfawcett
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but Claude Van Damme is not it! Not a fan, here, of a guy who has more wood in him than the Bastoin forest. Maybe I'm just not a karate fan: it always seems to me that by the time you've finishing spinning and getting your leg up, any adversary could have laid you out, end of. The slow-motion sequences just make me want to give the guy a Coors Light, so he can take his pay check and get out of there. Seagal is a much more engaging actor for me, and his Aikido seems more credible. However, I find this movie an enjoyable ride! Firstly, the premise is powerful and interesting. Sick gun-loving sons- of-bitches run a business which stages real-life hunts of some poor wretch who 'will not be missed'. They always take care to choose somebody with a fighting background, like a Nam Vet, just to give them a bit of a challenge. The script makes an effort to lend this credibility by explaining that 'trouble spots' in the world are always chosen for this, and they move on from country to country after each 'hunt' to evade fallout. Secondly, some of the characters are extremely strong, particularly the villains. Lance Henriksen is always good value, and here puts in a wonderfully hard-assed and droll portrayal of the 'Director' (for want of a better title). Legendary movie quote #33: "Now you know why we insist on payment up front." LOL His side-kick, 'Pik', is a superbly sadistic piece of work by Arnold Vosloo. He doesn't overplay it, yet leaves the viewer in no doubt as to his nature. He has a quiet and chilling business-like manner most of the time, but when time comes for an execution you see what a hobby it is for him, with the twinkle in his eye. The two lead females are sympathetic and credible characters, especially policewoman Kasi Lemmons. Unfortunately the same cannot be said for the 'lovable' but ridiculous Uncle Douvee. I guess he was injected into the final phase of the movie to lend a sprinkling of humour, but imo it did not need it. We already have the two main good characters to engage with, and the movie should have been allowed to stand on its gritty and punchy violence and the quite disturbing aspects of human nature. We really care if some of these characters live or die, even the psychos! In a downtown New Orleans scene, one of the 'hunted' is totally unable to get anybody to help him, which made me really angry. All too believable, and really lent credibility to how the company gets away with it. Uncle Douvee... jeez. If you can get past the image of this old fool playing the hero, then fair play to you (maybe I need to 'lighten up'). If you can get past the attempts at a French (or Belgian, whatever) accent by the very American bit-part actor Wilfred Brimley, then you were not getitng properly into the movie in the first place. Sorry to pick on him, but for me it really grated. It's all the more sad when you remember him in his straight-up role as a mafia henchman in 'The Firm': believable and exactly the tone called for here. Bit-part is what it was, though, and the strengths of the movie outweigh the weaknesses. I would have loved to see Harrison Ford or even Bruce Willis in the Van Damme role - with the every-guy credibility and minus the slow motion, please!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's like a drug isn't it, to bring a man down?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hard Target is directed by John Woo and written by Chuck Pfarrer. It stars Jean-Claude Van Damme, Lance Henriksen, Yancy Butler, Arnold Vosloo and Wilford Brimley. Music is by Graeme Revell and cinematography by Russell Carpenter. New Orleans and ex-merchant marine Chance Boudreaux (Damme) is struggling to gain employment on account of some muscular indiscretions. However, after saving Natasha Binder (Butler) from the hands of robbers, he is offered some work by her that pays handsomely. The task is to find out where her father is, a homeless ex-forces man who has mysteriously disappeared. It's a search that leads them to a sick urban safari being run by Emil Fouchon (Henriksen), the prey? Man! After pushing the boundaries of action cinema in Hong Kong, it was only a matter of time before John Woo got lured to America to dabble in the dollar. Hard Target was his first American movie, which in spite of the studio being nervous about his hiring (Sam Raimi was on standby should it implode) and cuts being made on demand for a certificate rating to open it up to a wider audience, it worked out well. It was a financial success, even though there was the inevitable mixed reviews from critics and today it rightly is held in high regard amongst action movie die- hards. OK! Nobody could seriously claim it's a titan of cinema, it's an absurd story derived from The Most Dangerous Game, the acting is of the usual Van Damme kick assery standard (JC pouts and mumbles, Butler is terrible, Brimley is miscast, Henriksen so over the top we almost lose him from our vision) and preposterousness reaches new levels. Yes it's a dumb fun action movie where leaving the brain at the door is a requisite. But what action delights await the faithful, what grace and style does Woo bring to the mayhem, it's a visceral thriller that once it gets the plot initiations out of the way, unleashes beautiful carnage that thunders the chest royally. Can violence be lyrical? In Woo's hands yes, certainly. The action film is one of the most maligned in cinema, but there is great artistry to many of them, to that end Hard Target scores incredibly high. The stunt work is amazing, the choreography of the fight scenes, with Van Damme showing his wonderful skills, are exquisite sights for the action film fan. Woo's tricks involving slow-mo, freeze frames and juddering close ups all get worked out here, quite often forming part of another ballet of bloodshed. Woo and Van Damme were a good fit, the film rocks for those so inclined for such kinetic malarkey, and not even The Muscles from Brussels' mullet can spoil the enjoyment. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What made you want to complicate my life like this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS*** Even for a Jean-Claude Van Damme action movie "Hard Target" is just a bit too hard to take despite all its action scenes as well as Mr. Van Damme's kick boxing & martial art talents. At first the film starts off like the 1932 classic "The Most Dangerous Game" but quickly deteriorates into a mindless and disjointed free for all. With Van Damme as merchant marine Chance Boudreaux taking on an entire army of bikers in the Louisiana bayous lead by the villainous Emil Fouchon played by Lance Henriksen. Totally unbelievable fight & action scenes even for Van Damme to preform with or without a stunt double that has him have more lives in the movie then a dozen cats. There's also Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's love interest in the film Nat Binder, Nancy Butler, who despite being a damsel in distress seems to have trouble keeping a straight face in many of the action as well as love scenes she's in the movie. It was Nat's missing dad, Douglas Pfarrer,who was later found to be murdered that had Van Damme, who was hired by Net to find him, get involved in this holy mess in the first place. And who can forget Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's moon shine drinking uncle Douvee played by William Brimley who about the best, after Lance Henriksen, actor in the film. Who no matter how much booze he drinks is still able to ride his horse without falling off as well as shoot arrows as accurately as Robin Hood. And as things turned out it was the booze, or the flask that he stored it in, that ended up saving his life! The final showdown in the film between Van Damme-Chance Boudreaux-and Emil Fouchon-Lance Henriksen-just went on and on to the point where all the fighting shooting and exploding lost their effect since for a time it didn't effect the two at all. And when it finally ended you couldn't care less who ended up winning but was happy as hell to know the movie, and all the suffering you went through in watching it, was thank God finally over!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good plot, entertaining, but nowhere near a Woo classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a far cry from Woo's masterpeices in Hong Kong. It was his first American movie and one must say that in a lot of ways it is a disappointment. I am not saying that it is a bad movie, but it seems that the creative genius that is John Woo is seriously hindered by the capital focus of the American market. Us Westerners like movies with happy endings and movies that do not challenge us to think. This movie is action but its action is not beautifully crafted within a movie with real characters struggling in a real world. Hard Target is set in New Orleans during a police strike, though this does not seem evident. A group has set itself up where they hire vagrants to run 10 kilometers with $10 000 while they are being chased by hunters. These vagrants are not supposed to have any ties, but unfortunately they chose somebody who does. When his daughter comes to New Orleans to find him dead, she starts asking questions, and brings Van Damme in to help her. The plot is good, but the thing with Woo's movies from Hong Kong is that it is about the characters struggling with themselves and the bad guys were simply around to make their life even harder. No such struggle occurs within this movie. Van Damme, who is simply a sailor that happens to be good at martial arts, is not able to play a character with any depth. Personally I do not think much of his acting ability, and people really only watch his movies to see his moves - and they are not even martial arts. The only reason Van Damme can do these moves is because he is a dancer. The movie plasters John Woo as being the director and attempts to attract people to the movie on this fact. The action is good, and the imagery used is typical of John Woo. He is a brilliant director, but is even better when he is not restrained. I feel that this film is let down in the fact that there is no character struggle in this movie. The characters are not anti-heroes, which is one of the aspects that elevates Woo movies above the others. It is not until Face Off that John Woo's American movies began to stand out. There are two things that seem to form a part of Woo movies. The main characters either begin as friends but slowly drift apart until they are fighting each other at the end, or they are apart and through the struggles that they face, they are drawn together and realise that they need to help each other. Face Off is a completely different idea where the good guy suddenly finds that he is the bad guy and cannot do anything about it. A Bullet in the Head, Too Catch a Thief, and Broken Arrow are examples of the first type, while The Killer and Hard Boiled are examples of the second type. Hard Target doesn't fall into either category. The characters do not entertain me as their struggles are purely action orientated and as such it doesn't grab me as Woo's other movies do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Competent action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DaRick89
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As with many action movies, Hard to Kill's strengths and weaknesses are fairly simple to analyse. It's a competent action thriller, notable for some stylish action scenes that have John Woo's touch; one particularly memorable example is when Chance Boudreaux (Jean-Claude Van Damme) quite literally blasts a bikie thug out a window with a shotgun and a petrol can! These moments pretty much make the film worth seeing by themselves, despite the usual weaknesses in the plotting and JCVD's ever wooden countenance. As JCVD himself noted however, viewers paid the money to see him waste bad guys and he does plenty of this - sometimes in more inventive ways than expected (using snake traps). It very much makes the film worth seeing for action buffs, even though I'm reluctant to give a really high rating based on this alone. The plot is not too extraordinary: a homeless veteran gets murdered by a team of mercenaries led by Emil Fouchoud (Henriksen) and Van Cleaf (Vosloo), after which his daughter Nat (Butler) comes looking for him and commissions Boudreaux, a homeless Cajun merchant marine (!) to help her out after he rescues her from marauding thugs, raising the ire of the mercenary team. A few plot holes are obvious (shouldn't this mercenary team have been dealt with a while ago, police strike or not? Why is JCVD made a CAJUN?), but it works well as a vehicle for blowing stuff up and killing people. The dialogue is pretty standard stuff: some profanity, some hilariously cringeworthy lines ("don't worry about Randall; he's all ears!) and some macho stuff. As for the acting, the villains are better than the heroes. Of course, when JCVD is your hero, that's bound to be the case, with his unconvincing delivery. He has recently shown that he is capable of acting, but he was a long off that in 1993. Still, English is probably his third language (after French and Dutch); Yancy Butler has no such excuses, being quite wooden in a role that doesn't demand that much. Vosloo and Henriksen are much better though. Vosloo has that quiet menace that always makes him a good villain, while Henriksen goes from menacing and purposeful to merrily nuts as Boudreaux causes him more difficulties than expected. Even Wilford Brimley is amusing as Chance's crazy uncle, reeling off some zany lines. In the end, Hard Target is not a great movie, but it's a competent action thriller with some nice stylistic touches from John Woo during the action scenes. Henriksen, Vosloo and Brimley compensate somewhat for JCVD and Butler, but you still shouldn't watch this film for the acting and especially not for the plotting. Action fans generally don't really look for either that much though, so that's alright. Movie-goers looking for a bit more will probably like some of the style, but won't find that much else. 3/5 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Lance Henriksen show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies starring Jean-Claude Van Damme can't be labeled as anything else than "so bad it's good" material. This one makes no exception. Lance Henriksen however, transcends the genre with a grandiose over-the-top performance that's great fun to watch. As to Van Damme, this actor is not merely campy. His lack of charisma, not to mention linguistic competence, is simply astonishing. Butler is a perfect match  she's fake as a Latino soap-opera, although her English is better than Van Damme's. The film's plot is ridiculous and it gets over- violent to the point of being unpleasant, but it's all worth watching for Lance Henriksen's gleefully villainous show-off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    HK Neo Reviews: Hard Target
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (webmaster@thehkneo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director John Woo's first venture into Hollywood was not without its obstacles. With Van Damme being one of Hollywood's bright action stars back in the early 90s, it is pretty much certain that Woo lacked what he received in his later works  control. The film for most of it, seems uneven, especially when there are scenes you can clearly see as Woo's footprints all over it and there are others that are just plain awful. Still, if you ignore the bad acting from Van Damme, poor pacing, poor editing, there is still fun to be had. Namely the majority of the shooting sequences, a wonderful villainous turn by future "The Mummy" star  Lance Henriksen and a few pigeons to boost, Hard Target is really not that bad Neo rates it 6/10. - www.thehkneo.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best Van Damme movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chris1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First saw this movie when i was buying a video of Maximum Risk,which is a decent Van Damme film.So i watched this film and was not disappointed,i was entertained throughout the whole movie.The action was practically non-stop.The storyline is decent enough with ruthless business men hunting homeless war veterans,and the street-wise Chance Boudreaux was going to find out sooner or later,to bad for the bad guys.The action scenes are spot on.When Van Damme first appears,you just know the s**t is going down.In roughly the first half hour of the film sees a fight at a caf&eacute; in which Van Damme breaks a guys arm it is brutal.As the film rolls on,we discover Chance's background and how he himself has experienced the streets.Lance Henrickson is great as the Emil Fouchon chief bad guy,you just love to hate.And Arnold Vosloo as his sidekick Pick Van Cleef was great and funny at times.You just know when he utters the words "Randall,Randall,Randall" that Randall was in for a very bad day.Wilford Brimley as the enjoyable and funny uncle Douvee.The tag-line for this movie is "Don't Hunt What You Cant Kill" and the bad guys should have realised this.This is a decent and enjoyable Van Damme film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High-quality Van Damme at his absolute best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance Boudreaux (Van Damme) is a New Orleans longshoreman who is down on his luck and struggling to find work. Opportunity comes his way when Nat (Butler) hires him to help her find her missing father. As it turns out, her father isn't missing, necessarily, he was a victim of a malevolent gang of "human hunters". Led by Fouchon (Henriksen), and with his second in command Pik Van Cleef (Vosloo), they get their kicks (and get rich) letting weekend warriors pay them to go on the ultimate hunting expedition: for man! But they meet their match with the fearless Chance, a man they cannot kill. Along for the ride is Chance's uncle Douvee (Brimley). Will Chance get his chance at glory? Or, to the human hunters, is he just another HARD TARGET? Hard Target is hands-down one of Van Damme's best. It's explosively entertaining and lives up to the promise of a Van Damme and John Woo team-up. It's everything a combination of those two men could be and should be, and doesn't let the audience down. Once again, this is classic 90's action fun from the golden time when Van Damme movies went to the theater. Back then, we remember joking with our friends that because there's so much slow motion in this movie, if it was all played at regular speed, the film would be about 20 minutes. And it's true, there is a lot of dramatic slo-mo, but it's all for the best. And Van Damme and others get a lot of unnecessarily portentous entrances and exits, which just adds to the style of Hard Target, which is just a tad bit off-kilter. But that's far from a bad thing. It separates itself from its many competitors that way. Besides Van Damme and his absurd hair, the cast assembled for this is just killer: Lance Henriksen is great as the baddie who's so bad, even his piano-playing is evil. Vosloo is also adept at being bad, and his quasi-Scottish (?) accent, well, accentuates his sinister glares. Yancy Butler gives a bug-eyed performance who always seems surprised at the proceedings. But top marks must go to the great Wilford Brimley. In a strange role for him, the barely-intelligible, bow-and-arrow toting, horseback riding uncle is truly lovable and you root for him, even though he doesn't appear until late in the film. That's a tribute to Brimley that the audience can grow to love him so quickly. This movie puts a twist on the time-honored Most Dangerous Game (1932) idea. The formula's been tried before, with varying degrees of success, in everything from Death Ring (1992) to Avenging Force (1986). But Hard Target has plenty of awesome moments, including the extended climax in (what else) an abandoned warehouse. Never one to be afraid of wasting bullets, Woo pulls out all the stops in an extended feast of overkill. It's over-the-top fun everyone should see. On a technical note, the British DVD is longer than the American cut, including more violence. So try to track that down if you can, for the complete picture. Go down to the bayou tonight for some high-octane, high-quality Van Damme at his absolute best. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How can something so bad be this good?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put Hard Target is a terrible movie. It is a testament to how big Jean Claude Van Damme really was in the early nineties. He was a master of the action/Martial Arts film. Nearly every scene in this film feels like a spoof...a joke and yet its not at all. I am actually surprised Van Damme would do something like this given his ego because couldn't he see just how ridiculous it was. Its like the ultimate spoof of the 80's action genre. Who better to do it than John Woo? I constantly hear how legendary this director is but I often wonder if this opinion too is a joke. The guy almost killed the Mission Impossible franchise with ridiculous hair, constant slow motion camera tricks, and ridiculous "hero" analogies. And here we have Hard Target with the exact same MO. Hair, slow-mo, hero analogies all over again. Some day I might have someone watch this film and tell me how many times he goes into slow motion which is not dramatic in this case or even remotely "cool" but instead looks ridiculous, hokey and dumb. Especially when your hero is sporting a greasy, stringy mullet. Now all this being said, I'll be darned if this isn't some sort of bizarre cheeky entertainment. Maybe because its laughable or just how incredibly outlandish the action scenes are. The scene with Van Damme standing on the seat of a dirt bike, shooting bad guys and then rolling over the top of their car...is just too ridiculously legendary to not be cool. This is the stuff Chuck Norris wishes he had under his belt. Jean Claude Van Damme is not a great actor, never was. But there is no arguing his chemistry in the 90's. There is just something slick and cool about that enormous ego that he has. His character in Hard Target is just about portrayed as God-like. He has this untouchable, swoon at his feet persona that it so ridiculous that its fun to watch. Yancy Butler is the stereotypical required female partner to Van Damme. She does alright and certainly has the "deer in the headlights" look down pat. She literally looks 90% of the time like she is on an infomercial that is selling Jean Claude Van Damme and she wants it! Her longing looks and open mouthed gaping is hilarious. Their chemistry is okay but really sort of unnecessary. Lance Henriksen is actually the perfect action hero villain. He has the look down and he a cold blooded horrifying killer. He probably has the best role in the entire film. He is a very worthy action film villain. Not to be outdone Arnold Vosloo is a brilliant right hand man to Henriksen. He could have easily been the lead villain in his own right. He is equally as cold and calculating and you get two great final battles when Van Damme takes them on. Wilford Brimley makes a cameo as the obligatory old man that the hero cares about. John Woo gets constant praise from fans for being a "brilliant" action director but his style is always the same and is so awkward at times. He has to be the king of overusing slow motion and when you pair it together with Van Damme and this story it just makes it even more cheesy. Now all this being said Hard Target has found its niche. Twenty years later and it can sit comfortably in action classic status. You can laugh at it and marvel at the action scenes. Plenty of explosions and gun fights and non-stop action especially towards the end of the movie. I can give them kudos for actually creating a solid story even if its a little cookie cutter and predictable. Ultimately Hard Target is nothing but sheer entertainment no matter how you take it or look at it. Nothing wrong with that but it certainly makes a lot of grievous errors in film making and they should just be lucky that it will likely continue to achieve cult status amongst action fans and Van Damme junkies. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot going for it...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phillipfawcett
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but Claude Van Damme is not it! Not a fan, here, of a guy who has more wood in him than the Bastoin forest. Maybe I'm just not a karate fan: it always seems to me that by the time you've finishing spinning and getting your leg up, any adversary could have laid you out, end of. The slow-motion sequences just make me want to give the guy a Coors Light, so he can take his pay check and get out of there. Seagal is a much more engaging actor for me, and his Aikido seems more credible. However, I find this movie an enjoyable ride! Firstly, the premise is powerful and interesting. Sick gun-loving sons- of-bitches run a business which stages real-life hunts of some poor wretch who 'will not be missed'. They always take care to choose somebody with a fighting background, like a Nam Vet, just to give them a bit of a challenge. The script makes an effort to lend this credibility by explaining that 'trouble spots' in the world are always chosen for this, and they move on from country to country after each 'hunt' to evade fallout. Secondly, some of the characters are extremely strong, particularly the villains. Lance Henriksen is always good value, and here puts in a wonderfully hard-assed and droll portrayal of the 'Director' (for want of a better title). Legendary movie quote #33: "Now you know why we insist on payment up front." LOL His side-kick, 'Pik', is a superbly sadistic piece of work by Arnold Vosloo. He doesn't overplay it, yet leaves the viewer in no doubt as to his nature. He has a quiet and chilling business-like manner most of the time, but when time comes for an execution you see what a hobby it is for him, with the twinkle in his eye. The two lead females are sympathetic and credible characters, especially policewoman Kasi Lemmons. Unfortunately the same cannot be said for the 'lovable' but ridiculous Uncle Douvee. I guess he was injected into the final phase of the movie to lend a sprinkling of humour, but imo it did not need it. We already have the two main good characters to engage with, and the movie should have been allowed to stand on its gritty and punchy violence and the quite disturbing aspects of human nature. We really care if some of these characters live or die, even the psychos! In a downtown New Orleans scene, one of the 'hunted' is totally unable to get anybody to help him, which made me really angry. All too believable, and really lent credibility to how the company gets away with it. Uncle Douvee... jeez. If you can get past the image of this old fool playing the hero, then fair play to you (maybe I need to 'lighten up'). If you can get past the attempts at a French (or Belgian, whatever) accent by the very American bit-part actor Wilfred Brimley, then you were not getitng properly into the movie in the first place. Sorry to pick on him, but for me it really grated. It's all the more sad when you remember him in his straight-up role as a mafia henchman in 'The Firm': believable and exactly the tone called for here. Bit-part is what it was, though, and the strengths of the movie outweigh the weaknesses. I would have loved to see Harrison Ford or even Bruce Willis in the Van Damme role - with the every-guy credibility and minus the slow motion, please!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's like a drug isn't it, to bring a man down?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hard Target is directed by John Woo and written by Chuck Pfarrer. It stars Jean-Claude Van Damme, Lance Henriksen, Yancy Butler, Arnold Vosloo and Wilford Brimley. Music is by Graeme Revell and cinematography by Russell Carpenter. New Orleans and ex-merchant marine Chance Boudreaux (Damme) is struggling to gain employment on account of some muscular indiscretions. However, after saving Natasha Binder (Butler) from the hands of robbers, he is offered some work by her that pays handsomely. The task is to find out where her father is, a homeless ex-forces man who has mysteriously disappeared. It's a search that leads them to a sick urban safari being run by Emil Fouchon (Henriksen), the prey? Man! After pushing the boundaries of action cinema in Hong Kong, it was only a matter of time before John Woo got lured to America to dabble in the dollar. Hard Target was his first American movie, which in spite of the studio being nervous about his hiring (Sam Raimi was on standby should it implode) and cuts being made on demand for a certificate rating to open it up to a wider audience, it worked out well. It was a financial success, even though there was the inevitable mixed reviews from critics and today it rightly is held in high regard amongst action movie die- hards. OK! Nobody could seriously claim it's a titan of cinema, it's an absurd story derived from The Most Dangerous Game, the acting is of the usual Van Damme kick assery standard (JC pouts and mumbles, Butler is terrible, Brimley is miscast, Henriksen so over the top we almost lose him from our vision) and preposterousness reaches new levels. Yes it's a dumb fun action movie where leaving the brain at the door is a requisite. But what action delights await the faithful, what grace and style does Woo bring to the mayhem, it's a visceral thriller that once it gets the plot initiations out of the way, unleashes beautiful carnage that thunders the chest royally. Can violence be lyrical? In Woo's hands yes, certainly. The action film is one of the most maligned in cinema, but there is great artistry to many of them, to that end Hard Target scores incredibly high. The stunt work is amazing, the choreography of the fight scenes, with Van Damme showing his wonderful skills, are exquisite sights for the action film fan. Woo's tricks involving slow-mo, freeze frames and juddering close ups all get worked out here, quite often forming part of another ballet of bloodshed. Woo and Van Damme were a good fit, the film rocks for those so inclined for such kinetic malarkey, and not even The Muscles from Brussels' mullet can spoil the enjoyment. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What made you want to complicate my life like this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS*** Even for a Jean-Claude Van Damme action movie "Hard Target" is just a bit too hard to take despite all its action scenes as well as Mr. Van Damme's kick boxing & martial art talents. At first the film starts off like the 1932 classic "The Most Dangerous Game" but quickly deteriorates into a mindless and disjointed free for all. With Van Damme as merchant marine Chance Boudreaux taking on an entire army of bikers in the Louisiana bayous lead by the villainous Emil Fouchon played by Lance Henriksen. Totally unbelievable fight & action scenes even for Van Damme to preform with or without a stunt double that has him have more lives in the movie then a dozen cats. There's also Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's love interest in the film Nat Binder, Nancy Butler, who despite being a damsel in distress seems to have trouble keeping a straight face in many of the action as well as love scenes she's in the movie. It was Nat's missing dad, Douglas Pfarrer,who was later found to be murdered that had Van Damme, who was hired by Net to find him, get involved in this holy mess in the first place. And who can forget Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's moon shine drinking uncle Douvee played by William Brimley who about the best, after Lance Henriksen, actor in the film. Who no matter how much booze he drinks is still able to ride his horse without falling off as well as shoot arrows as accurately as Robin Hood. And as things turned out it was the booze, or the flask that he stored it in, that ended up saving his life! The final showdown in the film between Van Damme-Chance Boudreaux-and Emil Fouchon-Lance Henriksen-just went on and on to the point where all the fighting shooting and exploding lost their effect since for a time it didn't effect the two at all. And when it finally ended you couldn't care less who ended up winning but was happy as hell to know the movie, and all the suffering you went through in watching it, was thank God finally over!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good plot, entertaining, but nowhere near a Woo classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a far cry from Woo's masterpeices in Hong Kong. It was his first American movie and one must say that in a lot of ways it is a disappointment. I am not saying that it is a bad movie, but it seems that the creative genius that is John Woo is seriously hindered by the capital focus of the American market. Us Westerners like movies with happy endings and movies that do not challenge us to think. This movie is action but its action is not beautifully crafted within a movie with real characters struggling in a real world. Hard Target is set in New Orleans during a police strike, though this does not seem evident. A group has set itself up where they hire vagrants to run 10 kilometers with $10 000 while they are being chased by hunters. These vagrants are not supposed to have any ties, but unfortunately they chose somebody who does. When his daughter comes to New Orleans to find him dead, she starts asking questions, and brings Van Damme in to help her. The plot is good, but the thing with Woo's movies from Hong Kong is that it is about the characters struggling with themselves and the bad guys were simply around to make their life even harder. No such struggle occurs within this movie. Van Damme, who is simply a sailor that happens to be good at martial arts, is not able to play a character with any depth. Personally I do not think much of his acting ability, and people really only watch his movies to see his moves - and they are not even martial arts. The only reason Van Damme can do these moves is because he is a dancer. The movie plasters John Woo as being the director and attempts to attract people to the movie on this fact. The action is good, and the imagery used is typical of John Woo. He is a brilliant director, but is even better when he is not restrained. I feel that this film is let down in the fact that there is no character struggle in this movie. The characters are not anti-heroes, which is one of the aspects that elevates Woo movies above the others. It is not until Face Off that John Woo's American movies began to stand out. There are two things that seem to form a part of Woo movies. The main characters either begin as friends but slowly drift apart until they are fighting each other at the end, or they are apart and through the struggles that they face, they are drawn together and realise that they need to help each other. Face Off is a completely different idea where the good guy suddenly finds that he is the bad guy and cannot do anything about it. A Bullet in the Head, Too Catch a Thief, and Broken Arrow are examples of the first type, while The Killer and Hard Boiled are examples of the second type. Hard Target doesn't fall into either category. The characters do not entertain me as their struggles are purely action orientated and as such it doesn't grab me as Woo's other movies do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Competent action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DaRick89
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As with many action movies, Hard to Kill's strengths and weaknesses are fairly simple to analyse. It's a competent action thriller, notable for some stylish action scenes that have John Woo's touch; one particularly memorable example is when Chance Boudreaux (Jean-Claude Van Damme) quite literally blasts a bikie thug out a window with a shotgun and a petrol can! These moments pretty much make the film worth seeing by themselves, despite the usual weaknesses in the plotting and JCVD's ever wooden countenance. As JCVD himself noted however, viewers paid the money to see him waste bad guys and he does plenty of this - sometimes in more inventive ways than expected (using snake traps). It very much makes the film worth seeing for action buffs, even though I'm reluctant to give a really high rating based on this alone. The plot is not too extraordinary: a homeless veteran gets murdered by a team of mercenaries led by Emil Fouchoud (Henriksen) and Van Cleaf (Vosloo), after which his daughter Nat (Butler) comes looking for him and commissions Boudreaux, a homeless Cajun merchant marine (!) to help her out after he rescues her from marauding thugs, raising the ire of the mercenary team. A few plot holes are obvious (shouldn't this mercenary team have been dealt with a while ago, police strike or not? Why is JCVD made a CAJUN?), but it works well as a vehicle for blowing stuff up and killing people. The dialogue is pretty standard stuff: some profanity, some hilariously cringeworthy lines ("don't worry about Randall; he's all ears!) and some macho stuff. As for the acting, the villains are better than the heroes. Of course, when JCVD is your hero, that's bound to be the case, with his unconvincing delivery. He has recently shown that he is capable of acting, but he was a long off that in 1993. Still, English is probably his third language (after French and Dutch); Yancy Butler has no such excuses, being quite wooden in a role that doesn't demand that much. Vosloo and Henriksen are much better though. Vosloo has that quiet menace that always makes him a good villain, while Henriksen goes from menacing and purposeful to merrily nuts as Boudreaux causes him more difficulties than expected. Even Wilford Brimley is amusing as Chance's crazy uncle, reeling off some zany lines. In the end, Hard Target is not a great movie, but it's a competent action thriller with some nice stylistic touches from John Woo during the action scenes. Henriksen, Vosloo and Brimley compensate somewhat for JCVD and Butler, but you still shouldn't watch this film for the acting and especially not for the plotting. Action fans generally don't really look for either that much though, so that's alright. Movie-goers looking for a bit more will probably like some of the style, but won't find that much else. 3/5 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Lance Henriksen show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies starring Jean-Claude Van Damme can't be labeled as anything else than "so bad it's good" material. This one makes no exception. Lance Henriksen however, transcends the genre with a grandiose over-the-top performance that's great fun to watch. As to Van Damme, this actor is not merely campy. His lack of charisma, not to mention linguistic competence, is simply astonishing. Butler is a perfect match  she's fake as a Latino soap-opera, although her English is better than Van Damme's. The film's plot is ridiculous and it gets over- violent to the point of being unpleasant, but it's all worth watching for Lance Henriksen's gleefully villainous show-off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    HK Neo Reviews: Hard Target
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (webmaster@thehkneo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director John Woo's first venture into Hollywood was not without its obstacles. With Van Damme being one of Hollywood's bright action stars back in the early 90s, it is pretty much certain that Woo lacked what he received in his later works  control. The film for most of it, seems uneven, especially when there are scenes you can clearly see as Woo's footprints all over it and there are others that are just plain awful. Still, if you ignore the bad acting from Van Damme, poor pacing, poor editing, there is still fun to be had. Namely the majority of the shooting sequences, a wonderful villainous turn by future "The Mummy" star  Lance Henriksen and a few pigeons to boost, Hard Target is really not that bad Neo rates it 6/10. - www.thehkneo.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best Van Damme movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chris1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First saw this movie when i was buying a video of Maximum Risk,which is a decent Van Damme film.So i watched this film and was not disappointed,i was entertained throughout the whole movie.The action was practically non-stop.The storyline is decent enough with ruthless business men hunting homeless war veterans,and the street-wise Chance Boudreaux was going to find out sooner or later,to bad for the bad guys.The action scenes are spot on.When Van Damme first appears,you just know the s**t is going down.In roughly the first half hour of the film sees a fight at a caf&eacute; in which Van Damme breaks a guys arm it is brutal.As the film rolls on,we discover Chance's background and how he himself has experienced the streets.Lance Henrickson is great as the Emil Fouchon chief bad guy,you just love to hate.And Arnold Vosloo as his sidekick Pick Van Cleef was great and funny at times.You just know when he utters the words "Randall,Randall,Randall" that Randall was in for a very bad day.Wilford Brimley as the enjoyable and funny uncle Douvee.The tag-line for this movie is "Don't Hunt What You Cant Kill" and the bad guys should have realised this.This is a decent and enjoyable Van Damme film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High-quality Van Damme at his absolute best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance Boudreaux (Van Damme) is a New Orleans longshoreman who is down on his luck and struggling to find work. Opportunity comes his way when Nat (Butler) hires him to help her find her missing father. As it turns out, her father isn't missing, necessarily, he was a victim of a malevolent gang of "human hunters". Led by Fouchon (Henriksen), and with his second in command Pik Van Cleef (Vosloo), they get their kicks (and get rich) letting weekend warriors pay them to go on the ultimate hunting expedition: for man! But they meet their match with the fearless Chance, a man they cannot kill. Along for the ride is Chance's uncle Douvee (Brimley). Will Chance get his chance at glory? Or, to the human hunters, is he just another HARD TARGET? Hard Target is hands-down one of Van Damme's best. It's explosively entertaining and lives up to the promise of a Van Damme and John Woo team-up. It's everything a combination of those two men could be and should be, and doesn't let the audience down. Once again, this is classic 90's action fun from the golden time when Van Damme movies went to the theater. Back then, we remember joking with our friends that because there's so much slow motion in this movie, if it was all played at regular speed, the film would be about 20 minutes. And it's true, there is a lot of dramatic slo-mo, but it's all for the best. And Van Damme and others get a lot of unnecessarily portentous entrances and exits, which just adds to the style of Hard Target, which is just a tad bit off-kilter. But that's far from a bad thing. It separates itself from its many competitors that way. Besides Van Damme and his absurd hair, the cast assembled for this is just killer: Lance Henriksen is great as the baddie who's so bad, even his piano-playing is evil. Vosloo is also adept at being bad, and his quasi-Scottish (?) accent, well, accentuates his sinister glares. Yancy Butler gives a bug-eyed performance who always seems surprised at the proceedings. But top marks must go to the great Wilford Brimley. In a strange role for him, the barely-intelligible, bow-and-arrow toting, horseback riding uncle is truly lovable and you root for him, even though he doesn't appear until late in the film. That's a tribute to Brimley that the audience can grow to love him so quickly. This movie puts a twist on the time-honored Most Dangerous Game (1932) idea. The formula's been tried before, with varying degrees of success, in everything from Death Ring (1992) to Avenging Force (1986). But Hard Target has plenty of awesome moments, including the extended climax in (what else) an abandoned warehouse. Never one to be afraid of wasting bullets, Woo pulls out all the stops in an extended feast of overkill. It's over-the-top fun everyone should see. On a technical note, the British DVD is longer than the American cut, including more violence. So try to track that down if you can, for the complete picture. Go down to the bayou tonight for some high-octane, high-quality Van Damme at his absolute best. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How can something so bad be this good?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put Hard Target is a terrible movie. It is a testament to how big Jean Claude Van Damme really was in the early nineties. He was a master of the action/Martial Arts film. Nearly every scene in this film feels like a spoof...a joke and yet its not at all. I am actually surprised Van Damme would do something like this given his ego because couldn't he see just how ridiculous it was. Its like the ultimate spoof of the 80's action genre. Who better to do it than John Woo? I constantly hear how legendary this director is but I often wonder if this opinion too is a joke. The guy almost killed the Mission Impossible franchise with ridiculous hair, constant slow motion camera tricks, and ridiculous "hero" analogies. And here we have Hard Target with the exact same MO. Hair, slow-mo, hero analogies all over again. Some day I might have someone watch this film and tell me how many times he goes into slow motion which is not dramatic in this case or even remotely "cool" but instead looks ridiculous, hokey and dumb. Especially when your hero is sporting a greasy, stringy mullet. Now all this being said, I'll be darned if this isn't some sort of bizarre cheeky entertainment. Maybe because its laughable or just how incredibly outlandish the action scenes are. The scene with Van Damme standing on the seat of a dirt bike, shooting bad guys and then rolling over the top of their car...is just too ridiculously legendary to not be cool. This is the stuff Chuck Norris wishes he had under his belt. Jean Claude Van Damme is not a great actor, never was. But there is no arguing his chemistry in the 90's. There is just something slick and cool about that enormous ego that he has. His character in Hard Target is just about portrayed as God-like. He has this untouchable, swoon at his feet persona that it so ridiculous that its fun to watch. Yancy Butler is the stereotypical required female partner to Van Damme. She does alright and certainly has the "deer in the headlights" look down pat. She literally looks 90% of the time like she is on an infomercial that is selling Jean Claude Van Damme and she wants it! Her longing looks and open mouthed gaping is hilarious. Their chemistry is okay but really sort of unnecessary. Lance Henriksen is actually the perfect action hero villain. He has the look down and he a cold blooded horrifying killer. He probably has the best role in the entire film. He is a very worthy action film villain. Not to be outdone Arnold Vosloo is a brilliant right hand man to Henriksen. He could have easily been the lead villain in his own right. He is equally as cold and calculating and you get two great final battles when Van Damme takes them on. Wilford Brimley makes a cameo as the obligatory old man that the hero cares about. John Woo gets constant praise from fans for being a "brilliant" action director but his style is always the same and is so awkward at times. He has to be the king of overusing slow motion and when you pair it together with Van Damme and this story it just makes it even more cheesy. Now all this being said Hard Target has found its niche. Twenty years later and it can sit comfortably in action classic status. You can laugh at it and marvel at the action scenes. Plenty of explosions and gun fights and non-stop action especially towards the end of the movie. I can give them kudos for actually creating a solid story even if its a little cookie cutter and predictable. Ultimately Hard Target is nothing but sheer entertainment no matter how you take it or look at it. Nothing wrong with that but it certainly makes a lot of grievous errors in film making and they should just be lucky that it will likely continue to achieve cult status amongst action fans and Van Damme junkies. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot going for it...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phillipfawcett
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but Claude Van Damme is not it! Not a fan, here, of a guy who has more wood in him than the Bastoin forest. Maybe I'm just not a karate fan: it always seems to me that by the time you've finishing spinning and getting your leg up, any adversary could have laid you out, end of. The slow-motion sequences just make me want to give the guy a Coors Light, so he can take his pay check and get out of there. Seagal is a much more engaging actor for me, and his Aikido seems more credible. However, I find this movie an enjoyable ride! Firstly, the premise is powerful and interesting. Sick gun-loving sons- of-bitches run a business which stages real-life hunts of some poor wretch who 'will not be missed'. They always take care to choose somebody with a fighting background, like a Nam Vet, just to give them a bit of a challenge. The script makes an effort to lend this credibility by explaining that 'trouble spots' in the world are always chosen for this, and they move on from country to country after each 'hunt' to evade fallout. Secondly, some of the characters are extremely strong, particularly the villains. Lance Henriksen is always good value, and here puts in a wonderfully hard-assed and droll portrayal of the 'Director' (for want of a better title). Legendary movie quote #33: "Now you know why we insist on payment up front." LOL His side-kick, 'Pik', is a superbly sadistic piece of work by Arnold Vosloo. He doesn't overplay it, yet leaves the viewer in no doubt as to his nature. He has a quiet and chilling business-like manner most of the time, but when time comes for an execution you see what a hobby it is for him, with the twinkle in his eye. The two lead females are sympathetic and credible characters, especially policewoman Kasi Lemmons. Unfortunately the same cannot be said for the 'lovable' but ridiculous Uncle Douvee. I guess he was injected into the final phase of the movie to lend a sprinkling of humour, but imo it did not need it. We already have the two main good characters to engage with, and the movie should have been allowed to stand on its gritty and punchy violence and the quite disturbing aspects of human nature. We really care if some of these characters live or die, even the psychos! In a downtown New Orleans scene, one of the 'hunted' is totally unable to get anybody to help him, which made me really angry. All too believable, and really lent credibility to how the company gets away with it. Uncle Douvee... jeez. If you can get past the image of this old fool playing the hero, then fair play to you (maybe I need to 'lighten up'). If you can get past the attempts at a French (or Belgian, whatever) accent by the very American bit-part actor Wilfred Brimley, then you were not getitng properly into the movie in the first place. Sorry to pick on him, but for me it really grated. It's all the more sad when you remember him in his straight-up role as a mafia henchman in 'The Firm': believable and exactly the tone called for here. Bit-part is what it was, though, and the strengths of the movie outweigh the weaknesses. I would have loved to see Harrison Ford or even Bruce Willis in the Van Damme role - with the every-guy credibility and minus the slow motion, please!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's like a drug isn't it, to bring a man down?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hard Target is directed by John Woo and written by Chuck Pfarrer. It stars Jean-Claude Van Damme, Lance Henriksen, Yancy Butler, Arnold Vosloo and Wilford Brimley. Music is by Graeme Revell and cinematography by Russell Carpenter. New Orleans and ex-merchant marine Chance Boudreaux (Damme) is struggling to gain employment on account of some muscular indiscretions. However, after saving Natasha Binder (Butler) from the hands of robbers, he is offered some work by her that pays handsomely. The task is to find out where her father is, a homeless ex-forces man who has mysteriously disappeared. It's a search that leads them to a sick urban safari being run by Emil Fouchon (Henriksen), the prey? Man! After pushing the boundaries of action cinema in Hong Kong, it was only a matter of time before John Woo got lured to America to dabble in the dollar. Hard Target was his first American movie, which in spite of the studio being nervous about his hiring (Sam Raimi was on standby should it implode) and cuts being made on demand for a certificate rating to open it up to a wider audience, it worked out well. It was a financial success, even though there was the inevitable mixed reviews from critics and today it rightly is held in high regard amongst action movie die- hards. OK! Nobody could seriously claim it's a titan of cinema, it's an absurd story derived from The Most Dangerous Game, the acting is of the usual Van Damme kick assery standard (JC pouts and mumbles, Butler is terrible, Brimley is miscast, Henriksen so over the top we almost lose him from our vision) and preposterousness reaches new levels. Yes it's a dumb fun action movie where leaving the brain at the door is a requisite. But what action delights await the faithful, what grace and style does Woo bring to the mayhem, it's a visceral thriller that once it gets the plot initiations out of the way, unleashes beautiful carnage that thunders the chest royally. Can violence be lyrical? In Woo's hands yes, certainly. The action film is one of the most maligned in cinema, but there is great artistry to many of them, to that end Hard Target scores incredibly high. The stunt work is amazing, the choreography of the fight scenes, with Van Damme showing his wonderful skills, are exquisite sights for the action film fan. Woo's tricks involving slow-mo, freeze frames and juddering close ups all get worked out here, quite often forming part of another ballet of bloodshed. Woo and Van Damme were a good fit, the film rocks for those so inclined for such kinetic malarkey, and not even The Muscles from Brussels' mullet can spoil the enjoyment. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What made you want to complicate my life like this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS*** Even for a Jean-Claude Van Damme action movie "Hard Target" is just a bit too hard to take despite all its action scenes as well as Mr. Van Damme's kick boxing & martial art talents. At first the film starts off like the 1932 classic "The Most Dangerous Game" but quickly deteriorates into a mindless and disjointed free for all. With Van Damme as merchant marine Chance Boudreaux taking on an entire army of bikers in the Louisiana bayous lead by the villainous Emil Fouchon played by Lance Henriksen. Totally unbelievable fight & action scenes even for Van Damme to preform with or without a stunt double that has him have more lives in the movie then a dozen cats. There's also Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's love interest in the film Nat Binder, Nancy Butler, who despite being a damsel in distress seems to have trouble keeping a straight face in many of the action as well as love scenes she's in the movie. It was Nat's missing dad, Douglas Pfarrer,who was later found to be murdered that had Van Damme, who was hired by Net to find him, get involved in this holy mess in the first place. And who can forget Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's moon shine drinking uncle Douvee played by William Brimley who about the best, after Lance Henriksen, actor in the film. Who no matter how much booze he drinks is still able to ride his horse without falling off as well as shoot arrows as accurately as Robin Hood. And as things turned out it was the booze, or the flask that he stored it in, that ended up saving his life! The final showdown in the film between Van Damme-Chance Boudreaux-and Emil Fouchon-Lance Henriksen-just went on and on to the point where all the fighting shooting and exploding lost their effect since for a time it didn't effect the two at all. And when it finally ended you couldn't care less who ended up winning but was happy as hell to know the movie, and all the suffering you went through in watching it, was thank God finally over!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good plot, entertaining, but nowhere near a Woo classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a far cry from Woo's masterpeices in Hong Kong. It was his first American movie and one must say that in a lot of ways it is a disappointment. I am not saying that it is a bad movie, but it seems that the creative genius that is John Woo is seriously hindered by the capital focus of the American market. Us Westerners like movies with happy endings and movies that do not challenge us to think. This movie is action but its action is not beautifully crafted within a movie with real characters struggling in a real world. Hard Target is set in New Orleans during a police strike, though this does not seem evident. A group has set itself up where they hire vagrants to run 10 kilometers with $10 000 while they are being chased by hunters. These vagrants are not supposed to have any ties, but unfortunately they chose somebody who does. When his daughter comes to New Orleans to find him dead, she starts asking questions, and brings Van Damme in to help her. The plot is good, but the thing with Woo's movies from Hong Kong is that it is about the characters struggling with themselves and the bad guys were simply around to make their life even harder. No such struggle occurs within this movie. Van Damme, who is simply a sailor that happens to be good at martial arts, is not able to play a character with any depth. Personally I do not think much of his acting ability, and people really only watch his movies to see his moves - and they are not even martial arts. The only reason Van Damme can do these moves is because he is a dancer. The movie plasters John Woo as being the director and attempts to attract people to the movie on this fact. The action is good, and the imagery used is typical of John Woo. He is a brilliant director, but is even better when he is not restrained. I feel that this film is let down in the fact that there is no character struggle in this movie. The characters are not anti-heroes, which is one of the aspects that elevates Woo movies above the others. It is not until Face Off that John Woo's American movies began to stand out. There are two things that seem to form a part of Woo movies. The main characters either begin as friends but slowly drift apart until they are fighting each other at the end, or they are apart and through the struggles that they face, they are drawn together and realise that they need to help each other. Face Off is a completely different idea where the good guy suddenly finds that he is the bad guy and cannot do anything about it. A Bullet in the Head, Too Catch a Thief, and Broken Arrow are examples of the first type, while The Killer and Hard Boiled are examples of the second type. Hard Target doesn't fall into either category. The characters do not entertain me as their struggles are purely action orientated and as such it doesn't grab me as Woo's other movies do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Competent action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DaRick89
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As with many action movies, Hard to Kill's strengths and weaknesses are fairly simple to analyse. It's a competent action thriller, notable for some stylish action scenes that have John Woo's touch; one particularly memorable example is when Chance Boudreaux (Jean-Claude Van Damme) quite literally blasts a bikie thug out a window with a shotgun and a petrol can! These moments pretty much make the film worth seeing by themselves, despite the usual weaknesses in the plotting and JCVD's ever wooden countenance. As JCVD himself noted however, viewers paid the money to see him waste bad guys and he does plenty of this - sometimes in more inventive ways than expected (using snake traps). It very much makes the film worth seeing for action buffs, even though I'm reluctant to give a really high rating based on this alone. The plot is not too extraordinary: a homeless veteran gets murdered by a team of mercenaries led by Emil Fouchoud (Henriksen) and Van Cleaf (Vosloo), after which his daughter Nat (Butler) comes looking for him and commissions Boudreaux, a homeless Cajun merchant marine (!) to help her out after he rescues her from marauding thugs, raising the ire of the mercenary team. A few plot holes are obvious (shouldn't this mercenary team have been dealt with a while ago, police strike or not? Why is JCVD made a CAJUN?), but it works well as a vehicle for blowing stuff up and killing people. The dialogue is pretty standard stuff: some profanity, some hilariously cringeworthy lines ("don't worry about Randall; he's all ears!) and some macho stuff. As for the acting, the villains are better than the heroes. Of course, when JCVD is your hero, that's bound to be the case, with his unconvincing delivery. He has recently shown that he is capable of acting, but he was a long off that in 1993. Still, English is probably his third language (after French and Dutch); Yancy Butler has no such excuses, being quite wooden in a role that doesn't demand that much. Vosloo and Henriksen are much better though. Vosloo has that quiet menace that always makes him a good villain, while Henriksen goes from menacing and purposeful to merrily nuts as Boudreaux causes him more difficulties than expected. Even Wilford Brimley is amusing as Chance's crazy uncle, reeling off some zany lines. In the end, Hard Target is not a great movie, but it's a competent action thriller with some nice stylistic touches from John Woo during the action scenes. Henriksen, Vosloo and Brimley compensate somewhat for JCVD and Butler, but you still shouldn't watch this film for the acting and especially not for the plotting. Action fans generally don't really look for either that much though, so that's alright. Movie-goers looking for a bit more will probably like some of the style, but won't find that much else. 3/5 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Lance Henriksen show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies starring Jean-Claude Van Damme can't be labeled as anything else than "so bad it's good" material. This one makes no exception. Lance Henriksen however, transcends the genre with a grandiose over-the-top performance that's great fun to watch. As to Van Damme, this actor is not merely campy. His lack of charisma, not to mention linguistic competence, is simply astonishing. Butler is a perfect match  she's fake as a Latino soap-opera, although her English is better than Van Damme's. The film's plot is ridiculous and it gets over- violent to the point of being unpleasant, but it's all worth watching for Lance Henriksen's gleefully villainous show-off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    HK Neo Reviews: Hard Target
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (webmaster@thehkneo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director John Woo's first venture into Hollywood was not without its obstacles. With Van Damme being one of Hollywood's bright action stars back in the early 90s, it is pretty much certain that Woo lacked what he received in his later works  control. The film for most of it, seems uneven, especially when there are scenes you can clearly see as Woo's footprints all over it and there are others that are just plain awful. Still, if you ignore the bad acting from Van Damme, poor pacing, poor editing, there is still fun to be had. Namely the majority of the shooting sequences, a wonderful villainous turn by future "The Mummy" star  Lance Henriksen and a few pigeons to boost, Hard Target is really not that bad Neo rates it 6/10. - www.thehkneo.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best Van Damme movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chris1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First saw this movie when i was buying a video of Maximum Risk,which is a decent Van Damme film.So i watched this film and was not disappointed,i was entertained throughout the whole movie.The action was practically non-stop.The storyline is decent enough with ruthless business men hunting homeless war veterans,and the street-wise Chance Boudreaux was going to find out sooner or later,to bad for the bad guys.The action scenes are spot on.When Van Damme first appears,you just know the s**t is going down.In roughly the first half hour of the film sees a fight at a caf&eacute; in which Van Damme breaks a guys arm it is brutal.As the film rolls on,we discover Chance's background and how he himself has experienced the streets.Lance Henrickson is great as the Emil Fouchon chief bad guy,you just love to hate.And Arnold Vosloo as his sidekick Pick Van Cleef was great and funny at times.You just know when he utters the words "Randall,Randall,Randall" that Randall was in for a very bad day.Wilford Brimley as the enjoyable and funny uncle Douvee.The tag-line for this movie is "Don't Hunt What You Cant Kill" and the bad guys should have realised this.This is a decent and enjoyable Van Damme film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High-quality Van Damme at his absolute best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance Boudreaux (Van Damme) is a New Orleans longshoreman who is down on his luck and struggling to find work. Opportunity comes his way when Nat (Butler) hires him to help her find her missing father. As it turns out, her father isn't missing, necessarily, he was a victim of a malevolent gang of "human hunters". Led by Fouchon (Henriksen), and with his second in command Pik Van Cleef (Vosloo), they get their kicks (and get rich) letting weekend warriors pay them to go on the ultimate hunting expedition: for man! But they meet their match with the fearless Chance, a man they cannot kill. Along for the ride is Chance's uncle Douvee (Brimley). Will Chance get his chance at glory? Or, to the human hunters, is he just another HARD TARGET? Hard Target is hands-down one of Van Damme's best. It's explosively entertaining and lives up to the promise of a Van Damme and John Woo team-up. It's everything a combination of those two men could be and should be, and doesn't let the audience down. Once again, this is classic 90's action fun from the golden time when Van Damme movies went to the theater. Back then, we remember joking with our friends that because there's so much slow motion in this movie, if it was all played at regular speed, the film would be about 20 minutes. And it's true, there is a lot of dramatic slo-mo, but it's all for the best. And Van Damme and others get a lot of unnecessarily portentous entrances and exits, which just adds to the style of Hard Target, which is just a tad bit off-kilter. But that's far from a bad thing. It separates itself from its many competitors that way. Besides Van Damme and his absurd hair, the cast assembled for this is just killer: Lance Henriksen is great as the baddie who's so bad, even his piano-playing is evil. Vosloo is also adept at being bad, and his quasi-Scottish (?) accent, well, accentuates his sinister glares. Yancy Butler gives a bug-eyed performance who always seems surprised at the proceedings. But top marks must go to the great Wilford Brimley. In a strange role for him, the barely-intelligible, bow-and-arrow toting, horseback riding uncle is truly lovable and you root for him, even though he doesn't appear until late in the film. That's a tribute to Brimley that the audience can grow to love him so quickly. This movie puts a twist on the time-honored Most Dangerous Game (1932) idea. The formula's been tried before, with varying degrees of success, in everything from Death Ring (1992) to Avenging Force (1986). But Hard Target has plenty of awesome moments, including the extended climax in (what else) an abandoned warehouse. Never one to be afraid of wasting bullets, Woo pulls out all the stops in an extended feast of overkill. It's over-the-top fun everyone should see. On a technical note, the British DVD is longer than the American cut, including more violence. So try to track that down if you can, for the complete picture. Go down to the bayou tonight for some high-octane, high-quality Van Damme at his absolute best. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How can something so bad be this good?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put Hard Target is a terrible movie. It is a testament to how big Jean Claude Van Damme really was in the early nineties. He was a master of the action/Martial Arts film. Nearly every scene in this film feels like a spoof...a joke and yet its not at all. I am actually surprised Van Damme would do something like this given his ego because couldn't he see just how ridiculous it was. Its like the ultimate spoof of the 80's action genre. Who better to do it than John Woo? I constantly hear how legendary this director is but I often wonder if this opinion too is a joke. The guy almost killed the Mission Impossible franchise with ridiculous hair, constant slow motion camera tricks, and ridiculous "hero" analogies. And here we have Hard Target with the exact same MO. Hair, slow-mo, hero analogies all over again. Some day I might have someone watch this film and tell me how many times he goes into slow motion which is not dramatic in this case or even remotely "cool" but instead looks ridiculous, hokey and dumb. Especially when your hero is sporting a greasy, stringy mullet. Now all this being said, I'll be darned if this isn't some sort of bizarre cheeky entertainment. Maybe because its laughable or just how incredibly outlandish the action scenes are. The scene with Van Damme standing on the seat of a dirt bike, shooting bad guys and then rolling over the top of their car...is just too ridiculously legendary to not be cool. This is the stuff Chuck Norris wishes he had under his belt. Jean Claude Van Damme is not a great actor, never was. But there is no arguing his chemistry in the 90's. There is just something slick and cool about that enormous ego that he has. His character in Hard Target is just about portrayed as God-like. He has this untouchable, swoon at his feet persona that it so ridiculous that its fun to watch. Yancy Butler is the stereotypical required female partner to Van Damme. She does alright and certainly has the "deer in the headlights" look down pat. She literally looks 90% of the time like she is on an infomercial that is selling Jean Claude Van Damme and she wants it! Her longing looks and open mouthed gaping is hilarious. Their chemistry is okay but really sort of unnecessary. Lance Henriksen is actually the perfect action hero villain. He has the look down and he a cold blooded horrifying killer. He probably has the best role in the entire film. He is a very worthy action film villain. Not to be outdone Arnold Vosloo is a brilliant right hand man to Henriksen. He could have easily been the lead villain in his own right. He is equally as cold and calculating and you get two great final battles when Van Damme takes them on. Wilford Brimley makes a cameo as the obligatory old man that the hero cares about. John Woo gets constant praise from fans for being a "brilliant" action director but his style is always the same and is so awkward at times. He has to be the king of overusing slow motion and when you pair it together with Van Damme and this story it just makes it even more cheesy. Now all this being said Hard Target has found its niche. Twenty years later and it can sit comfortably in action classic status. You can laugh at it and marvel at the action scenes. Plenty of explosions and gun fights and non-stop action especially towards the end of the movie. I can give them kudos for actually creating a solid story even if its a little cookie cutter and predictable. Ultimately Hard Target is nothing but sheer entertainment no matter how you take it or look at it. Nothing wrong with that but it certainly makes a lot of grievous errors in film making and they should just be lucky that it will likely continue to achieve cult status amongst action fans and Van Damme junkies. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot going for it...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phillipfawcett
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but Claude Van Damme is not it! Not a fan, here, of a guy who has more wood in him than the Bastoin forest. Maybe I'm just not a karate fan: it always seems to me that by the time you've finishing spinning and getting your leg up, any adversary could have laid you out, end of. The slow-motion sequences just make me want to give the guy a Coors Light, so he can take his pay check and get out of there. Seagal is a much more engaging actor for me, and his Aikido seems more credible. However, I find this movie an enjoyable ride! Firstly, the premise is powerful and interesting. Sick gun-loving sons- of-bitches run a business which stages real-life hunts of some poor wretch who 'will not be missed'. They always take care to choose somebody with a fighting background, like a Nam Vet, just to give them a bit of a challenge. The script makes an effort to lend this credibility by explaining that 'trouble spots' in the world are always chosen for this, and they move on from country to country after each 'hunt' to evade fallout. Secondly, some of the characters are extremely strong, particularly the villains. Lance Henriksen is always good value, and here puts in a wonderfully hard-assed and droll portrayal of the 'Director' (for want of a better title). Legendary movie quote #33: "Now you know why we insist on payment up front." LOL His side-kick, 'Pik', is a superbly sadistic piece of work by Arnold Vosloo. He doesn't overplay it, yet leaves the viewer in no doubt as to his nature. He has a quiet and chilling business-like manner most of the time, but when time comes for an execution you see what a hobby it is for him, with the twinkle in his eye. The two lead females are sympathetic and credible characters, especially policewoman Kasi Lemmons. Unfortunately the same cannot be said for the 'lovable' but ridiculous Uncle Douvee. I guess he was injected into the final phase of the movie to lend a sprinkling of humour, but imo it did not need it. We already have the two main good characters to engage with, and the movie should have been allowed to stand on its gritty and punchy violence and the quite disturbing aspects of human nature. We really care if some of these characters live or die, even the psychos! In a downtown New Orleans scene, one of the 'hunted' is totally unable to get anybody to help him, which made me really angry. All too believable, and really lent credibility to how the company gets away with it. Uncle Douvee... jeez. If you can get past the image of this old fool playing the hero, then fair play to you (maybe I need to 'lighten up'). If you can get past the attempts at a French (or Belgian, whatever) accent by the very American bit-part actor Wilfred Brimley, then you were not getitng properly into the movie in the first place. Sorry to pick on him, but for me it really grated. It's all the more sad when you remember him in his straight-up role as a mafia henchman in 'The Firm': believable and exactly the tone called for here. Bit-part is what it was, though, and the strengths of the movie outweigh the weaknesses. I would have loved to see Harrison Ford or even Bruce Willis in the Van Damme role - with the every-guy credibility and minus the slow motion, please!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's like a drug isn't it, to bring a man down?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hard Target is directed by John Woo and written by Chuck Pfarrer. It stars Jean-Claude Van Damme, Lance Henriksen, Yancy Butler, Arnold Vosloo and Wilford Brimley. Music is by Graeme Revell and cinematography by Russell Carpenter. New Orleans and ex-merchant marine Chance Boudreaux (Damme) is struggling to gain employment on account of some muscular indiscretions. However, after saving Natasha Binder (Butler) from the hands of robbers, he is offered some work by her that pays handsomely. The task is to find out where her father is, a homeless ex-forces man who has mysteriously disappeared. It's a search that leads them to a sick urban safari being run by Emil Fouchon (Henriksen), the prey? Man! After pushing the boundaries of action cinema in Hong Kong, it was only a matter of time before John Woo got lured to America to dabble in the dollar. Hard Target was his first American movie, which in spite of the studio being nervous about his hiring (Sam Raimi was on standby should it implode) and cuts being made on demand for a certificate rating to open it up to a wider audience, it worked out well. It was a financial success, even though there was the inevitable mixed reviews from critics and today it rightly is held in high regard amongst action movie die- hards. OK! Nobody could seriously claim it's a titan of cinema, it's an absurd story derived from The Most Dangerous Game, the acting is of the usual Van Damme kick assery standard (JC pouts and mumbles, Butler is terrible, Brimley is miscast, Henriksen so over the top we almost lose him from our vision) and preposterousness reaches new levels. Yes it's a dumb fun action movie where leaving the brain at the door is a requisite. But what action delights await the faithful, what grace and style does Woo bring to the mayhem, it's a visceral thriller that once it gets the plot initiations out of the way, unleashes beautiful carnage that thunders the chest royally. Can violence be lyrical? In Woo's hands yes, certainly. The action film is one of the most maligned in cinema, but there is great artistry to many of them, to that end Hard Target scores incredibly high. The stunt work is amazing, the choreography of the fight scenes, with Van Damme showing his wonderful skills, are exquisite sights for the action film fan. Woo's tricks involving slow-mo, freeze frames and juddering close ups all get worked out here, quite often forming part of another ballet of bloodshed. Woo and Van Damme were a good fit, the film rocks for those so inclined for such kinetic malarkey, and not even The Muscles from Brussels' mullet can spoil the enjoyment. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What made you want to complicate my life like this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS*** Even for a Jean-Claude Van Damme action movie "Hard Target" is just a bit too hard to take despite all its action scenes as well as Mr. Van Damme's kick boxing & martial art talents. At first the film starts off like the 1932 classic "The Most Dangerous Game" but quickly deteriorates into a mindless and disjointed free for all. With Van Damme as merchant marine Chance Boudreaux taking on an entire army of bikers in the Louisiana bayous lead by the villainous Emil Fouchon played by Lance Henriksen. Totally unbelievable fight & action scenes even for Van Damme to preform with or without a stunt double that has him have more lives in the movie then a dozen cats. There's also Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's love interest in the film Nat Binder, Nancy Butler, who despite being a damsel in distress seems to have trouble keeping a straight face in many of the action as well as love scenes she's in the movie. It was Nat's missing dad, Douglas Pfarrer,who was later found to be murdered that had Van Damme, who was hired by Net to find him, get involved in this holy mess in the first place. And who can forget Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's moon shine drinking uncle Douvee played by William Brimley who about the best, after Lance Henriksen, actor in the film. Who no matter how much booze he drinks is still able to ride his horse without falling off as well as shoot arrows as accurately as Robin Hood. And as things turned out it was the booze, or the flask that he stored it in, that ended up saving his life! The final showdown in the film between Van Damme-Chance Boudreaux-and Emil Fouchon-Lance Henriksen-just went on and on to the point where all the fighting shooting and exploding lost their effect since for a time it didn't effect the two at all. And when it finally ended you couldn't care less who ended up winning but was happy as hell to know the movie, and all the suffering you went through in watching it, was thank God finally over!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good plot, entertaining, but nowhere near a Woo classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a far cry from Woo's masterpeices in Hong Kong. It was his first American movie and one must say that in a lot of ways it is a disappointment. I am not saying that it is a bad movie, but it seems that the creative genius that is John Woo is seriously hindered by the capital focus of the American market. Us Westerners like movies with happy endings and movies that do not challenge us to think. This movie is action but its action is not beautifully crafted within a movie with real characters struggling in a real world. Hard Target is set in New Orleans during a police strike, though this does not seem evident. A group has set itself up where they hire vagrants to run 10 kilometers with $10 000 while they are being chased by hunters. These vagrants are not supposed to have any ties, but unfortunately they chose somebody who does. When his daughter comes to New Orleans to find him dead, she starts asking questions, and brings Van Damme in to help her. The plot is good, but the thing with Woo's movies from Hong Kong is that it is about the characters struggling with themselves and the bad guys were simply around to make their life even harder. No such struggle occurs within this movie. Van Damme, who is simply a sailor that happens to be good at martial arts, is not able to play a character with any depth. Personally I do not think much of his acting ability, and people really only watch his movies to see his moves - and they are not even martial arts. The only reason Van Damme can do these moves is because he is a dancer. The movie plasters John Woo as being the director and attempts to attract people to the movie on this fact. The action is good, and the imagery used is typical of John Woo. He is a brilliant director, but is even better when he is not restrained. I feel that this film is let down in the fact that there is no character struggle in this movie. The characters are not anti-heroes, which is one of the aspects that elevates Woo movies above the others. It is not until Face Off that John Woo's American movies began to stand out. There are two things that seem to form a part of Woo movies. The main characters either begin as friends but slowly drift apart until they are fighting each other at the end, or they are apart and through the struggles that they face, they are drawn together and realise that they need to help each other. Face Off is a completely different idea where the good guy suddenly finds that he is the bad guy and cannot do anything about it. A Bullet in the Head, Too Catch a Thief, and Broken Arrow are examples of the first type, while The Killer and Hard Boiled are examples of the second type. Hard Target doesn't fall into either category. The characters do not entertain me as their struggles are purely action orientated and as such it doesn't grab me as Woo's other movies do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Competent action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DaRick89
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As with many action movies, Hard to Kill's strengths and weaknesses are fairly simple to analyse. It's a competent action thriller, notable for some stylish action scenes that have John Woo's touch; one particularly memorable example is when Chance Boudreaux (Jean-Claude Van Damme) quite literally blasts a bikie thug out a window with a shotgun and a petrol can! These moments pretty much make the film worth seeing by themselves, despite the usual weaknesses in the plotting and JCVD's ever wooden countenance. As JCVD himself noted however, viewers paid the money to see him waste bad guys and he does plenty of this - sometimes in more inventive ways than expected (using snake traps). It very much makes the film worth seeing for action buffs, even though I'm reluctant to give a really high rating based on this alone. The plot is not too extraordinary: a homeless veteran gets murdered by a team of mercenaries led by Emil Fouchoud (Henriksen) and Van Cleaf (Vosloo), after which his daughter Nat (Butler) comes looking for him and commissions Boudreaux, a homeless Cajun merchant marine (!) to help her out after he rescues her from marauding thugs, raising the ire of the mercenary team. A few plot holes are obvious (shouldn't this mercenary team have been dealt with a while ago, police strike or not? Why is JCVD made a CAJUN?), but it works well as a vehicle for blowing stuff up and killing people. The dialogue is pretty standard stuff: some profanity, some hilariously cringeworthy lines ("don't worry about Randall; he's all ears!) and some macho stuff. As for the acting, the villains are better than the heroes. Of course, when JCVD is your hero, that's bound to be the case, with his unconvincing delivery. He has recently shown that he is capable of acting, but he was a long off that in 1993. Still, English is probably his third language (after French and Dutch); Yancy Butler has no such excuses, being quite wooden in a role that doesn't demand that much. Vosloo and Henriksen are much better though. Vosloo has that quiet menace that always makes him a good villain, while Henriksen goes from menacing and purposeful to merrily nuts as Boudreaux causes him more difficulties than expected. Even Wilford Brimley is amusing as Chance's crazy uncle, reeling off some zany lines. In the end, Hard Target is not a great movie, but it's a competent action thriller with some nice stylistic touches from John Woo during the action scenes. Henriksen, Vosloo and Brimley compensate somewhat for JCVD and Butler, but you still shouldn't watch this film for the acting and especially not for the plotting. Action fans generally don't really look for either that much though, so that's alright. Movie-goers looking for a bit more will probably like some of the style, but won't find that much else. 3/5 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Lance Henriksen show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies starring Jean-Claude Van Damme can't be labeled as anything else than "so bad it's good" material. This one makes no exception. Lance Henriksen however, transcends the genre with a grandiose over-the-top performance that's great fun to watch. As to Van Damme, this actor is not merely campy. His lack of charisma, not to mention linguistic competence, is simply astonishing. Butler is a perfect match  she's fake as a Latino soap-opera, although her English is better than Van Damme's. The film's plot is ridiculous and it gets over- violent to the point of being unpleasant, but it's all worth watching for Lance Henriksen's gleefully villainous show-off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    HK Neo Reviews: Hard Target
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (webmaster@thehkneo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director John Woo's first venture into Hollywood was not without its obstacles. With Van Damme being one of Hollywood's bright action stars back in the early 90s, it is pretty much certain that Woo lacked what he received in his later works  control. The film for most of it, seems uneven, especially when there are scenes you can clearly see as Woo's footprints all over it and there are others that are just plain awful. Still, if you ignore the bad acting from Van Damme, poor pacing, poor editing, there is still fun to be had. Namely the majority of the shooting sequences, a wonderful villainous turn by future "The Mummy" star  Lance Henriksen and a few pigeons to boost, Hard Target is really not that bad Neo rates it 6/10. - www.thehkneo.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best Van Damme movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chris1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First saw this movie when i was buying a video of Maximum Risk,which is a decent Van Damme film.So i watched this film and was not disappointed,i was entertained throughout the whole movie.The action was practically non-stop.The storyline is decent enough with ruthless business men hunting homeless war veterans,and the street-wise Chance Boudreaux was going to find out sooner or later,to bad for the bad guys.The action scenes are spot on.When Van Damme first appears,you just know the s**t is going down.In roughly the first half hour of the film sees a fight at a caf&eacute; in which Van Damme breaks a guys arm it is brutal.As the film rolls on,we discover Chance's background and how he himself has experienced the streets.Lance Henrickson is great as the Emil Fouchon chief bad guy,you just love to hate.And Arnold Vosloo as his sidekick Pick Van Cleef was great and funny at times.You just know when he utters the words "Randall,Randall,Randall" that Randall was in for a very bad day.Wilford Brimley as the enjoyable and funny uncle Douvee.The tag-line for this movie is "Don't Hunt What You Cant Kill" and the bad guys should have realised this.This is a decent and enjoyable Van Damme film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High-quality Van Damme at his absolute best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance Boudreaux (Van Damme) is a New Orleans longshoreman who is down on his luck and struggling to find work. Opportunity comes his way when Nat (Butler) hires him to help her find her missing father. As it turns out, her father isn't missing, necessarily, he was a victim of a malevolent gang of "human hunters". Led by Fouchon (Henriksen), and with his second in command Pik Van Cleef (Vosloo), they get their kicks (and get rich) letting weekend warriors pay them to go on the ultimate hunting expedition: for man! But they meet their match with the fearless Chance, a man they cannot kill. Along for the ride is Chance's uncle Douvee (Brimley). Will Chance get his chance at glory? Or, to the human hunters, is he just another HARD TARGET? Hard Target is hands-down one of Van Damme's best. It's explosively entertaining and lives up to the promise of a Van Damme and John Woo team-up. It's everything a combination of those two men could be and should be, and doesn't let the audience down. Once again, this is classic 90's action fun from the golden time when Van Damme movies went to the theater. Back then, we remember joking with our friends that because there's so much slow motion in this movie, if it was all played at regular speed, the film would be about 20 minutes. And it's true, there is a lot of dramatic slo-mo, but it's all for the best. And Van Damme and others get a lot of unnecessarily portentous entrances and exits, which just adds to the style of Hard Target, which is just a tad bit off-kilter. But that's far from a bad thing. It separates itself from its many competitors that way. Besides Van Damme and his absurd hair, the cast assembled for this is just killer: Lance Henriksen is great as the baddie who's so bad, even his piano-playing is evil. Vosloo is also adept at being bad, and his quasi-Scottish (?) accent, well, accentuates his sinister glares. Yancy Butler gives a bug-eyed performance who always seems surprised at the proceedings. But top marks must go to the great Wilford Brimley. In a strange role for him, the barely-intelligible, bow-and-arrow toting, horseback riding uncle is truly lovable and you root for him, even though he doesn't appear until late in the film. That's a tribute to Brimley that the audience can grow to love him so quickly. This movie puts a twist on the time-honored Most Dangerous Game (1932) idea. The formula's been tried before, with varying degrees of success, in everything from Death Ring (1992) to Avenging Force (1986). But Hard Target has plenty of awesome moments, including the extended climax in (what else) an abandoned warehouse. Never one to be afraid of wasting bullets, Woo pulls out all the stops in an extended feast of overkill. It's over-the-top fun everyone should see. On a technical note, the British DVD is longer than the American cut, including more violence. So try to track that down if you can, for the complete picture. Go down to the bayou tonight for some high-octane, high-quality Van Damme at his absolute best. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How can something so bad be this good?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put Hard Target is a terrible movie. It is a testament to how big Jean Claude Van Damme really was in the early nineties. He was a master of the action/Martial Arts film. Nearly every scene in this film feels like a spoof...a joke and yet its not at all. I am actually surprised Van Damme would do something like this given his ego because couldn't he see just how ridiculous it was. Its like the ultimate spoof of the 80's action genre. Who better to do it than John Woo? I constantly hear how legendary this director is but I often wonder if this opinion too is a joke. The guy almost killed the Mission Impossible franchise with ridiculous hair, constant slow motion camera tricks, and ridiculous "hero" analogies. And here we have Hard Target with the exact same MO. Hair, slow-mo, hero analogies all over again. Some day I might have someone watch this film and tell me how many times he goes into slow motion which is not dramatic in this case or even remotely "cool" but instead looks ridiculous, hokey and dumb. Especially when your hero is sporting a greasy, stringy mullet. Now all this being said, I'll be darned if this isn't some sort of bizarre cheeky entertainment. Maybe because its laughable or just how incredibly outlandish the action scenes are. The scene with Van Damme standing on the seat of a dirt bike, shooting bad guys and then rolling over the top of their car...is just too ridiculously legendary to not be cool. This is the stuff Chuck Norris wishes he had under his belt. Jean Claude Van Damme is not a great actor, never was. But there is no arguing his chemistry in the 90's. There is just something slick and cool about that enormous ego that he has. His character in Hard Target is just about portrayed as God-like. He has this untouchable, swoon at his feet persona that it so ridiculous that its fun to watch. Yancy Butler is the stereotypical required female partner to Van Damme. She does alright and certainly has the "deer in the headlights" look down pat. She literally looks 90% of the time like she is on an infomercial that is selling Jean Claude Van Damme and she wants it! Her longing looks and open mouthed gaping is hilarious. Their chemistry is okay but really sort of unnecessary. Lance Henriksen is actually the perfect action hero villain. He has the look down and he a cold blooded horrifying killer. He probably has the best role in the entire film. He is a very worthy action film villain. Not to be outdone Arnold Vosloo is a brilliant right hand man to Henriksen. He could have easily been the lead villain in his own right. He is equally as cold and calculating and you get two great final battles when Van Damme takes them on. Wilford Brimley makes a cameo as the obligatory old man that the hero cares about. John Woo gets constant praise from fans for being a "brilliant" action director but his style is always the same and is so awkward at times. He has to be the king of overusing slow motion and when you pair it together with Van Damme and this story it just makes it even more cheesy. Now all this being said Hard Target has found its niche. Twenty years later and it can sit comfortably in action classic status. You can laugh at it and marvel at the action scenes. Plenty of explosions and gun fights and non-stop action especially towards the end of the movie. I can give them kudos for actually creating a solid story even if its a little cookie cutter and predictable. Ultimately Hard Target is nothing but sheer entertainment no matter how you take it or look at it. Nothing wrong with that but it certainly makes a lot of grievous errors in film making and they should just be lucky that it will likely continue to achieve cult status amongst action fans and Van Damme junkies. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot going for it...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phillipfawcett
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but Claude Van Damme is not it! Not a fan, here, of a guy who has more wood in him than the Bastoin forest. Maybe I'm just not a karate fan: it always seems to me that by the time you've finishing spinning and getting your leg up, any adversary could have laid you out, end of. The slow-motion sequences just make me want to give the guy a Coors Light, so he can take his pay check and get out of there. Seagal is a much more engaging actor for me, and his Aikido seems more credible. However, I find this movie an enjoyable ride! Firstly, the premise is powerful and interesting. Sick gun-loving sons- of-bitches run a business which stages real-life hunts of some poor wretch who 'will not be missed'. They always take care to choose somebody with a fighting background, like a Nam Vet, just to give them a bit of a challenge. The script makes an effort to lend this credibility by explaining that 'trouble spots' in the world are always chosen for this, and they move on from country to country after each 'hunt' to evade fallout. Secondly, some of the characters are extremely strong, particularly the villains. Lance Henriksen is always good value, and here puts in a wonderfully hard-assed and droll portrayal of the 'Director' (for want of a better title). Legendary movie quote #33: "Now you know why we insist on payment up front." LOL His side-kick, 'Pik', is a superbly sadistic piece of work by Arnold Vosloo. He doesn't overplay it, yet leaves the viewer in no doubt as to his nature. He has a quiet and chilling business-like manner most of the time, but when time comes for an execution you see what a hobby it is for him, with the twinkle in his eye. The two lead females are sympathetic and credible characters, especially policewoman Kasi Lemmons. Unfortunately the same cannot be said for the 'lovable' but ridiculous Uncle Douvee. I guess he was injected into the final phase of the movie to lend a sprinkling of humour, but imo it did not need it. We already have the two main good characters to engage with, and the movie should have been allowed to stand on its gritty and punchy violence and the quite disturbing aspects of human nature. We really care if some of these characters live or die, even the psychos! In a downtown New Orleans scene, one of the 'hunted' is totally unable to get anybody to help him, which made me really angry. All too believable, and really lent credibility to how the company gets away with it. Uncle Douvee... jeez. If you can get past the image of this old fool playing the hero, then fair play to you (maybe I need to 'lighten up'). If you can get past the attempts at a French (or Belgian, whatever) accent by the very American bit-part actor Wilfred Brimley, then you were not getitng properly into the movie in the first place. Sorry to pick on him, but for me it really grated. It's all the more sad when you remember him in his straight-up role as a mafia henchman in 'The Firm': believable and exactly the tone called for here. Bit-part is what it was, though, and the strengths of the movie outweigh the weaknesses. I would have loved to see Harrison Ford or even Bruce Willis in the Van Damme role - with the every-guy credibility and minus the slow motion, please!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's like a drug isn't it, to bring a man down?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hard Target is directed by John Woo and written by Chuck Pfarrer. It stars Jean-Claude Van Damme, Lance Henriksen, Yancy Butler, Arnold Vosloo and Wilford Brimley. Music is by Graeme Revell and cinematography by Russell Carpenter. New Orleans and ex-merchant marine Chance Boudreaux (Damme) is struggling to gain employment on account of some muscular indiscretions. However, after saving Natasha Binder (Butler) from the hands of robbers, he is offered some work by her that pays handsomely. The task is to find out where her father is, a homeless ex-forces man who has mysteriously disappeared. It's a search that leads them to a sick urban safari being run by Emil Fouchon (Henriksen), the prey? Man! After pushing the boundaries of action cinema in Hong Kong, it was only a matter of time before John Woo got lured to America to dabble in the dollar. Hard Target was his first American movie, which in spite of the studio being nervous about his hiring (Sam Raimi was on standby should it implode) and cuts being made on demand for a certificate rating to open it up to a wider audience, it worked out well. It was a financial success, even though there was the inevitable mixed reviews from critics and today it rightly is held in high regard amongst action movie die- hards. OK! Nobody could seriously claim it's a titan of cinema, it's an absurd story derived from The Most Dangerous Game, the acting is of the usual Van Damme kick assery standard (JC pouts and mumbles, Butler is terrible, Brimley is miscast, Henriksen so over the top we almost lose him from our vision) and preposterousness reaches new levels. Yes it's a dumb fun action movie where leaving the brain at the door is a requisite. But what action delights await the faithful, what grace and style does Woo bring to the mayhem, it's a visceral thriller that once it gets the plot initiations out of the way, unleashes beautiful carnage that thunders the chest royally. Can violence be lyrical? In Woo's hands yes, certainly. The action film is one of the most maligned in cinema, but there is great artistry to many of them, to that end Hard Target scores incredibly high. The stunt work is amazing, the choreography of the fight scenes, with Van Damme showing his wonderful skills, are exquisite sights for the action film fan. Woo's tricks involving slow-mo, freeze frames and juddering close ups all get worked out here, quite often forming part of another ballet of bloodshed. Woo and Van Damme were a good fit, the film rocks for those so inclined for such kinetic malarkey, and not even The Muscles from Brussels' mullet can spoil the enjoyment. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What made you want to complicate my life like this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS*** Even for a Jean-Claude Van Damme action movie "Hard Target" is just a bit too hard to take despite all its action scenes as well as Mr. Van Damme's kick boxing & martial art talents. At first the film starts off like the 1932 classic "The Most Dangerous Game" but quickly deteriorates into a mindless and disjointed free for all. With Van Damme as merchant marine Chance Boudreaux taking on an entire army of bikers in the Louisiana bayous lead by the villainous Emil Fouchon played by Lance Henriksen. Totally unbelievable fight & action scenes even for Van Damme to preform with or without a stunt double that has him have more lives in the movie then a dozen cats. There's also Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's love interest in the film Nat Binder, Nancy Butler, who despite being a damsel in distress seems to have trouble keeping a straight face in many of the action as well as love scenes she's in the movie. It was Nat's missing dad, Douglas Pfarrer,who was later found to be murdered that had Van Damme, who was hired by Net to find him, get involved in this holy mess in the first place. And who can forget Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's moon shine drinking uncle Douvee played by William Brimley who about the best, after Lance Henriksen, actor in the film. Who no matter how much booze he drinks is still able to ride his horse without falling off as well as shoot arrows as accurately as Robin Hood. And as things turned out it was the booze, or the flask that he stored it in, that ended up saving his life! The final showdown in the film between Van Damme-Chance Boudreaux-and Emil Fouchon-Lance Henriksen-just went on and on to the point where all the fighting shooting and exploding lost their effect since for a time it didn't effect the two at all. And when it finally ended you couldn't care less who ended up winning but was happy as hell to know the movie, and all the suffering you went through in watching it, was thank God finally over!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good plot, entertaining, but nowhere near a Woo classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a far cry from Woo's masterpeices in Hong Kong. It was his first American movie and one must say that in a lot of ways it is a disappointment. I am not saying that it is a bad movie, but it seems that the creative genius that is John Woo is seriously hindered by the capital focus of the American market. Us Westerners like movies with happy endings and movies that do not challenge us to think. This movie is action but its action is not beautifully crafted within a movie with real characters struggling in a real world. Hard Target is set in New Orleans during a police strike, though this does not seem evident. A group has set itself up where they hire vagrants to run 10 kilometers with $10 000 while they are being chased by hunters. These vagrants are not supposed to have any ties, but unfortunately they chose somebody who does. When his daughter comes to New Orleans to find him dead, she starts asking questions, and brings Van Damme in to help her. The plot is good, but the thing with Woo's movies from Hong Kong is that it is about the characters struggling with themselves and the bad guys were simply around to make their life even harder. No such struggle occurs within this movie. Van Damme, who is simply a sailor that happens to be good at martial arts, is not able to play a character with any depth. Personally I do not think much of his acting ability, and people really only watch his movies to see his moves - and they are not even martial arts. The only reason Van Damme can do these moves is because he is a dancer. The movie plasters John Woo as being the director and attempts to attract people to the movie on this fact. The action is good, and the imagery used is typical of John Woo. He is a brilliant director, but is even better when he is not restrained. I feel that this film is let down in the fact that there is no character struggle in this movie. The characters are not anti-heroes, which is one of the aspects that elevates Woo movies above the others. It is not until Face Off that John Woo's American movies began to stand out. There are two things that seem to form a part of Woo movies. The main characters either begin as friends but slowly drift apart until they are fighting each other at the end, or they are apart and through the struggles that they face, they are drawn together and realise that they need to help each other. Face Off is a completely different idea where the good guy suddenly finds that he is the bad guy and cannot do anything about it. A Bullet in the Head, Too Catch a Thief, and Broken Arrow are examples of the first type, while The Killer and Hard Boiled are examples of the second type. Hard Target doesn't fall into either category. The characters do not entertain me as their struggles are purely action orientated and as such it doesn't grab me as Woo's other movies do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Competent action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DaRick89
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As with many action movies, Hard to Kill's strengths and weaknesses are fairly simple to analyse. It's a competent action thriller, notable for some stylish action scenes that have John Woo's touch; one particularly memorable example is when Chance Boudreaux (Jean-Claude Van Damme) quite literally blasts a bikie thug out a window with a shotgun and a petrol can! These moments pretty much make the film worth seeing by themselves, despite the usual weaknesses in the plotting and JCVD's ever wooden countenance. As JCVD himself noted however, viewers paid the money to see him waste bad guys and he does plenty of this - sometimes in more inventive ways than expected (using snake traps). It very much makes the film worth seeing for action buffs, even though I'm reluctant to give a really high rating based on this alone. The plot is not too extraordinary: a homeless veteran gets murdered by a team of mercenaries led by Emil Fouchoud (Henriksen) and Van Cleaf (Vosloo), after which his daughter Nat (Butler) comes looking for him and commissions Boudreaux, a homeless Cajun merchant marine (!) to help her out after he rescues her from marauding thugs, raising the ire of the mercenary team. A few plot holes are obvious (shouldn't this mercenary team have been dealt with a while ago, police strike or not? Why is JCVD made a CAJUN?), but it works well as a vehicle for blowing stuff up and killing people. The dialogue is pretty standard stuff: some profanity, some hilariously cringeworthy lines ("don't worry about Randall; he's all ears!) and some macho stuff. As for the acting, the villains are better than the heroes. Of course, when JCVD is your hero, that's bound to be the case, with his unconvincing delivery. He has recently shown that he is capable of acting, but he was a long off that in 1993. Still, English is probably his third language (after French and Dutch); Yancy Butler has no such excuses, being quite wooden in a role that doesn't demand that much. Vosloo and Henriksen are much better though. Vosloo has that quiet menace that always makes him a good villain, while Henriksen goes from menacing and purposeful to merrily nuts as Boudreaux causes him more difficulties than expected. Even Wilford Brimley is amusing as Chance's crazy uncle, reeling off some zany lines. In the end, Hard Target is not a great movie, but it's a competent action thriller with some nice stylistic touches from John Woo during the action scenes. Henriksen, Vosloo and Brimley compensate somewhat for JCVD and Butler, but you still shouldn't watch this film for the acting and especially not for the plotting. Action fans generally don't really look for either that much though, so that's alright. Movie-goers looking for a bit more will probably like some of the style, but won't find that much else. 3/5 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Lance Henriksen show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies starring Jean-Claude Van Damme can't be labeled as anything else than "so bad it's good" material. This one makes no exception. Lance Henriksen however, transcends the genre with a grandiose over-the-top performance that's great fun to watch. As to Van Damme, this actor is not merely campy. His lack of charisma, not to mention linguistic competence, is simply astonishing. Butler is a perfect match  she's fake as a Latino soap-opera, although her English is better than Van Damme's. The film's plot is ridiculous and it gets over- violent to the point of being unpleasant, but it's all worth watching for Lance Henriksen's gleefully villainous show-off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    HK Neo Reviews: Hard Target
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (webmaster@thehkneo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director John Woo's first venture into Hollywood was not without its obstacles. With Van Damme being one of Hollywood's bright action stars back in the early 90s, it is pretty much certain that Woo lacked what he received in his later works  control. The film for most of it, seems uneven, especially when there are scenes you can clearly see as Woo's footprints all over it and there are others that are just plain awful. Still, if you ignore the bad acting from Van Damme, poor pacing, poor editing, there is still fun to be had. Namely the majority of the shooting sequences, a wonderful villainous turn by future "The Mummy" star  Lance Henriksen and a few pigeons to boost, Hard Target is really not that bad Neo rates it 6/10. - www.thehkneo.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best Van Damme movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chris1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First saw this movie when i was buying a video of Maximum Risk,which is a decent Van Damme film.So i watched this film and was not disappointed,i was entertained throughout the whole movie.The action was practically non-stop.The storyline is decent enough with ruthless business men hunting homeless war veterans,and the street-wise Chance Boudreaux was going to find out sooner or later,to bad for the bad guys.The action scenes are spot on.When Van Damme first appears,you just know the s**t is going down.In roughly the first half hour of the film sees a fight at a caf&eacute; in which Van Damme breaks a guys arm it is brutal.As the film rolls on,we discover Chance's background and how he himself has experienced the streets.Lance Henrickson is great as the Emil Fouchon chief bad guy,you just love to hate.And Arnold Vosloo as his sidekick Pick Van Cleef was great and funny at times.You just know when he utters the words "Randall,Randall,Randall" that Randall was in for a very bad day.Wilford Brimley as the enjoyable and funny uncle Douvee.The tag-line for this movie is "Don't Hunt What You Cant Kill" and the bad guys should have realised this.This is a decent and enjoyable Van Damme film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High-quality Van Damme at his absolute best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance Boudreaux (Van Damme) is a New Orleans longshoreman who is down on his luck and struggling to find work. Opportunity comes his way when Nat (Butler) hires him to help her find her missing father. As it turns out, her father isn't missing, necessarily, he was a victim of a malevolent gang of "human hunters". Led by Fouchon (Henriksen), and with his second in command Pik Van Cleef (Vosloo), they get their kicks (and get rich) letting weekend warriors pay them to go on the ultimate hunting expedition: for man! But they meet their match with the fearless Chance, a man they cannot kill. Along for the ride is Chance's uncle Douvee (Brimley). Will Chance get his chance at glory? Or, to the human hunters, is he just another HARD TARGET? Hard Target is hands-down one of Van Damme's best. It's explosively entertaining and lives up to the promise of a Van Damme and John Woo team-up. It's everything a combination of those two men could be and should be, and doesn't let the audience down. Once again, this is classic 90's action fun from the golden time when Van Damme movies went to the theater. Back then, we remember joking with our friends that because there's so much slow motion in this movie, if it was all played at regular speed, the film would be about 20 minutes. And it's true, there is a lot of dramatic slo-mo, but it's all for the best. And Van Damme and others get a lot of unnecessarily portentous entrances and exits, which just adds to the style of Hard Target, which is just a tad bit off-kilter. But that's far from a bad thing. It separates itself from its many competitors that way. Besides Van Damme and his absurd hair, the cast assembled for this is just killer: Lance Henriksen is great as the baddie who's so bad, even his piano-playing is evil. Vosloo is also adept at being bad, and his quasi-Scottish (?) accent, well, accentuates his sinister glares. Yancy Butler gives a bug-eyed performance who always seems surprised at the proceedings. But top marks must go to the great Wilford Brimley. In a strange role for him, the barely-intelligible, bow-and-arrow toting, horseback riding uncle is truly lovable and you root for him, even though he doesn't appear until late in the film. That's a tribute to Brimley that the audience can grow to love him so quickly. This movie puts a twist on the time-honored Most Dangerous Game (1932) idea. The formula's been tried before, with varying degrees of success, in everything from Death Ring (1992) to Avenging Force (1986). But Hard Target has plenty of awesome moments, including the extended climax in (what else) an abandoned warehouse. Never one to be afraid of wasting bullets, Woo pulls out all the stops in an extended feast of overkill. It's over-the-top fun everyone should see. On a technical note, the British DVD is longer than the American cut, including more violence. So try to track that down if you can, for the complete picture. Go down to the bayou tonight for some high-octane, high-quality Van Damme at his absolute best. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How can something so bad be this good?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put Hard Target is a terrible movie. It is a testament to how big Jean Claude Van Damme really was in the early nineties. He was a master of the action/Martial Arts film. Nearly every scene in this film feels like a spoof...a joke and yet its not at all. I am actually surprised Van Damme would do something like this given his ego because couldn't he see just how ridiculous it was. Its like the ultimate spoof of the 80's action genre. Who better to do it than John Woo? I constantly hear how legendary this director is but I often wonder if this opinion too is a joke. The guy almost killed the Mission Impossible franchise with ridiculous hair, constant slow motion camera tricks, and ridiculous "hero" analogies. And here we have Hard Target with the exact same MO. Hair, slow-mo, hero analogies all over again. Some day I might have someone watch this film and tell me how many times he goes into slow motion which is not dramatic in this case or even remotely "cool" but instead looks ridiculous, hokey and dumb. Especially when your hero is sporting a greasy, stringy mullet. Now all this being said, I'll be darned if this isn't some sort of bizarre cheeky entertainment. Maybe because its laughable or just how incredibly outlandish the action scenes are. The scene with Van Damme standing on the seat of a dirt bike, shooting bad guys and then rolling over the top of their car...is just too ridiculously legendary to not be cool. This is the stuff Chuck Norris wishes he had under his belt. Jean Claude Van Damme is not a great actor, never was. But there is no arguing his chemistry in the 90's. There is just something slick and cool about that enormous ego that he has. His character in Hard Target is just about portrayed as God-like. He has this untouchable, swoon at his feet persona that it so ridiculous that its fun to watch. Yancy Butler is the stereotypical required female partner to Van Damme. She does alright and certainly has the "deer in the headlights" look down pat. She literally looks 90% of the time like she is on an infomercial that is selling Jean Claude Van Damme and she wants it! Her longing looks and open mouthed gaping is hilarious. Their chemistry is okay but really sort of unnecessary. Lance Henriksen is actually the perfect action hero villain. He has the look down and he a cold blooded horrifying killer. He probably has the best role in the entire film. He is a very worthy action film villain. Not to be outdone Arnold Vosloo is a brilliant right hand man to Henriksen. He could have easily been the lead villain in his own right. He is equally as cold and calculating and you get two great final battles when Van Damme takes them on. Wilford Brimley makes a cameo as the obligatory old man that the hero cares about. John Woo gets constant praise from fans for being a "brilliant" action director but his style is always the same and is so awkward at times. He has to be the king of overusing slow motion and when you pair it together with Van Damme and this story it just makes it even more cheesy. Now all this being said Hard Target has found its niche. Twenty years later and it can sit comfortably in action classic status. You can laugh at it and marvel at the action scenes. Plenty of explosions and gun fights and non-stop action especially towards the end of the movie. I can give them kudos for actually creating a solid story even if its a little cookie cutter and predictable. Ultimately Hard Target is nothing but sheer entertainment no matter how you take it or look at it. Nothing wrong with that but it certainly makes a lot of grievous errors in film making and they should just be lucky that it will likely continue to achieve cult status amongst action fans and Van Damme junkies. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot going for it...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phillipfawcett
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but Claude Van Damme is not it! Not a fan, here, of a guy who has more wood in him than the Bastoin forest. Maybe I'm just not a karate fan: it always seems to me that by the time you've finishing spinning and getting your leg up, any adversary could have laid you out, end of. The slow-motion sequences just make me want to give the guy a Coors Light, so he can take his pay check and get out of there. Seagal is a much more engaging actor for me, and his Aikido seems more credible. However, I find this movie an enjoyable ride! Firstly, the premise is powerful and interesting. Sick gun-loving sons- of-bitches run a business which stages real-life hunts of some poor wretch who 'will not be missed'. They always take care to choose somebody with a fighting background, like a Nam Vet, just to give them a bit of a challenge. The script makes an effort to lend this credibility by explaining that 'trouble spots' in the world are always chosen for this, and they move on from country to country after each 'hunt' to evade fallout. Secondly, some of the characters are extremely strong, particularly the villains. Lance Henriksen is always good value, and here puts in a wonderfully hard-assed and droll portrayal of the 'Director' (for want of a better title). Legendary movie quote #33: "Now you know why we insist on payment up front." LOL His side-kick, 'Pik', is a superbly sadistic piece of work by Arnold Vosloo. He doesn't overplay it, yet leaves the viewer in no doubt as to his nature. He has a quiet and chilling business-like manner most of the time, but when time comes for an execution you see what a hobby it is for him, with the twinkle in his eye. The two lead females are sympathetic and credible characters, especially policewoman Kasi Lemmons. Unfortunately the same cannot be said for the 'lovable' but ridiculous Uncle Douvee. I guess he was injected into the final phase of the movie to lend a sprinkling of humour, but imo it did not need it. We already have the two main good characters to engage with, and the movie should have been allowed to stand on its gritty and punchy violence and the quite disturbing aspects of human nature. We really care if some of these characters live or die, even the psychos! In a downtown New Orleans scene, one of the 'hunted' is totally unable to get anybody to help him, which made me really angry. All too believable, and really lent credibility to how the company gets away with it. Uncle Douvee... jeez. If you can get past the image of this old fool playing the hero, then fair play to you (maybe I need to 'lighten up'). If you can get past the attempts at a French (or Belgian, whatever) accent by the very American bit-part actor Wilfred Brimley, then you were not getitng properly into the movie in the first place. Sorry to pick on him, but for me it really grated. It's all the more sad when you remember him in his straight-up role as a mafia henchman in 'The Firm': believable and exactly the tone called for here. Bit-part is what it was, though, and the strengths of the movie outweigh the weaknesses. I would have loved to see Harrison Ford or even Bruce Willis in the Van Damme role - with the every-guy credibility and minus the slow motion, please!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's like a drug isn't it, to bring a man down?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hard Target is directed by John Woo and written by Chuck Pfarrer. It stars Jean-Claude Van Damme, Lance Henriksen, Yancy Butler, Arnold Vosloo and Wilford Brimley. Music is by Graeme Revell and cinematography by Russell Carpenter. New Orleans and ex-merchant marine Chance Boudreaux (Damme) is struggling to gain employment on account of some muscular indiscretions. However, after saving Natasha Binder (Butler) from the hands of robbers, he is offered some work by her that pays handsomely. The task is to find out where her father is, a homeless ex-forces man who has mysteriously disappeared. It's a search that leads them to a sick urban safari being run by Emil Fouchon (Henriksen), the prey? Man! After pushing the boundaries of action cinema in Hong Kong, it was only a matter of time before John Woo got lured to America to dabble in the dollar. Hard Target was his first American movie, which in spite of the studio being nervous about his hiring (Sam Raimi was on standby should it implode) and cuts being made on demand for a certificate rating to open it up to a wider audience, it worked out well. It was a financial success, even though there was the inevitable mixed reviews from critics and today it rightly is held in high regard amongst action movie die- hards. OK! Nobody could seriously claim it's a titan of cinema, it's an absurd story derived from The Most Dangerous Game, the acting is of the usual Van Damme kick assery standard (JC pouts and mumbles, Butler is terrible, Brimley is miscast, Henriksen so over the top we almost lose him from our vision) and preposterousness reaches new levels. Yes it's a dumb fun action movie where leaving the brain at the door is a requisite. But what action delights await the faithful, what grace and style does Woo bring to the mayhem, it's a visceral thriller that once it gets the plot initiations out of the way, unleashes beautiful carnage that thunders the chest royally. Can violence be lyrical? In Woo's hands yes, certainly. The action film is one of the most maligned in cinema, but there is great artistry to many of them, to that end Hard Target scores incredibly high. The stunt work is amazing, the choreography of the fight scenes, with Van Damme showing his wonderful skills, are exquisite sights for the action film fan. Woo's tricks involving slow-mo, freeze frames and juddering close ups all get worked out here, quite often forming part of another ballet of bloodshed. Woo and Van Damme were a good fit, the film rocks for those so inclined for such kinetic malarkey, and not even The Muscles from Brussels' mullet can spoil the enjoyment. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What made you want to complicate my life like this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS*** Even for a Jean-Claude Van Damme action movie "Hard Target" is just a bit too hard to take despite all its action scenes as well as Mr. Van Damme's kick boxing & martial art talents. At first the film starts off like the 1932 classic "The Most Dangerous Game" but quickly deteriorates into a mindless and disjointed free for all. With Van Damme as merchant marine Chance Boudreaux taking on an entire army of bikers in the Louisiana bayous lead by the villainous Emil Fouchon played by Lance Henriksen. Totally unbelievable fight & action scenes even for Van Damme to preform with or without a stunt double that has him have more lives in the movie then a dozen cats. There's also Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's love interest in the film Nat Binder, Nancy Butler, who despite being a damsel in distress seems to have trouble keeping a straight face in many of the action as well as love scenes she's in the movie. It was Nat's missing dad, Douglas Pfarrer,who was later found to be murdered that had Van Damme, who was hired by Net to find him, get involved in this holy mess in the first place. And who can forget Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's moon shine drinking uncle Douvee played by William Brimley who about the best, after Lance Henriksen, actor in the film. Who no matter how much booze he drinks is still able to ride his horse without falling off as well as shoot arrows as accurately as Robin Hood. And as things turned out it was the booze, or the flask that he stored it in, that ended up saving his life! The final showdown in the film between Van Damme-Chance Boudreaux-and Emil Fouchon-Lance Henriksen-just went on and on to the point where all the fighting shooting and exploding lost their effect since for a time it didn't effect the two at all. And when it finally ended you couldn't care less who ended up winning but was happy as hell to know the movie, and all the suffering you went through in watching it, was thank God finally over!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good plot, entertaining, but nowhere near a Woo classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a far cry from Woo's masterpeices in Hong Kong. It was his first American movie and one must say that in a lot of ways it is a disappointment. I am not saying that it is a bad movie, but it seems that the creative genius that is John Woo is seriously hindered by the capital focus of the American market. Us Westerners like movies with happy endings and movies that do not challenge us to think. This movie is action but its action is not beautifully crafted within a movie with real characters struggling in a real world. Hard Target is set in New Orleans during a police strike, though this does not seem evident. A group has set itself up where they hire vagrants to run 10 kilometers with $10 000 while they are being chased by hunters. These vagrants are not supposed to have any ties, but unfortunately they chose somebody who does. When his daughter comes to New Orleans to find him dead, she starts asking questions, and brings Van Damme in to help her. The plot is good, but the thing with Woo's movies from Hong Kong is that it is about the characters struggling with themselves and the bad guys were simply around to make their life even harder. No such struggle occurs within this movie. Van Damme, who is simply a sailor that happens to be good at martial arts, is not able to play a character with any depth. Personally I do not think much of his acting ability, and people really only watch his movies to see his moves - and they are not even martial arts. The only reason Van Damme can do these moves is because he is a dancer. The movie plasters John Woo as being the director and attempts to attract people to the movie on this fact. The action is good, and the imagery used is typical of John Woo. He is a brilliant director, but is even better when he is not restrained. I feel that this film is let down in the fact that there is no character struggle in this movie. The characters are not anti-heroes, which is one of the aspects that elevates Woo movies above the others. It is not until Face Off that John Woo's American movies began to stand out. There are two things that seem to form a part of Woo movies. The main characters either begin as friends but slowly drift apart until they are fighting each other at the end, or they are apart and through the struggles that they face, they are drawn together and realise that they need to help each other. Face Off is a completely different idea where the good guy suddenly finds that he is the bad guy and cannot do anything about it. A Bullet in the Head, Too Catch a Thief, and Broken Arrow are examples of the first type, while The Killer and Hard Boiled are examples of the second type. Hard Target doesn't fall into either category. The characters do not entertain me as their struggles are purely action orientated and as such it doesn't grab me as Woo's other movies do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Competent action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DaRick89
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As with many action movies, Hard to Kill's strengths and weaknesses are fairly simple to analyse. It's a competent action thriller, notable for some stylish action scenes that have John Woo's touch; one particularly memorable example is when Chance Boudreaux (Jean-Claude Van Damme) quite literally blasts a bikie thug out a window with a shotgun and a petrol can! These moments pretty much make the film worth seeing by themselves, despite the usual weaknesses in the plotting and JCVD's ever wooden countenance. As JCVD himself noted however, viewers paid the money to see him waste bad guys and he does plenty of this - sometimes in more inventive ways than expected (using snake traps). It very much makes the film worth seeing for action buffs, even though I'm reluctant to give a really high rating based on this alone. The plot is not too extraordinary: a homeless veteran gets murdered by a team of mercenaries led by Emil Fouchoud (Henriksen) and Van Cleaf (Vosloo), after which his daughter Nat (Butler) comes looking for him and commissions Boudreaux, a homeless Cajun merchant marine (!) to help her out after he rescues her from marauding thugs, raising the ire of the mercenary team. A few plot holes are obvious (shouldn't this mercenary team have been dealt with a while ago, police strike or not? Why is JCVD made a CAJUN?), but it works well as a vehicle for blowing stuff up and killing people. The dialogue is pretty standard stuff: some profanity, some hilariously cringeworthy lines ("don't worry about Randall; he's all ears!) and some macho stuff. As for the acting, the villains are better than the heroes. Of course, when JCVD is your hero, that's bound to be the case, with his unconvincing delivery. He has recently shown that he is capable of acting, but he was a long off that in 1993. Still, English is probably his third language (after French and Dutch); Yancy Butler has no such excuses, being quite wooden in a role that doesn't demand that much. Vosloo and Henriksen are much better though. Vosloo has that quiet menace that always makes him a good villain, while Henriksen goes from menacing and purposeful to merrily nuts as Boudreaux causes him more difficulties than expected. Even Wilford Brimley is amusing as Chance's crazy uncle, reeling off some zany lines. In the end, Hard Target is not a great movie, but it's a competent action thriller with some nice stylistic touches from John Woo during the action scenes. Henriksen, Vosloo and Brimley compensate somewhat for JCVD and Butler, but you still shouldn't watch this film for the acting and especially not for the plotting. Action fans generally don't really look for either that much though, so that's alright. Movie-goers looking for a bit more will probably like some of the style, but won't find that much else. 3/5 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Lance Henriksen show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies starring Jean-Claude Van Damme can't be labeled as anything else than "so bad it's good" material. This one makes no exception. Lance Henriksen however, transcends the genre with a grandiose over-the-top performance that's great fun to watch. As to Van Damme, this actor is not merely campy. His lack of charisma, not to mention linguistic competence, is simply astonishing. Butler is a perfect match  she's fake as a Latino soap-opera, although her English is better than Van Damme's. The film's plot is ridiculous and it gets over- violent to the point of being unpleasant, but it's all worth watching for Lance Henriksen's gleefully villainous show-off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    HK Neo Reviews: Hard Target
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (webmaster@thehkneo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director John Woo's first venture into Hollywood was not without its obstacles. With Van Damme being one of Hollywood's bright action stars back in the early 90s, it is pretty much certain that Woo lacked what he received in his later works  control. The film for most of it, seems uneven, especially when there are scenes you can clearly see as Woo's footprints all over it and there are others that are just plain awful. Still, if you ignore the bad acting from Van Damme, poor pacing, poor editing, there is still fun to be had. Namely the majority of the shooting sequences, a wonderful villainous turn by future "The Mummy" star  Lance Henriksen and a few pigeons to boost, Hard Target is really not that bad Neo rates it 6/10. - www.thehkneo.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best Van Damme movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chris1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First saw this movie when i was buying a video of Maximum Risk,which is a decent Van Damme film.So i watched this film and was not disappointed,i was entertained throughout the whole movie.The action was practically non-stop.The storyline is decent enough with ruthless business men hunting homeless war veterans,and the street-wise Chance Boudreaux was going to find out sooner or later,to bad for the bad guys.The action scenes are spot on.When Van Damme first appears,you just know the s**t is going down.In roughly the first half hour of the film sees a fight at a caf&eacute; in which Van Damme breaks a guys arm it is brutal.As the film rolls on,we discover Chance's background and how he himself has experienced the streets.Lance Henrickson is great as the Emil Fouchon chief bad guy,you just love to hate.And Arnold Vosloo as his sidekick Pick Van Cleef was great and funny at times.You just know when he utters the words "Randall,Randall,Randall" that Randall was in for a very bad day.Wilford Brimley as the enjoyable and funny uncle Douvee.The tag-line for this movie is "Don't Hunt What You Cant Kill" and the bad guys should have realised this.This is a decent and enjoyable Van Damme film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High-quality Van Damme at his absolute best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance Boudreaux (Van Damme) is a New Orleans longshoreman who is down on his luck and struggling to find work. Opportunity comes his way when Nat (Butler) hires him to help her find her missing father. As it turns out, her father isn't missing, necessarily, he was a victim of a malevolent gang of "human hunters". Led by Fouchon (Henriksen), and with his second in command Pik Van Cleef (Vosloo), they get their kicks (and get rich) letting weekend warriors pay them to go on the ultimate hunting expedition: for man! But they meet their match with the fearless Chance, a man they cannot kill. Along for the ride is Chance's uncle Douvee (Brimley). Will Chance get his chance at glory? Or, to the human hunters, is he just another HARD TARGET? Hard Target is hands-down one of Van Damme's best. It's explosively entertaining and lives up to the promise of a Van Damme and John Woo team-up. It's everything a combination of those two men could be and should be, and doesn't let the audience down. Once again, this is classic 90's action fun from the golden time when Van Damme movies went to the theater. Back then, we remember joking with our friends that because there's so much slow motion in this movie, if it was all played at regular speed, the film would be about 20 minutes. And it's true, there is a lot of dramatic slo-mo, but it's all for the best. And Van Damme and others get a lot of unnecessarily portentous entrances and exits, which just adds to the style of Hard Target, which is just a tad bit off-kilter. But that's far from a bad thing. It separates itself from its many competitors that way. Besides Van Damme and his absurd hair, the cast assembled for this is just killer: Lance Henriksen is great as the baddie who's so bad, even his piano-playing is evil. Vosloo is also adept at being bad, and his quasi-Scottish (?) accent, well, accentuates his sinister glares. Yancy Butler gives a bug-eyed performance who always seems surprised at the proceedings. But top marks must go to the great Wilford Brimley. In a strange role for him, the barely-intelligible, bow-and-arrow toting, horseback riding uncle is truly lovable and you root for him, even though he doesn't appear until late in the film. That's a tribute to Brimley that the audience can grow to love him so quickly. This movie puts a twist on the time-honored Most Dangerous Game (1932) idea. The formula's been tried before, with varying degrees of success, in everything from Death Ring (1992) to Avenging Force (1986). But Hard Target has plenty of awesome moments, including the extended climax in (what else) an abandoned warehouse. Never one to be afraid of wasting bullets, Woo pulls out all the stops in an extended feast of overkill. It's over-the-top fun everyone should see. On a technical note, the British DVD is longer than the American cut, including more violence. So try to track that down if you can, for the complete picture. Go down to the bayou tonight for some high-octane, high-quality Van Damme at his absolute best. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How can something so bad be this good?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put Hard Target is a terrible movie. It is a testament to how big Jean Claude Van Damme really was in the early nineties. He was a master of the action/Martial Arts film. Nearly every scene in this film feels like a spoof...a joke and yet its not at all. I am actually surprised Van Damme would do something like this given his ego because couldn't he see just how ridiculous it was. Its like the ultimate spoof of the 80's action genre. Who better to do it than John Woo? I constantly hear how legendary this director is but I often wonder if this opinion too is a joke. The guy almost killed the Mission Impossible franchise with ridiculous hair, constant slow motion camera tricks, and ridiculous "hero" analogies. And here we have Hard Target with the exact same MO. Hair, slow-mo, hero analogies all over again. Some day I might have someone watch this film and tell me how many times he goes into slow motion which is not dramatic in this case or even remotely "cool" but instead looks ridiculous, hokey and dumb. Especially when your hero is sporting a greasy, stringy mullet. Now all this being said, I'll be darned if this isn't some sort of bizarre cheeky entertainment. Maybe because its laughable or just how incredibly outlandish the action scenes are. The scene with Van Damme standing on the seat of a dirt bike, shooting bad guys and then rolling over the top of their car...is just too ridiculously legendary to not be cool. This is the stuff Chuck Norris wishes he had under his belt. Jean Claude Van Damme is not a great actor, never was. But there is no arguing his chemistry in the 90's. There is just something slick and cool about that enormous ego that he has. His character in Hard Target is just about portrayed as God-like. He has this untouchable, swoon at his feet persona that it so ridiculous that its fun to watch. Yancy Butler is the stereotypical required female partner to Van Damme. She does alright and certainly has the "deer in the headlights" look down pat. She literally looks 90% of the time like she is on an infomercial that is selling Jean Claude Van Damme and she wants it! Her longing looks and open mouthed gaping is hilarious. Their chemistry is okay but really sort of unnecessary. Lance Henriksen is actually the perfect action hero villain. He has the look down and he a cold blooded horrifying killer. He probably has the best role in the entire film. He is a very worthy action film villain. Not to be outdone Arnold Vosloo is a brilliant right hand man to Henriksen. He could have easily been the lead villain in his own right. He is equally as cold and calculating and you get two great final battles when Van Damme takes them on. Wilford Brimley makes a cameo as the obligatory old man that the hero cares about. John Woo gets constant praise from fans for being a "brilliant" action director but his style is always the same and is so awkward at times. He has to be the king of overusing slow motion and when you pair it together with Van Damme and this story it just makes it even more cheesy. Now all this being said Hard Target has found its niche. Twenty years later and it can sit comfortably in action classic status. You can laugh at it and marvel at the action scenes. Plenty of explosions and gun fights and non-stop action especially towards the end of the movie. I can give them kudos for actually creating a solid story even if its a little cookie cutter and predictable. Ultimately Hard Target is nothing but sheer entertainment no matter how you take it or look at it. Nothing wrong with that but it certainly makes a lot of grievous errors in film making and they should just be lucky that it will likely continue to achieve cult status amongst action fans and Van Damme junkies. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot going for it...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phillipfawcett
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but Claude Van Damme is not it! Not a fan, here, of a guy who has more wood in him than the Bastoin forest. Maybe I'm just not a karate fan: it always seems to me that by the time you've finishing spinning and getting your leg up, any adversary could have laid you out, end of. The slow-motion sequences just make me want to give the guy a Coors Light, so he can take his pay check and get out of there. Seagal is a much more engaging actor for me, and his Aikido seems more credible. However, I find this movie an enjoyable ride! Firstly, the premise is powerful and interesting. Sick gun-loving sons- of-bitches run a business which stages real-life hunts of some poor wretch who 'will not be missed'. They always take care to choose somebody with a fighting background, like a Nam Vet, just to give them a bit of a challenge. The script makes an effort to lend this credibility by explaining that 'trouble spots' in the world are always chosen for this, and they move on from country to country after each 'hunt' to evade fallout. Secondly, some of the characters are extremely strong, particularly the villains. Lance Henriksen is always good value, and here puts in a wonderfully hard-assed and droll portrayal of the 'Director' (for want of a better title). Legendary movie quote #33: "Now you know why we insist on payment up front." LOL His side-kick, 'Pik', is a superbly sadistic piece of work by Arnold Vosloo. He doesn't overplay it, yet leaves the viewer in no doubt as to his nature. He has a quiet and chilling business-like manner most of the time, but when time comes for an execution you see what a hobby it is for him, with the twinkle in his eye. The two lead females are sympathetic and credible characters, especially policewoman Kasi Lemmons. Unfortunately the same cannot be said for the 'lovable' but ridiculous Uncle Douvee. I guess he was injected into the final phase of the movie to lend a sprinkling of humour, but imo it did not need it. We already have the two main good characters to engage with, and the movie should have been allowed to stand on its gritty and punchy violence and the quite disturbing aspects of human nature. We really care if some of these characters live or die, even the psychos! In a downtown New Orleans scene, one of the 'hunted' is totally unable to get anybody to help him, which made me really angry. All too believable, and really lent credibility to how the company gets away with it. Uncle Douvee... jeez. If you can get past the image of this old fool playing the hero, then fair play to you (maybe I need to 'lighten up'). If you can get past the attempts at a French (or Belgian, whatever) accent by the very American bit-part actor Wilfred Brimley, then you were not getitng properly into the movie in the first place. Sorry to pick on him, but for me it really grated. It's all the more sad when you remember him in his straight-up role as a mafia henchman in 'The Firm': believable and exactly the tone called for here. Bit-part is what it was, though, and the strengths of the movie outweigh the weaknesses. I would have loved to see Harrison Ford or even Bruce Willis in the Van Damme role - with the every-guy credibility and minus the slow motion, please!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's like a drug isn't it, to bring a man down?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hard Target is directed by John Woo and written by Chuck Pfarrer. It stars Jean-Claude Van Damme, Lance Henriksen, Yancy Butler, Arnold Vosloo and Wilford Brimley. Music is by Graeme Revell and cinematography by Russell Carpenter. New Orleans and ex-merchant marine Chance Boudreaux (Damme) is struggling to gain employment on account of some muscular indiscretions. However, after saving Natasha Binder (Butler) from the hands of robbers, he is offered some work by her that pays handsomely. The task is to find out where her father is, a homeless ex-forces man who has mysteriously disappeared. It's a search that leads them to a sick urban safari being run by Emil Fouchon (Henriksen), the prey? Man! After pushing the boundaries of action cinema in Hong Kong, it was only a matter of time before John Woo got lured to America to dabble in the dollar. Hard Target was his first American movie, which in spite of the studio being nervous about his hiring (Sam Raimi was on standby should it implode) and cuts being made on demand for a certificate rating to open it up to a wider audience, it worked out well. It was a financial success, even though there was the inevitable mixed reviews from critics and today it rightly is held in high regard amongst action movie die- hards. OK! Nobody could seriously claim it's a titan of cinema, it's an absurd story derived from The Most Dangerous Game, the acting is of the usual Van Damme kick assery standard (JC pouts and mumbles, Butler is terrible, Brimley is miscast, Henriksen so over the top we almost lose him from our vision) and preposterousness reaches new levels. Yes it's a dumb fun action movie where leaving the brain at the door is a requisite. But what action delights await the faithful, what grace and style does Woo bring to the mayhem, it's a visceral thriller that once it gets the plot initiations out of the way, unleashes beautiful carnage that thunders the chest royally. Can violence be lyrical? In Woo's hands yes, certainly. The action film is one of the most maligned in cinema, but there is great artistry to many of them, to that end Hard Target scores incredibly high. The stunt work is amazing, the choreography of the fight scenes, with Van Damme showing his wonderful skills, are exquisite sights for the action film fan. Woo's tricks involving slow-mo, freeze frames and juddering close ups all get worked out here, quite often forming part of another ballet of bloodshed. Woo and Van Damme were a good fit, the film rocks for those so inclined for such kinetic malarkey, and not even The Muscles from Brussels' mullet can spoil the enjoyment. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What made you want to complicate my life like this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS*** Even for a Jean-Claude Van Damme action movie "Hard Target" is just a bit too hard to take despite all its action scenes as well as Mr. Van Damme's kick boxing & martial art talents. At first the film starts off like the 1932 classic "The Most Dangerous Game" but quickly deteriorates into a mindless and disjointed free for all. With Van Damme as merchant marine Chance Boudreaux taking on an entire army of bikers in the Louisiana bayous lead by the villainous Emil Fouchon played by Lance Henriksen. Totally unbelievable fight & action scenes even for Van Damme to preform with or without a stunt double that has him have more lives in the movie then a dozen cats. There's also Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's love interest in the film Nat Binder, Nancy Butler, who despite being a damsel in distress seems to have trouble keeping a straight face in many of the action as well as love scenes she's in the movie. It was Nat's missing dad, Douglas Pfarrer,who was later found to be murdered that had Van Damme, who was hired by Net to find him, get involved in this holy mess in the first place. And who can forget Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's moon shine drinking uncle Douvee played by William Brimley who about the best, after Lance Henriksen, actor in the film. Who no matter how much booze he drinks is still able to ride his horse without falling off as well as shoot arrows as accurately as Robin Hood. And as things turned out it was the booze, or the flask that he stored it in, that ended up saving his life! The final showdown in the film between Van Damme-Chance Boudreaux-and Emil Fouchon-Lance Henriksen-just went on and on to the point where all the fighting shooting and exploding lost their effect since for a time it didn't effect the two at all. And when it finally ended you couldn't care less who ended up winning but was happy as hell to know the movie, and all the suffering you went through in watching it, was thank God finally over!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good plot, entertaining, but nowhere near a Woo classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a far cry from Woo's masterpeices in Hong Kong. It was his first American movie and one must say that in a lot of ways it is a disappointment. I am not saying that it is a bad movie, but it seems that the creative genius that is John Woo is seriously hindered by the capital focus of the American market. Us Westerners like movies with happy endings and movies that do not challenge us to think. This movie is action but its action is not beautifully crafted within a movie with real characters struggling in a real world. Hard Target is set in New Orleans during a police strike, though this does not seem evident. A group has set itself up where they hire vagrants to run 10 kilometers with $10 000 while they are being chased by hunters. These vagrants are not supposed to have any ties, but unfortunately they chose somebody who does. When his daughter comes to New Orleans to find him dead, she starts asking questions, and brings Van Damme in to help her. The plot is good, but the thing with Woo's movies from Hong Kong is that it is about the characters struggling with themselves and the bad guys were simply around to make their life even harder. No such struggle occurs within this movie. Van Damme, who is simply a sailor that happens to be good at martial arts, is not able to play a character with any depth. Personally I do not think much of his acting ability, and people really only watch his movies to see his moves - and they are not even martial arts. The only reason Van Damme can do these moves is because he is a dancer. The movie plasters John Woo as being the director and attempts to attract people to the movie on this fact. The action is good, and the imagery used is typical of John Woo. He is a brilliant director, but is even better when he is not restrained. I feel that this film is let down in the fact that there is no character struggle in this movie. The characters are not anti-heroes, which is one of the aspects that elevates Woo movies above the others. It is not until Face Off that John Woo's American movies began to stand out. There are two things that seem to form a part of Woo movies. The main characters either begin as friends but slowly drift apart until they are fighting each other at the end, or they are apart and through the struggles that they face, they are drawn together and realise that they need to help each other. Face Off is a completely different idea where the good guy suddenly finds that he is the bad guy and cannot do anything about it. A Bullet in the Head, Too Catch a Thief, and Broken Arrow are examples of the first type, while The Killer and Hard Boiled are examples of the second type. Hard Target doesn't fall into either category. The characters do not entertain me as their struggles are purely action orientated and as such it doesn't grab me as Woo's other movies do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Competent action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DaRick89
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As with many action movies, Hard to Kill's strengths and weaknesses are fairly simple to analyse. It's a competent action thriller, notable for some stylish action scenes that have John Woo's touch; one particularly memorable example is when Chance Boudreaux (Jean-Claude Van Damme) quite literally blasts a bikie thug out a window with a shotgun and a petrol can! These moments pretty much make the film worth seeing by themselves, despite the usual weaknesses in the plotting and JCVD's ever wooden countenance. As JCVD himself noted however, viewers paid the money to see him waste bad guys and he does plenty of this - sometimes in more inventive ways than expected (using snake traps). It very much makes the film worth seeing for action buffs, even though I'm reluctant to give a really high rating based on this alone. The plot is not too extraordinary: a homeless veteran gets murdered by a team of mercenaries led by Emil Fouchoud (Henriksen) and Van Cleaf (Vosloo), after which his daughter Nat (Butler) comes looking for him and commissions Boudreaux, a homeless Cajun merchant marine (!) to help her out after he rescues her from marauding thugs, raising the ire of the mercenary team. A few plot holes are obvious (shouldn't this mercenary team have been dealt with a while ago, police strike or not? Why is JCVD made a CAJUN?), but it works well as a vehicle for blowing stuff up and killing people. The dialogue is pretty standard stuff: some profanity, some hilariously cringeworthy lines ("don't worry about Randall; he's all ears!) and some macho stuff. As for the acting, the villains are better than the heroes. Of course, when JCVD is your hero, that's bound to be the case, with his unconvincing delivery. He has recently shown that he is capable of acting, but he was a long off that in 1993. Still, English is probably his third language (after French and Dutch); Yancy Butler has no such excuses, being quite wooden in a role that doesn't demand that much. Vosloo and Henriksen are much better though. Vosloo has that quiet menace that always makes him a good villain, while Henriksen goes from menacing and purposeful to merrily nuts as Boudreaux causes him more difficulties than expected. Even Wilford Brimley is amusing as Chance's crazy uncle, reeling off some zany lines. In the end, Hard Target is not a great movie, but it's a competent action thriller with some nice stylistic touches from John Woo during the action scenes. Henriksen, Vosloo and Brimley compensate somewhat for JCVD and Butler, but you still shouldn't watch this film for the acting and especially not for the plotting. Action fans generally don't really look for either that much though, so that's alright. Movie-goers looking for a bit more will probably like some of the style, but won't find that much else. 3/5 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Lance Henriksen show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies starring Jean-Claude Van Damme can't be labeled as anything else than "so bad it's good" material. This one makes no exception. Lance Henriksen however, transcends the genre with a grandiose over-the-top performance that's great fun to watch. As to Van Damme, this actor is not merely campy. His lack of charisma, not to mention linguistic competence, is simply astonishing. Butler is a perfect match  she's fake as a Latino soap-opera, although her English is better than Van Damme's. The film's plot is ridiculous and it gets over- violent to the point of being unpleasant, but it's all worth watching for Lance Henriksen's gleefully villainous show-off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    HK Neo Reviews: Hard Target
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (webmaster@thehkneo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director John Woo's first venture into Hollywood was not without its obstacles. With Van Damme being one of Hollywood's bright action stars back in the early 90s, it is pretty much certain that Woo lacked what he received in his later works  control. The film for most of it, seems uneven, especially when there are scenes you can clearly see as Woo's footprints all over it and there are others that are just plain awful. Still, if you ignore the bad acting from Van Damme, poor pacing, poor editing, there is still fun to be had. Namely the majority of the shooting sequences, a wonderful villainous turn by future "The Mummy" star  Lance Henriksen and a few pigeons to boost, Hard Target is really not that bad Neo rates it 6/10. - www.thehkneo.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best Van Damme movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chris1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First saw this movie when i was buying a video of Maximum Risk,which is a decent Van Damme film.So i watched this film and was not disappointed,i was entertained throughout the whole movie.The action was practically non-stop.The storyline is decent enough with ruthless business men hunting homeless war veterans,and the street-wise Chance Boudreaux was going to find out sooner or later,to bad for the bad guys.The action scenes are spot on.When Van Damme first appears,you just know the s**t is going down.In roughly the first half hour of the film sees a fight at a caf&eacute; in which Van Damme breaks a guys arm it is brutal.As the film rolls on,we discover Chance's background and how he himself has experienced the streets.Lance Henrickson is great as the Emil Fouchon chief bad guy,you just love to hate.And Arnold Vosloo as his sidekick Pick Van Cleef was great and funny at times.You just know when he utters the words "Randall,Randall,Randall" that Randall was in for a very bad day.Wilford Brimley as the enjoyable and funny uncle Douvee.The tag-line for this movie is "Don't Hunt What You Cant Kill" and the bad guys should have realised this.This is a decent and enjoyable Van Damme film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High-quality Van Damme at his absolute best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance Boudreaux (Van Damme) is a New Orleans longshoreman who is down on his luck and struggling to find work. Opportunity comes his way when Nat (Butler) hires him to help her find her missing father. As it turns out, her father isn't missing, necessarily, he was a victim of a malevolent gang of "human hunters". Led by Fouchon (Henriksen), and with his second in command Pik Van Cleef (Vosloo), they get their kicks (and get rich) letting weekend warriors pay them to go on the ultimate hunting expedition: for man! But they meet their match with the fearless Chance, a man they cannot kill. Along for the ride is Chance's uncle Douvee (Brimley). Will Chance get his chance at glory? Or, to the human hunters, is he just another HARD TARGET? Hard Target is hands-down one of Van Damme's best. It's explosively entertaining and lives up to the promise of a Van Damme and John Woo team-up. It's everything a combination of those two men could be and should be, and doesn't let the audience down. Once again, this is classic 90's action fun from the golden time when Van Damme movies went to the theater. Back then, we remember joking with our friends that because there's so much slow motion in this movie, if it was all played at regular speed, the film would be about 20 minutes. And it's true, there is a lot of dramatic slo-mo, but it's all for the best. And Van Damme and others get a lot of unnecessarily portentous entrances and exits, which just adds to the style of Hard Target, which is just a tad bit off-kilter. But that's far from a bad thing. It separates itself from its many competitors that way. Besides Van Damme and his absurd hair, the cast assembled for this is just killer: Lance Henriksen is great as the baddie who's so bad, even his piano-playing is evil. Vosloo is also adept at being bad, and his quasi-Scottish (?) accent, well, accentuates his sinister glares. Yancy Butler gives a bug-eyed performance who always seems surprised at the proceedings. But top marks must go to the great Wilford Brimley. In a strange role for him, the barely-intelligible, bow-and-arrow toting, horseback riding uncle is truly lovable and you root for him, even though he doesn't appear until late in the film. That's a tribute to Brimley that the audience can grow to love him so quickly. This movie puts a twist on the time-honored Most Dangerous Game (1932) idea. The formula's been tried before, with varying degrees of success, in everything from Death Ring (1992) to Avenging Force (1986). But Hard Target has plenty of awesome moments, including the extended climax in (what else) an abandoned warehouse. Never one to be afraid of wasting bullets, Woo pulls out all the stops in an extended feast of overkill. It's over-the-top fun everyone should see. On a technical note, the British DVD is longer than the American cut, including more violence. So try to track that down if you can, for the complete picture. Go down to the bayou tonight for some high-octane, high-quality Van Damme at his absolute best. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How can something so bad be this good?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put Hard Target is a terrible movie. It is a testament to how big Jean Claude Van Damme really was in the early nineties. He was a master of the action/Martial Arts film. Nearly every scene in this film feels like a spoof...a joke and yet its not at all. I am actually surprised Van Damme would do something like this given his ego because couldn't he see just how ridiculous it was. Its like the ultimate spoof of the 80's action genre. Who better to do it than John Woo? I constantly hear how legendary this director is but I often wonder if this opinion too is a joke. The guy almost killed the Mission Impossible franchise with ridiculous hair, constant slow motion camera tricks, and ridiculous "hero" analogies. And here we have Hard Target with the exact same MO. Hair, slow-mo, hero analogies all over again. Some day I might have someone watch this film and tell me how many times he goes into slow motion which is not dramatic in this case or even remotely "cool" but instead looks ridiculous, hokey and dumb. Especially when your hero is sporting a greasy, stringy mullet. Now all this being said, I'll be darned if this isn't some sort of bizarre cheeky entertainment. Maybe because its laughable or just how incredibly outlandish the action scenes are. The scene with Van Damme standing on the seat of a dirt bike, shooting bad guys and then rolling over the top of their car...is just too ridiculously legendary to not be cool. This is the stuff Chuck Norris wishes he had under his belt. Jean Claude Van Damme is not a great actor, never was. But there is no arguing his chemistry in the 90's. There is just something slick and cool about that enormous ego that he has. His character in Hard Target is just about portrayed as God-like. He has this untouchable, swoon at his feet persona that it so ridiculous that its fun to watch. Yancy Butler is the stereotypical required female partner to Van Damme. She does alright and certainly has the "deer in the headlights" look down pat. She literally looks 90% of the time like she is on an infomercial that is selling Jean Claude Van Damme and she wants it! Her longing looks and open mouthed gaping is hilarious. Their chemistry is okay but really sort of unnecessary. Lance Henriksen is actually the perfect action hero villain. He has the look down and he a cold blooded horrifying killer. He probably has the best role in the entire film. He is a very worthy action film villain. Not to be outdone Arnold Vosloo is a brilliant right hand man to Henriksen. He could have easily been the lead villain in his own right. He is equally as cold and calculating and you get two great final battles when Van Damme takes them on. Wilford Brimley makes a cameo as the obligatory old man that the hero cares about. John Woo gets constant praise from fans for being a "brilliant" action director but his style is always the same and is so awkward at times. He has to be the king of overusing slow motion and when you pair it together with Van Damme and this story it just makes it even more cheesy. Now all this being said Hard Target has found its niche. Twenty years later and it can sit comfortably in action classic status. You can laugh at it and marvel at the action scenes. Plenty of explosions and gun fights and non-stop action especially towards the end of the movie. I can give them kudos for actually creating a solid story even if its a little cookie cutter and predictable. Ultimately Hard Target is nothing but sheer entertainment no matter how you take it or look at it. Nothing wrong with that but it certainly makes a lot of grievous errors in film making and they should just be lucky that it will likely continue to achieve cult status amongst action fans and Van Damme junkies. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot going for it...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phillipfawcett
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but Claude Van Damme is not it! Not a fan, here, of a guy who has more wood in him than the Bastoin forest. Maybe I'm just not a karate fan: it always seems to me that by the time you've finishing spinning and getting your leg up, any adversary could have laid you out, end of. The slow-motion sequences just make me want to give the guy a Coors Light, so he can take his pay check and get out of there. Seagal is a much more engaging actor for me, and his Aikido seems more credible. However, I find this movie an enjoyable ride! Firstly, the premise is powerful and interesting. Sick gun-loving sons- of-bitches run a business which stages real-life hunts of some poor wretch who 'will not be missed'. They always take care to choose somebody with a fighting background, like a Nam Vet, just to give them a bit of a challenge. The script makes an effort to lend this credibility by explaining that 'trouble spots' in the world are always chosen for this, and they move on from country to country after each 'hunt' to evade fallout. Secondly, some of the characters are extremely strong, particularly the villains. Lance Henriksen is always good value, and here puts in a wonderfully hard-assed and droll portrayal of the 'Director' (for want of a better title). Legendary movie quote #33: "Now you know why we insist on payment up front." LOL His side-kick, 'Pik', is a superbly sadistic piece of work by Arnold Vosloo. He doesn't overplay it, yet leaves the viewer in no doubt as to his nature. He has a quiet and chilling business-like manner most of the time, but when time comes for an execution you see what a hobby it is for him, with the twinkle in his eye. The two lead females are sympathetic and credible characters, especially policewoman Kasi Lemmons. Unfortunately the same cannot be said for the 'lovable' but ridiculous Uncle Douvee. I guess he was injected into the final phase of the movie to lend a sprinkling of humour, but imo it did not need it. We already have the two main good characters to engage with, and the movie should have been allowed to stand on its gritty and punchy violence and the quite disturbing aspects of human nature. We really care if some of these characters live or die, even the psychos! In a downtown New Orleans scene, one of the 'hunted' is totally unable to get anybody to help him, which made me really angry. All too believable, and really lent credibility to how the company gets away with it. Uncle Douvee... jeez. If you can get past the image of this old fool playing the hero, then fair play to you (maybe I need to 'lighten up'). If you can get past the attempts at a French (or Belgian, whatever) accent by the very American bit-part actor Wilfred Brimley, then you were not getitng properly into the movie in the first place. Sorry to pick on him, but for me it really grated. It's all the more sad when you remember him in his straight-up role as a mafia henchman in 'The Firm': believable and exactly the tone called for here. Bit-part is what it was, though, and the strengths of the movie outweigh the weaknesses. I would have loved to see Harrison Ford or even Bruce Willis in the Van Damme role - with the every-guy credibility and minus the slow motion, please!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's like a drug isn't it, to bring a man down?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hard Target is directed by John Woo and written by Chuck Pfarrer. It stars Jean-Claude Van Damme, Lance Henriksen, Yancy Butler, Arnold Vosloo and Wilford Brimley. Music is by Graeme Revell and cinematography by Russell Carpenter. New Orleans and ex-merchant marine Chance Boudreaux (Damme) is struggling to gain employment on account of some muscular indiscretions. However, after saving Natasha Binder (Butler) from the hands of robbers, he is offered some work by her that pays handsomely. The task is to find out where her father is, a homeless ex-forces man who has mysteriously disappeared. It's a search that leads them to a sick urban safari being run by Emil Fouchon (Henriksen), the prey? Man! After pushing the boundaries of action cinema in Hong Kong, it was only a matter of time before John Woo got lured to America to dabble in the dollar. Hard Target was his first American movie, which in spite of the studio being nervous about his hiring (Sam Raimi was on standby should it implode) and cuts being made on demand for a certificate rating to open it up to a wider audience, it worked out well. It was a financial success, even though there was the inevitable mixed reviews from critics and today it rightly is held in high regard amongst action movie die- hards. OK! Nobody could seriously claim it's a titan of cinema, it's an absurd story derived from The Most Dangerous Game, the acting is of the usual Van Damme kick assery standard (JC pouts and mumbles, Butler is terrible, Brimley is miscast, Henriksen so over the top we almost lose him from our vision) and preposterousness reaches new levels. Yes it's a dumb fun action movie where leaving the brain at the door is a requisite. But what action delights await the faithful, what grace and style does Woo bring to the mayhem, it's a visceral thriller that once it gets the plot initiations out of the way, unleashes beautiful carnage that thunders the chest royally. Can violence be lyrical? In Woo's hands yes, certainly. The action film is one of the most maligned in cinema, but there is great artistry to many of them, to that end Hard Target scores incredibly high. The stunt work is amazing, the choreography of the fight scenes, with Van Damme showing his wonderful skills, are exquisite sights for the action film fan. Woo's tricks involving slow-mo, freeze frames and juddering close ups all get worked out here, quite often forming part of another ballet of bloodshed. Woo and Van Damme were a good fit, the film rocks for those so inclined for such kinetic malarkey, and not even The Muscles from Brussels' mullet can spoil the enjoyment. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What made you want to complicate my life like this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS*** Even for a Jean-Claude Van Damme action movie "Hard Target" is just a bit too hard to take despite all its action scenes as well as Mr. Van Damme's kick boxing & martial art talents. At first the film starts off like the 1932 classic "The Most Dangerous Game" but quickly deteriorates into a mindless and disjointed free for all. With Van Damme as merchant marine Chance Boudreaux taking on an entire army of bikers in the Louisiana bayous lead by the villainous Emil Fouchon played by Lance Henriksen. Totally unbelievable fight & action scenes even for Van Damme to preform with or without a stunt double that has him have more lives in the movie then a dozen cats. There's also Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's love interest in the film Nat Binder, Nancy Butler, who despite being a damsel in distress seems to have trouble keeping a straight face in many of the action as well as love scenes she's in the movie. It was Nat's missing dad, Douglas Pfarrer,who was later found to be murdered that had Van Damme, who was hired by Net to find him, get involved in this holy mess in the first place. And who can forget Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's moon shine drinking uncle Douvee played by William Brimley who about the best, after Lance Henriksen, actor in the film. Who no matter how much booze he drinks is still able to ride his horse without falling off as well as shoot arrows as accurately as Robin Hood. And as things turned out it was the booze, or the flask that he stored it in, that ended up saving his life! The final showdown in the film between Van Damme-Chance Boudreaux-and Emil Fouchon-Lance Henriksen-just went on and on to the point where all the fighting shooting and exploding lost their effect since for a time it didn't effect the two at all. And when it finally ended you couldn't care less who ended up winning but was happy as hell to know the movie, and all the suffering you went through in watching it, was thank God finally over!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good plot, entertaining, but nowhere near a Woo classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a far cry from Woo's masterpeices in Hong Kong. It was his first American movie and one must say that in a lot of ways it is a disappointment. I am not saying that it is a bad movie, but it seems that the creative genius that is John Woo is seriously hindered by the capital focus of the American market. Us Westerners like movies with happy endings and movies that do not challenge us to think. This movie is action but its action is not beautifully crafted within a movie with real characters struggling in a real world. Hard Target is set in New Orleans during a police strike, though this does not seem evident. A group has set itself up where they hire vagrants to run 10 kilometers with $10 000 while they are being chased by hunters. These vagrants are not supposed to have any ties, but unfortunately they chose somebody who does. When his daughter comes to New Orleans to find him dead, she starts asking questions, and brings Van Damme in to help her. The plot is good, but the thing with Woo's movies from Hong Kong is that it is about the characters struggling with themselves and the bad guys were simply around to make their life even harder. No such struggle occurs within this movie. Van Damme, who is simply a sailor that happens to be good at martial arts, is not able to play a character with any depth. Personally I do not think much of his acting ability, and people really only watch his movies to see his moves - and they are not even martial arts. The only reason Van Damme can do these moves is because he is a dancer. The movie plasters John Woo as being the director and attempts to attract people to the movie on this fact. The action is good, and the imagery used is typical of John Woo. He is a brilliant director, but is even better when he is not restrained. I feel that this film is let down in the fact that there is no character struggle in this movie. The characters are not anti-heroes, which is one of the aspects that elevates Woo movies above the others. It is not until Face Off that John Woo's American movies began to stand out. There are two things that seem to form a part of Woo movies. The main characters either begin as friends but slowly drift apart until they are fighting each other at the end, or they are apart and through the struggles that they face, they are drawn together and realise that they need to help each other. Face Off is a completely different idea where the good guy suddenly finds that he is the bad guy and cannot do anything about it. A Bullet in the Head, Too Catch a Thief, and Broken Arrow are examples of the first type, while The Killer and Hard Boiled are examples of the second type. Hard Target doesn't fall into either category. The characters do not entertain me as their struggles are purely action orientated and as such it doesn't grab me as Woo's other movies do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Competent action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DaRick89
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As with many action movies, Hard to Kill's strengths and weaknesses are fairly simple to analyse. It's a competent action thriller, notable for some stylish action scenes that have John Woo's touch; one particularly memorable example is when Chance Boudreaux (Jean-Claude Van Damme) quite literally blasts a bikie thug out a window with a shotgun and a petrol can! These moments pretty much make the film worth seeing by themselves, despite the usual weaknesses in the plotting and JCVD's ever wooden countenance. As JCVD himself noted however, viewers paid the money to see him waste bad guys and he does plenty of this - sometimes in more inventive ways than expected (using snake traps). It very much makes the film worth seeing for action buffs, even though I'm reluctant to give a really high rating based on this alone. The plot is not too extraordinary: a homeless veteran gets murdered by a team of mercenaries led by Emil Fouchoud (Henriksen) and Van Cleaf (Vosloo), after which his daughter Nat (Butler) comes looking for him and commissions Boudreaux, a homeless Cajun merchant marine (!) to help her out after he rescues her from marauding thugs, raising the ire of the mercenary team. A few plot holes are obvious (shouldn't this mercenary team have been dealt with a while ago, police strike or not? Why is JCVD made a CAJUN?), but it works well as a vehicle for blowing stuff up and killing people. The dialogue is pretty standard stuff: some profanity, some hilariously cringeworthy lines ("don't worry about Randall; he's all ears!) and some macho stuff. As for the acting, the villains are better than the heroes. Of course, when JCVD is your hero, that's bound to be the case, with his unconvincing delivery. He has recently shown that he is capable of acting, but he was a long off that in 1993. Still, English is probably his third language (after French and Dutch); Yancy Butler has no such excuses, being quite wooden in a role that doesn't demand that much. Vosloo and Henriksen are much better though. Vosloo has that quiet menace that always makes him a good villain, while Henriksen goes from menacing and purposeful to merrily nuts as Boudreaux causes him more difficulties than expected. Even Wilford Brimley is amusing as Chance's crazy uncle, reeling off some zany lines. In the end, Hard Target is not a great movie, but it's a competent action thriller with some nice stylistic touches from John Woo during the action scenes. Henriksen, Vosloo and Brimley compensate somewhat for JCVD and Butler, but you still shouldn't watch this film for the acting and especially not for the plotting. Action fans generally don't really look for either that much though, so that's alright. Movie-goers looking for a bit more will probably like some of the style, but won't find that much else. 3/5 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Lance Henriksen show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies starring Jean-Claude Van Damme can't be labeled as anything else than "so bad it's good" material. This one makes no exception. Lance Henriksen however, transcends the genre with a grandiose over-the-top performance that's great fun to watch. As to Van Damme, this actor is not merely campy. His lack of charisma, not to mention linguistic competence, is simply astonishing. Butler is a perfect match  she's fake as a Latino soap-opera, although her English is better than Van Damme's. The film's plot is ridiculous and it gets over- violent to the point of being unpleasant, but it's all worth watching for Lance Henriksen's gleefully villainous show-off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    HK Neo Reviews: Hard Target
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (webmaster@thehkneo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director John Woo's first venture into Hollywood was not without its obstacles. With Van Damme being one of Hollywood's bright action stars back in the early 90s, it is pretty much certain that Woo lacked what he received in his later works  control. The film for most of it, seems uneven, especially when there are scenes you can clearly see as Woo's footprints all over it and there are others that are just plain awful. Still, if you ignore the bad acting from Van Damme, poor pacing, poor editing, there is still fun to be had. Namely the majority of the shooting sequences, a wonderful villainous turn by future "The Mummy" star  Lance Henriksen and a few pigeons to boost, Hard Target is really not that bad Neo rates it 6/10. - www.thehkneo.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best Van Damme movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chris1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First saw this movie when i was buying a video of Maximum Risk,which is a decent Van Damme film.So i watched this film and was not disappointed,i was entertained throughout the whole movie.The action was practically non-stop.The storyline is decent enough with ruthless business men hunting homeless war veterans,and the street-wise Chance Boudreaux was going to find out sooner or later,to bad for the bad guys.The action scenes are spot on.When Van Damme first appears,you just know the s**t is going down.In roughly the first half hour of the film sees a fight at a caf&eacute; in which Van Damme breaks a guys arm it is brutal.As the film rolls on,we discover Chance's background and how he himself has experienced the streets.Lance Henrickson is great as the Emil Fouchon chief bad guy,you just love to hate.And Arnold Vosloo as his sidekick Pick Van Cleef was great and funny at times.You just know when he utters the words "Randall,Randall,Randall" that Randall was in for a very bad day.Wilford Brimley as the enjoyable and funny uncle Douvee.The tag-line for this movie is "Don't Hunt What You Cant Kill" and the bad guys should have realised this.This is a decent and enjoyable Van Damme film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High-quality Van Damme at his absolute best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance Boudreaux (Van Damme) is a New Orleans longshoreman who is down on his luck and struggling to find work. Opportunity comes his way when Nat (Butler) hires him to help her find her missing father. As it turns out, her father isn't missing, necessarily, he was a victim of a malevolent gang of "human hunters". Led by Fouchon (Henriksen), and with his second in command Pik Van Cleef (Vosloo), they get their kicks (and get rich) letting weekend warriors pay them to go on the ultimate hunting expedition: for man! But they meet their match with the fearless Chance, a man they cannot kill. Along for the ride is Chance's uncle Douvee (Brimley). Will Chance get his chance at glory? Or, to the human hunters, is he just another HARD TARGET? Hard Target is hands-down one of Van Damme's best. It's explosively entertaining and lives up to the promise of a Van Damme and John Woo team-up. It's everything a combination of those two men could be and should be, and doesn't let the audience down. Once again, this is classic 90's action fun from the golden time when Van Damme movies went to the theater. Back then, we remember joking with our friends that because there's so much slow motion in this movie, if it was all played at regular speed, the film would be about 20 minutes. And it's true, there is a lot of dramatic slo-mo, but it's all for the best. And Van Damme and others get a lot of unnecessarily portentous entrances and exits, which just adds to the style of Hard Target, which is just a tad bit off-kilter. But that's far from a bad thing. It separates itself from its many competitors that way. Besides Van Damme and his absurd hair, the cast assembled for this is just killer: Lance Henriksen is great as the baddie who's so bad, even his piano-playing is evil. Vosloo is also adept at being bad, and his quasi-Scottish (?) accent, well, accentuates his sinister glares. Yancy Butler gives a bug-eyed performance who always seems surprised at the proceedings. But top marks must go to the great Wilford Brimley. In a strange role for him, the barely-intelligible, bow-and-arrow toting, horseback riding uncle is truly lovable and you root for him, even though he doesn't appear until late in the film. That's a tribute to Brimley that the audience can grow to love him so quickly. This movie puts a twist on the time-honored Most Dangerous Game (1932) idea. The formula's been tried before, with varying degrees of success, in everything from Death Ring (1992) to Avenging Force (1986). But Hard Target has plenty of awesome moments, including the extended climax in (what else) an abandoned warehouse. Never one to be afraid of wasting bullets, Woo pulls out all the stops in an extended feast of overkill. It's over-the-top fun everyone should see. On a technical note, the British DVD is longer than the American cut, including more violence. So try to track that down if you can, for the complete picture. Go down to the bayou tonight for some high-octane, high-quality Van Damme at his absolute best. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How can something so bad be this good?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put Hard Target is a terrible movie. It is a testament to how big Jean Claude Van Damme really was in the early nineties. He was a master of the action/Martial Arts film. Nearly every scene in this film feels like a spoof...a joke and yet its not at all. I am actually surprised Van Damme would do something like this given his ego because couldn't he see just how ridiculous it was. Its like the ultimate spoof of the 80's action genre. Who better to do it than John Woo? I constantly hear how legendary this director is but I often wonder if this opinion too is a joke. The guy almost killed the Mission Impossible franchise with ridiculous hair, constant slow motion camera tricks, and ridiculous "hero" analogies. And here we have Hard Target with the exact same MO. Hair, slow-mo, hero analogies all over again. Some day I might have someone watch this film and tell me how many times he goes into slow motion which is not dramatic in this case or even remotely "cool" but instead looks ridiculous, hokey and dumb. Especially when your hero is sporting a greasy, stringy mullet. Now all this being said, I'll be darned if this isn't some sort of bizarre cheeky entertainment. Maybe because its laughable or just how incredibly outlandish the action scenes are. The scene with Van Damme standing on the seat of a dirt bike, shooting bad guys and then rolling over the top of their car...is just too ridiculously legendary to not be cool. This is the stuff Chuck Norris wishes he had under his belt. Jean Claude Van Damme is not a great actor, never was. But there is no arguing his chemistry in the 90's. There is just something slick and cool about that enormous ego that he has. His character in Hard Target is just about portrayed as God-like. He has this untouchable, swoon at his feet persona that it so ridiculous that its fun to watch. Yancy Butler is the stereotypical required female partner to Van Damme. She does alright and certainly has the "deer in the headlights" look down pat. She literally looks 90% of the time like she is on an infomercial that is selling Jean Claude Van Damme and she wants it! Her longing looks and open mouthed gaping is hilarious. Their chemistry is okay but really sort of unnecessary. Lance Henriksen is actually the perfect action hero villain. He has the look down and he a cold blooded horrifying killer. He probably has the best role in the entire film. He is a very worthy action film villain. Not to be outdone Arnold Vosloo is a brilliant right hand man to Henriksen. He could have easily been the lead villain in his own right. He is equally as cold and calculating and you get two great final battles when Van Damme takes them on. Wilford Brimley makes a cameo as the obligatory old man that the hero cares about. John Woo gets constant praise from fans for being a "brilliant" action director but his style is always the same and is so awkward at times. He has to be the king of overusing slow motion and when you pair it together with Van Damme and this story it just makes it even more cheesy. Now all this being said Hard Target has found its niche. Twenty years later and it can sit comfortably in action classic status. You can laugh at it and marvel at the action scenes. Plenty of explosions and gun fights and non-stop action especially towards the end of the movie. I can give them kudos for actually creating a solid story even if its a little cookie cutter and predictable. Ultimately Hard Target is nothing but sheer entertainment no matter how you take it or look at it. Nothing wrong with that but it certainly makes a lot of grievous errors in film making and they should just be lucky that it will likely continue to achieve cult status amongst action fans and Van Damme junkies. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot going for it...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phillipfawcett
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... but Claude Van Damme is not it! Not a fan, here, of a guy who has more wood in him than the Bastoin forest. Maybe I'm just not a karate fan: it always seems to me that by the time you've finishing spinning and getting your leg up, any adversary could have laid you out, end of. The slow-motion sequences just make me want to give the guy a Coors Light, so he can take his pay check and get out of there. Seagal is a much more engaging actor for me, and his Aikido seems more credible. However, I find this movie an enjoyable ride! Firstly, the premise is powerful and interesting. Sick gun-loving sons- of-bitches run a business which stages real-life hunts of some poor wretch who 'will not be missed'. They always take care to choose somebody with a fighting background, like a Nam Vet, just to give them a bit of a challenge. The script makes an effort to lend this credibility by explaining that 'trouble spots' in the world are always chosen for this, and they move on from country to country after each 'hunt' to evade fallout. Secondly, some of the characters are extremely strong, particularly the villains. Lance Henriksen is always good value, and here puts in a wonderfully hard-assed and droll portrayal of the 'Director' (for want of a better title). Legendary movie quote #33: "Now you know why we insist on payment up front." LOL His side-kick, 'Pik', is a superbly sadistic piece of work by Arnold Vosloo. He doesn't overplay it, yet leaves the viewer in no doubt as to his nature. He has a quiet and chilling business-like manner most of the time, but when time comes for an execution you see what a hobby it is for him, with the twinkle in his eye. The two lead females are sympathetic and credible characters, especially policewoman Kasi Lemmons. Unfortunately the same cannot be said for the 'lovable' but ridiculous Uncle Douvee. I guess he was injected into the final phase of the movie to lend a sprinkling of humour, but imo it did not need it. We already have the two main good characters to engage with, and the movie should have been allowed to stand on its gritty and punchy violence and the quite disturbing aspects of human nature. We really care if some of these characters live or die, even the psychos! In a downtown New Orleans scene, one of the 'hunted' is totally unable to get anybody to help him, which made me really angry. All too believable, and really lent credibility to how the company gets away with it. Uncle Douvee... jeez. If you can get past the image of this old fool playing the hero, then fair play to you (maybe I need to 'lighten up'). If you can get past the attempts at a French (or Belgian, whatever) accent by the very American bit-part actor Wilfred Brimley, then you were not getitng properly into the movie in the first place. Sorry to pick on him, but for me it really grated. It's all the more sad when you remember him in his straight-up role as a mafia henchman in 'The Firm': believable and exactly the tone called for here. Bit-part is what it was, though, and the strengths of the movie outweigh the weaknesses. I would have loved to see Harrison Ford or even Bruce Willis in the Van Damme role - with the every-guy credibility and minus the slow motion, please!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's like a drug isn't it, to bring a man down?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hard Target is directed by John Woo and written by Chuck Pfarrer. It stars Jean-Claude Van Damme, Lance Henriksen, Yancy Butler, Arnold Vosloo and Wilford Brimley. Music is by Graeme Revell and cinematography by Russell Carpenter. New Orleans and ex-merchant marine Chance Boudreaux (Damme) is struggling to gain employment on account of some muscular indiscretions. However, after saving Natasha Binder (Butler) from the hands of robbers, he is offered some work by her that pays handsomely. The task is to find out where her father is, a homeless ex-forces man who has mysteriously disappeared. It's a search that leads them to a sick urban safari being run by Emil Fouchon (Henriksen), the prey? Man! After pushing the boundaries of action cinema in Hong Kong, it was only a matter of time before John Woo got lured to America to dabble in the dollar. Hard Target was his first American movie, which in spite of the studio being nervous about his hiring (Sam Raimi was on standby should it implode) and cuts being made on demand for a certificate rating to open it up to a wider audience, it worked out well. It was a financial success, even though there was the inevitable mixed reviews from critics and today it rightly is held in high regard amongst action movie die- hards. OK! Nobody could seriously claim it's a titan of cinema, it's an absurd story derived from The Most Dangerous Game, the acting is of the usual Van Damme kick assery standard (JC pouts and mumbles, Butler is terrible, Brimley is miscast, Henriksen so over the top we almost lose him from our vision) and preposterousness reaches new levels. Yes it's a dumb fun action movie where leaving the brain at the door is a requisite. But what action delights await the faithful, what grace and style does Woo bring to the mayhem, it's a visceral thriller that once it gets the plot initiations out of the way, unleashes beautiful carnage that thunders the chest royally. Can violence be lyrical? In Woo's hands yes, certainly. The action film is one of the most maligned in cinema, but there is great artistry to many of them, to that end Hard Target scores incredibly high. The stunt work is amazing, the choreography of the fight scenes, with Van Damme showing his wonderful skills, are exquisite sights for the action film fan. Woo's tricks involving slow-mo, freeze frames and juddering close ups all get worked out here, quite often forming part of another ballet of bloodshed. Woo and Van Damme were a good fit, the film rocks for those so inclined for such kinetic malarkey, and not even The Muscles from Brussels' mullet can spoil the enjoyment. 7.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What made you want to complicate my life like this
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol1218
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **SPOILERS*** Even for a Jean-Claude Van Damme action movie "Hard Target" is just a bit too hard to take despite all its action scenes as well as Mr. Van Damme's kick boxing & martial art talents. At first the film starts off like the 1932 classic "The Most Dangerous Game" but quickly deteriorates into a mindless and disjointed free for all. With Van Damme as merchant marine Chance Boudreaux taking on an entire army of bikers in the Louisiana bayous lead by the villainous Emil Fouchon played by Lance Henriksen. Totally unbelievable fight & action scenes even for Van Damme to preform with or without a stunt double that has him have more lives in the movie then a dozen cats. There's also Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's love interest in the film Nat Binder, Nancy Butler, who despite being a damsel in distress seems to have trouble keeping a straight face in many of the action as well as love scenes she's in the movie. It was Nat's missing dad, Douglas Pfarrer,who was later found to be murdered that had Van Damme, who was hired by Net to find him, get involved in this holy mess in the first place. And who can forget Van Damme or Chance Boudreaux's moon shine drinking uncle Douvee played by William Brimley who about the best, after Lance Henriksen, actor in the film. Who no matter how much booze he drinks is still able to ride his horse without falling off as well as shoot arrows as accurately as Robin Hood. And as things turned out it was the booze, or the flask that he stored it in, that ended up saving his life! The final showdown in the film between Van Damme-Chance Boudreaux-and Emil Fouchon-Lance Henriksen-just went on and on to the point where all the fighting shooting and exploding lost their effect since for a time it didn't effect the two at all. And when it finally ended you couldn't care less who ended up winning but was happy as hell to know the movie, and all the suffering you went through in watching it, was thank God finally over!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good plot, entertaining, but nowhere near a Woo classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a far cry from Woo's masterpeices in Hong Kong. It was his first American movie and one must say that in a lot of ways it is a disappointment. I am not saying that it is a bad movie, but it seems that the creative genius that is John Woo is seriously hindered by the capital focus of the American market. Us Westerners like movies with happy endings and movies that do not challenge us to think. This movie is action but its action is not beautifully crafted within a movie with real characters struggling in a real world. Hard Target is set in New Orleans during a police strike, though this does not seem evident. A group has set itself up where they hire vagrants to run 10 kilometers with $10 000 while they are being chased by hunters. These vagrants are not supposed to have any ties, but unfortunately they chose somebody who does. When his daughter comes to New Orleans to find him dead, she starts asking questions, and brings Van Damme in to help her. The plot is good, but the thing with Woo's movies from Hong Kong is that it is about the characters struggling with themselves and the bad guys were simply around to make their life even harder. No such struggle occurs within this movie. Van Damme, who is simply a sailor that happens to be good at martial arts, is not able to play a character with any depth. Personally I do not think much of his acting ability, and people really only watch his movies to see his moves - and they are not even martial arts. The only reason Van Damme can do these moves is because he is a dancer. The movie plasters John Woo as being the director and attempts to attract people to the movie on this fact. The action is good, and the imagery used is typical of John Woo. He is a brilliant director, but is even better when he is not restrained. I feel that this film is let down in the fact that there is no character struggle in this movie. The characters are not anti-heroes, which is one of the aspects that elevates Woo movies above the others. It is not until Face Off that John Woo's American movies began to stand out. There are two things that seem to form a part of Woo movies. The main characters either begin as friends but slowly drift apart until they are fighting each other at the end, or they are apart and through the struggles that they face, they are drawn together and realise that they need to help each other. Face Off is a completely different idea where the good guy suddenly finds that he is the bad guy and cannot do anything about it. A Bullet in the Head, Too Catch a Thief, and Broken Arrow are examples of the first type, while The Killer and Hard Boiled are examples of the second type. Hard Target doesn't fall into either category. The characters do not entertain me as their struggles are purely action orientated and as such it doesn't grab me as Woo's other movies do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Competent action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DaRick89
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As with many action movies, Hard to Kill's strengths and weaknesses are fairly simple to analyse. It's a competent action thriller, notable for some stylish action scenes that have John Woo's touch; one particularly memorable example is when Chance Boudreaux (Jean-Claude Van Damme) quite literally blasts a bikie thug out a window with a shotgun and a petrol can! These moments pretty much make the film worth seeing by themselves, despite the usual weaknesses in the plotting and JCVD's ever wooden countenance. As JCVD himself noted however, viewers paid the money to see him waste bad guys and he does plenty of this - sometimes in more inventive ways than expected (using snake traps). It very much makes the film worth seeing for action buffs, even though I'm reluctant to give a really high rating based on this alone. The plot is not too extraordinary: a homeless veteran gets murdered by a team of mercenaries led by Emil Fouchoud (Henriksen) and Van Cleaf (Vosloo), after which his daughter Nat (Butler) comes looking for him and commissions Boudreaux, a homeless Cajun merchant marine (!) to help her out after he rescues her from marauding thugs, raising the ire of the mercenary team. A few plot holes are obvious (shouldn't this mercenary team have been dealt with a while ago, police strike or not? Why is JCVD made a CAJUN?), but it works well as a vehicle for blowing stuff up and killing people. The dialogue is pretty standard stuff: some profanity, some hilariously cringeworthy lines ("don't worry about Randall; he's all ears!) and some macho stuff. As for the acting, the villains are better than the heroes. Of course, when JCVD is your hero, that's bound to be the case, with his unconvincing delivery. He has recently shown that he is capable of acting, but he was a long off that in 1993. Still, English is probably his third language (after French and Dutch); Yancy Butler has no such excuses, being quite wooden in a role that doesn't demand that much. Vosloo and Henriksen are much better though. Vosloo has that quiet menace that always makes him a good villain, while Henriksen goes from menacing and purposeful to merrily nuts as Boudreaux causes him more difficulties than expected. Even Wilford Brimley is amusing as Chance's crazy uncle, reeling off some zany lines. In the end, Hard Target is not a great movie, but it's a competent action thriller with some nice stylistic touches from John Woo during the action scenes. Henriksen, Vosloo and Brimley compensate somewhat for JCVD and Butler, but you still shouldn't watch this film for the acting and especially not for the plotting. Action fans generally don't really look for either that much though, so that's alright. Movie-goers looking for a bit more will probably like some of the style, but won't find that much else. 3/5 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Lance Henriksen show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies starring Jean-Claude Van Damme can't be labeled as anything else than "so bad it's good" material. This one makes no exception. Lance Henriksen however, transcends the genre with a grandiose over-the-top performance that's great fun to watch. As to Van Damme, this actor is not merely campy. His lack of charisma, not to mention linguistic competence, is simply astonishing. Butler is a perfect match  she's fake as a Latino soap-opera, although her English is better than Van Damme's. The film's plot is ridiculous and it gets over- violent to the point of being unpleasant, but it's all worth watching for Lance Henriksen's gleefully villainous show-off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    HK Neo Reviews: Hard Target
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (webmaster@thehkneo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Director John Woo's first venture into Hollywood was not without its obstacles. With Van Damme being one of Hollywood's bright action stars back in the early 90s, it is pretty much certain that Woo lacked what he received in his later works  control. The film for most of it, seems uneven, especially when there are scenes you can clearly see as Woo's footprints all over it and there are others that are just plain awful. Still, if you ignore the bad acting from Van Damme, poor pacing, poor editing, there is still fun to be had. Namely the majority of the shooting sequences, a wonderful villainous turn by future "The Mummy" star  Lance Henriksen and a few pigeons to boost, Hard Target is really not that bad Neo rates it 6/10. - www.thehkneo.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best Van Damme movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chris1987
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First saw this movie when i was buying a video of Maximum Risk,which is a decent Van Damme film.So i watched this film and was not disappointed,i was entertained throughout the whole movie.The action was practically non-stop.The storyline is decent enough with ruthless business men hunting homeless war veterans,and the street-wise Chance Boudreaux was going to find out sooner or later,to bad for the bad guys.The action scenes are spot on.When Van Damme first appears,you just know the s**t is going down.In roughly the first half hour of the film sees a fight at a caf&eacute; in which Van Damme breaks a guys arm it is brutal.As the film rolls on,we discover Chance's background and how he himself has experienced the streets.Lance Henrickson is great as the Emil Fouchon chief bad guy,you just love to hate.And Arnold Vosloo as his sidekick Pick Van Cleef was great and funny at times.You just know when he utters the words "Randall,Randall,Randall" that Randall was in for a very bad day.Wilford Brimley as the enjoyable and funny uncle Douvee.The tag-line for this movie is "Don't Hunt What You Cant Kill" and the bad guys should have realised this.This is a decent and enjoyable Van Damme film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High-quality Van Damme at his absolute best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Comeuppance Reviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance Boudreaux (Van Damme) is a New Orleans longshoreman who is down on his luck and struggling to find work. Opportunity comes his way when Nat (Butler) hires him to help her find her missing father. As it turns out, her father isn't missing, necessarily, he was a victim of a malevolent gang of "human hunters". Led by Fouchon (Henriksen), and with his second in command Pik Van Cleef (Vosloo), they get their kicks (and get rich) letting weekend warriors pay them to go on the ultimate hunting expedition: for man! But they meet their match with the fearless Chance, a man they cannot kill. Along for the ride is Chance's uncle Douvee (Brimley). Will Chance get his chance at glory? Or, to the human hunters, is he just another HARD TARGET? Hard Target is hands-down one of Van Damme's best. It's explosively entertaining and lives up to the promise of a Van Damme and John Woo team-up. It's everything a combination of those two men could be and should be, and doesn't let the audience down. Once again, this is classic 90's action fun from the golden time when Van Damme movies went to the theater. Back then, we remember joking with our friends that because there's so much slow motion in this movie, if it was all played at regular speed, the film would be about 20 minutes. And it's true, there is a lot of dramatic slo-mo, but it's all for the best. And Van Damme and others get a lot of unnecessarily portentous entrances and exits, which just adds to the style of Hard Target, which is just a tad bit off-kilter. But that's far from a bad thing. It separates itself from its many competitors that way. Besides Van Damme and his absurd hair, the cast assembled for this is just killer: Lance Henriksen is great as the baddie who's so bad, even his piano-playing is evil. Vosloo is also adept at being bad, and his quasi-Scottish (?) accent, well, accentuates his sinister glares. Yancy Butler gives a bug-eyed performance who always seems surprised at the proceedings. But top marks must go to the great Wilford Brimley. In a strange role for him, the barely-intelligible, bow-and-arrow toting, horseback riding uncle is truly lovable and you root for him, even though he doesn't appear until late in the film. That's a tribute to Brimley that the audience can grow to love him so quickly. This movie puts a twist on the time-honored Most Dangerous Game (1932) idea. The formula's been tried before, with varying degrees of success, in everything from Death Ring (1992) to Avenging Force (1986). But Hard Target has plenty of awesome moments, including the extended climax in (what else) an abandoned warehouse. Never one to be afraid of wasting bullets, Woo pulls out all the stops in an extended feast of overkill. It's over-the-top fun everyone should see. On a technical note, the British DVD is longer than the American cut, including more violence. So try to track that down if you can, for the complete picture. Go down to the bayou tonight for some high-octane, high-quality Van Damme at his absolute best. For more insanity, please visit: comeuppancereviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
