<filme>
 <id>
  813
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112651
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  The Celluloid Closet
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A documentary surveying the various Hollywood screen depictions of homosexuals and the attitudes behind them throughout the history of North American film.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A comprehensive documentary of the history of gays and lesbians in cinema, from negative to positive reflections of gay characters and the troubles of actors and actresses.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Documentary
  </genero>
  <genero>
   History
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   gay
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   lesbian
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   social studies
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hayes office
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   homophobia
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Rob Epstein
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   Jeffrey Friedman
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Vito Russo
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Rob Epstein
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Lily Tomlin
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Tony Curtis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Susie Bright
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Celluloid Closet Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jbolante93
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is well-put-together documentary style film that does an excellent job in revealing how homosexuals were portrayed in Hollywood. The narration, along with movie clips, served as both informative and entertaining; with a perfect balance. It was informative enough to be taken seriously, yet at the same time, entertaining enough that the documentary was interesting, if not fascinating. In terms of organization, the film is very orderly and sequential. It starts with the early 1900s and proceeds to move forward till the late 1900s. I must also compliment the way the movie effectively compares and contrasts portrayals of homosexuals in different time periods, allowing for a smooth and easy to follow transition. What I loved most about the film is that it also features the varying opinions of different actors (such as Tom Hanks, Whoopie Goldberg, Tony Curtis, and others). This gives a wider variety of insight than just your own thought on watching the small movie clips. Although I do recommend the film, I did hope to see more on how the movies mentioned in the film became accepted. Another complaint is that the film lacked information on the directors or actors that should be given credit for exposing queer films into the public (especially during the early-mid 1900s when homosexuality wasn't socially acceptable). Overall, this is a great documentary for any gender or sex, whether you're homosexual or heterosexual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This documentary is enjoyable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hcandelario
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet", released in 1995, gives a keen insight into the history of homosexuals depicted in the art of film. This documentary has a great set up of commentators. They are all qualified to be speaking on the subject matter. Names and job descriptions are all given in the documentary. A younger audience can even recognize commentators such as Whoopi Goldberg and Tom Hanks. There is a sneak peek into the political influence on film production. The classic movie "Ben-Hur" released in 1959 and directed by William Wyler, is just one of the examples given for film with underlying homosexual influences. This justifies the use of "Closet" in the title. In many of the films used in the documentary the sexuality of the characters is not directly addressed, but none the less evident after watching "The Celluloid Closet". The documentary follows the changing social views of sexuality and what is acceptable chronologically, all the way from black and white films to colored films. Watching this documentary is sure to enlighten the viewer, and would be helpful to all who would like to have a better understanding of homosexuality in relation to films and film production. While being very informative the documentary is also enjoyable and engaging.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The great controversy on sexuality in Hollywood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    E Chan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" is a documentary that focuses on the evolution of sexuality in a multitude of Hollywood films and movies from the early 1900's to the early 1990's. The directors, Rob Epstein and Jeffrey Friedman portrays the views of homosexuality through a series of clips from numerous films and interviews of early actors, directors, and screenwriters. Throughout this documentary, the interviewees reveal how society reacted from the beginning of the queer films and up until modern times. This documentary is heavily based on book, "The Celluloid Closet" written by Vitto Russo. There are no main characters throughout this film, but rather focuses on the comments of each of the interviewees on the incredible growth of LGBTQ films and its effect on society. Many simply think of watching movies for entertainment purposes. However, movies have a greater influence on everyone's life than one may think, whether he or she is straight, gay or lesbian. Actors and screenwriters described the impact of movies during their early childhood and how people mainly went to see movies to see if the movies could relate to themselves. In early American society, homosexuality was viewed as humorous. The documentary then continues to describe the slander on queer films by the Catholic Church and its role in the portraying of LGBTQ content, thus leading to complications and censorship. Homosexuality was then viewed in the roles of numerous cold- blooded villains such as Dracula's Daughter and was shown in desperate gay characters that were unhappy and suicidal. Moreover, homophobia was seen as a disease in the 1950's and many people resented homosexuals. Finally, Hollywood presented homosexuality in a positive manner, shedding a new light in American culture. Overall, "The Celluloid Closet" is an interesting documentary portraying the incredible evolution of queer films in Hollywood. Even though the content is portrayed in movies and films, its effect on society was greater than one may have thought. It is informative, interesting, and funny. It is incredible on how society during the early 1900's portrays queer films being risky, impossible, and forbidden yet exciting and daring. Therefore, this documentary is highly recommended to movies fans who are interested in the making of queer films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Provides wonderful insight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guigy93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a wonderful documentary that gives an overview of homosexuality in films throughout the decades. This film manages to be both a joy to watch, while giving rare insights into classic films through actors and screenwriters such as Tony Curtis, Gore Vidal, Jay Presson Allen, and Whoopi Goldberg. Celluloid Closet manages to give a frank view of how homosexuals were portrayed without condemning or belittling any group of people. There was startling revelations of how far homosexuality had to come; from being portrayed as "sissies", villains, completely ignored, something to be ashamed of, or something to be condemned. The discussion of how homosexuals were made into villains was particularly shocking and upsetting. In addition, the Hays Codes surprises a modern film goer with the strict regulations. The documentary brings to light how movie producers managed to get the point across while being subtle enough to avoid being cut. Perhaps most importantly, the Celluloid Closet captures how gay people felt ostracized and ashamed while watching films growing up. Overall, this film was a joy to watch, funny, at times heartbreaking, and a must see for anyone interested in queer cinema, one could only wish for a continuation into today's films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Evolution of Queer Cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lauren McGinnis (pointeshoes721@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" is an excellent documentary outlining the journey that queer films have taken over the last few decades. Directors Rob Epstein and Jeffery Friedman do a nearly perfect job at explaining the stereotypes, humiliations, and "hidings" that queer cinematographic love has had to face, fear and admit. "Celluloid Closet" is a film that bases itself off of some of the most famous motion pictures that the world has seen. Some of them, however, do remain as an underdog to some of the major movie successes. For those of us that are unfamiliar with queer films, "Celluloid Closet" is a spectacular orientation into that genre of movies; taking us as early as the silent films in 1895 (Thomas Edison's Experimental Movie with two male dancers) up to some of cinemas recent releases (Brokeback Mountain, 2005). Although there are no main characters, we are presented with some familiar actors, actresses, and directors such as Whoopi Goldberg, Tom Hanks, Tony Curtis and many others. This documentary presents its audience with films that some viewers wouldn't qualify as "queer" simply because they enjoy watching it. This documentary presents some of the "questionable" films upside down so the messages are clear to us but were able to remain uncensored by the Production (Hay's) Codes that had restricted certain theatrical content. "Celluloid Closet" is empathetic, understanding and entertaining. It is elegantly put together, neatly organized, personally touching and very well informative.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overview of Queer Film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    n_col13
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a documentary that offers a comprehensive overview of portrayal of LGBTQ characters in Hollywood, from the time of first motion pictures up to the early 1990s. The documentary explores the various stereotypes that persisted in Hollywood when portraying queer characters and how they gradually gave way to a more realistic portrayal. The Celluloid Closet manages to include a substantial amount of footage from various films, and points out the subtext, for example, in films like Ben-Hur. It was especially interesting to see how, even when censorship was in effect, some film-makers still managed to include subtle hints, encouraging the viewer to see between the lines. The interviews with writers, actors and film-makers help to connect the documentary to the real world and to understand what real people who are closely connected to the industry think about the way the representation of queer characters on screen evolved with time. The Celluloid Closet is a fascinating look at the history of queer film, and it can be a great starting point for someone who is unfamiliar with the subject, as this documentary is both highly entertaining and very informative, with the amount of information not being too overwhelming.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the tremendous progression of queer film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpathak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" was an overall great documentary on how homosexuality has evolved in film over decades of movies. In the early 1930s the film explained how movies portray homosexuality to be humorous. The actors that played the gay role were called "Sissies" subliminally portraying to the audience that they are homosexuals. As the movie progressed it had displayed other aspects on how the community now pictured homosexuals. The "Hayes Code" was created to rate movies on how appropriate they were. The Catholic Church as well joined in the process of rating by evaluating certain films to see if the movie was "appropriate" by their religious standards. Films later depicted homosexuals as villains such as Dracula's sister forcing the main actress to undress in front of her. In Albert Hitchcock the two villain murderers were homosexuals as well. At a certain point in these movies they had many gay subliminal symbols that the censors did not understand. During the 40s queer film was progressing to different degree. "The Celluloid Closet" explained that seeming gay was almost as bad as being gay. There would be films that would criticize a character for walking a certain way or even saying certain words. The screenwriter of Rebel without a cause stated that he would make the main character to be displayed as a gay outcast if it were during the millennium time period. In the 50's and 60's many characters of films were obviously gay. The first film to admit the homosexual intention was "The Victim" in 1961. Although there was a steadily progress of queer film, homosexuality was then presented as a crime. In the queer films the gay character would end up dying whether it be by a hero slaying the homosexual, or they became depressed and committed suicide. Queer film over the last four decades has evolved from a mental illness to being presented a sign of affection and love. Now in the 20th century queer film is accepted in the theaters almost everywhere in the nation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Introduction to Hollywood's Development of Queer Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pmata
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a documentary that focuses on Hollywood's evolution of queer film from the 1920's until the mid-1990's. The documentary's use of clips from complements clips from interviews of screenwriters and actors to show the chronology of not only queers and queer film, but also of censorship in Hollywood. The film also emphasizes how society's view of homosexuals shaped queer film. The film discusses how not only Hollywood's views of homosexuality have developed and shaped throughout the decades, but also all of America's (i.e. how all gay men were effeminate, and all lesbians were masculine). Screenwriters and actors further discuss how the Catholic Church became very involved in cinema and influenced the institution of the Hays Codes for censorship. The film emphasizes how screenwriters were able to avoid this censorship through connotations and subtleties; however, they still had to please the Church by portraying homosexuals as victims or villains to show that there was no happy ending for them. However, by the late 70's onward, depictions of homosexuality on screen became more positive as the Gay Rights Movement started in the United States, creating new norms and shaping more positive views of homosexuality in individuals. The Celluloid Closet gives an excellent history and analysis of queer film and how influential Hollywood can be. It was interesting to see how many old Hollywood films were considered part of queer cinemasuch as Rebel Without a Cause, The Maltese Falcon, and Rebecca. It was truly enlightening, and it expanded my scope of queer film. The Celluloid Closet is highly recommended to watch, for it sheds a new light for watching films, old and new, and for how to pick up different themes and subtleties to bring a deeper appreciation for "just watching a movie."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The History of Hollywood's Perception of Homosexuals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natwon93
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet was a film that documented the use of homosexual characters in the world of Hollywood. Clips from films with LGBTQ characters, actors and writers of those movies, and current actors and actresses were all used to help display the history of the progression of homosexual characters in movies. The documentary was shown in chronological order, from the 1930s to the early 1990s, emphasizing the stereotypical and sometimes unfair to normal ways in which homosexuals were portrayed. The commentary from the actors, actresses, and actors provided an entertainment and informative factor that kept the audience attentive to the subject of the documentary. It was interesting to see how in the films, LGBTQ had transitioned from light hearted humorous characters, to stereotypical sissies, to villainous individuals suffering from some sort of mental illness. Hollywood has such an effect to the everyday life that many individuals in Presbyterian Church called for a reform on the homosexual exposure in films. The Hays Codes being enforced and the amount of censorship that had to be enforced in movies made directing a film with a homosexual character in it much more difficult. The coded language and subtle movements by the actors portraying the LGBTQ characters made it clear to audiences that there was homosexual exposure in the film, just not so obvious. This film is highly recommended for it brings new knowledge of the film world to light, in regards to the issue of homosexuality. It also depicts a clear representation of how the values of different eras change drastically throughout time. Because the documentary was made in the early 1990s, it would be interesting to see how the commentators view LGBTQ characters in film today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An analysis of the perception of homosexuality in films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tsan4
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet gave an in-depth analysis of the compilation of gay films that also provided a broader identification of how the role of homosexuality has progressed. The initial depiction of homosexuality in film best described the future struggle of gays in both society and media. Beginning with the use of homosexual content as a way of humor, the atmosphere was set for the harsh reality of the portrayal of homosexuals in film. The documentary best portrays the ups and downs of how societal view on homosexuality was clearly influenced by film. The documentary highlighted specific clips from films that gave both an educational and entertainment value toward each claim made. The documentary gave clear themes, ideas and thought provoking questions that best described and in some ways shaped the idea of being or appearing homosexual. While the ideas present a clear and logical time line, the content emphasizes the ever-changing identity and perception of homosexuals by their appearance as feminine, villainous, unhappy or even suicidal. Additionally, the analysis of censored gay films also gave an interesting look on how the need to relate to media influences the way people view a movie. Above all, a great effort and successful effort was made in understanding the progression and highlight of homosexual roles in film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Celluloid Closet Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jbolante93
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is well-put-together documentary style film that does an excellent job in revealing how homosexuals were portrayed in Hollywood. The narration, along with movie clips, served as both informative and entertaining; with a perfect balance. It was informative enough to be taken seriously, yet at the same time, entertaining enough that the documentary was interesting, if not fascinating. In terms of organization, the film is very orderly and sequential. It starts with the early 1900s and proceeds to move forward till the late 1900s. I must also compliment the way the movie effectively compares and contrasts portrayals of homosexuals in different time periods, allowing for a smooth and easy to follow transition. What I loved most about the film is that it also features the varying opinions of different actors (such as Tom Hanks, Whoopie Goldberg, Tony Curtis, and others). This gives a wider variety of insight than just your own thought on watching the small movie clips. Although I do recommend the film, I did hope to see more on how the movies mentioned in the film became accepted. Another complaint is that the film lacked information on the directors or actors that should be given credit for exposing queer films into the public (especially during the early-mid 1900s when homosexuality wasn't socially acceptable). Overall, this is a great documentary for any gender or sex, whether you're homosexual or heterosexual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This documentary is enjoyable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hcandelario
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet", released in 1995, gives a keen insight into the history of homosexuals depicted in the art of film. This documentary has a great set up of commentators. They are all qualified to be speaking on the subject matter. Names and job descriptions are all given in the documentary. A younger audience can even recognize commentators such as Whoopi Goldberg and Tom Hanks. There is a sneak peek into the political influence on film production. The classic movie "Ben-Hur" released in 1959 and directed by William Wyler, is just one of the examples given for film with underlying homosexual influences. This justifies the use of "Closet" in the title. In many of the films used in the documentary the sexuality of the characters is not directly addressed, but none the less evident after watching "The Celluloid Closet". The documentary follows the changing social views of sexuality and what is acceptable chronologically, all the way from black and white films to colored films. Watching this documentary is sure to enlighten the viewer, and would be helpful to all who would like to have a better understanding of homosexuality in relation to films and film production. While being very informative the documentary is also enjoyable and engaging.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The great controversy on sexuality in Hollywood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    E Chan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" is a documentary that focuses on the evolution of sexuality in a multitude of Hollywood films and movies from the early 1900's to the early 1990's. The directors, Rob Epstein and Jeffrey Friedman portrays the views of homosexuality through a series of clips from numerous films and interviews of early actors, directors, and screenwriters. Throughout this documentary, the interviewees reveal how society reacted from the beginning of the queer films and up until modern times. This documentary is heavily based on book, "The Celluloid Closet" written by Vitto Russo. There are no main characters throughout this film, but rather focuses on the comments of each of the interviewees on the incredible growth of LGBTQ films and its effect on society. Many simply think of watching movies for entertainment purposes. However, movies have a greater influence on everyone's life than one may think, whether he or she is straight, gay or lesbian. Actors and screenwriters described the impact of movies during their early childhood and how people mainly went to see movies to see if the movies could relate to themselves. In early American society, homosexuality was viewed as humorous. The documentary then continues to describe the slander on queer films by the Catholic Church and its role in the portraying of LGBTQ content, thus leading to complications and censorship. Homosexuality was then viewed in the roles of numerous cold- blooded villains such as Dracula's Daughter and was shown in desperate gay characters that were unhappy and suicidal. Moreover, homophobia was seen as a disease in the 1950's and many people resented homosexuals. Finally, Hollywood presented homosexuality in a positive manner, shedding a new light in American culture. Overall, "The Celluloid Closet" is an interesting documentary portraying the incredible evolution of queer films in Hollywood. Even though the content is portrayed in movies and films, its effect on society was greater than one may have thought. It is informative, interesting, and funny. It is incredible on how society during the early 1900's portrays queer films being risky, impossible, and forbidden yet exciting and daring. Therefore, this documentary is highly recommended to movies fans who are interested in the making of queer films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Provides wonderful insight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guigy93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a wonderful documentary that gives an overview of homosexuality in films throughout the decades. This film manages to be both a joy to watch, while giving rare insights into classic films through actors and screenwriters such as Tony Curtis, Gore Vidal, Jay Presson Allen, and Whoopi Goldberg. Celluloid Closet manages to give a frank view of how homosexuals were portrayed without condemning or belittling any group of people. There was startling revelations of how far homosexuality had to come; from being portrayed as "sissies", villains, completely ignored, something to be ashamed of, or something to be condemned. The discussion of how homosexuals were made into villains was particularly shocking and upsetting. In addition, the Hays Codes surprises a modern film goer with the strict regulations. The documentary brings to light how movie producers managed to get the point across while being subtle enough to avoid being cut. Perhaps most importantly, the Celluloid Closet captures how gay people felt ostracized and ashamed while watching films growing up. Overall, this film was a joy to watch, funny, at times heartbreaking, and a must see for anyone interested in queer cinema, one could only wish for a continuation into today's films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Evolution of Queer Cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lauren McGinnis (pointeshoes721@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" is an excellent documentary outlining the journey that queer films have taken over the last few decades. Directors Rob Epstein and Jeffery Friedman do a nearly perfect job at explaining the stereotypes, humiliations, and "hidings" that queer cinematographic love has had to face, fear and admit. "Celluloid Closet" is a film that bases itself off of some of the most famous motion pictures that the world has seen. Some of them, however, do remain as an underdog to some of the major movie successes. For those of us that are unfamiliar with queer films, "Celluloid Closet" is a spectacular orientation into that genre of movies; taking us as early as the silent films in 1895 (Thomas Edison's Experimental Movie with two male dancers) up to some of cinemas recent releases (Brokeback Mountain, 2005). Although there are no main characters, we are presented with some familiar actors, actresses, and directors such as Whoopi Goldberg, Tom Hanks, Tony Curtis and many others. This documentary presents its audience with films that some viewers wouldn't qualify as "queer" simply because they enjoy watching it. This documentary presents some of the "questionable" films upside down so the messages are clear to us but were able to remain uncensored by the Production (Hay's) Codes that had restricted certain theatrical content. "Celluloid Closet" is empathetic, understanding and entertaining. It is elegantly put together, neatly organized, personally touching and very well informative.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overview of Queer Film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    n_col13
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a documentary that offers a comprehensive overview of portrayal of LGBTQ characters in Hollywood, from the time of first motion pictures up to the early 1990s. The documentary explores the various stereotypes that persisted in Hollywood when portraying queer characters and how they gradually gave way to a more realistic portrayal. The Celluloid Closet manages to include a substantial amount of footage from various films, and points out the subtext, for example, in films like Ben-Hur. It was especially interesting to see how, even when censorship was in effect, some film-makers still managed to include subtle hints, encouraging the viewer to see between the lines. The interviews with writers, actors and film-makers help to connect the documentary to the real world and to understand what real people who are closely connected to the industry think about the way the representation of queer characters on screen evolved with time. The Celluloid Closet is a fascinating look at the history of queer film, and it can be a great starting point for someone who is unfamiliar with the subject, as this documentary is both highly entertaining and very informative, with the amount of information not being too overwhelming.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the tremendous progression of queer film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpathak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" was an overall great documentary on how homosexuality has evolved in film over decades of movies. In the early 1930s the film explained how movies portray homosexuality to be humorous. The actors that played the gay role were called "Sissies" subliminally portraying to the audience that they are homosexuals. As the movie progressed it had displayed other aspects on how the community now pictured homosexuals. The "Hayes Code" was created to rate movies on how appropriate they were. The Catholic Church as well joined in the process of rating by evaluating certain films to see if the movie was "appropriate" by their religious standards. Films later depicted homosexuals as villains such as Dracula's sister forcing the main actress to undress in front of her. In Albert Hitchcock the two villain murderers were homosexuals as well. At a certain point in these movies they had many gay subliminal symbols that the censors did not understand. During the 40s queer film was progressing to different degree. "The Celluloid Closet" explained that seeming gay was almost as bad as being gay. There would be films that would criticize a character for walking a certain way or even saying certain words. The screenwriter of Rebel without a cause stated that he would make the main character to be displayed as a gay outcast if it were during the millennium time period. In the 50's and 60's many characters of films were obviously gay. The first film to admit the homosexual intention was "The Victim" in 1961. Although there was a steadily progress of queer film, homosexuality was then presented as a crime. In the queer films the gay character would end up dying whether it be by a hero slaying the homosexual, or they became depressed and committed suicide. Queer film over the last four decades has evolved from a mental illness to being presented a sign of affection and love. Now in the 20th century queer film is accepted in the theaters almost everywhere in the nation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Introduction to Hollywood's Development of Queer Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pmata
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a documentary that focuses on Hollywood's evolution of queer film from the 1920's until the mid-1990's. The documentary's use of clips from complements clips from interviews of screenwriters and actors to show the chronology of not only queers and queer film, but also of censorship in Hollywood. The film also emphasizes how society's view of homosexuals shaped queer film. The film discusses how not only Hollywood's views of homosexuality have developed and shaped throughout the decades, but also all of America's (i.e. how all gay men were effeminate, and all lesbians were masculine). Screenwriters and actors further discuss how the Catholic Church became very involved in cinema and influenced the institution of the Hays Codes for censorship. The film emphasizes how screenwriters were able to avoid this censorship through connotations and subtleties; however, they still had to please the Church by portraying homosexuals as victims or villains to show that there was no happy ending for them. However, by the late 70's onward, depictions of homosexuality on screen became more positive as the Gay Rights Movement started in the United States, creating new norms and shaping more positive views of homosexuality in individuals. The Celluloid Closet gives an excellent history and analysis of queer film and how influential Hollywood can be. It was interesting to see how many old Hollywood films were considered part of queer cinemasuch as Rebel Without a Cause, The Maltese Falcon, and Rebecca. It was truly enlightening, and it expanded my scope of queer film. The Celluloid Closet is highly recommended to watch, for it sheds a new light for watching films, old and new, and for how to pick up different themes and subtleties to bring a deeper appreciation for "just watching a movie."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The History of Hollywood's Perception of Homosexuals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natwon93
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet was a film that documented the use of homosexual characters in the world of Hollywood. Clips from films with LGBTQ characters, actors and writers of those movies, and current actors and actresses were all used to help display the history of the progression of homosexual characters in movies. The documentary was shown in chronological order, from the 1930s to the early 1990s, emphasizing the stereotypical and sometimes unfair to normal ways in which homosexuals were portrayed. The commentary from the actors, actresses, and actors provided an entertainment and informative factor that kept the audience attentive to the subject of the documentary. It was interesting to see how in the films, LGBTQ had transitioned from light hearted humorous characters, to stereotypical sissies, to villainous individuals suffering from some sort of mental illness. Hollywood has such an effect to the everyday life that many individuals in Presbyterian Church called for a reform on the homosexual exposure in films. The Hays Codes being enforced and the amount of censorship that had to be enforced in movies made directing a film with a homosexual character in it much more difficult. The coded language and subtle movements by the actors portraying the LGBTQ characters made it clear to audiences that there was homosexual exposure in the film, just not so obvious. This film is highly recommended for it brings new knowledge of the film world to light, in regards to the issue of homosexuality. It also depicts a clear representation of how the values of different eras change drastically throughout time. Because the documentary was made in the early 1990s, it would be interesting to see how the commentators view LGBTQ characters in film today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An analysis of the perception of homosexuality in films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tsan4
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet gave an in-depth analysis of the compilation of gay films that also provided a broader identification of how the role of homosexuality has progressed. The initial depiction of homosexuality in film best described the future struggle of gays in both society and media. Beginning with the use of homosexual content as a way of humor, the atmosphere was set for the harsh reality of the portrayal of homosexuals in film. The documentary best portrays the ups and downs of how societal view on homosexuality was clearly influenced by film. The documentary highlighted specific clips from films that gave both an educational and entertainment value toward each claim made. The documentary gave clear themes, ideas and thought provoking questions that best described and in some ways shaped the idea of being or appearing homosexual. While the ideas present a clear and logical time line, the content emphasizes the ever-changing identity and perception of homosexuals by their appearance as feminine, villainous, unhappy or even suicidal. Additionally, the analysis of censored gay films also gave an interesting look on how the need to relate to media influences the way people view a movie. Above all, a great effort and successful effort was made in understanding the progression and highlight of homosexual roles in film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Celluloid Closet Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jbolante93
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is well-put-together documentary style film that does an excellent job in revealing how homosexuals were portrayed in Hollywood. The narration, along with movie clips, served as both informative and entertaining; with a perfect balance. It was informative enough to be taken seriously, yet at the same time, entertaining enough that the documentary was interesting, if not fascinating. In terms of organization, the film is very orderly and sequential. It starts with the early 1900s and proceeds to move forward till the late 1900s. I must also compliment the way the movie effectively compares and contrasts portrayals of homosexuals in different time periods, allowing for a smooth and easy to follow transition. What I loved most about the film is that it also features the varying opinions of different actors (such as Tom Hanks, Whoopie Goldberg, Tony Curtis, and others). This gives a wider variety of insight than just your own thought on watching the small movie clips. Although I do recommend the film, I did hope to see more on how the movies mentioned in the film became accepted. Another complaint is that the film lacked information on the directors or actors that should be given credit for exposing queer films into the public (especially during the early-mid 1900s when homosexuality wasn't socially acceptable). Overall, this is a great documentary for any gender or sex, whether you're homosexual or heterosexual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This documentary is enjoyable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hcandelario
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet", released in 1995, gives a keen insight into the history of homosexuals depicted in the art of film. This documentary has a great set up of commentators. They are all qualified to be speaking on the subject matter. Names and job descriptions are all given in the documentary. A younger audience can even recognize commentators such as Whoopi Goldberg and Tom Hanks. There is a sneak peek into the political influence on film production. The classic movie "Ben-Hur" released in 1959 and directed by William Wyler, is just one of the examples given for film with underlying homosexual influences. This justifies the use of "Closet" in the title. In many of the films used in the documentary the sexuality of the characters is not directly addressed, but none the less evident after watching "The Celluloid Closet". The documentary follows the changing social views of sexuality and what is acceptable chronologically, all the way from black and white films to colored films. Watching this documentary is sure to enlighten the viewer, and would be helpful to all who would like to have a better understanding of homosexuality in relation to films and film production. While being very informative the documentary is also enjoyable and engaging.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The great controversy on sexuality in Hollywood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    E Chan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" is a documentary that focuses on the evolution of sexuality in a multitude of Hollywood films and movies from the early 1900's to the early 1990's. The directors, Rob Epstein and Jeffrey Friedman portrays the views of homosexuality through a series of clips from numerous films and interviews of early actors, directors, and screenwriters. Throughout this documentary, the interviewees reveal how society reacted from the beginning of the queer films and up until modern times. This documentary is heavily based on book, "The Celluloid Closet" written by Vitto Russo. There are no main characters throughout this film, but rather focuses on the comments of each of the interviewees on the incredible growth of LGBTQ films and its effect on society. Many simply think of watching movies for entertainment purposes. However, movies have a greater influence on everyone's life than one may think, whether he or she is straight, gay or lesbian. Actors and screenwriters described the impact of movies during their early childhood and how people mainly went to see movies to see if the movies could relate to themselves. In early American society, homosexuality was viewed as humorous. The documentary then continues to describe the slander on queer films by the Catholic Church and its role in the portraying of LGBTQ content, thus leading to complications and censorship. Homosexuality was then viewed in the roles of numerous cold- blooded villains such as Dracula's Daughter and was shown in desperate gay characters that were unhappy and suicidal. Moreover, homophobia was seen as a disease in the 1950's and many people resented homosexuals. Finally, Hollywood presented homosexuality in a positive manner, shedding a new light in American culture. Overall, "The Celluloid Closet" is an interesting documentary portraying the incredible evolution of queer films in Hollywood. Even though the content is portrayed in movies and films, its effect on society was greater than one may have thought. It is informative, interesting, and funny. It is incredible on how society during the early 1900's portrays queer films being risky, impossible, and forbidden yet exciting and daring. Therefore, this documentary is highly recommended to movies fans who are interested in the making of queer films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Provides wonderful insight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guigy93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a wonderful documentary that gives an overview of homosexuality in films throughout the decades. This film manages to be both a joy to watch, while giving rare insights into classic films through actors and screenwriters such as Tony Curtis, Gore Vidal, Jay Presson Allen, and Whoopi Goldberg. Celluloid Closet manages to give a frank view of how homosexuals were portrayed without condemning or belittling any group of people. There was startling revelations of how far homosexuality had to come; from being portrayed as "sissies", villains, completely ignored, something to be ashamed of, or something to be condemned. The discussion of how homosexuals were made into villains was particularly shocking and upsetting. In addition, the Hays Codes surprises a modern film goer with the strict regulations. The documentary brings to light how movie producers managed to get the point across while being subtle enough to avoid being cut. Perhaps most importantly, the Celluloid Closet captures how gay people felt ostracized and ashamed while watching films growing up. Overall, this film was a joy to watch, funny, at times heartbreaking, and a must see for anyone interested in queer cinema, one could only wish for a continuation into today's films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Evolution of Queer Cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lauren McGinnis (pointeshoes721@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" is an excellent documentary outlining the journey that queer films have taken over the last few decades. Directors Rob Epstein and Jeffery Friedman do a nearly perfect job at explaining the stereotypes, humiliations, and "hidings" that queer cinematographic love has had to face, fear and admit. "Celluloid Closet" is a film that bases itself off of some of the most famous motion pictures that the world has seen. Some of them, however, do remain as an underdog to some of the major movie successes. For those of us that are unfamiliar with queer films, "Celluloid Closet" is a spectacular orientation into that genre of movies; taking us as early as the silent films in 1895 (Thomas Edison's Experimental Movie with two male dancers) up to some of cinemas recent releases (Brokeback Mountain, 2005). Although there are no main characters, we are presented with some familiar actors, actresses, and directors such as Whoopi Goldberg, Tom Hanks, Tony Curtis and many others. This documentary presents its audience with films that some viewers wouldn't qualify as "queer" simply because they enjoy watching it. This documentary presents some of the "questionable" films upside down so the messages are clear to us but were able to remain uncensored by the Production (Hay's) Codes that had restricted certain theatrical content. "Celluloid Closet" is empathetic, understanding and entertaining. It is elegantly put together, neatly organized, personally touching and very well informative.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overview of Queer Film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    n_col13
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a documentary that offers a comprehensive overview of portrayal of LGBTQ characters in Hollywood, from the time of first motion pictures up to the early 1990s. The documentary explores the various stereotypes that persisted in Hollywood when portraying queer characters and how they gradually gave way to a more realistic portrayal. The Celluloid Closet manages to include a substantial amount of footage from various films, and points out the subtext, for example, in films like Ben-Hur. It was especially interesting to see how, even when censorship was in effect, some film-makers still managed to include subtle hints, encouraging the viewer to see between the lines. The interviews with writers, actors and film-makers help to connect the documentary to the real world and to understand what real people who are closely connected to the industry think about the way the representation of queer characters on screen evolved with time. The Celluloid Closet is a fascinating look at the history of queer film, and it can be a great starting point for someone who is unfamiliar with the subject, as this documentary is both highly entertaining and very informative, with the amount of information not being too overwhelming.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the tremendous progression of queer film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpathak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" was an overall great documentary on how homosexuality has evolved in film over decades of movies. In the early 1930s the film explained how movies portray homosexuality to be humorous. The actors that played the gay role were called "Sissies" subliminally portraying to the audience that they are homosexuals. As the movie progressed it had displayed other aspects on how the community now pictured homosexuals. The "Hayes Code" was created to rate movies on how appropriate they were. The Catholic Church as well joined in the process of rating by evaluating certain films to see if the movie was "appropriate" by their religious standards. Films later depicted homosexuals as villains such as Dracula's sister forcing the main actress to undress in front of her. In Albert Hitchcock the two villain murderers were homosexuals as well. At a certain point in these movies they had many gay subliminal symbols that the censors did not understand. During the 40s queer film was progressing to different degree. "The Celluloid Closet" explained that seeming gay was almost as bad as being gay. There would be films that would criticize a character for walking a certain way or even saying certain words. The screenwriter of Rebel without a cause stated that he would make the main character to be displayed as a gay outcast if it were during the millennium time period. In the 50's and 60's many characters of films were obviously gay. The first film to admit the homosexual intention was "The Victim" in 1961. Although there was a steadily progress of queer film, homosexuality was then presented as a crime. In the queer films the gay character would end up dying whether it be by a hero slaying the homosexual, or they became depressed and committed suicide. Queer film over the last four decades has evolved from a mental illness to being presented a sign of affection and love. Now in the 20th century queer film is accepted in the theaters almost everywhere in the nation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Introduction to Hollywood's Development of Queer Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pmata
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a documentary that focuses on Hollywood's evolution of queer film from the 1920's until the mid-1990's. The documentary's use of clips from complements clips from interviews of screenwriters and actors to show the chronology of not only queers and queer film, but also of censorship in Hollywood. The film also emphasizes how society's view of homosexuals shaped queer film. The film discusses how not only Hollywood's views of homosexuality have developed and shaped throughout the decades, but also all of America's (i.e. how all gay men were effeminate, and all lesbians were masculine). Screenwriters and actors further discuss how the Catholic Church became very involved in cinema and influenced the institution of the Hays Codes for censorship. The film emphasizes how screenwriters were able to avoid this censorship through connotations and subtleties; however, they still had to please the Church by portraying homosexuals as victims or villains to show that there was no happy ending for them. However, by the late 70's onward, depictions of homosexuality on screen became more positive as the Gay Rights Movement started in the United States, creating new norms and shaping more positive views of homosexuality in individuals. The Celluloid Closet gives an excellent history and analysis of queer film and how influential Hollywood can be. It was interesting to see how many old Hollywood films were considered part of queer cinemasuch as Rebel Without a Cause, The Maltese Falcon, and Rebecca. It was truly enlightening, and it expanded my scope of queer film. The Celluloid Closet is highly recommended to watch, for it sheds a new light for watching films, old and new, and for how to pick up different themes and subtleties to bring a deeper appreciation for "just watching a movie."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The History of Hollywood's Perception of Homosexuals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natwon93
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet was a film that documented the use of homosexual characters in the world of Hollywood. Clips from films with LGBTQ characters, actors and writers of those movies, and current actors and actresses were all used to help display the history of the progression of homosexual characters in movies. The documentary was shown in chronological order, from the 1930s to the early 1990s, emphasizing the stereotypical and sometimes unfair to normal ways in which homosexuals were portrayed. The commentary from the actors, actresses, and actors provided an entertainment and informative factor that kept the audience attentive to the subject of the documentary. It was interesting to see how in the films, LGBTQ had transitioned from light hearted humorous characters, to stereotypical sissies, to villainous individuals suffering from some sort of mental illness. Hollywood has such an effect to the everyday life that many individuals in Presbyterian Church called for a reform on the homosexual exposure in films. The Hays Codes being enforced and the amount of censorship that had to be enforced in movies made directing a film with a homosexual character in it much more difficult. The coded language and subtle movements by the actors portraying the LGBTQ characters made it clear to audiences that there was homosexual exposure in the film, just not so obvious. This film is highly recommended for it brings new knowledge of the film world to light, in regards to the issue of homosexuality. It also depicts a clear representation of how the values of different eras change drastically throughout time. Because the documentary was made in the early 1990s, it would be interesting to see how the commentators view LGBTQ characters in film today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An analysis of the perception of homosexuality in films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tsan4
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet gave an in-depth analysis of the compilation of gay films that also provided a broader identification of how the role of homosexuality has progressed. The initial depiction of homosexuality in film best described the future struggle of gays in both society and media. Beginning with the use of homosexual content as a way of humor, the atmosphere was set for the harsh reality of the portrayal of homosexuals in film. The documentary best portrays the ups and downs of how societal view on homosexuality was clearly influenced by film. The documentary highlighted specific clips from films that gave both an educational and entertainment value toward each claim made. The documentary gave clear themes, ideas and thought provoking questions that best described and in some ways shaped the idea of being or appearing homosexual. While the ideas present a clear and logical time line, the content emphasizes the ever-changing identity and perception of homosexuals by their appearance as feminine, villainous, unhappy or even suicidal. Additionally, the analysis of censored gay films also gave an interesting look on how the need to relate to media influences the way people view a movie. Above all, a great effort and successful effort was made in understanding the progression and highlight of homosexual roles in film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Celluloid Closet Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jbolante93
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is well-put-together documentary style film that does an excellent job in revealing how homosexuals were portrayed in Hollywood. The narration, along with movie clips, served as both informative and entertaining; with a perfect balance. It was informative enough to be taken seriously, yet at the same time, entertaining enough that the documentary was interesting, if not fascinating. In terms of organization, the film is very orderly and sequential. It starts with the early 1900s and proceeds to move forward till the late 1900s. I must also compliment the way the movie effectively compares and contrasts portrayals of homosexuals in different time periods, allowing for a smooth and easy to follow transition. What I loved most about the film is that it also features the varying opinions of different actors (such as Tom Hanks, Whoopie Goldberg, Tony Curtis, and others). This gives a wider variety of insight than just your own thought on watching the small movie clips. Although I do recommend the film, I did hope to see more on how the movies mentioned in the film became accepted. Another complaint is that the film lacked information on the directors or actors that should be given credit for exposing queer films into the public (especially during the early-mid 1900s when homosexuality wasn't socially acceptable). Overall, this is a great documentary for any gender or sex, whether you're homosexual or heterosexual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This documentary is enjoyable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hcandelario
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet", released in 1995, gives a keen insight into the history of homosexuals depicted in the art of film. This documentary has a great set up of commentators. They are all qualified to be speaking on the subject matter. Names and job descriptions are all given in the documentary. A younger audience can even recognize commentators such as Whoopi Goldberg and Tom Hanks. There is a sneak peek into the political influence on film production. The classic movie "Ben-Hur" released in 1959 and directed by William Wyler, is just one of the examples given for film with underlying homosexual influences. This justifies the use of "Closet" in the title. In many of the films used in the documentary the sexuality of the characters is not directly addressed, but none the less evident after watching "The Celluloid Closet". The documentary follows the changing social views of sexuality and what is acceptable chronologically, all the way from black and white films to colored films. Watching this documentary is sure to enlighten the viewer, and would be helpful to all who would like to have a better understanding of homosexuality in relation to films and film production. While being very informative the documentary is also enjoyable and engaging.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The great controversy on sexuality in Hollywood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    E Chan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" is a documentary that focuses on the evolution of sexuality in a multitude of Hollywood films and movies from the early 1900's to the early 1990's. The directors, Rob Epstein and Jeffrey Friedman portrays the views of homosexuality through a series of clips from numerous films and interviews of early actors, directors, and screenwriters. Throughout this documentary, the interviewees reveal how society reacted from the beginning of the queer films and up until modern times. This documentary is heavily based on book, "The Celluloid Closet" written by Vitto Russo. There are no main characters throughout this film, but rather focuses on the comments of each of the interviewees on the incredible growth of LGBTQ films and its effect on society. Many simply think of watching movies for entertainment purposes. However, movies have a greater influence on everyone's life than one may think, whether he or she is straight, gay or lesbian. Actors and screenwriters described the impact of movies during their early childhood and how people mainly went to see movies to see if the movies could relate to themselves. In early American society, homosexuality was viewed as humorous. The documentary then continues to describe the slander on queer films by the Catholic Church and its role in the portraying of LGBTQ content, thus leading to complications and censorship. Homosexuality was then viewed in the roles of numerous cold- blooded villains such as Dracula's Daughter and was shown in desperate gay characters that were unhappy and suicidal. Moreover, homophobia was seen as a disease in the 1950's and many people resented homosexuals. Finally, Hollywood presented homosexuality in a positive manner, shedding a new light in American culture. Overall, "The Celluloid Closet" is an interesting documentary portraying the incredible evolution of queer films in Hollywood. Even though the content is portrayed in movies and films, its effect on society was greater than one may have thought. It is informative, interesting, and funny. It is incredible on how society during the early 1900's portrays queer films being risky, impossible, and forbidden yet exciting and daring. Therefore, this documentary is highly recommended to movies fans who are interested in the making of queer films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Provides wonderful insight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guigy93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a wonderful documentary that gives an overview of homosexuality in films throughout the decades. This film manages to be both a joy to watch, while giving rare insights into classic films through actors and screenwriters such as Tony Curtis, Gore Vidal, Jay Presson Allen, and Whoopi Goldberg. Celluloid Closet manages to give a frank view of how homosexuals were portrayed without condemning or belittling any group of people. There was startling revelations of how far homosexuality had to come; from being portrayed as "sissies", villains, completely ignored, something to be ashamed of, or something to be condemned. The discussion of how homosexuals were made into villains was particularly shocking and upsetting. In addition, the Hays Codes surprises a modern film goer with the strict regulations. The documentary brings to light how movie producers managed to get the point across while being subtle enough to avoid being cut. Perhaps most importantly, the Celluloid Closet captures how gay people felt ostracized and ashamed while watching films growing up. Overall, this film was a joy to watch, funny, at times heartbreaking, and a must see for anyone interested in queer cinema, one could only wish for a continuation into today's films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Evolution of Queer Cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lauren McGinnis (pointeshoes721@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" is an excellent documentary outlining the journey that queer films have taken over the last few decades. Directors Rob Epstein and Jeffery Friedman do a nearly perfect job at explaining the stereotypes, humiliations, and "hidings" that queer cinematographic love has had to face, fear and admit. "Celluloid Closet" is a film that bases itself off of some of the most famous motion pictures that the world has seen. Some of them, however, do remain as an underdog to some of the major movie successes. For those of us that are unfamiliar with queer films, "Celluloid Closet" is a spectacular orientation into that genre of movies; taking us as early as the silent films in 1895 (Thomas Edison's Experimental Movie with two male dancers) up to some of cinemas recent releases (Brokeback Mountain, 2005). Although there are no main characters, we are presented with some familiar actors, actresses, and directors such as Whoopi Goldberg, Tom Hanks, Tony Curtis and many others. This documentary presents its audience with films that some viewers wouldn't qualify as "queer" simply because they enjoy watching it. This documentary presents some of the "questionable" films upside down so the messages are clear to us but were able to remain uncensored by the Production (Hay's) Codes that had restricted certain theatrical content. "Celluloid Closet" is empathetic, understanding and entertaining. It is elegantly put together, neatly organized, personally touching and very well informative.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overview of Queer Film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    n_col13
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a documentary that offers a comprehensive overview of portrayal of LGBTQ characters in Hollywood, from the time of first motion pictures up to the early 1990s. The documentary explores the various stereotypes that persisted in Hollywood when portraying queer characters and how they gradually gave way to a more realistic portrayal. The Celluloid Closet manages to include a substantial amount of footage from various films, and points out the subtext, for example, in films like Ben-Hur. It was especially interesting to see how, even when censorship was in effect, some film-makers still managed to include subtle hints, encouraging the viewer to see between the lines. The interviews with writers, actors and film-makers help to connect the documentary to the real world and to understand what real people who are closely connected to the industry think about the way the representation of queer characters on screen evolved with time. The Celluloid Closet is a fascinating look at the history of queer film, and it can be a great starting point for someone who is unfamiliar with the subject, as this documentary is both highly entertaining and very informative, with the amount of information not being too overwhelming.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the tremendous progression of queer film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpathak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" was an overall great documentary on how homosexuality has evolved in film over decades of movies. In the early 1930s the film explained how movies portray homosexuality to be humorous. The actors that played the gay role were called "Sissies" subliminally portraying to the audience that they are homosexuals. As the movie progressed it had displayed other aspects on how the community now pictured homosexuals. The "Hayes Code" was created to rate movies on how appropriate they were. The Catholic Church as well joined in the process of rating by evaluating certain films to see if the movie was "appropriate" by their religious standards. Films later depicted homosexuals as villains such as Dracula's sister forcing the main actress to undress in front of her. In Albert Hitchcock the two villain murderers were homosexuals as well. At a certain point in these movies they had many gay subliminal symbols that the censors did not understand. During the 40s queer film was progressing to different degree. "The Celluloid Closet" explained that seeming gay was almost as bad as being gay. There would be films that would criticize a character for walking a certain way or even saying certain words. The screenwriter of Rebel without a cause stated that he would make the main character to be displayed as a gay outcast if it were during the millennium time period. In the 50's and 60's many characters of films were obviously gay. The first film to admit the homosexual intention was "The Victim" in 1961. Although there was a steadily progress of queer film, homosexuality was then presented as a crime. In the queer films the gay character would end up dying whether it be by a hero slaying the homosexual, or they became depressed and committed suicide. Queer film over the last four decades has evolved from a mental illness to being presented a sign of affection and love. Now in the 20th century queer film is accepted in the theaters almost everywhere in the nation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Introduction to Hollywood's Development of Queer Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pmata
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a documentary that focuses on Hollywood's evolution of queer film from the 1920's until the mid-1990's. The documentary's use of clips from complements clips from interviews of screenwriters and actors to show the chronology of not only queers and queer film, but also of censorship in Hollywood. The film also emphasizes how society's view of homosexuals shaped queer film. The film discusses how not only Hollywood's views of homosexuality have developed and shaped throughout the decades, but also all of America's (i.e. how all gay men were effeminate, and all lesbians were masculine). Screenwriters and actors further discuss how the Catholic Church became very involved in cinema and influenced the institution of the Hays Codes for censorship. The film emphasizes how screenwriters were able to avoid this censorship through connotations and subtleties; however, they still had to please the Church by portraying homosexuals as victims or villains to show that there was no happy ending for them. However, by the late 70's onward, depictions of homosexuality on screen became more positive as the Gay Rights Movement started in the United States, creating new norms and shaping more positive views of homosexuality in individuals. The Celluloid Closet gives an excellent history and analysis of queer film and how influential Hollywood can be. It was interesting to see how many old Hollywood films were considered part of queer cinemasuch as Rebel Without a Cause, The Maltese Falcon, and Rebecca. It was truly enlightening, and it expanded my scope of queer film. The Celluloid Closet is highly recommended to watch, for it sheds a new light for watching films, old and new, and for how to pick up different themes and subtleties to bring a deeper appreciation for "just watching a movie."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The History of Hollywood's Perception of Homosexuals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natwon93
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet was a film that documented the use of homosexual characters in the world of Hollywood. Clips from films with LGBTQ characters, actors and writers of those movies, and current actors and actresses were all used to help display the history of the progression of homosexual characters in movies. The documentary was shown in chronological order, from the 1930s to the early 1990s, emphasizing the stereotypical and sometimes unfair to normal ways in which homosexuals were portrayed. The commentary from the actors, actresses, and actors provided an entertainment and informative factor that kept the audience attentive to the subject of the documentary. It was interesting to see how in the films, LGBTQ had transitioned from light hearted humorous characters, to stereotypical sissies, to villainous individuals suffering from some sort of mental illness. Hollywood has such an effect to the everyday life that many individuals in Presbyterian Church called for a reform on the homosexual exposure in films. The Hays Codes being enforced and the amount of censorship that had to be enforced in movies made directing a film with a homosexual character in it much more difficult. The coded language and subtle movements by the actors portraying the LGBTQ characters made it clear to audiences that there was homosexual exposure in the film, just not so obvious. This film is highly recommended for it brings new knowledge of the film world to light, in regards to the issue of homosexuality. It also depicts a clear representation of how the values of different eras change drastically throughout time. Because the documentary was made in the early 1990s, it would be interesting to see how the commentators view LGBTQ characters in film today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An analysis of the perception of homosexuality in films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tsan4
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet gave an in-depth analysis of the compilation of gay films that also provided a broader identification of how the role of homosexuality has progressed. The initial depiction of homosexuality in film best described the future struggle of gays in both society and media. Beginning with the use of homosexual content as a way of humor, the atmosphere was set for the harsh reality of the portrayal of homosexuals in film. The documentary best portrays the ups and downs of how societal view on homosexuality was clearly influenced by film. The documentary highlighted specific clips from films that gave both an educational and entertainment value toward each claim made. The documentary gave clear themes, ideas and thought provoking questions that best described and in some ways shaped the idea of being or appearing homosexual. While the ideas present a clear and logical time line, the content emphasizes the ever-changing identity and perception of homosexuals by their appearance as feminine, villainous, unhappy or even suicidal. Additionally, the analysis of censored gay films also gave an interesting look on how the need to relate to media influences the way people view a movie. Above all, a great effort and successful effort was made in understanding the progression and highlight of homosexual roles in film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Celluloid Closet Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jbolante93
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is well-put-together documentary style film that does an excellent job in revealing how homosexuals were portrayed in Hollywood. The narration, along with movie clips, served as both informative and entertaining; with a perfect balance. It was informative enough to be taken seriously, yet at the same time, entertaining enough that the documentary was interesting, if not fascinating. In terms of organization, the film is very orderly and sequential. It starts with the early 1900s and proceeds to move forward till the late 1900s. I must also compliment the way the movie effectively compares and contrasts portrayals of homosexuals in different time periods, allowing for a smooth and easy to follow transition. What I loved most about the film is that it also features the varying opinions of different actors (such as Tom Hanks, Whoopie Goldberg, Tony Curtis, and others). This gives a wider variety of insight than just your own thought on watching the small movie clips. Although I do recommend the film, I did hope to see more on how the movies mentioned in the film became accepted. Another complaint is that the film lacked information on the directors or actors that should be given credit for exposing queer films into the public (especially during the early-mid 1900s when homosexuality wasn't socially acceptable). Overall, this is a great documentary for any gender or sex, whether you're homosexual or heterosexual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This documentary is enjoyable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hcandelario
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet", released in 1995, gives a keen insight into the history of homosexuals depicted in the art of film. This documentary has a great set up of commentators. They are all qualified to be speaking on the subject matter. Names and job descriptions are all given in the documentary. A younger audience can even recognize commentators such as Whoopi Goldberg and Tom Hanks. There is a sneak peek into the political influence on film production. The classic movie "Ben-Hur" released in 1959 and directed by William Wyler, is just one of the examples given for film with underlying homosexual influences. This justifies the use of "Closet" in the title. In many of the films used in the documentary the sexuality of the characters is not directly addressed, but none the less evident after watching "The Celluloid Closet". The documentary follows the changing social views of sexuality and what is acceptable chronologically, all the way from black and white films to colored films. Watching this documentary is sure to enlighten the viewer, and would be helpful to all who would like to have a better understanding of homosexuality in relation to films and film production. While being very informative the documentary is also enjoyable and engaging.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The great controversy on sexuality in Hollywood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    E Chan
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" is a documentary that focuses on the evolution of sexuality in a multitude of Hollywood films and movies from the early 1900's to the early 1990's. The directors, Rob Epstein and Jeffrey Friedman portrays the views of homosexuality through a series of clips from numerous films and interviews of early actors, directors, and screenwriters. Throughout this documentary, the interviewees reveal how society reacted from the beginning of the queer films and up until modern times. This documentary is heavily based on book, "The Celluloid Closet" written by Vitto Russo. There are no main characters throughout this film, but rather focuses on the comments of each of the interviewees on the incredible growth of LGBTQ films and its effect on society. Many simply think of watching movies for entertainment purposes. However, movies have a greater influence on everyone's life than one may think, whether he or she is straight, gay or lesbian. Actors and screenwriters described the impact of movies during their early childhood and how people mainly went to see movies to see if the movies could relate to themselves. In early American society, homosexuality was viewed as humorous. The documentary then continues to describe the slander on queer films by the Catholic Church and its role in the portraying of LGBTQ content, thus leading to complications and censorship. Homosexuality was then viewed in the roles of numerous cold- blooded villains such as Dracula's Daughter and was shown in desperate gay characters that were unhappy and suicidal. Moreover, homophobia was seen as a disease in the 1950's and many people resented homosexuals. Finally, Hollywood presented homosexuality in a positive manner, shedding a new light in American culture. Overall, "The Celluloid Closet" is an interesting documentary portraying the incredible evolution of queer films in Hollywood. Even though the content is portrayed in movies and films, its effect on society was greater than one may have thought. It is informative, interesting, and funny. It is incredible on how society during the early 1900's portrays queer films being risky, impossible, and forbidden yet exciting and daring. Therefore, this documentary is highly recommended to movies fans who are interested in the making of queer films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Provides wonderful insight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guigy93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a wonderful documentary that gives an overview of homosexuality in films throughout the decades. This film manages to be both a joy to watch, while giving rare insights into classic films through actors and screenwriters such as Tony Curtis, Gore Vidal, Jay Presson Allen, and Whoopi Goldberg. Celluloid Closet manages to give a frank view of how homosexuals were portrayed without condemning or belittling any group of people. There was startling revelations of how far homosexuality had to come; from being portrayed as "sissies", villains, completely ignored, something to be ashamed of, or something to be condemned. The discussion of how homosexuals were made into villains was particularly shocking and upsetting. In addition, the Hays Codes surprises a modern film goer with the strict regulations. The documentary brings to light how movie producers managed to get the point across while being subtle enough to avoid being cut. Perhaps most importantly, the Celluloid Closet captures how gay people felt ostracized and ashamed while watching films growing up. Overall, this film was a joy to watch, funny, at times heartbreaking, and a must see for anyone interested in queer cinema, one could only wish for a continuation into today's films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Evolution of Queer Cinematography
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lauren McGinnis (pointeshoes721@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" is an excellent documentary outlining the journey that queer films have taken over the last few decades. Directors Rob Epstein and Jeffery Friedman do a nearly perfect job at explaining the stereotypes, humiliations, and "hidings" that queer cinematographic love has had to face, fear and admit. "Celluloid Closet" is a film that bases itself off of some of the most famous motion pictures that the world has seen. Some of them, however, do remain as an underdog to some of the major movie successes. For those of us that are unfamiliar with queer films, "Celluloid Closet" is a spectacular orientation into that genre of movies; taking us as early as the silent films in 1895 (Thomas Edison's Experimental Movie with two male dancers) up to some of cinemas recent releases (Brokeback Mountain, 2005). Although there are no main characters, we are presented with some familiar actors, actresses, and directors such as Whoopi Goldberg, Tom Hanks, Tony Curtis and many others. This documentary presents its audience with films that some viewers wouldn't qualify as "queer" simply because they enjoy watching it. This documentary presents some of the "questionable" films upside down so the messages are clear to us but were able to remain uncensored by the Production (Hay's) Codes that had restricted certain theatrical content. "Celluloid Closet" is empathetic, understanding and entertaining. It is elegantly put together, neatly organized, personally touching and very well informative.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An overview of Queer Film history
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    n_col13
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a documentary that offers a comprehensive overview of portrayal of LGBTQ characters in Hollywood, from the time of first motion pictures up to the early 1990s. The documentary explores the various stereotypes that persisted in Hollywood when portraying queer characters and how they gradually gave way to a more realistic portrayal. The Celluloid Closet manages to include a substantial amount of footage from various films, and points out the subtext, for example, in films like Ben-Hur. It was especially interesting to see how, even when censorship was in effect, some film-makers still managed to include subtle hints, encouraging the viewer to see between the lines. The interviews with writers, actors and film-makers help to connect the documentary to the real world and to understand what real people who are closely connected to the industry think about the way the representation of queer characters on screen evolved with time. The Celluloid Closet is a fascinating look at the history of queer film, and it can be a great starting point for someone who is unfamiliar with the subject, as this documentary is both highly entertaining and very informative, with the amount of information not being too overwhelming.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the tremendous progression of queer film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpathak
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Celluloid Closet" was an overall great documentary on how homosexuality has evolved in film over decades of movies. In the early 1930s the film explained how movies portray homosexuality to be humorous. The actors that played the gay role were called "Sissies" subliminally portraying to the audience that they are homosexuals. As the movie progressed it had displayed other aspects on how the community now pictured homosexuals. The "Hayes Code" was created to rate movies on how appropriate they were. The Catholic Church as well joined in the process of rating by evaluating certain films to see if the movie was "appropriate" by their religious standards. Films later depicted homosexuals as villains such as Dracula's sister forcing the main actress to undress in front of her. In Albert Hitchcock the two villain murderers were homosexuals as well. At a certain point in these movies they had many gay subliminal symbols that the censors did not understand. During the 40s queer film was progressing to different degree. "The Celluloid Closet" explained that seeming gay was almost as bad as being gay. There would be films that would criticize a character for walking a certain way or even saying certain words. The screenwriter of Rebel without a cause stated that he would make the main character to be displayed as a gay outcast if it were during the millennium time period. In the 50's and 60's many characters of films were obviously gay. The first film to admit the homosexual intention was "The Victim" in 1961. Although there was a steadily progress of queer film, homosexuality was then presented as a crime. In the queer films the gay character would end up dying whether it be by a hero slaying the homosexual, or they became depressed and committed suicide. Queer film over the last four decades has evolved from a mental illness to being presented a sign of affection and love. Now in the 20th century queer film is accepted in the theaters almost everywhere in the nation.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Introduction to Hollywood's Development of Queer Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pmata
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet is a documentary that focuses on Hollywood's evolution of queer film from the 1920's until the mid-1990's. The documentary's use of clips from complements clips from interviews of screenwriters and actors to show the chronology of not only queers and queer film, but also of censorship in Hollywood. The film also emphasizes how society's view of homosexuals shaped queer film. The film discusses how not only Hollywood's views of homosexuality have developed and shaped throughout the decades, but also all of America's (i.e. how all gay men were effeminate, and all lesbians were masculine). Screenwriters and actors further discuss how the Catholic Church became very involved in cinema and influenced the institution of the Hays Codes for censorship. The film emphasizes how screenwriters were able to avoid this censorship through connotations and subtleties; however, they still had to please the Church by portraying homosexuals as victims or villains to show that there was no happy ending for them. However, by the late 70's onward, depictions of homosexuality on screen became more positive as the Gay Rights Movement started in the United States, creating new norms and shaping more positive views of homosexuality in individuals. The Celluloid Closet gives an excellent history and analysis of queer film and how influential Hollywood can be. It was interesting to see how many old Hollywood films were considered part of queer cinemasuch as Rebel Without a Cause, The Maltese Falcon, and Rebecca. It was truly enlightening, and it expanded my scope of queer film. The Celluloid Closet is highly recommended to watch, for it sheds a new light for watching films, old and new, and for how to pick up different themes and subtleties to bring a deeper appreciation for "just watching a movie."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The History of Hollywood's Perception of Homosexuals
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natwon93
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet was a film that documented the use of homosexual characters in the world of Hollywood. Clips from films with LGBTQ characters, actors and writers of those movies, and current actors and actresses were all used to help display the history of the progression of homosexual characters in movies. The documentary was shown in chronological order, from the 1930s to the early 1990s, emphasizing the stereotypical and sometimes unfair to normal ways in which homosexuals were portrayed. The commentary from the actors, actresses, and actors provided an entertainment and informative factor that kept the audience attentive to the subject of the documentary. It was interesting to see how in the films, LGBTQ had transitioned from light hearted humorous characters, to stereotypical sissies, to villainous individuals suffering from some sort of mental illness. Hollywood has such an effect to the everyday life that many individuals in Presbyterian Church called for a reform on the homosexual exposure in films. The Hays Codes being enforced and the amount of censorship that had to be enforced in movies made directing a film with a homosexual character in it much more difficult. The coded language and subtle movements by the actors portraying the LGBTQ characters made it clear to audiences that there was homosexual exposure in the film, just not so obvious. This film is highly recommended for it brings new knowledge of the film world to light, in regards to the issue of homosexuality. It also depicts a clear representation of how the values of different eras change drastically throughout time. Because the documentary was made in the early 1990s, it would be interesting to see how the commentators view LGBTQ characters in film today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An analysis of the perception of homosexuality in films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tsan4
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Celluloid Closet gave an in-depth analysis of the compilation of gay films that also provided a broader identification of how the role of homosexuality has progressed. The initial depiction of homosexuality in film best described the future struggle of gays in both society and media. Beginning with the use of homosexual content as a way of humor, the atmosphere was set for the harsh reality of the portrayal of homosexuals in film. The documentary best portrays the ups and downs of how societal view on homosexuality was clearly influenced by film. The documentary highlighted specific clips from films that gave both an educational and entertainment value toward each claim made. The documentary gave clear themes, ideas and thought provoking questions that best described and in some ways shaped the idea of being or appearing homosexual. While the ideas present a clear and logical time line, the content emphasizes the ever-changing identity and perception of homosexuals by their appearance as feminine, villainous, unhappy or even suicidal. Additionally, the analysis of censored gay films also gave an interesting look on how the need to relate to media influences the way people view a movie. Above all, a great effort and successful effort was made in understanding the progression and highlight of homosexual roles in film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
