<filme>
 <id>
  814
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109934
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Great Day in Harlem
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Art Kane, now deceased, coordinated a group photograph of all the top jazz musicians in NYC in the year 1958, for a piece in Esquire magazine. Just about every jazz musician at the time ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Art Kane, now deceased, coordinated a group photograph of all the top jazz musicians in NYC in the year 1958, for a piece in Esquire magazine. Just about every jazz musician at the time showed up for the photo shoot which took place in front of a brownstone near the 125th street station. The documentary compiles interviews of many of the musicians in the photograph to talk about the day of the photograph, and it shows film footage taken that day by Milt Hinton and his wife.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Documentary
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   photograph
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jazz
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   esquire magazine
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   voice over narration
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   harlem manhattan new york city
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jean Bach
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jean Bach
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Susan Peehl
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Dizzy Gillespie
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Milt Hinton
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Marian McPartland
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay take on the music
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cosmoeticadotcom (cosmoetica@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recall first seeing the lauded and multiply awarded jazz documentary A Great Day In Harlem a dozen or so years ago on PBS, and while not a jazz fan nor aficionado, it was a short film (only an hour) that seemed to compress much of jazz history into a convenient package. Later on, when PBS historian Ken Burns turned his formulaic eye on the art form, with a monstrous nineteen hour documentary series, I felt he could have learned a lot from this film. Yes, like too many documentaries, especially on subjects like jazz, there is far too much hagiography of mediocrities going on, but the key difference as to why this slight film is considered a 'success', filmically, while Burns' far more professional and well-financed series is considered a 'failure', is due to one reason: concision. Thus, when I came upon a new two disk DVD version of the old documentary, I decided to revisit it, especially since it had a second disk that would probably have quite a bit more information than the actual film did. Where Burns was ponderous and pontificating in his simply named film Jazz, A Great Day In Harlem has a few of the then still living participants in first time photographer Art Kane's famous 1958 Esquire magazine photograph merely reminiscing about the day the shot was taken. Some, like drummer Art Blakey, seem to have gone senile, while others, like Marian McPartland, seem to be as sharp as ever. While certainly not insightful into the subject of jazz itself, the film does serve as a time capsule, and it does convey a more human side to the intellectually masturbated over art of jazz. Yes, there is far too much personal reminiscence and far too little insight into why the music is good and relevant- the lack of which may actually explain why jazz is in such steep decline in the country of its birth, but A Great Day In Harlem tackles almost all of its subjects- 58 in all, in just about a minute apiece, making it an MTV style documentary about pre-MTV music. What little narration is required is provided by Quincy Jones, and the film was directed by a New York City radio show host named Jean Bach- an aging white Upper West Side diva who seems to be the walking embodiment of the term dilettante. That said, she is an engaging old bird, especially in the bonus features, where she goes into great detail about how she went about conceiving of and making the film, which was co-produced and written with Matthew Seig and Susan Peehl. The story of the film is not about jazz, but the photograph, and the music takes a backseat to the personalities, even as it rambles on in the background, spiced with bits from films and TV specials from that era. The TV clips are especially revealing, and watching them give more insight into the art form's mid-Twentieth Century appeal than hours of egghead philosophizing by Burns cronies could. However, folks from the photo, such as Dizzy Gillespie, Sonny Rollins, Bud Freeman, Art Farmer, Marian McPartland, Art Blakey, Gerry Mulligan, and others go on and on, and the suspicion the film leves- that they really did spend hours rambling, is confirmed with humorous punctuation in the bonus features. There are also many other photographs taken that day by the participants- and used in the film, as well as color 8mm film taken by bassist Milt Hinton and his wife Mona, which illustrates just how difficult it was to get the often egoistic participants to group together as needed, especially with jazz superstars like Count Basie, Thelonius Monk, Coleman Hawkins, Charlie Mingus, Lester Young, and Gene Krupa all present. Also, many of the musicians spent far too long reminiscing, as the whole photo shoot took over an hour when it could have been done in five minutes. There are funny little stories, such as why Count Basie is sitting on the sidewalk with some children, and why certain musicians are standing next to others, or turned away from the camera. But, the film itself is not particularly deep. What makes this new release on DVD a treat is a wealth of extra features on both disks. There is an insert with an essay, and on the first disk, with the film itself, are featurettes on photographer Art Kane, latter day hagiographers Bill Charlap and Kenny Washington- who seemingly drool over the photo, a segment on 'Copycat Photos' which try to get great people from different arts and cities in similar poses, as well as the filmmakers reminiscing on the making of the documentary, with a wealth of humorous outtakes. But, the real treat is on disk two, where nearly three hours of comments on certain musicians can be accessed by scrolling over to the person in the photo and pressing the play button for their segment. In sum, no one who is not acquainted with jazz will learn much of why to like the art form by watching A Great Day In Harlem, but they will still be entertained by the comments of those involved, and the manifest love and care, if not skill, that went into the photo and this documentary about it. That's more than most DVDs these days give you, right?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A "Great Day" plus a worthwhile bonus disc
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ecjones1951
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jean Bach does the seemingly impossible with "A Great Day in Harlem. She makes a 40-year-old B&W photograph come alive. Art Kane's first photo assignment for Esquire magazine in 1958 must have been his own personal Everest. Get 50+ jazz musicians in one place at one time, stand across the street, point and shoot. Sure, no problem. But the cats came in droves, some of them having not yet gone to bed after a gig the night before. Some were probably nursing hangovers. But Kane captured a photo that is a cult icon, a time capsule of the heyday of hard bop, with many seminal figures from an earlier day standing proudly beside them. The late great bassist, Milt Hinton, who is one of the warmest and most charming people interviewed, was also a fine photographer. His wife captured much of the Great Day with a color 8mm movie camera, and it's a treat to see the ensemble milling about on the street and taking their places for the final picture. Many of the people in this photo are not and never were household names. But the musicians Jean Bach tracked down to give their reminiscences are quick to give them their due. They recognize their skill and talent and recall the personalities of their lesser-known counterparts. Perhaps those just getting into jazz will be motivated to seek out CDs by Benny Golson, Roy Eldridge and others by virtue of the "props" given them by their old buddies and bandmates. The Bonus Disc is worth watching, if only for the segment on "copycat" photos, and there have been many. A restaging of the original photo is quite poignant. But nothing on it is filler: the jazzmen really did warm up to Jean Bach if they didn't already know her, and they ended up talking about everything. This documentary was as great an idea as the Art Kane photo that inspired it. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Best documentary about jazz ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael-1012
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best documentary about jazz ever. If you want to know what jazz performers are like, you will learn more from this one hour film than all the hours of Ken Burns' documentary put together. It makes Burns' film insignificant by comparison. Jazz performers shine in this work because Jean Bach is such a skillful interviewer. You can tell the musicians all like her, and since they are always shown talking to the camera, not to her, it comes across as if they all like you, too, the viewer. The film makes you feel very privileged. I own this film and I watch it over and over and never get tired of it. Who could get tired of hanging out for an hour with Dizzy Gillespie, Sonny Rollins, Bud Freeman, Art Farmer, etc. and listening to the excellent narration of Quicy Jones?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Day for Jazz Buffs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BerkeleyFarmer
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine gathering 57 of the greatest legends, the creme de la creme, the absolute je ne sais quoi elite of the American art form; the people who created, shaped, formed and reformed, coddled and nursed, and were themselves that art form. The men and women of Jazz, capital "jay", in 1958. Imagine gathering not a dozen or so, but 57 of the greatest, most influential musicians of the day. In one place. At the same time. To capture one photograph. Now try to imagine not only how difficult that feat would be, but consider that the photo shoot was scheduled for daylight hours when jazz musicians are just getting home from their all-night gigs!! And yet, without having a real sense at the significance of the gathering at the time, one man, Art Kane, was able to accomplish that feat. What remains is not only the still black and white image of that one moment, but the moving pictures recorded before, during and after the photo was taken. This film is a labor of love. Of love for the craft of jazz. Of love for the craftspeople of jazz. Of love for the art of jazz. On the ode scale, which rates movies based on the total cost of seeing it versus the quality of the film itself: Definitely worth the cost of a full-price admission, plus large popcorn and large drink. Worth seeing even if you have to pay a baby sitter and a cab fare. Seeing it on the big screen is the only way to get the full impact, the full resonance of what this day represented then and what it represents to jazz lovers today. Plus, it is pure joy to watch the Giants at play!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    engaging documentary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    camel-9 (arzewski@shiprps.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/1999
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A one hour documentary on how a famous picture of some 30 jazzmen in 1958 was prepared one morning in 125th Street and Lenox Avenue. Thirty-five years later, those that were still alive were interviewed reminiscing of how the event took place. Even the small kid sitting on the curb, now a grown adult, was interviewed. There is also footage of a small portable movie camera that one had at the time. Funny too listening on the stories of these jazz giants.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great film about a truly great day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DrWatson
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/1999
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is a must not only for jazz fans, but for those who are interested in a history of American music. This film truly captures a moment in time. In the early 1950's all of the prominent jazz musicians in New York were asked to assemble in front of a Harlem brown-stone for their photograph to be taken. The photo would be used as the cover for an all jazz issue of Esquire magazine. The young photographer who was in charge of the shoot (this was his first assignment as a photographer)was soon overwhelmed at the amount of talent which assembled that morning. Among the luminaries: Count Basie, Thelonius Monk, Dizzy Gillespie, Lester Young, Gene Krupa, and countless others. All who turned out that day were legends in their own right. The day is recalled through a series of interviews with those participants still living. Some of the stories are humorous, some touching, but the warmth and emotion felt by the interviewees is evident throughout. All in all a wonderful film about a moment captured forever in time. It can be safely said that the moment this film and the photo captured, is a moment when the greatest musicians of the century were at the same place at the same time. An important and entertaining film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
