<filme>
 <id>
  817
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113122
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Frisk
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A first person narrative of the exploits of a gay serial killer in deeply disturbing, controversial drama about violence, sexuality, and the imagination. Dennis, the main character, whose ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A first person narrative of the exploits of a gay serial killer in deeply disturbing, controversial drama about violence, sexuality, and the imagination. Dennis, the main character, whose lead we follow on this path between what is real and what we can only hope is surreal. His friends attempt to determine if he's truly a psychopath. The story, is told in the form of a succession of ritual-like murders, comes to life through the letters he writes to his sometime lover and best friend Julian and the object of his desire, Julian's younger brother, Kevin. The film is set in an erotic world of sado-masochism and portrays the sexual appetites of a young man for whom killing and engorging the victim become the ultimate thrill.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   gay
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   violence
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   queer cinema
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gay interest
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   s&m
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Todd Verow
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Dennis Cooper
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jim Dwyer
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Michael Gunther
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Craig Chester
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Michael Stock
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a film for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a gay man who has had fantasies about killing other men since teenage. Honestly, I see little point in the existence of "Frisk". It is a poorly made B movie with poor acting and poor production. The plot is not well explained or particularly engaging. Apart from the main character Dennis, there is no character development. So most people in the film seem like random people, making the plot more confusing to follow. I am very disturbed by these perverted and sick minds portrayed in the movie. It is not a film for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A B-movie not at all as described in the comments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    true9999
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I make it a general rule to dismiss any comment by someone using "trangressive" somewhere in the review. Folks I braced myself for a horrible, bloody, unredeeming movie and came away underwhelmed. Frankly, there is no gore and there is less blood in the entire movie than one sees in the first 3 minutes of any slasher film. The only reason to rate this movie low is because it is a B-movie with cheap production values and some wooden acting. Other than that, it managed to keep my interest throughout the entire film. I cannot believe people would boo this film. That is absurd. If the characters were straight, no one would have a problem. But the main characters are gay and all of a sudden, we now have "social commentary" instead of just mindless entertainment. Except for some male frontal nudity, this movie could be shown on network TV, although late-night. For those that believe all gay movies should be affirming, this movie is not for you. For those that are looking for yet another gay romantic comedy with lots of eye candy and bad acting, well there is some eye candy and bad acting, but not much romance or humor. It's not the greatest movie, it has flaws, but I didn't come away feeling as if I totally wasted my time watching it. Ignore the prudes. See the movie. Make up your own mind. You will be shocked at how mild this movie is given the strange plot and subject matter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes moments as a top movie, sometimes not that good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bertoele
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay. There are moments I think this is a top movie and sometimes it's not that good. What is top is the acting of Raoul O'Connell. The guy brings so much into the movie as character. Unbelievable!. Really awesome. I have no other word for it. When he appears the story starts to be interesting. He takes my attention. He wakes me up. And he brings depth into what the director thinks and wants. He is a a gift from heaven I think. Okay. That means. Please great directors. Please take him and ask him to play in your movie. It's a selfish thing of me. Because I like to see him. Frisk is a movie you like or dislike. It's a kind of horror story. It shows some dark side of human. Of a gay man. It tells about our society nowdays. I 's really something do make a movie like this, without to much money. Hope they will spent some more money into the story and ask Raoul O'Connel again and there will be a master piece. Okay. Hugs from Bert in Amsterdam
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dull and obvious, and not the least bit transgressive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rick Powell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps it's not entirely fair for me to review this movie since I walked out in disgust about halfway through and came back only for the last ten minutes. But I agree with Dennis Cooper: The literal interpretation of his book makes the film an entirely predictable exploitation flick - in terms of narrative and in the amateurish way it's all presented - instead of a compelling and artful auto-interrogation of f*cked-up desire. The most damage done is by director Todd Verow's inability to transpose the colloquial first-person of the book into something that makes sense for a movie. At this point in his career, he doesn't have the skills to pull it off, which results in a decision to make the serial killing explicitly real. I suppose Verow thinks that makes his movie more transgressive than Cooper's book which only tells me he didn't understand the book in the first place. Verow can be a creative and entertaining filmmaker - his Once and Future Queen is a scream; and Anonymous showed promise - but Frisk is dull and obvious, and only a half-star away from being complete garbage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Homophobic piece of trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-153
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on a bet. I hated every minute of it. Why? 1. Bad acting (except for Parker Posey, who can make a telephone book seem interesting...and should have done so instead of taking this trash on). 2. Insipid script filled with self-important dialog and voice-over that sounded like fake high-school ennui laced with a dash of faux philosophy 101. 3. A-B-C directing. 4. Pseudo-stylish editing flashes that even MTV would find silly. 5. Nothing sets. 6. 1-2-3 style lighting. 7. A loathing of all things homosexual and the fag-hags who adore them. Not one normal person was allowed to counterpoint the non-stop anti-gay depiction of gay men as self-mutilating drug abusers into kinky anything so long as it winds up with them ejaculating at the end. 8. The wimpy non-stop suggestion that it's all in Dennis' mind. Maybe. Except it might not be. Or might be. Maybe. Sort of. Except it isn't. Or is it? And on and on and on, ad nauseum. Edgy? Avant guarde? A whole new genre of in your face "I don't care about anybody" sort of movies, with this being a prime piece? Give me a break. At best, this is limp- wiener porn gussied up with occasional flashes of male genitalia and a low-rent idea that self-destruction and serial murder are part of the queer gene. That this homophobic piece of trash was (supposedly) shown at Sundance and the Berlin Film Festival only shows how second rate those venues have become. You want to see a real serial killer movie full of "I don't care about anybody" done right? Rent "Henry, Portrait Of A Serial Killer" or "Monster" or even "Citizen X". Anything but this garbage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gay serial killers in love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Incomprehensible. It's something about a gay guy who may (or may not) be a serial killer. The film jumps all over the place--there are flash backs, flash forwards, dream sequences all mashed together. Supposedly if you read the book you'll understand the movie. Well--I haven't read the book and I don't think I should have to read it to make heads or tails out of the movie. A movie should stand on its own and this one certainly doesn't. It looks grimy (but I heard that was on purpose); the acting is truly abominable (some of the guys are cute but that's about it); the same actors play multiple roles (which is confusing), and the dialogue read during the killings is just so matter of fact I didn't know HOW to take it! And I didn't find it disturbing or confusing--just dull and irritating. The only saving grace is Parker Posey--she manages to take a nothing role and actually make something of it. She has lousy dialogue too but she makes it work. So--aside from Posey and some cute guys there's nothing to recommend this. I give it a 1.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disturbing behavior
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    strangekindaboy
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being an avid fan of Cooper's novels, I purchased this film hoping that it would capture the truly disturbing yet poetic quality of his books. This film succeeds in being disturbing but falls short of being poetic. Although at times certain scenes or frames of the film border on indie film brilliance, unless you have read the book, it's certainly hard to follow--as it probably was intended to be. Parker Posey is the redeeming quality in this film--a strange quirkiness to a murderous she-devil who shows no remorse and offers no motive. It's a shame she was not introduced until much later in the film. Some other thoughts: The odd underground electronic soundtrack compliments the film well. The foreign porn star is incredibly eerie. The lead is not terribly convincing as a murderer. And...the most disturbing scene is the duct tape and broom scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    um, sure...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deathrockgrrl
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really don't see how anyone that hasn't read the book could possibly really understand what this film is supposed to be about. The character development was pretty weak, making me constantly wonder *why* the characters were doing what they were doing... and never getting an answer. And the acting really didn't help either. It was just... well, bad. It made the characters look cheap and one dimensional. Dialogue was spoken as if it was the actors' first times going over the script. You know, porn-like. I really don't get why people act like this was such a disturbing movie... I was bored throughout mostly the entire thing. If the characters had been straight, it may very well have been just another late night HBO erotic thriller. If I had to guess, I'd say this film was made solely to shock, not to actually tell a really quite interesting story written by a brilliant author.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad film with one great moment.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Otto
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pretty awful. Even though I had read and loved the book, I couldn't make heads or tails of the movie. Although one thing needs to be pointed out, in the films brief conventional narrative moment, Craig Chester is brilliant as the semi-comatose whore. When his trick for the evening is trying to drag his lifeless body out of his house, Chester wakes up to ask if there was anything he could have done better for them. It's hard to explain, but in a way, that one moment almost gives this terrible, rootless film a sense of humanity that leaves an impression. I would watch the first 30 minutes again for that scene alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating but ultimately pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Havan_IronOak
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is another of those art films that goes nowhere but gets there in style. This film is gritty and fascinating in a sick, can't help but look at the car wreck on the highway sort of way. It's not bad enough to turn off so you keep watching hoping that sanity will be restored. It won't be but you watch nonetheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a film for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a gay man who has had fantasies about killing other men since teenage. Honestly, I see little point in the existence of "Frisk". It is a poorly made B movie with poor acting and poor production. The plot is not well explained or particularly engaging. Apart from the main character Dennis, there is no character development. So most people in the film seem like random people, making the plot more confusing to follow. I am very disturbed by these perverted and sick minds portrayed in the movie. It is not a film for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A B-movie not at all as described in the comments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    true9999
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I make it a general rule to dismiss any comment by someone using "trangressive" somewhere in the review. Folks I braced myself for a horrible, bloody, unredeeming movie and came away underwhelmed. Frankly, there is no gore and there is less blood in the entire movie than one sees in the first 3 minutes of any slasher film. The only reason to rate this movie low is because it is a B-movie with cheap production values and some wooden acting. Other than that, it managed to keep my interest throughout the entire film. I cannot believe people would boo this film. That is absurd. If the characters were straight, no one would have a problem. But the main characters are gay and all of a sudden, we now have "social commentary" instead of just mindless entertainment. Except for some male frontal nudity, this movie could be shown on network TV, although late-night. For those that believe all gay movies should be affirming, this movie is not for you. For those that are looking for yet another gay romantic comedy with lots of eye candy and bad acting, well there is some eye candy and bad acting, but not much romance or humor. It's not the greatest movie, it has flaws, but I didn't come away feeling as if I totally wasted my time watching it. Ignore the prudes. See the movie. Make up your own mind. You will be shocked at how mild this movie is given the strange plot and subject matter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes moments as a top movie, sometimes not that good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bertoele
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay. There are moments I think this is a top movie and sometimes it's not that good. What is top is the acting of Raoul O'Connell. The guy brings so much into the movie as character. Unbelievable!. Really awesome. I have no other word for it. When he appears the story starts to be interesting. He takes my attention. He wakes me up. And he brings depth into what the director thinks and wants. He is a a gift from heaven I think. Okay. That means. Please great directors. Please take him and ask him to play in your movie. It's a selfish thing of me. Because I like to see him. Frisk is a movie you like or dislike. It's a kind of horror story. It shows some dark side of human. Of a gay man. It tells about our society nowdays. I 's really something do make a movie like this, without to much money. Hope they will spent some more money into the story and ask Raoul O'Connel again and there will be a master piece. Okay. Hugs from Bert in Amsterdam
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dull and obvious, and not the least bit transgressive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rick Powell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps it's not entirely fair for me to review this movie since I walked out in disgust about halfway through and came back only for the last ten minutes. But I agree with Dennis Cooper: The literal interpretation of his book makes the film an entirely predictable exploitation flick - in terms of narrative and in the amateurish way it's all presented - instead of a compelling and artful auto-interrogation of f*cked-up desire. The most damage done is by director Todd Verow's inability to transpose the colloquial first-person of the book into something that makes sense for a movie. At this point in his career, he doesn't have the skills to pull it off, which results in a decision to make the serial killing explicitly real. I suppose Verow thinks that makes his movie more transgressive than Cooper's book which only tells me he didn't understand the book in the first place. Verow can be a creative and entertaining filmmaker - his Once and Future Queen is a scream; and Anonymous showed promise - but Frisk is dull and obvious, and only a half-star away from being complete garbage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Homophobic piece of trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-153
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this movie on a bet. I hated every minute of it. Why? 1. Bad acting (except for Parker Posey, who can make a telephone book seem interesting...and should have done so instead of taking this trash on). 2. Insipid script filled with self-important dialog and voice-over that sounded like fake high-school ennui laced with a dash of faux philosophy 101. 3. A-B-C directing. 4. Pseudo-stylish editing flashes that even MTV would find silly. 5. Nothing sets. 6. 1-2-3 style lighting. 7. A loathing of all things homosexual and the fag-hags who adore them. Not one normal person was allowed to counterpoint the non-stop anti-gay depiction of gay men as self-mutilating drug abusers into kinky anything so long as it winds up with them ejaculating at the end. 8. The wimpy non-stop suggestion that it's all in Dennis' mind. Maybe. Except it might not be. Or might be. Maybe. Sort of. Except it isn't. Or is it? And on and on and on, ad nauseum. Edgy? Avant guarde? A whole new genre of in your face "I don't care about anybody" sort of movies, with this being a prime piece? Give me a break. At best, this is limp- wiener porn gussied up with occasional flashes of male genitalia and a low-rent idea that self-destruction and serial murder are part of the queer gene. That this homophobic piece of trash was (supposedly) shown at Sundance and the Berlin Film Festival only shows how second rate those venues have become. You want to see a real serial killer movie full of "I don't care about anybody" done right? Rent "Henry, Portrait Of A Serial Killer" or "Monster" or even "Citizen X". Anything but this garbage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gay serial killers in love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Incomprehensible. It's something about a gay guy who may (or may not) be a serial killer. The film jumps all over the place--there are flash backs, flash forwards, dream sequences all mashed together. Supposedly if you read the book you'll understand the movie. Well--I haven't read the book and I don't think I should have to read it to make heads or tails out of the movie. A movie should stand on its own and this one certainly doesn't. It looks grimy (but I heard that was on purpose); the acting is truly abominable (some of the guys are cute but that's about it); the same actors play multiple roles (which is confusing), and the dialogue read during the killings is just so matter of fact I didn't know HOW to take it! And I didn't find it disturbing or confusing--just dull and irritating. The only saving grace is Parker Posey--she manages to take a nothing role and actually make something of it. She has lousy dialogue too but she makes it work. So--aside from Posey and some cute guys there's nothing to recommend this. I give it a 1.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disturbing behavior
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    strangekindaboy
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being an avid fan of Cooper's novels, I purchased this film hoping that it would capture the truly disturbing yet poetic quality of his books. This film succeeds in being disturbing but falls short of being poetic. Although at times certain scenes or frames of the film border on indie film brilliance, unless you have read the book, it's certainly hard to follow--as it probably was intended to be. Parker Posey is the redeeming quality in this film--a strange quirkiness to a murderous she-devil who shows no remorse and offers no motive. It's a shame she was not introduced until much later in the film. Some other thoughts: The odd underground electronic soundtrack compliments the film well. The foreign porn star is incredibly eerie. The lead is not terribly convincing as a murderer. And...the most disturbing scene is the duct tape and broom scene.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    um, sure...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deathrockgrrl
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really don't see how anyone that hasn't read the book could possibly really understand what this film is supposed to be about. The character development was pretty weak, making me constantly wonder *why* the characters were doing what they were doing... and never getting an answer. And the acting really didn't help either. It was just... well, bad. It made the characters look cheap and one dimensional. Dialogue was spoken as if it was the actors' first times going over the script. You know, porn-like. I really don't get why people act like this was such a disturbing movie... I was bored throughout mostly the entire thing. If the characters had been straight, it may very well have been just another late night HBO erotic thriller. If I had to guess, I'd say this film was made solely to shock, not to actually tell a really quite interesting story written by a brilliant author.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad film with one great moment.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Otto
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pretty awful. Even though I had read and loved the book, I couldn't make heads or tails of the movie. Although one thing needs to be pointed out, in the films brief conventional narrative moment, Craig Chester is brilliant as the semi-comatose whore. When his trick for the evening is trying to drag his lifeless body out of his house, Chester wakes up to ask if there was anything he could have done better for them. It's hard to explain, but in a way, that one moment almost gives this terrible, rootless film a sense of humanity that leaves an impression. I would watch the first 30 minutes again for that scene alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating but ultimately pointless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Havan_IronOak
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is another of those art films that goes nowhere but gets there in style. This film is gritty and fascinating in a sick, can't help but look at the car wreck on the highway sort of way. It's not bad enough to turn off so you keep watching hoping that sanity will be restored. It won't be but you watch nonetheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
