<filme>
 <id>
  819
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116168
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Eddie
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Eddie is a New York limo driver and a fanatical follower of the New York Knicks professional basketball team. The team is struggling with a mediocre record when, in mid-season, "Wild Bill" ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Eddie is a New York limo driver and a fanatical follower of the New York Knicks professional basketball team. The team is struggling with a mediocre record when, in mid-season, "Wild Bill" Burgess, the new owner, as a public relations gimmick, stages an 'honorary coach' contest, which Eddie wins. The fans love it, so "Wild Bill" fires the coach and hires her. She takes the bunch of overpaid prima donnas that make up the team and turns them around. But the owner hopes to move the team, now the darling of the New York fans, to St. Louis. He may OWN the team, but it BELONGS to the city and the fans!
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sport
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   coach
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new york knicks
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   basketball
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female protagonist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sports team
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Steve Rash
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Steve Zacharias
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jeff Buhai
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Whoopi Goldberg
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Frank Langella
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dennis Farina
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It has its moments, but somewhat disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie concept: Promising. Actors: Goldberg perfect for the role. Script: 6 writers couldn't put something together with a tighter script than this????? This film has a pretty low rating on IMDb, and I'm not surprised. Although the concept was pretty good, the execution was sloppy...just about as sloppy as the team was during the first half of the film. I had the idea throughout the film that most people involved were just going through the motions. That's not to say there aren't some good moments here. There are some good laughs. Occasionally Whoppi shines like I expected her to shine. It's all pretty good natured, and some of the cameos by politicians and others are fun. Whoopi does fairly well in the lead. Although it's hardly his finest hour, Frank Langella is decent as the new Texan club owner. And Dennis Farina is fine as the old and opposing coach. But there was no danger here of anyone winning an Oscar or Golden Globe. It's a couple of hours of fun, but I'd never be tempted to watch it a second time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feel-good Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    harperelf-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll try to keep this short and to the point. This is not a complex drama, not was it meant to be. As a previous reviewer pointed out, the pacing is quick and timely. On some levels, you could view this as a moral tale. The good guys win in the end. The heroine puts out a max effort, remains true to her values, but also discovers her view of the situation was a bit too simple. (Perhaps as many of us have a tendency towards?). As in life, a little attitude and approach adjustment, and she zeroes in on the goal. The willingness to risk failing, however, remaining steadfast to her morals, provides the final tension that is resolved with the cathartic victory in the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    NBA all the way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnykeane10
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie starring Whoppi Goldberg is a product of the tremendous interest generated by the game of Basketball in the 90s in the USA, mostly because of the jazz and excitement of the game and players like Michael Jordan, Dennis Rodman etc who drew in large crowds and made the NBA big business. The best feature about this film is it does not take itself seriously from the beginning. There fun poked at greedy players, foreign imports and egotistical coaches! The film itself is about a huge fan of the New York Knicks who becomes coach of the New York Knicks by becoming close to the new owner of the Knicks Wild Bill Burgess( Frank Langella) The cameos in the film are plentiful and while MJ himself does not make an appearance it gives a funny insight into what its like to be on the court and what makes players tick. One shot of John Salley making a free throw is very striking and would send a shiver down any sports fan of any sport. Its not a blue chips type basketball film, its a comedy/sports movie that is easy to watch and thats why i am giving it a 7! P.S look out for a rare cameo from Leroy from Fame as a dancer!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Ole Fashion Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyshimah3
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie: Just about a pro team overcoming obstacles that many teams face in a season. Basketball is my favorite sport. Rick Fox is my favorite actor. So this is definitely one of my favorite movies. There are so many good "life" points in the movie. Whoppi Goldberg is great in this movie and it is filled with a lot of stars without the movie being egotistical and whatnot. It is just a feel good movie with a lot of funny bits. And I watch it because of Goldberg, Fox and Malik Sealy who was so good in this movie and who was killed a while after it was released. It will keep you laughing non-stop and the music is good as well. I hope this is helpful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you laugh at this, you must be a very happy person - or on drugs.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people feel that this pitiful comedy is underrated and unjustly forgotten. Maybe they're just rabid Goldberg fans for whom she can do no cinematic wrong, or maybe they grew up locked away in various basements, being allowed only to watch bad French comedies. "Eddie" is a movie totally lacking in comic timing. The direction is uninspired and sleep-inducing. The ridiculous premise could only be acceptable in a ZAZ-type movie, which this is very far from being; in fact, the story actually gets sentimental and serious as it goes along, asking the viewers to actually take the premise and these silly characters seriously. (You can't have your funny cake and eat its sentimentality, too... One of the most common mistakes made in U.S. comedies.) Some of the "gags" bomb so badly that they're frankly even embarrassing to watch - and that's the absolute LAST thing you want your audiences to feel. (First comes cringing, and then running out of the theater, or throwing the DVD out of the window like a useless, one-throw Frisbee...) Goldberg is more annoying than charismatic in her absurdly written role, but it's really the direction, as mentioned, and especially the script which are to blame for this mediocre mess. As much as I dislike the somewhat overrated Goldberg, even this dumb vehicle is beneath her talents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Family Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwardi-koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whoopi Goldberg is ideally cast as a passionate and loud-mouthed Knicks fan with the best of intentions. The film does as a good job of setting up its fantastic premise: Whoopi appointed as coach of the Knicks to help the owner break obnoxious coach Dennis Farina's ironclad contract. Farina is terrific as the ex-coach of the Knicks who tries to edge the Knicks out for the last playoff spot in the East as the Coach of the Hornets. Vlade Divac is hysterically funny, but not-at-all over-the-top as Ivan. Frank Langella is perfectly sinister but never unbelievable as the larger-than-life Cowboy owner who buys the Knicks to try to sell them for a profit. There are hilarious cameos throughout especially by two former NYC mayors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Whoop
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember passing up many an opportunity to watch this film... I would catch commercials stating that it would air within days, I never made a point of watching it(in fact, I rather made one of missing it). Tonight, I saw it (as the famous line in Spaceballs goes) for the first time, for the last time. The movie is just not funny. I never laughed, smirked, heck, I didn't even smile. It wasn't charming, clever or even sporadically amusing. I'm generally not into movies about sports... but I have liked them. I didn't like this one. Didn't care for it a bit. Whoopi Goldberg has her moments, but they are few and far between... and none of them are in this flick. The plot is daft and poorly written. The acting is unimpressive. The characters are thin, clich&eacute;d stereotypes. The humor is simplistic and unfunny. The timing is off, more often than not. The sports scenes aren't particularly exciting or involving. The score is decent enough, with one or two great songs. All in all, the film is just not all that interesting... it might be decent entertainment for fans of basketball. But then again, the same could be said of Space Jam, and we all know the level of quality presented in that film... exactly. That film may actually be more entertaining, since it at least has one or two comedic talents(take that, Goldberg). I suggest you skip it, unless you *really* want to see a basketball flick. I recommend this to fans of basket and/or Whoopi Goldberg. Everyone else probably shouldn't bother. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I LAUGHED REALLY REALLY HARD it gets a 3 from me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrBlueo
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Non-stop hilarity. Genius Film-making. Unworldly writing. Heavenly Acting. This movie has it all.This movie gets an A+++ from me. Some people might say "You're Crazy Man This Movie is worse than an alligators ball sack". TO those people I say look no farther than Greg Ostertags genius acting. Why he hasn't been in more movies is beyond me. By the way. All that I said above is untrue. This movie is horrible. Whoopi Goldberg is horrible. Greg Ostertag is horrible (on the basketball court and the big screen). I currently rate this movie below the Power Rangers movie. Thats right. I rate this movie BELOW The Power Rangers Movie. Save yourself that free rental at Blockbuster and don't get this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable from start to finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    herbertatara
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a comedy-fantasy, people -- not a documentary. The pacing is bouncy and rollicking. The performances are precisely what they should be -- neither "villain" is one-dimensional or over-the-top, but just menacing enough in the right amounts, and the ways in which Eddie triumphs over each of them are quite clever. Mayor Koch's cameo is hysterical, as is the bit with Stacey's Mom. Ostertag shows good comic timing. The background of Eddie is just touching enough without being maudlin. The transition of the Knicks from selfish losers to re-motivated winners is handled just right for a comedy-fantasy. This is at least in a class with Angels In The Outfield as an enjoyable comedy-fantasy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Bardon
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a black man, I need inspiration from fellow African Americans. This film provides it...IN FOLDS! Whoopi Goldberg gives a heartwarming performance, perhaps even better than her work in "The Color Purple", "Amistad", "Ghostbusters." Goldberg's performance is masterful; however, the true star of this magical movie is Greg Ostertag. His bravery in portraying this enigma of a character is mindboggling. Little known fact about Mr.Ostertag, he portrayed the ghost of Christmas future in his 10th grade production of "A Christmas Carol." Ostertag is not only a dominating force on the basketball court, he is dominating with his screen presence in "Eddie." I recommend seeing this film immediately if only for Greg Ostertag's performance. 9/10. If you enjoy this film I would also recommend "Space Cowboys"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It has its moments, but somewhat disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vincentlynch-moonoi
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie concept: Promising. Actors: Goldberg perfect for the role. Script: 6 writers couldn't put something together with a tighter script than this????? This film has a pretty low rating on IMDb, and I'm not surprised. Although the concept was pretty good, the execution was sloppy...just about as sloppy as the team was during the first half of the film. I had the idea throughout the film that most people involved were just going through the motions. That's not to say there aren't some good moments here. There are some good laughs. Occasionally Whoppi shines like I expected her to shine. It's all pretty good natured, and some of the cameos by politicians and others are fun. Whoopi does fairly well in the lead. Although it's hardly his finest hour, Frank Langella is decent as the new Texan club owner. And Dennis Farina is fine as the old and opposing coach. But there was no danger here of anyone winning an Oscar or Golden Globe. It's a couple of hours of fun, but I'd never be tempted to watch it a second time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feel-good Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    harperelf-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll try to keep this short and to the point. This is not a complex drama, not was it meant to be. As a previous reviewer pointed out, the pacing is quick and timely. On some levels, you could view this as a moral tale. The good guys win in the end. The heroine puts out a max effort, remains true to her values, but also discovers her view of the situation was a bit too simple. (Perhaps as many of us have a tendency towards?). As in life, a little attitude and approach adjustment, and she zeroes in on the goal. The willingness to risk failing, however, remaining steadfast to her morals, provides the final tension that is resolved with the cathartic victory in the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    NBA all the way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnykeane10
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie starring Whoppi Goldberg is a product of the tremendous interest generated by the game of Basketball in the 90s in the USA, mostly because of the jazz and excitement of the game and players like Michael Jordan, Dennis Rodman etc who drew in large crowds and made the NBA big business. The best feature about this film is it does not take itself seriously from the beginning. There fun poked at greedy players, foreign imports and egotistical coaches! The film itself is about a huge fan of the New York Knicks who becomes coach of the New York Knicks by becoming close to the new owner of the Knicks Wild Bill Burgess( Frank Langella) The cameos in the film are plentiful and while MJ himself does not make an appearance it gives a funny insight into what its like to be on the court and what makes players tick. One shot of John Salley making a free throw is very striking and would send a shiver down any sports fan of any sport. Its not a blue chips type basketball film, its a comedy/sports movie that is easy to watch and thats why i am giving it a 7! P.S look out for a rare cameo from Leroy from Fame as a dancer!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Ole Fashion Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tyshimah3
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eddie: Just about a pro team overcoming obstacles that many teams face in a season. Basketball is my favorite sport. Rick Fox is my favorite actor. So this is definitely one of my favorite movies. There are so many good "life" points in the movie. Whoppi Goldberg is great in this movie and it is filled with a lot of stars without the movie being egotistical and whatnot. It is just a feel good movie with a lot of funny bits. And I watch it because of Goldberg, Fox and Malik Sealy who was so good in this movie and who was killed a while after it was released. It will keep you laughing non-stop and the music is good as well. I hope this is helpful.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you laugh at this, you must be a very happy person - or on drugs.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fedor8
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people feel that this pitiful comedy is underrated and unjustly forgotten. Maybe they're just rabid Goldberg fans for whom she can do no cinematic wrong, or maybe they grew up locked away in various basements, being allowed only to watch bad French comedies. "Eddie" is a movie totally lacking in comic timing. The direction is uninspired and sleep-inducing. The ridiculous premise could only be acceptable in a ZAZ-type movie, which this is very far from being; in fact, the story actually gets sentimental and serious as it goes along, asking the viewers to actually take the premise and these silly characters seriously. (You can't have your funny cake and eat its sentimentality, too... One of the most common mistakes made in U.S. comedies.) Some of the "gags" bomb so badly that they're frankly even embarrassing to watch - and that's the absolute LAST thing you want your audiences to feel. (First comes cringing, and then running out of the theater, or throwing the DVD out of the window like a useless, one-throw Frisbee...) Goldberg is more annoying than charismatic in her absurdly written role, but it's really the direction, as mentioned, and especially the script which are to blame for this mediocre mess. As much as I dislike the somewhat overrated Goldberg, even this dumb vehicle is beneath her talents.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Family Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwardi-koch
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whoopi Goldberg is ideally cast as a passionate and loud-mouthed Knicks fan with the best of intentions. The film does as a good job of setting up its fantastic premise: Whoopi appointed as coach of the Knicks to help the owner break obnoxious coach Dennis Farina's ironclad contract. Farina is terrific as the ex-coach of the Knicks who tries to edge the Knicks out for the last playoff spot in the East as the Coach of the Hornets. Vlade Divac is hysterically funny, but not-at-all over-the-top as Ivan. Frank Langella is perfectly sinister but never unbelievable as the larger-than-life Cowboy owner who buys the Knicks to try to sell them for a profit. There are hilarious cameos throughout especially by two former NYC mayors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Whoop
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember passing up many an opportunity to watch this film... I would catch commercials stating that it would air within days, I never made a point of watching it(in fact, I rather made one of missing it). Tonight, I saw it (as the famous line in Spaceballs goes) for the first time, for the last time. The movie is just not funny. I never laughed, smirked, heck, I didn't even smile. It wasn't charming, clever or even sporadically amusing. I'm generally not into movies about sports... but I have liked them. I didn't like this one. Didn't care for it a bit. Whoopi Goldberg has her moments, but they are few and far between... and none of them are in this flick. The plot is daft and poorly written. The acting is unimpressive. The characters are thin, clich&eacute;d stereotypes. The humor is simplistic and unfunny. The timing is off, more often than not. The sports scenes aren't particularly exciting or involving. The score is decent enough, with one or two great songs. All in all, the film is just not all that interesting... it might be decent entertainment for fans of basketball. But then again, the same could be said of Space Jam, and we all know the level of quality presented in that film... exactly. That film may actually be more entertaining, since it at least has one or two comedic talents(take that, Goldberg). I suggest you skip it, unless you *really* want to see a basketball flick. I recommend this to fans of basket and/or Whoopi Goldberg. Everyone else probably shouldn't bother. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I LAUGHED REALLY REALLY HARD it gets a 3 from me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrBlueo
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Non-stop hilarity. Genius Film-making. Unworldly writing. Heavenly Acting. This movie has it all.This movie gets an A+++ from me. Some people might say "You're Crazy Man This Movie is worse than an alligators ball sack". TO those people I say look no farther than Greg Ostertags genius acting. Why he hasn't been in more movies is beyond me. By the way. All that I said above is untrue. This movie is horrible. Whoopi Goldberg is horrible. Greg Ostertag is horrible (on the basketball court and the big screen). I currently rate this movie below the Power Rangers movie. Thats right. I rate this movie BELOW The Power Rangers Movie. Save yourself that free rental at Blockbuster and don't get this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable from start to finish
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    herbertatara
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a comedy-fantasy, people -- not a documentary. The pacing is bouncy and rollicking. The performances are precisely what they should be -- neither "villain" is one-dimensional or over-the-top, but just menacing enough in the right amounts, and the ways in which Eddie triumphs over each of them are quite clever. Mayor Koch's cameo is hysterical, as is the bit with Stacey's Mom. Ostertag shows good comic timing. The background of Eddie is just touching enough without being maudlin. The transition of the Knicks from selfish losers to re-motivated winners is handled just right for a comedy-fantasy. This is at least in a class with Angels In The Outfield as an enjoyable comedy-fantasy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Bardon
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a black man, I need inspiration from fellow African Americans. This film provides it...IN FOLDS! Whoopi Goldberg gives a heartwarming performance, perhaps even better than her work in "The Color Purple", "Amistad", "Ghostbusters." Goldberg's performance is masterful; however, the true star of this magical movie is Greg Ostertag. His bravery in portraying this enigma of a character is mindboggling. Little known fact about Mr.Ostertag, he portrayed the ghost of Christmas future in his 10th grade production of "A Christmas Carol." Ostertag is not only a dominating force on the basketball court, he is dominating with his screen presence in "Eddie." I recommend seeing this film immediately if only for Greg Ostertag's performance. 9/10. If you enjoy this film I would also recommend "Space Cowboys"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
