<filme>
 <id>
  821
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117104
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Mrs. Winterbourne
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Connie Doyle is eighteen and pregnant her boyfriend has kicked her out. She accidentaly ends up on a train where she meets Hugh Winterbourne and his wife Patricia who is pregnant. The train... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Connie Doyle is eighteen and pregnant her boyfriend has kicked her out. She accidentaly ends up on a train where she meets Hugh Winterbourne and his wife Patricia who is pregnant. The train wrecks and she wakes up in the hosptial to find out that it's been assumed that she's Patricia. Hugh's mother takes her in and she falls in love with Hugh's brother Bill. Just when she thinks everything is going her way, her ex-boyfriend shows up.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   train
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   train wreck
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   eccentric
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   forbidden love
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Richard Benjamin
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Cornell Woolrich
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Phoef Sutton
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Shirley MacLaine
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ricki Lake
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Brendan Fraser
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The premise was dated in 1950
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alsation72
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers are not possible for this predictable mawkish mess: its as obvious as it is brainless. This film is a remake of "No Man of Her Own", a 1950 clunker which starred Barbara Stanwyck. Obviously Ricki Lake is no Barbara Stanwyck, but in this film she comes across as conniving, irritating and unlike-able. Barefoot and pregnant, she is mistaken for Mrs. Winterbourne's daughter in law. This badly- concocted case of mistaken identity basically drives the weak story. Apparently despite a wedding and impending birth, Mrs Winterbourne has never seen even a picture of her son's wife. Did Shirley MacLain read the script before she signed up? Ricki Lake comes off as a tubby little tomboy; as a leading lady in a feature film she makes a great talk-show host. She says "ain't" a lot, just so we remember how impoverished the character was. The romance that blossoms between her and Fraser's character is not believable; together they have zero chemistry. When the jig is up and the deception is uncovered the family instantly seems to accept it because they are just so darned lovable. Maybe if they had used someone like Sandra Bullock and really made an effort to update this stinker of a storyline ... maybe then it might have been bearable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touching But Quite Flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My first bit of confusion was over exactly where this movie wanted to go. I imagined it as a romantic comedy of sorts, and yet from the very beginning it was really quite heavy, dealing as it did with young Connie (Rikki Lake) being homeless, then meeting up with a sleazebag and then being tossed out by him when he gets her pregnant. I really wasn't feeling much fun at that point in the movie. Then mistaken identity turns into deliberate deceit on Connie's part (although I understand it wasn't malicious.) Once she gets taken in by the Winterbourne's after the train wreck that kills their son and his wife (whom the family has never met, and whom Connie is mistaken for) the only character who really made sense to me was Bill (Brendan Fraser), who seemed appropriately suspicious of her given the circumstances. True, he was ridiculously obnoxious, but his suspicion was bang on, except that he then, for no obvious reason that I saw, fell head over heels in love with her, letting go of all his suspicions and deciding to marry her! Where did that come from? There are some moments of fun in this. Shirley MacLaine (as the matriarch of the Winterbourne clan) was probably the best part of the movie and provided much of the comedy, and the closing scenes (as everyone tries to protect Connie/Patricia) was quite touching, as was the point that the Winterbournes became the family she never had. There was a nice feel to that, especially because we know that Connie isn't out for the family's money, but just wants the sense of family for herself and even more for her son. There was one huge inconsistency here that just made everything else implausible, though. Bill finally figures out what's going on because he sees "Patricia" sign "Connie Doyle" on a check, and investigates who Connie Doyle is. He gets back a report that Connie and her unborn baby were killed in the train wreck (it was, of course, the real Patricia and her unborn baby who were killed.) How would he get that report? Connie wasn't supposed to be on that train. She got swept into it by a huge crowd of people, she had no ticket, and since it wasn't really Connie there would be no way of identifying the body as Connie. How then would anyone come to the conclusion that the dead body was Connie when no one knew Connie was on that train - and, in fact, no one on that train even knew Connie? This isn't an unenjoyable movie. It's quite touching, really - but it does have a lot of flaws! 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than I Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormy_daze
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So.... two hours before bed, I'm bored.... want to watch something fluffy and pointless, something i won't get too invested in before sleep... something i won't really care if i fall asleep during it... but something i haven't seen in a while. Always been a big fan of Frazer, and decided to watch this for a strange reason -- Frazer is ambidextrous and usually writes with his left hand. But I had this memory of him sitting at a desk writing with his right, and I couldn't remember what the movie is. So I'm trying to figure out what it was.... and then remembered him saying one of the lines of the movie. So I hopped on to IMDb and just as I was typing his name I remembered the movie. Looked for it online for a little while, finally found it via good ol' YouTube. I had expected, going in, a really wretched horrible movie; but had hoped to be at least somewhat entertained by Frazer. The man is really a fantastic actor; He always amuses me. So I thought, what the heck -- I watched The Air I Breathe last night, that was heavy. Let's have a Frazer fluffy movie (that's not Blast from the Past or the Mummy because i've seen them so many times) and had hoped to be, at least, mildly entertained. This is not a brilliant movie. But Frazer and MacLaine are absolutely wonderful and make the movie watchable. I just remember this movie coming out around the same time as While You Were Sleeping. Same basic premise -- following a confusion over identity, a lonely girl lies to family about who she really is because the family takes her in and she feels accepted for the first time in her life. ...This one has a baby in it. So, not original. Let's make that clear. Not believable. Not even that good a movie. However, Frazer and MacLaine are lovely and the movie has its moments -- like when Rikki Lake comes in the room asking MacLaine (who is smoking) who had been smoking in the room and MacLaine half-swallows the lit cigarette to avoid being caught. Or everyone constantly taking MacClaine's alcohol from her as well as her cigs. Cute little moments make it fun-- the Cuban butler getting drunk and dancing in the empty pool over a broken heart is a fun moment too. So, not original, not believable, not really great. But it's not nearly as bad as I remember. Frazer is fab at playing a snarky business man and there is definite chemistry between MacClaine and Frazer that make the whole thing not only watchable, but enjoyable if nothing else for them. A weaker story and someone like Lake who just doesn't have the magical charisma to stand up to someone like Frazer or MacClaine just reminds you what the movie is missing most of the time. If they'd cast someone with more charisma like Sandra Bullock in While You Were Sleeping, I'd have been very interested to see Sandra and Frazer together. Anyway, it's a good fluff, don't expect much and you might enjoy yourself. It's not brilliant, it's not even great, but you know, if you just want a mindless fluff and watch Frazer being snarky it's good enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartwarming fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was not what I expected at all. One hears Ricki Lake's name and automatically assumes that somewhere her pregnant character will burst into song and tease her hair to the heights, but I actually surprisingly enjoyed her in this movie. Yes, she was a little bit of a ham and her age didn't fit the character, but she did a good job playing the little downtrodden city girl who, through a battle with mistaken identity, finds the family she wished she'd always had. As for issues with her attitude and her changes into a society girl, did anyone ever think that maybe she was not that much of a wild child before, and that her acclimation into society was easier than she would have expected? Come on, who on this site doesn't speak a little differently in front of their parents versus their friends? I know I have to give myself a mental warning to try to keep my tongue from slipping when I visit my mom...seriously, everybody does this to some degree, you just don't think about it. I mean, imagine going to church...do you curse in front of your pastor or priest? No. You'd never dream of it. With your friends after a few margaritas? Yes, often something naughty would come out. With that said, Shirley MacLaine and Brendan Fraser are charming, warm and human. She is absolutely the perfect high society misfit leader of a crazy but accepted clan. She's funny, sweet and caring, and smarter than her son or Connie give her credit for. I love, love, love her in this role! Brendan's Hugh/Bill is a marvelous character. The brief moments we see Hugh are sweet, and we unknowingly get a contrast between the two men when we first see the movie. Hugh's free spirit is an instant draw, where Bill's all business attitude at the start takes getting used to. Others on this site have said that it is unconvincing for Bill to have gone from a bit of a cold fish to the warm, funny, in-love guy that he becomes, but I can see the possibilities. If you can put yourself into the character's shoes, here is a man who's just lost his twin brother and been thrown in with the man's wife. He feels some attraction to this pretty, goofy young woman, but this is his DEAD BROTHER'S WIFE! Society would frown upon it...wouldn't't't it? Besides, he's the more sensible twin. He hasn't found that woman who brings out the softer side, so why change? Well...because something about this girl is so endearing, so charming, that he finds himself warming up. It's out of his hands...he can't help it. He's crazy about her. And when he's ready to rat her out to Grace, but Connie tells Grace not to put her in the will, he realizes she really ISN'T there for the money, and that just makes her more lovable. How could he tell Grace and potentially cause another attack? I won't say anymore about what goes on in the movie, as I've done enough damage, but my mom introduced me to this sweet and funny movie, and I was charmed and pleased with the whole film. The ending was satisfying (and I know how the paperwork *flub* is fixable, but if I explain, I'll be saying too much!) and I came away happy, so it's definitely worth giving a shot! Rent it, watch it, don't expect too much, and you'll definitely be satisfied!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rikki Lake tries to look pretty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daveyd_2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I got stuck watching this absolute piece of crap and I am now writing about it to cleanse my soul. Once again I see that without good writers, even great actors, (MacLaine) wished they had called in sick or checked into rehab instead of appearing this achingly painful rehash of twenty different crappy movies already made. And, please, giving a makeover to Rikki Lake is like spraying Febreze on dog crap. You just can't fix that kind of ugly with a haircut and a band aid, sorry. I will never forgive the 'writers' or 'actors' of this petrified turd of a movie. So if this does come on make sure that you have caught up to your significant other and the massive amounts of wine they have drunk to find this celluloid enema entertaining!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, but full of plot holes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tex-42
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mrs. Winterbourne is perhaps the epitome of romantic comedies, in the requirement that you suspend disbelief. It almost commands that you not think about the plot too much, because if you do, the entire movie falls apart. The plot is simple. Connie Doyle is thrown out by her boyfriend when she becomes pregnant, and she ends up on a train with the Winterbournes, a wealthy young couple on their way to Boston. The train derails, and both Winterbournes are killed. However, as Connie was trying on Mrs. Winterbourne's ring at the time of the accident, she is mistaken for her, and her baby for the Winterbourne grandchild. What follows is what always happens in romantic comedies, Connie is taken in by the Winterbourne family and falls in love with the dead Winterbourne's twin brother, who is initially suspicious of her, but then grows to love her. Complications arise, but everything works out in the end. Shirley MacLaine is quite winning at Grace Winterbourne, and Miguel Sandoval steals most of his scenes. The problem is that neither Ricki Lake or Brendan Fraser have much chemistry with each other, and Ricki Lake seems miscast in general. Of course, there are also massive plot holes here, and even in the end, no one really seems to care that the real Mrs. Winterbourne and the real Winterbourne grandchild are off buried somewhere under someone else's name. This is not a bad movie, it's perfectly pleasant, but you really are required to not think about the plot at all to really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why it's a five...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    addylennox
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because Brendan Fraser and Shirley Maclaine make it surprisingly bearable. Ricki Lake, God bless her, was, in a word, miscast; without the strength of Fraser and Maclaine, this movie is a two, at best a three. She's brings no life to the role, no reality. At best, she was an over-actor. At worst... well, she was a bad over-actor. A really, really bad over-actor. Still, for a movie that had so much potential (if not for the sometimes unbelievable -yet entertaining- storyline, then definitely for the two aforementioned lead actors) that was lost beneath the looming shadow that is Lake, I'd watch it again. If it were on cable TV... and if nothing else is on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Add me to the "I liked it" camp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cruztacean
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that those who are most vocally panning "Mrs. Winterbourne" are doing so because they simply don't like the genre of light-hearted romantic comedy. As a comedy, not a drama, and especially as a mistaken identity plot bordering on farce, it isn't *supposed* to resemble a true-to-life documentary, OK? I don't understand those who say Ricki Lake shouldn't have been cast in the female lead role. Why? Because she isn't some A-list skeletal blonde? She played Connie/Patricia admirably, and says that this is the role that made her the proudest to play. It was the first role, she said, where her weight didn't factor into the casting. Should she be sorry she's too "average looking" for some people's Hottiewood tastes? I don't think so. Who says ordinary women don't deserve love and romance too? We'll get the obvious out of the way first. Of COURSE Shirley MacLaine shines as Grace Winterbourne. That lady could play a seashell and be absolutely spellbinding. Of COURSE Brendan Fraser has women swooning over his Hugh/Bill Winterbourne. That's what Brendan Fraser does. It's the smaller roles that make the movie wonderful: Loren Dean is altogether tops as Steven DeCunzo, the abusive womanizing lowlife who fathers Connie's baby and then abandons her to the streets, ultimately getting what he richly deserves. Convincing? Hey, I wanted to smack him myself. Nesbitt Blaisdell stole the scene as the homeless man who befriends a very pregnant Connie. "They pray at you," he warns her about a particular shelter, "but the food's good." Miguel Sandoval is truly enjoyable as Paco, the butler. The only small problem here is that Paco's homosexuality is a trait I gathered only from script, not from character development. In other words, I just never would have guessed Paco was gay without it being said outright. For all I know Sandoval himself could be homosexual (I have no idea) and my saying that he doesn't believably portray one could be hilarious in its irony, but it just doesn't seem that way to me. What do I want, a stereotype? Probably. Farces are usually full of them. Farce is all about exaggeration, and exaggeration relies heavily on stereotype. My favorite scene in the movie has got to be the aftermath of the "Sunny Side of the Street" fiasco. Streetwise teenager tells catty blonde d&eacute;butantes to "f--- off," leaving them flabbergasted with shock. That's funny enough, but then smooth, cultured, filthy rich family matriarch comes along behind her with, "You heard her. F--- off," which was one hundred percent hysterical. There's the scene at the train station where Paco delivers the line, "You are as much a Winterbourne as I am," putting a lump in my throat. I do have trouble with the wedding scene at the end. Connie stops the proceedings (and nearly stops the priest's pulse as well) by unexpectedly saying no. She, Patricia Winterbourne, does *not* take Bill Winterbourne to be her husband. "I, Constance Helen Doyle, do all that." And everything's back on again. My problem is that the marriage license would have read Patricia Winterbourne. They wouldn't have had time to correct it. Which, of course, would invalidate the ceremony, making Grandma Grace Winterbourne's closing line to baby Hughie--"They're married"--a false statement. Oh, no they're not. Also, I am forced to agree that Ricki Lake does NOT look like a character who just turned 18 years old. But hey, if I'm going to be consistent and say that farce isn't supposed to be completely believable, then we can suspend reality for those things too. To summarize, so what if Mrs. Winterbourne is a chick flick? Chicks are half the world's population, guys. Get used to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrible Adaption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    court99
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Contains spoilers* I watched this movie in the middle of a Sunday, having never heard of it and no prior expectations what so ever, I was pleasantly surprised. The concepts which this movie presented were so original and unpredictable, I got the impression that this was a classic and well celebrated American story. It was however the ideas in the story which had me captivated, that and the very attractive Brendan Fraser. It's hard to come by movies which surprise you. Having seen that it was based on the book "I Married a Dead man" by Cornell Woolrich, I managed to find it in the library, and I read it. Twice. It is one of my favourite books, haunting, subtle, brilliantly crafted. Nothing like the movie. I'm sorry to say that "Mrs. Winterbourne" is an atrocious adaption of the book, it butchers all the complex and beautiful themes and even changes the ending. "I Married a Dead man" does not have a happy ending as the movie does, Bill and Patrice are left suspecting one another of the murder and cannot live in happiness. Even when you have not read the book, the movie does not even really work as a stand alone romantic comedy. After having a complete character change which seemed to happen over night, Bill suddenly falls in love with Connie and marries her in what appears to be a few weeks after his brothers death. There is nothing to indicate the passage of time and it left me very confused as a viewer that they would so quickly move on. The book I recommend - it is brilliant. The movie I do not, thank goodness Cornell Woolrich is not alive to see it, it would make him want to cut off his other leg. (He had to have one of his legs removed due to gangrene)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bored on a winter's day or evening? Go find this film, Mrs. Winterbourne!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Connie (Ricki Lake) lost her mother at twelve in Hoboken, New Jersey. Because she did not get along with her father, Connie left NJ at 18 and went to NYC. Unfortunately, she immediately hooked up with a low-life named Steve and became pregnant. Steve was less than thrilled with the news and threw Connie out of the house. Although she works as a waitress for awhile, when her delivery date draws near, she finds herself broke and homeless. The next day , Connie boards a train she thinks is the subway but which turns out to be a railway to Boston. There, she is befriended by handsome, rich Hugh and his new and very pregnant wife Patricia. The train derails. Hugh and Patricia are killed. But, by a twist of fate, Connie is mistaken for Patricia and finds herself and her new baby in a private hospital, as befitting the wife of a member of the rich Winterbourne family. She meets her new mother-in-law (Shirley MacLaine) and her "husband's" twin brother, Bill (Brendan Fraser) and goes home to a posh, Boston mansion, complete with servants. Just how long will she be able to fool everyone into thinking she really is a part of the family? This is a nice little film for the proverbial romcom fan. MacLaine is wonderful as the matriarch of the wealthy family and Fraser is his usual handsome, quirky, affable self. Lake seems a bit miscast as the girl with a big secret but fulfills her role adequately. The sets, costumes, and production values are very high. Do you love improbable plots and unexpected, humorous romance? Make a date to see Mrs. W. and you will be in your element, absolutely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The premise was dated in 1950
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alsation72
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers are not possible for this predictable mawkish mess: its as obvious as it is brainless. This film is a remake of "No Man of Her Own", a 1950 clunker which starred Barbara Stanwyck. Obviously Ricki Lake is no Barbara Stanwyck, but in this film she comes across as conniving, irritating and unlike-able. Barefoot and pregnant, she is mistaken for Mrs. Winterbourne's daughter in law. This badly- concocted case of mistaken identity basically drives the weak story. Apparently despite a wedding and impending birth, Mrs Winterbourne has never seen even a picture of her son's wife. Did Shirley MacLain read the script before she signed up? Ricki Lake comes off as a tubby little tomboy; as a leading lady in a feature film she makes a great talk-show host. She says "ain't" a lot, just so we remember how impoverished the character was. The romance that blossoms between her and Fraser's character is not believable; together they have zero chemistry. When the jig is up and the deception is uncovered the family instantly seems to accept it because they are just so darned lovable. Maybe if they had used someone like Sandra Bullock and really made an effort to update this stinker of a storyline ... maybe then it might have been bearable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touching But Quite Flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My first bit of confusion was over exactly where this movie wanted to go. I imagined it as a romantic comedy of sorts, and yet from the very beginning it was really quite heavy, dealing as it did with young Connie (Rikki Lake) being homeless, then meeting up with a sleazebag and then being tossed out by him when he gets her pregnant. I really wasn't feeling much fun at that point in the movie. Then mistaken identity turns into deliberate deceit on Connie's part (although I understand it wasn't malicious.) Once she gets taken in by the Winterbourne's after the train wreck that kills their son and his wife (whom the family has never met, and whom Connie is mistaken for) the only character who really made sense to me was Bill (Brendan Fraser), who seemed appropriately suspicious of her given the circumstances. True, he was ridiculously obnoxious, but his suspicion was bang on, except that he then, for no obvious reason that I saw, fell head over heels in love with her, letting go of all his suspicions and deciding to marry her! Where did that come from? There are some moments of fun in this. Shirley MacLaine (as the matriarch of the Winterbourne clan) was probably the best part of the movie and provided much of the comedy, and the closing scenes (as everyone tries to protect Connie/Patricia) was quite touching, as was the point that the Winterbournes became the family she never had. There was a nice feel to that, especially because we know that Connie isn't out for the family's money, but just wants the sense of family for herself and even more for her son. There was one huge inconsistency here that just made everything else implausible, though. Bill finally figures out what's going on because he sees "Patricia" sign "Connie Doyle" on a check, and investigates who Connie Doyle is. He gets back a report that Connie and her unborn baby were killed in the train wreck (it was, of course, the real Patricia and her unborn baby who were killed.) How would he get that report? Connie wasn't supposed to be on that train. She got swept into it by a huge crowd of people, she had no ticket, and since it wasn't really Connie there would be no way of identifying the body as Connie. How then would anyone come to the conclusion that the dead body was Connie when no one knew Connie was on that train - and, in fact, no one on that train even knew Connie? This isn't an unenjoyable movie. It's quite touching, really - but it does have a lot of flaws! 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than I Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormy_daze
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So.... two hours before bed, I'm bored.... want to watch something fluffy and pointless, something i won't get too invested in before sleep... something i won't really care if i fall asleep during it... but something i haven't seen in a while. Always been a big fan of Frazer, and decided to watch this for a strange reason -- Frazer is ambidextrous and usually writes with his left hand. But I had this memory of him sitting at a desk writing with his right, and I couldn't remember what the movie is. So I'm trying to figure out what it was.... and then remembered him saying one of the lines of the movie. So I hopped on to IMDb and just as I was typing his name I remembered the movie. Looked for it online for a little while, finally found it via good ol' YouTube. I had expected, going in, a really wretched horrible movie; but had hoped to be at least somewhat entertained by Frazer. The man is really a fantastic actor; He always amuses me. So I thought, what the heck -- I watched The Air I Breathe last night, that was heavy. Let's have a Frazer fluffy movie (that's not Blast from the Past or the Mummy because i've seen them so many times) and had hoped to be, at least, mildly entertained. This is not a brilliant movie. But Frazer and MacLaine are absolutely wonderful and make the movie watchable. I just remember this movie coming out around the same time as While You Were Sleeping. Same basic premise -- following a confusion over identity, a lonely girl lies to family about who she really is because the family takes her in and she feels accepted for the first time in her life. ...This one has a baby in it. So, not original. Let's make that clear. Not believable. Not even that good a movie. However, Frazer and MacLaine are lovely and the movie has its moments -- like when Rikki Lake comes in the room asking MacLaine (who is smoking) who had been smoking in the room and MacLaine half-swallows the lit cigarette to avoid being caught. Or everyone constantly taking MacClaine's alcohol from her as well as her cigs. Cute little moments make it fun-- the Cuban butler getting drunk and dancing in the empty pool over a broken heart is a fun moment too. So, not original, not believable, not really great. But it's not nearly as bad as I remember. Frazer is fab at playing a snarky business man and there is definite chemistry between MacClaine and Frazer that make the whole thing not only watchable, but enjoyable if nothing else for them. A weaker story and someone like Lake who just doesn't have the magical charisma to stand up to someone like Frazer or MacClaine just reminds you what the movie is missing most of the time. If they'd cast someone with more charisma like Sandra Bullock in While You Were Sleeping, I'd have been very interested to see Sandra and Frazer together. Anyway, it's a good fluff, don't expect much and you might enjoy yourself. It's not brilliant, it's not even great, but you know, if you just want a mindless fluff and watch Frazer being snarky it's good enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartwarming fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was not what I expected at all. One hears Ricki Lake's name and automatically assumes that somewhere her pregnant character will burst into song and tease her hair to the heights, but I actually surprisingly enjoyed her in this movie. Yes, she was a little bit of a ham and her age didn't fit the character, but she did a good job playing the little downtrodden city girl who, through a battle with mistaken identity, finds the family she wished she'd always had. As for issues with her attitude and her changes into a society girl, did anyone ever think that maybe she was not that much of a wild child before, and that her acclimation into society was easier than she would have expected? Come on, who on this site doesn't speak a little differently in front of their parents versus their friends? I know I have to give myself a mental warning to try to keep my tongue from slipping when I visit my mom...seriously, everybody does this to some degree, you just don't think about it. I mean, imagine going to church...do you curse in front of your pastor or priest? No. You'd never dream of it. With your friends after a few margaritas? Yes, often something naughty would come out. With that said, Shirley MacLaine and Brendan Fraser are charming, warm and human. She is absolutely the perfect high society misfit leader of a crazy but accepted clan. She's funny, sweet and caring, and smarter than her son or Connie give her credit for. I love, love, love her in this role! Brendan's Hugh/Bill is a marvelous character. The brief moments we see Hugh are sweet, and we unknowingly get a contrast between the two men when we first see the movie. Hugh's free spirit is an instant draw, where Bill's all business attitude at the start takes getting used to. Others on this site have said that it is unconvincing for Bill to have gone from a bit of a cold fish to the warm, funny, in-love guy that he becomes, but I can see the possibilities. If you can put yourself into the character's shoes, here is a man who's just lost his twin brother and been thrown in with the man's wife. He feels some attraction to this pretty, goofy young woman, but this is his DEAD BROTHER'S WIFE! Society would frown upon it...wouldn't't't it? Besides, he's the more sensible twin. He hasn't found that woman who brings out the softer side, so why change? Well...because something about this girl is so endearing, so charming, that he finds himself warming up. It's out of his hands...he can't help it. He's crazy about her. And when he's ready to rat her out to Grace, but Connie tells Grace not to put her in the will, he realizes she really ISN'T there for the money, and that just makes her more lovable. How could he tell Grace and potentially cause another attack? I won't say anymore about what goes on in the movie, as I've done enough damage, but my mom introduced me to this sweet and funny movie, and I was charmed and pleased with the whole film. The ending was satisfying (and I know how the paperwork *flub* is fixable, but if I explain, I'll be saying too much!) and I came away happy, so it's definitely worth giving a shot! Rent it, watch it, don't expect too much, and you'll definitely be satisfied!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rikki Lake tries to look pretty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daveyd_2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I got stuck watching this absolute piece of crap and I am now writing about it to cleanse my soul. Once again I see that without good writers, even great actors, (MacLaine) wished they had called in sick or checked into rehab instead of appearing this achingly painful rehash of twenty different crappy movies already made. And, please, giving a makeover to Rikki Lake is like spraying Febreze on dog crap. You just can't fix that kind of ugly with a haircut and a band aid, sorry. I will never forgive the 'writers' or 'actors' of this petrified turd of a movie. So if this does come on make sure that you have caught up to your significant other and the massive amounts of wine they have drunk to find this celluloid enema entertaining!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, but full of plot holes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tex-42
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mrs. Winterbourne is perhaps the epitome of romantic comedies, in the requirement that you suspend disbelief. It almost commands that you not think about the plot too much, because if you do, the entire movie falls apart. The plot is simple. Connie Doyle is thrown out by her boyfriend when she becomes pregnant, and she ends up on a train with the Winterbournes, a wealthy young couple on their way to Boston. The train derails, and both Winterbournes are killed. However, as Connie was trying on Mrs. Winterbourne's ring at the time of the accident, she is mistaken for her, and her baby for the Winterbourne grandchild. What follows is what always happens in romantic comedies, Connie is taken in by the Winterbourne family and falls in love with the dead Winterbourne's twin brother, who is initially suspicious of her, but then grows to love her. Complications arise, but everything works out in the end. Shirley MacLaine is quite winning at Grace Winterbourne, and Miguel Sandoval steals most of his scenes. The problem is that neither Ricki Lake or Brendan Fraser have much chemistry with each other, and Ricki Lake seems miscast in general. Of course, there are also massive plot holes here, and even in the end, no one really seems to care that the real Mrs. Winterbourne and the real Winterbourne grandchild are off buried somewhere under someone else's name. This is not a bad movie, it's perfectly pleasant, but you really are required to not think about the plot at all to really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why it's a five...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    addylennox
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because Brendan Fraser and Shirley Maclaine make it surprisingly bearable. Ricki Lake, God bless her, was, in a word, miscast; without the strength of Fraser and Maclaine, this movie is a two, at best a three. She's brings no life to the role, no reality. At best, she was an over-actor. At worst... well, she was a bad over-actor. A really, really bad over-actor. Still, for a movie that had so much potential (if not for the sometimes unbelievable -yet entertaining- storyline, then definitely for the two aforementioned lead actors) that was lost beneath the looming shadow that is Lake, I'd watch it again. If it were on cable TV... and if nothing else is on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Add me to the "I liked it" camp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cruztacean
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that those who are most vocally panning "Mrs. Winterbourne" are doing so because they simply don't like the genre of light-hearted romantic comedy. As a comedy, not a drama, and especially as a mistaken identity plot bordering on farce, it isn't *supposed* to resemble a true-to-life documentary, OK? I don't understand those who say Ricki Lake shouldn't have been cast in the female lead role. Why? Because she isn't some A-list skeletal blonde? She played Connie/Patricia admirably, and says that this is the role that made her the proudest to play. It was the first role, she said, where her weight didn't factor into the casting. Should she be sorry she's too "average looking" for some people's Hottiewood tastes? I don't think so. Who says ordinary women don't deserve love and romance too? We'll get the obvious out of the way first. Of COURSE Shirley MacLaine shines as Grace Winterbourne. That lady could play a seashell and be absolutely spellbinding. Of COURSE Brendan Fraser has women swooning over his Hugh/Bill Winterbourne. That's what Brendan Fraser does. It's the smaller roles that make the movie wonderful: Loren Dean is altogether tops as Steven DeCunzo, the abusive womanizing lowlife who fathers Connie's baby and then abandons her to the streets, ultimately getting what he richly deserves. Convincing? Hey, I wanted to smack him myself. Nesbitt Blaisdell stole the scene as the homeless man who befriends a very pregnant Connie. "They pray at you," he warns her about a particular shelter, "but the food's good." Miguel Sandoval is truly enjoyable as Paco, the butler. The only small problem here is that Paco's homosexuality is a trait I gathered only from script, not from character development. In other words, I just never would have guessed Paco was gay without it being said outright. For all I know Sandoval himself could be homosexual (I have no idea) and my saying that he doesn't believably portray one could be hilarious in its irony, but it just doesn't seem that way to me. What do I want, a stereotype? Probably. Farces are usually full of them. Farce is all about exaggeration, and exaggeration relies heavily on stereotype. My favorite scene in the movie has got to be the aftermath of the "Sunny Side of the Street" fiasco. Streetwise teenager tells catty blonde d&eacute;butantes to "f--- off," leaving them flabbergasted with shock. That's funny enough, but then smooth, cultured, filthy rich family matriarch comes along behind her with, "You heard her. F--- off," which was one hundred percent hysterical. There's the scene at the train station where Paco delivers the line, "You are as much a Winterbourne as I am," putting a lump in my throat. I do have trouble with the wedding scene at the end. Connie stops the proceedings (and nearly stops the priest's pulse as well) by unexpectedly saying no. She, Patricia Winterbourne, does *not* take Bill Winterbourne to be her husband. "I, Constance Helen Doyle, do all that." And everything's back on again. My problem is that the marriage license would have read Patricia Winterbourne. They wouldn't have had time to correct it. Which, of course, would invalidate the ceremony, making Grandma Grace Winterbourne's closing line to baby Hughie--"They're married"--a false statement. Oh, no they're not. Also, I am forced to agree that Ricki Lake does NOT look like a character who just turned 18 years old. But hey, if I'm going to be consistent and say that farce isn't supposed to be completely believable, then we can suspend reality for those things too. To summarize, so what if Mrs. Winterbourne is a chick flick? Chicks are half the world's population, guys. Get used to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrible Adaption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    court99
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Contains spoilers* I watched this movie in the middle of a Sunday, having never heard of it and no prior expectations what so ever, I was pleasantly surprised. The concepts which this movie presented were so original and unpredictable, I got the impression that this was a classic and well celebrated American story. It was however the ideas in the story which had me captivated, that and the very attractive Brendan Fraser. It's hard to come by movies which surprise you. Having seen that it was based on the book "I Married a Dead man" by Cornell Woolrich, I managed to find it in the library, and I read it. Twice. It is one of my favourite books, haunting, subtle, brilliantly crafted. Nothing like the movie. I'm sorry to say that "Mrs. Winterbourne" is an atrocious adaption of the book, it butchers all the complex and beautiful themes and even changes the ending. "I Married a Dead man" does not have a happy ending as the movie does, Bill and Patrice are left suspecting one another of the murder and cannot live in happiness. Even when you have not read the book, the movie does not even really work as a stand alone romantic comedy. After having a complete character change which seemed to happen over night, Bill suddenly falls in love with Connie and marries her in what appears to be a few weeks after his brothers death. There is nothing to indicate the passage of time and it left me very confused as a viewer that they would so quickly move on. The book I recommend - it is brilliant. The movie I do not, thank goodness Cornell Woolrich is not alive to see it, it would make him want to cut off his other leg. (He had to have one of his legs removed due to gangrene)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bored on a winter's day or evening? Go find this film, Mrs. Winterbourne!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Connie (Ricki Lake) lost her mother at twelve in Hoboken, New Jersey. Because she did not get along with her father, Connie left NJ at 18 and went to NYC. Unfortunately, she immediately hooked up with a low-life named Steve and became pregnant. Steve was less than thrilled with the news and threw Connie out of the house. Although she works as a waitress for awhile, when her delivery date draws near, she finds herself broke and homeless. The next day , Connie boards a train she thinks is the subway but which turns out to be a railway to Boston. There, she is befriended by handsome, rich Hugh and his new and very pregnant wife Patricia. The train derails. Hugh and Patricia are killed. But, by a twist of fate, Connie is mistaken for Patricia and finds herself and her new baby in a private hospital, as befitting the wife of a member of the rich Winterbourne family. She meets her new mother-in-law (Shirley MacLaine) and her "husband's" twin brother, Bill (Brendan Fraser) and goes home to a posh, Boston mansion, complete with servants. Just how long will she be able to fool everyone into thinking she really is a part of the family? This is a nice little film for the proverbial romcom fan. MacLaine is wonderful as the matriarch of the wealthy family and Fraser is his usual handsome, quirky, affable self. Lake seems a bit miscast as the girl with a big secret but fulfills her role adequately. The sets, costumes, and production values are very high. Do you love improbable plots and unexpected, humorous romance? Make a date to see Mrs. W. and you will be in your element, absolutely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The premise was dated in 1950
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alsation72
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers are not possible for this predictable mawkish mess: its as obvious as it is brainless. This film is a remake of "No Man of Her Own", a 1950 clunker which starred Barbara Stanwyck. Obviously Ricki Lake is no Barbara Stanwyck, but in this film she comes across as conniving, irritating and unlike-able. Barefoot and pregnant, she is mistaken for Mrs. Winterbourne's daughter in law. This badly- concocted case of mistaken identity basically drives the weak story. Apparently despite a wedding and impending birth, Mrs Winterbourne has never seen even a picture of her son's wife. Did Shirley MacLain read the script before she signed up? Ricki Lake comes off as a tubby little tomboy; as a leading lady in a feature film she makes a great talk-show host. She says "ain't" a lot, just so we remember how impoverished the character was. The romance that blossoms between her and Fraser's character is not believable; together they have zero chemistry. When the jig is up and the deception is uncovered the family instantly seems to accept it because they are just so darned lovable. Maybe if they had used someone like Sandra Bullock and really made an effort to update this stinker of a storyline ... maybe then it might have been bearable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touching But Quite Flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My first bit of confusion was over exactly where this movie wanted to go. I imagined it as a romantic comedy of sorts, and yet from the very beginning it was really quite heavy, dealing as it did with young Connie (Rikki Lake) being homeless, then meeting up with a sleazebag and then being tossed out by him when he gets her pregnant. I really wasn't feeling much fun at that point in the movie. Then mistaken identity turns into deliberate deceit on Connie's part (although I understand it wasn't malicious.) Once she gets taken in by the Winterbourne's after the train wreck that kills their son and his wife (whom the family has never met, and whom Connie is mistaken for) the only character who really made sense to me was Bill (Brendan Fraser), who seemed appropriately suspicious of her given the circumstances. True, he was ridiculously obnoxious, but his suspicion was bang on, except that he then, for no obvious reason that I saw, fell head over heels in love with her, letting go of all his suspicions and deciding to marry her! Where did that come from? There are some moments of fun in this. Shirley MacLaine (as the matriarch of the Winterbourne clan) was probably the best part of the movie and provided much of the comedy, and the closing scenes (as everyone tries to protect Connie/Patricia) was quite touching, as was the point that the Winterbournes became the family she never had. There was a nice feel to that, especially because we know that Connie isn't out for the family's money, but just wants the sense of family for herself and even more for her son. There was one huge inconsistency here that just made everything else implausible, though. Bill finally figures out what's going on because he sees "Patricia" sign "Connie Doyle" on a check, and investigates who Connie Doyle is. He gets back a report that Connie and her unborn baby were killed in the train wreck (it was, of course, the real Patricia and her unborn baby who were killed.) How would he get that report? Connie wasn't supposed to be on that train. She got swept into it by a huge crowd of people, she had no ticket, and since it wasn't really Connie there would be no way of identifying the body as Connie. How then would anyone come to the conclusion that the dead body was Connie when no one knew Connie was on that train - and, in fact, no one on that train even knew Connie? This isn't an unenjoyable movie. It's quite touching, really - but it does have a lot of flaws! 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than I Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormy_daze
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So.... two hours before bed, I'm bored.... want to watch something fluffy and pointless, something i won't get too invested in before sleep... something i won't really care if i fall asleep during it... but something i haven't seen in a while. Always been a big fan of Frazer, and decided to watch this for a strange reason -- Frazer is ambidextrous and usually writes with his left hand. But I had this memory of him sitting at a desk writing with his right, and I couldn't remember what the movie is. So I'm trying to figure out what it was.... and then remembered him saying one of the lines of the movie. So I hopped on to IMDb and just as I was typing his name I remembered the movie. Looked for it online for a little while, finally found it via good ol' YouTube. I had expected, going in, a really wretched horrible movie; but had hoped to be at least somewhat entertained by Frazer. The man is really a fantastic actor; He always amuses me. So I thought, what the heck -- I watched The Air I Breathe last night, that was heavy. Let's have a Frazer fluffy movie (that's not Blast from the Past or the Mummy because i've seen them so many times) and had hoped to be, at least, mildly entertained. This is not a brilliant movie. But Frazer and MacLaine are absolutely wonderful and make the movie watchable. I just remember this movie coming out around the same time as While You Were Sleeping. Same basic premise -- following a confusion over identity, a lonely girl lies to family about who she really is because the family takes her in and she feels accepted for the first time in her life. ...This one has a baby in it. So, not original. Let's make that clear. Not believable. Not even that good a movie. However, Frazer and MacLaine are lovely and the movie has its moments -- like when Rikki Lake comes in the room asking MacLaine (who is smoking) who had been smoking in the room and MacLaine half-swallows the lit cigarette to avoid being caught. Or everyone constantly taking MacClaine's alcohol from her as well as her cigs. Cute little moments make it fun-- the Cuban butler getting drunk and dancing in the empty pool over a broken heart is a fun moment too. So, not original, not believable, not really great. But it's not nearly as bad as I remember. Frazer is fab at playing a snarky business man and there is definite chemistry between MacClaine and Frazer that make the whole thing not only watchable, but enjoyable if nothing else for them. A weaker story and someone like Lake who just doesn't have the magical charisma to stand up to someone like Frazer or MacClaine just reminds you what the movie is missing most of the time. If they'd cast someone with more charisma like Sandra Bullock in While You Were Sleeping, I'd have been very interested to see Sandra and Frazer together. Anyway, it's a good fluff, don't expect much and you might enjoy yourself. It's not brilliant, it's not even great, but you know, if you just want a mindless fluff and watch Frazer being snarky it's good enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartwarming fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was not what I expected at all. One hears Ricki Lake's name and automatically assumes that somewhere her pregnant character will burst into song and tease her hair to the heights, but I actually surprisingly enjoyed her in this movie. Yes, she was a little bit of a ham and her age didn't fit the character, but she did a good job playing the little downtrodden city girl who, through a battle with mistaken identity, finds the family she wished she'd always had. As for issues with her attitude and her changes into a society girl, did anyone ever think that maybe she was not that much of a wild child before, and that her acclimation into society was easier than she would have expected? Come on, who on this site doesn't speak a little differently in front of their parents versus their friends? I know I have to give myself a mental warning to try to keep my tongue from slipping when I visit my mom...seriously, everybody does this to some degree, you just don't think about it. I mean, imagine going to church...do you curse in front of your pastor or priest? No. You'd never dream of it. With your friends after a few margaritas? Yes, often something naughty would come out. With that said, Shirley MacLaine and Brendan Fraser are charming, warm and human. She is absolutely the perfect high society misfit leader of a crazy but accepted clan. She's funny, sweet and caring, and smarter than her son or Connie give her credit for. I love, love, love her in this role! Brendan's Hugh/Bill is a marvelous character. The brief moments we see Hugh are sweet, and we unknowingly get a contrast between the two men when we first see the movie. Hugh's free spirit is an instant draw, where Bill's all business attitude at the start takes getting used to. Others on this site have said that it is unconvincing for Bill to have gone from a bit of a cold fish to the warm, funny, in-love guy that he becomes, but I can see the possibilities. If you can put yourself into the character's shoes, here is a man who's just lost his twin brother and been thrown in with the man's wife. He feels some attraction to this pretty, goofy young woman, but this is his DEAD BROTHER'S WIFE! Society would frown upon it...wouldn't't't it? Besides, he's the more sensible twin. He hasn't found that woman who brings out the softer side, so why change? Well...because something about this girl is so endearing, so charming, that he finds himself warming up. It's out of his hands...he can't help it. He's crazy about her. And when he's ready to rat her out to Grace, but Connie tells Grace not to put her in the will, he realizes she really ISN'T there for the money, and that just makes her more lovable. How could he tell Grace and potentially cause another attack? I won't say anymore about what goes on in the movie, as I've done enough damage, but my mom introduced me to this sweet and funny movie, and I was charmed and pleased with the whole film. The ending was satisfying (and I know how the paperwork *flub* is fixable, but if I explain, I'll be saying too much!) and I came away happy, so it's definitely worth giving a shot! Rent it, watch it, don't expect too much, and you'll definitely be satisfied!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rikki Lake tries to look pretty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daveyd_2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I got stuck watching this absolute piece of crap and I am now writing about it to cleanse my soul. Once again I see that without good writers, even great actors, (MacLaine) wished they had called in sick or checked into rehab instead of appearing this achingly painful rehash of twenty different crappy movies already made. And, please, giving a makeover to Rikki Lake is like spraying Febreze on dog crap. You just can't fix that kind of ugly with a haircut and a band aid, sorry. I will never forgive the 'writers' or 'actors' of this petrified turd of a movie. So if this does come on make sure that you have caught up to your significant other and the massive amounts of wine they have drunk to find this celluloid enema entertaining!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, but full of plot holes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tex-42
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mrs. Winterbourne is perhaps the epitome of romantic comedies, in the requirement that you suspend disbelief. It almost commands that you not think about the plot too much, because if you do, the entire movie falls apart. The plot is simple. Connie Doyle is thrown out by her boyfriend when she becomes pregnant, and she ends up on a train with the Winterbournes, a wealthy young couple on their way to Boston. The train derails, and both Winterbournes are killed. However, as Connie was trying on Mrs. Winterbourne's ring at the time of the accident, she is mistaken for her, and her baby for the Winterbourne grandchild. What follows is what always happens in romantic comedies, Connie is taken in by the Winterbourne family and falls in love with the dead Winterbourne's twin brother, who is initially suspicious of her, but then grows to love her. Complications arise, but everything works out in the end. Shirley MacLaine is quite winning at Grace Winterbourne, and Miguel Sandoval steals most of his scenes. The problem is that neither Ricki Lake or Brendan Fraser have much chemistry with each other, and Ricki Lake seems miscast in general. Of course, there are also massive plot holes here, and even in the end, no one really seems to care that the real Mrs. Winterbourne and the real Winterbourne grandchild are off buried somewhere under someone else's name. This is not a bad movie, it's perfectly pleasant, but you really are required to not think about the plot at all to really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why it's a five...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    addylennox
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because Brendan Fraser and Shirley Maclaine make it surprisingly bearable. Ricki Lake, God bless her, was, in a word, miscast; without the strength of Fraser and Maclaine, this movie is a two, at best a three. She's brings no life to the role, no reality. At best, she was an over-actor. At worst... well, she was a bad over-actor. A really, really bad over-actor. Still, for a movie that had so much potential (if not for the sometimes unbelievable -yet entertaining- storyline, then definitely for the two aforementioned lead actors) that was lost beneath the looming shadow that is Lake, I'd watch it again. If it were on cable TV... and if nothing else is on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Add me to the "I liked it" camp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cruztacean
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that those who are most vocally panning "Mrs. Winterbourne" are doing so because they simply don't like the genre of light-hearted romantic comedy. As a comedy, not a drama, and especially as a mistaken identity plot bordering on farce, it isn't *supposed* to resemble a true-to-life documentary, OK? I don't understand those who say Ricki Lake shouldn't have been cast in the female lead role. Why? Because she isn't some A-list skeletal blonde? She played Connie/Patricia admirably, and says that this is the role that made her the proudest to play. It was the first role, she said, where her weight didn't factor into the casting. Should she be sorry she's too "average looking" for some people's Hottiewood tastes? I don't think so. Who says ordinary women don't deserve love and romance too? We'll get the obvious out of the way first. Of COURSE Shirley MacLaine shines as Grace Winterbourne. That lady could play a seashell and be absolutely spellbinding. Of COURSE Brendan Fraser has women swooning over his Hugh/Bill Winterbourne. That's what Brendan Fraser does. It's the smaller roles that make the movie wonderful: Loren Dean is altogether tops as Steven DeCunzo, the abusive womanizing lowlife who fathers Connie's baby and then abandons her to the streets, ultimately getting what he richly deserves. Convincing? Hey, I wanted to smack him myself. Nesbitt Blaisdell stole the scene as the homeless man who befriends a very pregnant Connie. "They pray at you," he warns her about a particular shelter, "but the food's good." Miguel Sandoval is truly enjoyable as Paco, the butler. The only small problem here is that Paco's homosexuality is a trait I gathered only from script, not from character development. In other words, I just never would have guessed Paco was gay without it being said outright. For all I know Sandoval himself could be homosexual (I have no idea) and my saying that he doesn't believably portray one could be hilarious in its irony, but it just doesn't seem that way to me. What do I want, a stereotype? Probably. Farces are usually full of them. Farce is all about exaggeration, and exaggeration relies heavily on stereotype. My favorite scene in the movie has got to be the aftermath of the "Sunny Side of the Street" fiasco. Streetwise teenager tells catty blonde d&eacute;butantes to "f--- off," leaving them flabbergasted with shock. That's funny enough, but then smooth, cultured, filthy rich family matriarch comes along behind her with, "You heard her. F--- off," which was one hundred percent hysterical. There's the scene at the train station where Paco delivers the line, "You are as much a Winterbourne as I am," putting a lump in my throat. I do have trouble with the wedding scene at the end. Connie stops the proceedings (and nearly stops the priest's pulse as well) by unexpectedly saying no. She, Patricia Winterbourne, does *not* take Bill Winterbourne to be her husband. "I, Constance Helen Doyle, do all that." And everything's back on again. My problem is that the marriage license would have read Patricia Winterbourne. They wouldn't have had time to correct it. Which, of course, would invalidate the ceremony, making Grandma Grace Winterbourne's closing line to baby Hughie--"They're married"--a false statement. Oh, no they're not. Also, I am forced to agree that Ricki Lake does NOT look like a character who just turned 18 years old. But hey, if I'm going to be consistent and say that farce isn't supposed to be completely believable, then we can suspend reality for those things too. To summarize, so what if Mrs. Winterbourne is a chick flick? Chicks are half the world's population, guys. Get used to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrible Adaption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    court99
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Contains spoilers* I watched this movie in the middle of a Sunday, having never heard of it and no prior expectations what so ever, I was pleasantly surprised. The concepts which this movie presented were so original and unpredictable, I got the impression that this was a classic and well celebrated American story. It was however the ideas in the story which had me captivated, that and the very attractive Brendan Fraser. It's hard to come by movies which surprise you. Having seen that it was based on the book "I Married a Dead man" by Cornell Woolrich, I managed to find it in the library, and I read it. Twice. It is one of my favourite books, haunting, subtle, brilliantly crafted. Nothing like the movie. I'm sorry to say that "Mrs. Winterbourne" is an atrocious adaption of the book, it butchers all the complex and beautiful themes and even changes the ending. "I Married a Dead man" does not have a happy ending as the movie does, Bill and Patrice are left suspecting one another of the murder and cannot live in happiness. Even when you have not read the book, the movie does not even really work as a stand alone romantic comedy. After having a complete character change which seemed to happen over night, Bill suddenly falls in love with Connie and marries her in what appears to be a few weeks after his brothers death. There is nothing to indicate the passage of time and it left me very confused as a viewer that they would so quickly move on. The book I recommend - it is brilliant. The movie I do not, thank goodness Cornell Woolrich is not alive to see it, it would make him want to cut off his other leg. (He had to have one of his legs removed due to gangrene)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bored on a winter's day or evening? Go find this film, Mrs. Winterbourne!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Connie (Ricki Lake) lost her mother at twelve in Hoboken, New Jersey. Because she did not get along with her father, Connie left NJ at 18 and went to NYC. Unfortunately, she immediately hooked up with a low-life named Steve and became pregnant. Steve was less than thrilled with the news and threw Connie out of the house. Although she works as a waitress for awhile, when her delivery date draws near, she finds herself broke and homeless. The next day , Connie boards a train she thinks is the subway but which turns out to be a railway to Boston. There, she is befriended by handsome, rich Hugh and his new and very pregnant wife Patricia. The train derails. Hugh and Patricia are killed. But, by a twist of fate, Connie is mistaken for Patricia and finds herself and her new baby in a private hospital, as befitting the wife of a member of the rich Winterbourne family. She meets her new mother-in-law (Shirley MacLaine) and her "husband's" twin brother, Bill (Brendan Fraser) and goes home to a posh, Boston mansion, complete with servants. Just how long will she be able to fool everyone into thinking she really is a part of the family? This is a nice little film for the proverbial romcom fan. MacLaine is wonderful as the matriarch of the wealthy family and Fraser is his usual handsome, quirky, affable self. Lake seems a bit miscast as the girl with a big secret but fulfills her role adequately. The sets, costumes, and production values are very high. Do you love improbable plots and unexpected, humorous romance? Make a date to see Mrs. W. and you will be in your element, absolutely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The premise was dated in 1950
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alsation72
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers are not possible for this predictable mawkish mess: its as obvious as it is brainless. This film is a remake of "No Man of Her Own", a 1950 clunker which starred Barbara Stanwyck. Obviously Ricki Lake is no Barbara Stanwyck, but in this film she comes across as conniving, irritating and unlike-able. Barefoot and pregnant, she is mistaken for Mrs. Winterbourne's daughter in law. This badly- concocted case of mistaken identity basically drives the weak story. Apparently despite a wedding and impending birth, Mrs Winterbourne has never seen even a picture of her son's wife. Did Shirley MacLain read the script before she signed up? Ricki Lake comes off as a tubby little tomboy; as a leading lady in a feature film she makes a great talk-show host. She says "ain't" a lot, just so we remember how impoverished the character was. The romance that blossoms between her and Fraser's character is not believable; together they have zero chemistry. When the jig is up and the deception is uncovered the family instantly seems to accept it because they are just so darned lovable. Maybe if they had used someone like Sandra Bullock and really made an effort to update this stinker of a storyline ... maybe then it might have been bearable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touching But Quite Flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My first bit of confusion was over exactly where this movie wanted to go. I imagined it as a romantic comedy of sorts, and yet from the very beginning it was really quite heavy, dealing as it did with young Connie (Rikki Lake) being homeless, then meeting up with a sleazebag and then being tossed out by him when he gets her pregnant. I really wasn't feeling much fun at that point in the movie. Then mistaken identity turns into deliberate deceit on Connie's part (although I understand it wasn't malicious.) Once she gets taken in by the Winterbourne's after the train wreck that kills their son and his wife (whom the family has never met, and whom Connie is mistaken for) the only character who really made sense to me was Bill (Brendan Fraser), who seemed appropriately suspicious of her given the circumstances. True, he was ridiculously obnoxious, but his suspicion was bang on, except that he then, for no obvious reason that I saw, fell head over heels in love with her, letting go of all his suspicions and deciding to marry her! Where did that come from? There are some moments of fun in this. Shirley MacLaine (as the matriarch of the Winterbourne clan) was probably the best part of the movie and provided much of the comedy, and the closing scenes (as everyone tries to protect Connie/Patricia) was quite touching, as was the point that the Winterbournes became the family she never had. There was a nice feel to that, especially because we know that Connie isn't out for the family's money, but just wants the sense of family for herself and even more for her son. There was one huge inconsistency here that just made everything else implausible, though. Bill finally figures out what's going on because he sees "Patricia" sign "Connie Doyle" on a check, and investigates who Connie Doyle is. He gets back a report that Connie and her unborn baby were killed in the train wreck (it was, of course, the real Patricia and her unborn baby who were killed.) How would he get that report? Connie wasn't supposed to be on that train. She got swept into it by a huge crowd of people, she had no ticket, and since it wasn't really Connie there would be no way of identifying the body as Connie. How then would anyone come to the conclusion that the dead body was Connie when no one knew Connie was on that train - and, in fact, no one on that train even knew Connie? This isn't an unenjoyable movie. It's quite touching, really - but it does have a lot of flaws! 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than I Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormy_daze
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So.... two hours before bed, I'm bored.... want to watch something fluffy and pointless, something i won't get too invested in before sleep... something i won't really care if i fall asleep during it... but something i haven't seen in a while. Always been a big fan of Frazer, and decided to watch this for a strange reason -- Frazer is ambidextrous and usually writes with his left hand. But I had this memory of him sitting at a desk writing with his right, and I couldn't remember what the movie is. So I'm trying to figure out what it was.... and then remembered him saying one of the lines of the movie. So I hopped on to IMDb and just as I was typing his name I remembered the movie. Looked for it online for a little while, finally found it via good ol' YouTube. I had expected, going in, a really wretched horrible movie; but had hoped to be at least somewhat entertained by Frazer. The man is really a fantastic actor; He always amuses me. So I thought, what the heck -- I watched The Air I Breathe last night, that was heavy. Let's have a Frazer fluffy movie (that's not Blast from the Past or the Mummy because i've seen them so many times) and had hoped to be, at least, mildly entertained. This is not a brilliant movie. But Frazer and MacLaine are absolutely wonderful and make the movie watchable. I just remember this movie coming out around the same time as While You Were Sleeping. Same basic premise -- following a confusion over identity, a lonely girl lies to family about who she really is because the family takes her in and she feels accepted for the first time in her life. ...This one has a baby in it. So, not original. Let's make that clear. Not believable. Not even that good a movie. However, Frazer and MacLaine are lovely and the movie has its moments -- like when Rikki Lake comes in the room asking MacLaine (who is smoking) who had been smoking in the room and MacLaine half-swallows the lit cigarette to avoid being caught. Or everyone constantly taking MacClaine's alcohol from her as well as her cigs. Cute little moments make it fun-- the Cuban butler getting drunk and dancing in the empty pool over a broken heart is a fun moment too. So, not original, not believable, not really great. But it's not nearly as bad as I remember. Frazer is fab at playing a snarky business man and there is definite chemistry between MacClaine and Frazer that make the whole thing not only watchable, but enjoyable if nothing else for them. A weaker story and someone like Lake who just doesn't have the magical charisma to stand up to someone like Frazer or MacClaine just reminds you what the movie is missing most of the time. If they'd cast someone with more charisma like Sandra Bullock in While You Were Sleeping, I'd have been very interested to see Sandra and Frazer together. Anyway, it's a good fluff, don't expect much and you might enjoy yourself. It's not brilliant, it's not even great, but you know, if you just want a mindless fluff and watch Frazer being snarky it's good enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartwarming fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was not what I expected at all. One hears Ricki Lake's name and automatically assumes that somewhere her pregnant character will burst into song and tease her hair to the heights, but I actually surprisingly enjoyed her in this movie. Yes, she was a little bit of a ham and her age didn't fit the character, but she did a good job playing the little downtrodden city girl who, through a battle with mistaken identity, finds the family she wished she'd always had. As for issues with her attitude and her changes into a society girl, did anyone ever think that maybe she was not that much of a wild child before, and that her acclimation into society was easier than she would have expected? Come on, who on this site doesn't speak a little differently in front of their parents versus their friends? I know I have to give myself a mental warning to try to keep my tongue from slipping when I visit my mom...seriously, everybody does this to some degree, you just don't think about it. I mean, imagine going to church...do you curse in front of your pastor or priest? No. You'd never dream of it. With your friends after a few margaritas? Yes, often something naughty would come out. With that said, Shirley MacLaine and Brendan Fraser are charming, warm and human. She is absolutely the perfect high society misfit leader of a crazy but accepted clan. She's funny, sweet and caring, and smarter than her son or Connie give her credit for. I love, love, love her in this role! Brendan's Hugh/Bill is a marvelous character. The brief moments we see Hugh are sweet, and we unknowingly get a contrast between the two men when we first see the movie. Hugh's free spirit is an instant draw, where Bill's all business attitude at the start takes getting used to. Others on this site have said that it is unconvincing for Bill to have gone from a bit of a cold fish to the warm, funny, in-love guy that he becomes, but I can see the possibilities. If you can put yourself into the character's shoes, here is a man who's just lost his twin brother and been thrown in with the man's wife. He feels some attraction to this pretty, goofy young woman, but this is his DEAD BROTHER'S WIFE! Society would frown upon it...wouldn't't't it? Besides, he's the more sensible twin. He hasn't found that woman who brings out the softer side, so why change? Well...because something about this girl is so endearing, so charming, that he finds himself warming up. It's out of his hands...he can't help it. He's crazy about her. And when he's ready to rat her out to Grace, but Connie tells Grace not to put her in the will, he realizes she really ISN'T there for the money, and that just makes her more lovable. How could he tell Grace and potentially cause another attack? I won't say anymore about what goes on in the movie, as I've done enough damage, but my mom introduced me to this sweet and funny movie, and I was charmed and pleased with the whole film. The ending was satisfying (and I know how the paperwork *flub* is fixable, but if I explain, I'll be saying too much!) and I came away happy, so it's definitely worth giving a shot! Rent it, watch it, don't expect too much, and you'll definitely be satisfied!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rikki Lake tries to look pretty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daveyd_2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I got stuck watching this absolute piece of crap and I am now writing about it to cleanse my soul. Once again I see that without good writers, even great actors, (MacLaine) wished they had called in sick or checked into rehab instead of appearing this achingly painful rehash of twenty different crappy movies already made. And, please, giving a makeover to Rikki Lake is like spraying Febreze on dog crap. You just can't fix that kind of ugly with a haircut and a band aid, sorry. I will never forgive the 'writers' or 'actors' of this petrified turd of a movie. So if this does come on make sure that you have caught up to your significant other and the massive amounts of wine they have drunk to find this celluloid enema entertaining!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, but full of plot holes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tex-42
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mrs. Winterbourne is perhaps the epitome of romantic comedies, in the requirement that you suspend disbelief. It almost commands that you not think about the plot too much, because if you do, the entire movie falls apart. The plot is simple. Connie Doyle is thrown out by her boyfriend when she becomes pregnant, and she ends up on a train with the Winterbournes, a wealthy young couple on their way to Boston. The train derails, and both Winterbournes are killed. However, as Connie was trying on Mrs. Winterbourne's ring at the time of the accident, she is mistaken for her, and her baby for the Winterbourne grandchild. What follows is what always happens in romantic comedies, Connie is taken in by the Winterbourne family and falls in love with the dead Winterbourne's twin brother, who is initially suspicious of her, but then grows to love her. Complications arise, but everything works out in the end. Shirley MacLaine is quite winning at Grace Winterbourne, and Miguel Sandoval steals most of his scenes. The problem is that neither Ricki Lake or Brendan Fraser have much chemistry with each other, and Ricki Lake seems miscast in general. Of course, there are also massive plot holes here, and even in the end, no one really seems to care that the real Mrs. Winterbourne and the real Winterbourne grandchild are off buried somewhere under someone else's name. This is not a bad movie, it's perfectly pleasant, but you really are required to not think about the plot at all to really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why it's a five...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    addylennox
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because Brendan Fraser and Shirley Maclaine make it surprisingly bearable. Ricki Lake, God bless her, was, in a word, miscast; without the strength of Fraser and Maclaine, this movie is a two, at best a three. She's brings no life to the role, no reality. At best, she was an over-actor. At worst... well, she was a bad over-actor. A really, really bad over-actor. Still, for a movie that had so much potential (if not for the sometimes unbelievable -yet entertaining- storyline, then definitely for the two aforementioned lead actors) that was lost beneath the looming shadow that is Lake, I'd watch it again. If it were on cable TV... and if nothing else is on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Add me to the "I liked it" camp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cruztacean
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that those who are most vocally panning "Mrs. Winterbourne" are doing so because they simply don't like the genre of light-hearted romantic comedy. As a comedy, not a drama, and especially as a mistaken identity plot bordering on farce, it isn't *supposed* to resemble a true-to-life documentary, OK? I don't understand those who say Ricki Lake shouldn't have been cast in the female lead role. Why? Because she isn't some A-list skeletal blonde? She played Connie/Patricia admirably, and says that this is the role that made her the proudest to play. It was the first role, she said, where her weight didn't factor into the casting. Should she be sorry she's too "average looking" for some people's Hottiewood tastes? I don't think so. Who says ordinary women don't deserve love and romance too? We'll get the obvious out of the way first. Of COURSE Shirley MacLaine shines as Grace Winterbourne. That lady could play a seashell and be absolutely spellbinding. Of COURSE Brendan Fraser has women swooning over his Hugh/Bill Winterbourne. That's what Brendan Fraser does. It's the smaller roles that make the movie wonderful: Loren Dean is altogether tops as Steven DeCunzo, the abusive womanizing lowlife who fathers Connie's baby and then abandons her to the streets, ultimately getting what he richly deserves. Convincing? Hey, I wanted to smack him myself. Nesbitt Blaisdell stole the scene as the homeless man who befriends a very pregnant Connie. "They pray at you," he warns her about a particular shelter, "but the food's good." Miguel Sandoval is truly enjoyable as Paco, the butler. The only small problem here is that Paco's homosexuality is a trait I gathered only from script, not from character development. In other words, I just never would have guessed Paco was gay without it being said outright. For all I know Sandoval himself could be homosexual (I have no idea) and my saying that he doesn't believably portray one could be hilarious in its irony, but it just doesn't seem that way to me. What do I want, a stereotype? Probably. Farces are usually full of them. Farce is all about exaggeration, and exaggeration relies heavily on stereotype. My favorite scene in the movie has got to be the aftermath of the "Sunny Side of the Street" fiasco. Streetwise teenager tells catty blonde d&eacute;butantes to "f--- off," leaving them flabbergasted with shock. That's funny enough, but then smooth, cultured, filthy rich family matriarch comes along behind her with, "You heard her. F--- off," which was one hundred percent hysterical. There's the scene at the train station where Paco delivers the line, "You are as much a Winterbourne as I am," putting a lump in my throat. I do have trouble with the wedding scene at the end. Connie stops the proceedings (and nearly stops the priest's pulse as well) by unexpectedly saying no. She, Patricia Winterbourne, does *not* take Bill Winterbourne to be her husband. "I, Constance Helen Doyle, do all that." And everything's back on again. My problem is that the marriage license would have read Patricia Winterbourne. They wouldn't have had time to correct it. Which, of course, would invalidate the ceremony, making Grandma Grace Winterbourne's closing line to baby Hughie--"They're married"--a false statement. Oh, no they're not. Also, I am forced to agree that Ricki Lake does NOT look like a character who just turned 18 years old. But hey, if I'm going to be consistent and say that farce isn't supposed to be completely believable, then we can suspend reality for those things too. To summarize, so what if Mrs. Winterbourne is a chick flick? Chicks are half the world's population, guys. Get used to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrible Adaption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    court99
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Contains spoilers* I watched this movie in the middle of a Sunday, having never heard of it and no prior expectations what so ever, I was pleasantly surprised. The concepts which this movie presented were so original and unpredictable, I got the impression that this was a classic and well celebrated American story. It was however the ideas in the story which had me captivated, that and the very attractive Brendan Fraser. It's hard to come by movies which surprise you. Having seen that it was based on the book "I Married a Dead man" by Cornell Woolrich, I managed to find it in the library, and I read it. Twice. It is one of my favourite books, haunting, subtle, brilliantly crafted. Nothing like the movie. I'm sorry to say that "Mrs. Winterbourne" is an atrocious adaption of the book, it butchers all the complex and beautiful themes and even changes the ending. "I Married a Dead man" does not have a happy ending as the movie does, Bill and Patrice are left suspecting one another of the murder and cannot live in happiness. Even when you have not read the book, the movie does not even really work as a stand alone romantic comedy. After having a complete character change which seemed to happen over night, Bill suddenly falls in love with Connie and marries her in what appears to be a few weeks after his brothers death. There is nothing to indicate the passage of time and it left me very confused as a viewer that they would so quickly move on. The book I recommend - it is brilliant. The movie I do not, thank goodness Cornell Woolrich is not alive to see it, it would make him want to cut off his other leg. (He had to have one of his legs removed due to gangrene)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bored on a winter's day or evening? Go find this film, Mrs. Winterbourne!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Connie (Ricki Lake) lost her mother at twelve in Hoboken, New Jersey. Because she did not get along with her father, Connie left NJ at 18 and went to NYC. Unfortunately, she immediately hooked up with a low-life named Steve and became pregnant. Steve was less than thrilled with the news and threw Connie out of the house. Although she works as a waitress for awhile, when her delivery date draws near, she finds herself broke and homeless. The next day , Connie boards a train she thinks is the subway but which turns out to be a railway to Boston. There, she is befriended by handsome, rich Hugh and his new and very pregnant wife Patricia. The train derails. Hugh and Patricia are killed. But, by a twist of fate, Connie is mistaken for Patricia and finds herself and her new baby in a private hospital, as befitting the wife of a member of the rich Winterbourne family. She meets her new mother-in-law (Shirley MacLaine) and her "husband's" twin brother, Bill (Brendan Fraser) and goes home to a posh, Boston mansion, complete with servants. Just how long will she be able to fool everyone into thinking she really is a part of the family? This is a nice little film for the proverbial romcom fan. MacLaine is wonderful as the matriarch of the wealthy family and Fraser is his usual handsome, quirky, affable self. Lake seems a bit miscast as the girl with a big secret but fulfills her role adequately. The sets, costumes, and production values are very high. Do you love improbable plots and unexpected, humorous romance? Make a date to see Mrs. W. and you will be in your element, absolutely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The premise was dated in 1950
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alsation72
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers are not possible for this predictable mawkish mess: its as obvious as it is brainless. This film is a remake of "No Man of Her Own", a 1950 clunker which starred Barbara Stanwyck. Obviously Ricki Lake is no Barbara Stanwyck, but in this film she comes across as conniving, irritating and unlike-able. Barefoot and pregnant, she is mistaken for Mrs. Winterbourne's daughter in law. This badly- concocted case of mistaken identity basically drives the weak story. Apparently despite a wedding and impending birth, Mrs Winterbourne has never seen even a picture of her son's wife. Did Shirley MacLain read the script before she signed up? Ricki Lake comes off as a tubby little tomboy; as a leading lady in a feature film she makes a great talk-show host. She says "ain't" a lot, just so we remember how impoverished the character was. The romance that blossoms between her and Fraser's character is not believable; together they have zero chemistry. When the jig is up and the deception is uncovered the family instantly seems to accept it because they are just so darned lovable. Maybe if they had used someone like Sandra Bullock and really made an effort to update this stinker of a storyline ... maybe then it might have been bearable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touching But Quite Flawed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My first bit of confusion was over exactly where this movie wanted to go. I imagined it as a romantic comedy of sorts, and yet from the very beginning it was really quite heavy, dealing as it did with young Connie (Rikki Lake) being homeless, then meeting up with a sleazebag and then being tossed out by him when he gets her pregnant. I really wasn't feeling much fun at that point in the movie. Then mistaken identity turns into deliberate deceit on Connie's part (although I understand it wasn't malicious.) Once she gets taken in by the Winterbourne's after the train wreck that kills their son and his wife (whom the family has never met, and whom Connie is mistaken for) the only character who really made sense to me was Bill (Brendan Fraser), who seemed appropriately suspicious of her given the circumstances. True, he was ridiculously obnoxious, but his suspicion was bang on, except that he then, for no obvious reason that I saw, fell head over heels in love with her, letting go of all his suspicions and deciding to marry her! Where did that come from? There are some moments of fun in this. Shirley MacLaine (as the matriarch of the Winterbourne clan) was probably the best part of the movie and provided much of the comedy, and the closing scenes (as everyone tries to protect Connie/Patricia) was quite touching, as was the point that the Winterbournes became the family she never had. There was a nice feel to that, especially because we know that Connie isn't out for the family's money, but just wants the sense of family for herself and even more for her son. There was one huge inconsistency here that just made everything else implausible, though. Bill finally figures out what's going on because he sees "Patricia" sign "Connie Doyle" on a check, and investigates who Connie Doyle is. He gets back a report that Connie and her unborn baby were killed in the train wreck (it was, of course, the real Patricia and her unborn baby who were killed.) How would he get that report? Connie wasn't supposed to be on that train. She got swept into it by a huge crowd of people, she had no ticket, and since it wasn't really Connie there would be no way of identifying the body as Connie. How then would anyone come to the conclusion that the dead body was Connie when no one knew Connie was on that train - and, in fact, no one on that train even knew Connie? This isn't an unenjoyable movie. It's quite touching, really - but it does have a lot of flaws! 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better than I Remember
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormy_daze
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So.... two hours before bed, I'm bored.... want to watch something fluffy and pointless, something i won't get too invested in before sleep... something i won't really care if i fall asleep during it... but something i haven't seen in a while. Always been a big fan of Frazer, and decided to watch this for a strange reason -- Frazer is ambidextrous and usually writes with his left hand. But I had this memory of him sitting at a desk writing with his right, and I couldn't remember what the movie is. So I'm trying to figure out what it was.... and then remembered him saying one of the lines of the movie. So I hopped on to IMDb and just as I was typing his name I remembered the movie. Looked for it online for a little while, finally found it via good ol' YouTube. I had expected, going in, a really wretched horrible movie; but had hoped to be at least somewhat entertained by Frazer. The man is really a fantastic actor; He always amuses me. So I thought, what the heck -- I watched The Air I Breathe last night, that was heavy. Let's have a Frazer fluffy movie (that's not Blast from the Past or the Mummy because i've seen them so many times) and had hoped to be, at least, mildly entertained. This is not a brilliant movie. But Frazer and MacLaine are absolutely wonderful and make the movie watchable. I just remember this movie coming out around the same time as While You Were Sleeping. Same basic premise -- following a confusion over identity, a lonely girl lies to family about who she really is because the family takes her in and she feels accepted for the first time in her life. ...This one has a baby in it. So, not original. Let's make that clear. Not believable. Not even that good a movie. However, Frazer and MacLaine are lovely and the movie has its moments -- like when Rikki Lake comes in the room asking MacLaine (who is smoking) who had been smoking in the room and MacLaine half-swallows the lit cigarette to avoid being caught. Or everyone constantly taking MacClaine's alcohol from her as well as her cigs. Cute little moments make it fun-- the Cuban butler getting drunk and dancing in the empty pool over a broken heart is a fun moment too. So, not original, not believable, not really great. But it's not nearly as bad as I remember. Frazer is fab at playing a snarky business man and there is definite chemistry between MacClaine and Frazer that make the whole thing not only watchable, but enjoyable if nothing else for them. A weaker story and someone like Lake who just doesn't have the magical charisma to stand up to someone like Frazer or MacClaine just reminds you what the movie is missing most of the time. If they'd cast someone with more charisma like Sandra Bullock in While You Were Sleeping, I'd have been very interested to see Sandra and Frazer together. Anyway, it's a good fluff, don't expect much and you might enjoy yourself. It's not brilliant, it's not even great, but you know, if you just want a mindless fluff and watch Frazer being snarky it's good enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Heartwarming fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie was not what I expected at all. One hears Ricki Lake's name and automatically assumes that somewhere her pregnant character will burst into song and tease her hair to the heights, but I actually surprisingly enjoyed her in this movie. Yes, she was a little bit of a ham and her age didn't fit the character, but she did a good job playing the little downtrodden city girl who, through a battle with mistaken identity, finds the family she wished she'd always had. As for issues with her attitude and her changes into a society girl, did anyone ever think that maybe she was not that much of a wild child before, and that her acclimation into society was easier than she would have expected? Come on, who on this site doesn't speak a little differently in front of their parents versus their friends? I know I have to give myself a mental warning to try to keep my tongue from slipping when I visit my mom...seriously, everybody does this to some degree, you just don't think about it. I mean, imagine going to church...do you curse in front of your pastor or priest? No. You'd never dream of it. With your friends after a few margaritas? Yes, often something naughty would come out. With that said, Shirley MacLaine and Brendan Fraser are charming, warm and human. She is absolutely the perfect high society misfit leader of a crazy but accepted clan. She's funny, sweet and caring, and smarter than her son or Connie give her credit for. I love, love, love her in this role! Brendan's Hugh/Bill is a marvelous character. The brief moments we see Hugh are sweet, and we unknowingly get a contrast between the two men when we first see the movie. Hugh's free spirit is an instant draw, where Bill's all business attitude at the start takes getting used to. Others on this site have said that it is unconvincing for Bill to have gone from a bit of a cold fish to the warm, funny, in-love guy that he becomes, but I can see the possibilities. If you can put yourself into the character's shoes, here is a man who's just lost his twin brother and been thrown in with the man's wife. He feels some attraction to this pretty, goofy young woman, but this is his DEAD BROTHER'S WIFE! Society would frown upon it...wouldn't't't it? Besides, he's the more sensible twin. He hasn't found that woman who brings out the softer side, so why change? Well...because something about this girl is so endearing, so charming, that he finds himself warming up. It's out of his hands...he can't help it. He's crazy about her. And when he's ready to rat her out to Grace, but Connie tells Grace not to put her in the will, he realizes she really ISN'T there for the money, and that just makes her more lovable. How could he tell Grace and potentially cause another attack? I won't say anymore about what goes on in the movie, as I've done enough damage, but my mom introduced me to this sweet and funny movie, and I was charmed and pleased with the whole film. The ending was satisfying (and I know how the paperwork *flub* is fixable, but if I explain, I'll be saying too much!) and I came away happy, so it's definitely worth giving a shot! Rent it, watch it, don't expect too much, and you'll definitely be satisfied!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rikki Lake tries to look pretty
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daveyd_2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I got stuck watching this absolute piece of crap and I am now writing about it to cleanse my soul. Once again I see that without good writers, even great actors, (MacLaine) wished they had called in sick or checked into rehab instead of appearing this achingly painful rehash of twenty different crappy movies already made. And, please, giving a makeover to Rikki Lake is like spraying Febreze on dog crap. You just can't fix that kind of ugly with a haircut and a band aid, sorry. I will never forgive the 'writers' or 'actors' of this petrified turd of a movie. So if this does come on make sure that you have caught up to your significant other and the massive amounts of wine they have drunk to find this celluloid enema entertaining!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sweet, but full of plot holes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tex-42
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mrs. Winterbourne is perhaps the epitome of romantic comedies, in the requirement that you suspend disbelief. It almost commands that you not think about the plot too much, because if you do, the entire movie falls apart. The plot is simple. Connie Doyle is thrown out by her boyfriend when she becomes pregnant, and she ends up on a train with the Winterbournes, a wealthy young couple on their way to Boston. The train derails, and both Winterbournes are killed. However, as Connie was trying on Mrs. Winterbourne's ring at the time of the accident, she is mistaken for her, and her baby for the Winterbourne grandchild. What follows is what always happens in romantic comedies, Connie is taken in by the Winterbourne family and falls in love with the dead Winterbourne's twin brother, who is initially suspicious of her, but then grows to love her. Complications arise, but everything works out in the end. Shirley MacLaine is quite winning at Grace Winterbourne, and Miguel Sandoval steals most of his scenes. The problem is that neither Ricki Lake or Brendan Fraser have much chemistry with each other, and Ricki Lake seems miscast in general. Of course, there are also massive plot holes here, and even in the end, no one really seems to care that the real Mrs. Winterbourne and the real Winterbourne grandchild are off buried somewhere under someone else's name. This is not a bad movie, it's perfectly pleasant, but you really are required to not think about the plot at all to really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why it's a five...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    addylennox
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because Brendan Fraser and Shirley Maclaine make it surprisingly bearable. Ricki Lake, God bless her, was, in a word, miscast; without the strength of Fraser and Maclaine, this movie is a two, at best a three. She's brings no life to the role, no reality. At best, she was an over-actor. At worst... well, she was a bad over-actor. A really, really bad over-actor. Still, for a movie that had so much potential (if not for the sometimes unbelievable -yet entertaining- storyline, then definitely for the two aforementioned lead actors) that was lost beneath the looming shadow that is Lake, I'd watch it again. If it were on cable TV... and if nothing else is on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Add me to the "I liked it" camp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cruztacean
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I believe that those who are most vocally panning "Mrs. Winterbourne" are doing so because they simply don't like the genre of light-hearted romantic comedy. As a comedy, not a drama, and especially as a mistaken identity plot bordering on farce, it isn't *supposed* to resemble a true-to-life documentary, OK? I don't understand those who say Ricki Lake shouldn't have been cast in the female lead role. Why? Because she isn't some A-list skeletal blonde? She played Connie/Patricia admirably, and says that this is the role that made her the proudest to play. It was the first role, she said, where her weight didn't factor into the casting. Should she be sorry she's too "average looking" for some people's Hottiewood tastes? I don't think so. Who says ordinary women don't deserve love and romance too? We'll get the obvious out of the way first. Of COURSE Shirley MacLaine shines as Grace Winterbourne. That lady could play a seashell and be absolutely spellbinding. Of COURSE Brendan Fraser has women swooning over his Hugh/Bill Winterbourne. That's what Brendan Fraser does. It's the smaller roles that make the movie wonderful: Loren Dean is altogether tops as Steven DeCunzo, the abusive womanizing lowlife who fathers Connie's baby and then abandons her to the streets, ultimately getting what he richly deserves. Convincing? Hey, I wanted to smack him myself. Nesbitt Blaisdell stole the scene as the homeless man who befriends a very pregnant Connie. "They pray at you," he warns her about a particular shelter, "but the food's good." Miguel Sandoval is truly enjoyable as Paco, the butler. The only small problem here is that Paco's homosexuality is a trait I gathered only from script, not from character development. In other words, I just never would have guessed Paco was gay without it being said outright. For all I know Sandoval himself could be homosexual (I have no idea) and my saying that he doesn't believably portray one could be hilarious in its irony, but it just doesn't seem that way to me. What do I want, a stereotype? Probably. Farces are usually full of them. Farce is all about exaggeration, and exaggeration relies heavily on stereotype. My favorite scene in the movie has got to be the aftermath of the "Sunny Side of the Street" fiasco. Streetwise teenager tells catty blonde d&eacute;butantes to "f--- off," leaving them flabbergasted with shock. That's funny enough, but then smooth, cultured, filthy rich family matriarch comes along behind her with, "You heard her. F--- off," which was one hundred percent hysterical. There's the scene at the train station where Paco delivers the line, "You are as much a Winterbourne as I am," putting a lump in my throat. I do have trouble with the wedding scene at the end. Connie stops the proceedings (and nearly stops the priest's pulse as well) by unexpectedly saying no. She, Patricia Winterbourne, does *not* take Bill Winterbourne to be her husband. "I, Constance Helen Doyle, do all that." And everything's back on again. My problem is that the marriage license would have read Patricia Winterbourne. They wouldn't have had time to correct it. Which, of course, would invalidate the ceremony, making Grandma Grace Winterbourne's closing line to baby Hughie--"They're married"--a false statement. Oh, no they're not. Also, I am forced to agree that Ricki Lake does NOT look like a character who just turned 18 years old. But hey, if I'm going to be consistent and say that farce isn't supposed to be completely believable, then we can suspend reality for those things too. To summarize, so what if Mrs. Winterbourne is a chick flick? Chicks are half the world's population, guys. Get used to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Terrible Adaption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    court99
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *Contains spoilers* I watched this movie in the middle of a Sunday, having never heard of it and no prior expectations what so ever, I was pleasantly surprised. The concepts which this movie presented were so original and unpredictable, I got the impression that this was a classic and well celebrated American story. It was however the ideas in the story which had me captivated, that and the very attractive Brendan Fraser. It's hard to come by movies which surprise you. Having seen that it was based on the book "I Married a Dead man" by Cornell Woolrich, I managed to find it in the library, and I read it. Twice. It is one of my favourite books, haunting, subtle, brilliantly crafted. Nothing like the movie. I'm sorry to say that "Mrs. Winterbourne" is an atrocious adaption of the book, it butchers all the complex and beautiful themes and even changes the ending. "I Married a Dead man" does not have a happy ending as the movie does, Bill and Patrice are left suspecting one another of the murder and cannot live in happiness. Even when you have not read the book, the movie does not even really work as a stand alone romantic comedy. After having a complete character change which seemed to happen over night, Bill suddenly falls in love with Connie and marries her in what appears to be a few weeks after his brothers death. There is nothing to indicate the passage of time and it left me very confused as a viewer that they would so quickly move on. The book I recommend - it is brilliant. The movie I do not, thank goodness Cornell Woolrich is not alive to see it, it would make him want to cut off his other leg. (He had to have one of his legs removed due to gangrene)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bored on a winter's day or evening? Go find this film, Mrs. Winterbourne!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Connie (Ricki Lake) lost her mother at twelve in Hoboken, New Jersey. Because she did not get along with her father, Connie left NJ at 18 and went to NYC. Unfortunately, she immediately hooked up with a low-life named Steve and became pregnant. Steve was less than thrilled with the news and threw Connie out of the house. Although she works as a waitress for awhile, when her delivery date draws near, she finds herself broke and homeless. The next day , Connie boards a train she thinks is the subway but which turns out to be a railway to Boston. There, she is befriended by handsome, rich Hugh and his new and very pregnant wife Patricia. The train derails. Hugh and Patricia are killed. But, by a twist of fate, Connie is mistaken for Patricia and finds herself and her new baby in a private hospital, as befitting the wife of a member of the rich Winterbourne family. She meets her new mother-in-law (Shirley MacLaine) and her "husband's" twin brother, Bill (Brendan Fraser) and goes home to a posh, Boston mansion, complete with servants. Just how long will she be able to fool everyone into thinking she really is a part of the family? This is a nice little film for the proverbial romcom fan. MacLaine is wonderful as the matriarch of the wealthy family and Fraser is his usual handsome, quirky, affable self. Lake seems a bit miscast as the girl with a big secret but fulfills her role adequately. The sets, costumes, and production values are very high. Do you love improbable plots and unexpected, humorous romance? Make a date to see Mrs. W. and you will be in your element, absolutely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
