<filme>
 <id>
  838
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0093229
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1985
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Huang jia shi jie
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   gunfight
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gun fu
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gun battle
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   martial arts
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   slow motion scene
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Corey Yuen
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   James Clouse
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Barry Wong
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Michelle Yeoh
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Cynthia Rothrock
  </ator>
  <ator>
   John Sham
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Movie Already Is A Legend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This to me is the best movie Cynthia Rothrock ever made, and one of the best movie from Michelle Yeoh's early career. The final action scene involving the two guarantees it. This was one of very early D&B movie studio's production. D&B movies brought more modern style to Hong Kong movies, and it's clear from this movie that it's years ahead compared other action movies of the time in terms of content, the fashion the actors are wearing, the modern looking background, the speed the scene moves, and the three dimensional shooting. Hong Kong movies in few short years following this movie makes a stellar leap in terms of quality, but you can already see most of the elements in this movie. Cynthia Rothrock plays inspector Carrie Morris from Scotland Yard, and Michelle Yeoh plays inspector Ng of Hong Kong police department. They're after a microfilm that was stolen by two small time crooks. The microfilm contains the names of the ones who are involved in criminal activity. The real bad guy who's got most to lose from the microfilm is Mr. Tin and is willing to go any extent to get the microfilm. Eventually, the small time crook, Yeoh, and Rothrock ends up in Tin's house, and massive fight ensues. The number of casts appearing in this movie is amazing, and this helps to weave many threads in this story. The story has comedic touch, serious touch, and lot of action depending on who's playing the part of the story. It's definitely not one dimensional, and is entertaining to watch. The production is classy, and has high quality looks to it. This movie started the "Huang Ka" (Royal) movie craze in Hong Kong, and many movies crowning these two characters were made. The movie has confusing number of titles like "Super Cops", "In the line of Duty", "Yes Madam", "Ultra Force", which actually makes finding this movie difficult. The final fight scenes appears in many specials that chronicles Hong Kong martial arts movies to this day. The amazing physical ability of Michelle Yeoh, and Cynthia Rothrock launched them into superstar status. This is one of the best martial arts themed movie to come out of Hong Kong, and is highly recommended for viewing whether you're a martial arts movie fan or not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit too much cringe-worthy Chinese comedy, but the quality of martial arts more than made up for it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Tokmenko
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Moments of slapstick comedy are nothing but expected when Sammmo Hung makes an appearance, however it may be a touch overdone here in this sub-genre defining "femme-fatale" flick. Two female officers of the law present themselves as hard-hitting women which should be shown absolute respect, but another group of protagonists weighs them down and the overall result is more comedic than dramatic. There simply wasn't enough Michelle Yeoh and Cynthia Rothrock on-screen to provide sufficient character development, but even at a basic level it works to support the crime investigation story (which is also very simple). A reel of film ends up being passed around Hong Kong as a triad corporation tries to obtain and destroy it in order to avoid the legal consequences attached. Meanwhile, a group of idiotic underdogs inadvertently become mixed up with the triad affair, as well as our two female hero cops Yeoh and Rothrock. The adventure is goofy yet fun, and the finale will take your breath away in terms of martial arts prowess. This is an iconic movie of both Hong Kong action cinema and the femme- fatale sub genre, and if your mildly interested in either you'll have a great time with this one. - 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michelle Yeoh's first starring role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As with most original movies that create a long series of sequels, this one is good. Basically a couple of small time crooks who are scrapping money to get their master out of a nursing home get caught up in a fraudulent business. They accidentally steal a micro-fiche upon which a false contract, which will destroy the credibility of a major corporation, has been printed. Unfortunately this corporation wants it destroyed and thus they find nasty hit men after them. This movie stars Cythia Kahn, the star of the In the Line of Duty movies, but it also stars Cynthia Rockwell, an American martial artist. From what I remember of her, she was an attractive woman that could kick butt, but in this movie she is much more masculine, and scary. Both Cynthias come across as very competent and are two women which you do not want to mess with. The movie opens with action and the action goes right through to the end, and the suspense is gripping. It all winds up to a movie where there is a shallow victory because even though the bad guys have lost, the good guys have not won. It is a movie that is not willing to kill off major characters and to show that even though violence may solve problems, it will create a lot more. The axiom that violence never solves anything is not entirely true. Rather it should be that violence creates more problems than it solves. For an action movie, this is great, but if you are wanting a simple movie where the good guys beat the bad guys and come out on top, then this is not that type of movie. It is a movie where things go from bad to worse, and the end comes about from a final act of desperation to make sure that justice is done. The one thing that I got from reading the bible tonight is that even if somebody seems to have everything, that will not last forever. The thing is that God will bring about their destruction, not us, so to attempt to speed up the inevitable will not solve anything. Here all of the evidence may have been destroyed, the bad guy will have to die sometime, and when he dies he will learn the truth of what life is really all about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay actioner if you don't think too much
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hong Kong action movies in the 80s were made on such short production schedules that calling them 'quickies' is almost flattery. This one is no exception, a serio-comic cop actioner with a crazy plot that is at once simplistic and yet totally unbelievable. The police procedural plot is so silly and slap-dash it makes Crockett and Tubbs look like Holmes and Watson. Famed director Tsui Hark stars as a two-bit forger who, by a series of coincidences, stumbles across a valuable piece of microfilm, then discovers that a dangerous hit man is after it too. Detectives Michelle Yeoh and Cynthia Rothrock team up to follow the microfilm up the criminal food chain, hoping it will lead them, by another series of coincidences, I guess, to the hit man. Or something. I swear, Hong Kong is about the only place where a movie maker would attempt to shoot a murder mystery / police procedural story without bothering to fully work out the plot first... Or bothering to check with a police technical adviser to see how many laws the cops broke in 90 minutes. Anyway, Hark is pretty funny in his scenes as a coward adept at dodging and running away and sticking other people with his problems, and Yeoh and Rothrock kick major butt in their action scenes. If you take the movie on its merits and don't compare it to CSI too closely it makes for pretty decent low brow entertainment. Note that (this film having been shot in 1985) Yeoh and Rothrock - and everybody else - did all of their own stunts and that no wire work was used in the fight scenes, just a little slo-mo to stylize the action. As athletes, they were pretty impressive!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun but could've been better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    henrydeluca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this '80s Hong Kong action film, Michelle Yeoh and Cynthia Rothrock team up to find a microfilm containing group of villains' illegal activities after a British diplomat has been killed. Unfortunately three thieves have the microfilm and the police need to find it in order to have evidence to make an arrest. Although the film stars Michelle Yeoh and Cynthia Rothrock as kick-ass ladies working as police officers, the story seems to focus more on the three thieves who have the microfilm, which bothered me in a way. The main reason is because I was looking forward to see the chemistry between Yeoh and Rothrock. But instead they are presented as if they are secondary characters. And not only that all of the characters here are one dimensional, which leaves the audience asking themselves questions such as why would Rothrock's character beat up a suspect for answers or why one of the villains is wearing a U.S military- like uniform. Regardless of the film's plot there are some great action sequences, especially the fight in the finale. The stunts shown will make you say out loud "that's gotta hurt!" Remember, we're talking about no CGI, green screen, or wire work!!!!!! Overall I think the film could've been better if the filmmakers worked on character development, a better ending, and focused more on our two female leads' chemistry!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly fun but very much flawed Hong Kong action fare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bloodwank
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, this film could have been so great. I tend to like Hong Kong actioners from the 80's so Police Assassins didn't cause me too much irritation for all its flaws, but its sad that the film is the way it is given its potential. Potential that amounts to this: Michelle Yeoh teamed up with Cynthia Rothrock. Two great ass-kicking ladies, Rothrcok with her genuine martial arts talents and Yeoh a graceful mover with some great training behind her (though she wasn't originally a martial artist), they make for a fine team and the film zings whenever they are together. Regrettably their time together is much less than it should have been, as the film inexplicably chooses to focus on a trio of dimwitted petty criminals who get in over their heads in a bit of dirty corporate dealing. John Sham and Hoi Mang are little more than irritating as the oddly named Strepsil and Asprin, while Tsui Hark (best known as a veteran director) does a bit better as the wheeler dealer forgery expert Panadol, perhaps the only one of the three who actually fits into the film. He puts across his sly and shifty, mischievous role pretty nicely and gets a few decent scenes, and isn't cloying in his comedy or emotions like the other two, who overact, mug and generally detract from affairs. Most of the comedy in this film is "off", the mixture of light and seriousness is even less well handled here than it is in other films of the same stripe. The films other problem is that the plot is pretty inconsequential, the device on which events hinge is never well explained, thus the film lacks suspense, and the arch baddies is never quite villainous enough to be an effective force, though his two head hench-people (Dick Wei and Fat Chung) are appropriately menacing and fine fighters. Also, the film is largely inconsequential in events until the halfway mark, there are fights and the pace is fair, but it all feels contrived and hastily put together. For all this the film isn't too bad in the end, mostly due to some great action and the fine style on display from director Cory Yuen. He knows just when to slow up or slow down a fight, plenty of smart angles and fast paced editing that remains coherent whilst keeping the pace rapid, also fitting in a couple of nifty jump cuts. His choreography ranges from solid in earlier stages to excellent in the rip-snorting finale and even with the aforementioned plot contrivances, when the film gets moving it gets pretty exciting. To sum up the good points, they just about balance out the bad and leave the film ultimately moderately satisfying. It surely isn't great (it took me a few viewings to really warm to it), but if 80's style Hong Kong action is your cup of tea, this film is certainly better than a poke in the eye with a wet stick. A low 6/10 then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mostly lives up to its reputation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gridoon2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Police Assassins" AKA "Yes, Madam!" marked the first action role of the now internationally famous Michelle Yeoh, and established her as one of THE top female stars in her field. When you see the movie, it's easy to understand her success: she moves, shoots, fights and poses with the speed and confidence of a veteran, as well as with the enthusiasm of a rookie. The film also marked the Honk Kong debut of the fierce Cynthia Rothrock, who is generally considered to have done her best work in this part of the world and not later in America. Essentially this is a female buddy-cop film, except that the rivalry between the two women doesn't last as long as in most male examples of the genre, and they soon join forces to get the bad guys. The most notable among those is Dick Wei, the kind of guy who doesn't pull any punches when he fights women (check out his fights with Cynthia Khan in "In The Line Of Duty 3"), which ends up making both him AND the women look good. There are some overextended "slapstick" sequences that don't really fit with the violent style of the movie (particularly those with Tsui Hark), but the action scenes deliver what they promise. *** out of 4.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Dizzying But Fun Ride
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    crossbow0106
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michelle Yeoh plays a fast moving cop in Hong Kong who is exposed to Dirty Harry type situations in this film which is part of the "In The Line Of Duty" film series. The film is mostly at accelerated speed, and it is the action that carries the scene. The constant fighting and attempted escapes make you forget what is a simple plot about microfilm. Cynthia Rothrock is also in this, so you have two butt kicking cops. The movie loses some steam due to the silliness of some of its characters, but you'll still like the action. It plays in high definition on the Kung Fu Channel, so if you have access this is the way to see it. Michelle Yeoh has, of course, done more compelling work after this, but I think you'll enjoy it, even the violent scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing action scenes that exceeded my expectations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    petep
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So here it is -- Yes, Madam -- Michelle Yeoh's first starring role, back in 1985. I'd been wanting to see this one for a few years. I was a bit worried because the DVD appeared to be a bootleg once it arrived, but it worked fine, so I won't complain. But wow, Yeoh was so amazing in the film. She had won the title of Miss Malaysia just a couple years earlier, for damn good reason, but she took her start in the action genre seriously and trained hard for a few months before shooting began. Sammo Hung himself was the producer (and has a cameo, along with half the industry), and he was looking for two female leads, to make something different from the typical male buddy-cop films. For a co-star they got Cynthia Rothrock, who was making her start in the genre as well. Though she was the real deal as far as martial arts skill. I was interested in the film more for Yeoh but Rothrock certainly held her own. Well, with the action, not the acting, ha ha. Now then, the average American audience might not think much of the movie. It's full of the kind of very odd and stupid HK humor that I've gotten used to. But Yeoh shines in every moment she's on screen, and the action scenes are incredible. In particular the final fights near the end of the film had me as excited as being at a Bulls game. I couldn't believe some of the stuff they were pulling off. My heart goes out to those stunt men!! The actual final minute of the film caught me off guard, though it was realistic. But damn... that ten minutes or so of fighting was among the best I've ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Battling Babes at their best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tony Ryan (tpr007)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A revolutionary a film for kick starting and defining the Battling Babes genre, in the same way 'Zu' was for the fantasy swordplay movies, 'Yes, Madam!' combined the best of Hong Kong action cinema with a fresh, sexy and exciting look. Rarely ever had women played such dominant roles and kicked as much butt as they do here, while still being allowed to show a coy, feminine side. Both Yeoh and Rothrock made their action debuts in this film, and they couldn't have been picked at a better time. The action choreography in HK was entering a new, fast and brutal phase while both girls were at the peak of their physical fitness. The end result is not only the definitive femme-fatale flick, but also one of the finest actioners to leap on to the screen in the mid 80's. The final fight scene alone is more than worth the cost of the DVD and puts Hollywood to shame with its raw power and inventiveness. The best offered in the West at the time was a macho Sigourney Weaver in 'Aliens', but even she wouldn't have been able to touch these girls! Also known as 'In the line of Duty 2' following the later produced 'Royal Warriors' aka 'In the line of Duty' (1986) 'Yes, Madam!' set a new trend in the later 80's whereby attractive women such as Cynthia Khan, Moon Lee, Yukari Oshima and many more were given free reign to dish out the pain, being made to look like the greatest screen fighters ever courtesy of rigorous training from the likes of Dick Wei, Yuen Kwai and Yuen Woo Ping. Even today we are reaping the rewards as female faces, new and old, do battle on the screen in modern classics like 'Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon'. Entertaining cameos from Sammo Hung and Richard Ng as well as great fighting performances from the likes of Chung Fa and Dick Wei makes this a testosterone junkies dream! Ultimately lacking in great cinematography or even much of a plot, the name of the game is to excite the audience in as many ways possible, whether it's with lingering shots of a luscious, young Michelle Yeoh or an animated, head and arm cracking La Rothrock - this movie should not be missed by anyone interested in action - "Hong Kong style".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Movie Already Is A Legend
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This to me is the best movie Cynthia Rothrock ever made, and one of the best movie from Michelle Yeoh's early career. The final action scene involving the two guarantees it. This was one of very early D&B movie studio's production. D&B movies brought more modern style to Hong Kong movies, and it's clear from this movie that it's years ahead compared other action movies of the time in terms of content, the fashion the actors are wearing, the modern looking background, the speed the scene moves, and the three dimensional shooting. Hong Kong movies in few short years following this movie makes a stellar leap in terms of quality, but you can already see most of the elements in this movie. Cynthia Rothrock plays inspector Carrie Morris from Scotland Yard, and Michelle Yeoh plays inspector Ng of Hong Kong police department. They're after a microfilm that was stolen by two small time crooks. The microfilm contains the names of the ones who are involved in criminal activity. The real bad guy who's got most to lose from the microfilm is Mr. Tin and is willing to go any extent to get the microfilm. Eventually, the small time crook, Yeoh, and Rothrock ends up in Tin's house, and massive fight ensues. The number of casts appearing in this movie is amazing, and this helps to weave many threads in this story. The story has comedic touch, serious touch, and lot of action depending on who's playing the part of the story. It's definitely not one dimensional, and is entertaining to watch. The production is classy, and has high quality looks to it. This movie started the "Huang Ka" (Royal) movie craze in Hong Kong, and many movies crowning these two characters were made. The movie has confusing number of titles like "Super Cops", "In the line of Duty", "Yes Madam", "Ultra Force", which actually makes finding this movie difficult. The final fight scenes appears in many specials that chronicles Hong Kong martial arts movies to this day. The amazing physical ability of Michelle Yeoh, and Cynthia Rothrock launched them into superstar status. This is one of the best martial arts themed movie to come out of Hong Kong, and is highly recommended for viewing whether you're a martial arts movie fan or not.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit too much cringe-worthy Chinese comedy, but the quality of martial arts more than made up for it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thomas Tokmenko
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Moments of slapstick comedy are nothing but expected when Sammmo Hung makes an appearance, however it may be a touch overdone here in this sub-genre defining "femme-fatale" flick. Two female officers of the law present themselves as hard-hitting women which should be shown absolute respect, but another group of protagonists weighs them down and the overall result is more comedic than dramatic. There simply wasn't enough Michelle Yeoh and Cynthia Rothrock on-screen to provide sufficient character development, but even at a basic level it works to support the crime investigation story (which is also very simple). A reel of film ends up being passed around Hong Kong as a triad corporation tries to obtain and destroy it in order to avoid the legal consequences attached. Meanwhile, a group of idiotic underdogs inadvertently become mixed up with the triad affair, as well as our two female hero cops Yeoh and Rothrock. The adventure is goofy yet fun, and the finale will take your breath away in terms of martial arts prowess. This is an iconic movie of both Hong Kong action cinema and the femme- fatale sub genre, and if your mildly interested in either you'll have a great time with this one. - 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Michelle Yeoh's first starring role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As with most original movies that create a long series of sequels, this one is good. Basically a couple of small time crooks who are scrapping money to get their master out of a nursing home get caught up in a fraudulent business. They accidentally steal a micro-fiche upon which a false contract, which will destroy the credibility of a major corporation, has been printed. Unfortunately this corporation wants it destroyed and thus they find nasty hit men after them. This movie stars Cythia Kahn, the star of the In the Line of Duty movies, but it also stars Cynthia Rockwell, an American martial artist. From what I remember of her, she was an attractive woman that could kick butt, but in this movie she is much more masculine, and scary. Both Cynthias come across as very competent and are two women which you do not want to mess with. The movie opens with action and the action goes right through to the end, and the suspense is gripping. It all winds up to a movie where there is a shallow victory because even though the bad guys have lost, the good guys have not won. It is a movie that is not willing to kill off major characters and to show that even though violence may solve problems, it will create a lot more. The axiom that violence never solves anything is not entirely true. Rather it should be that violence creates more problems than it solves. For an action movie, this is great, but if you are wanting a simple movie where the good guys beat the bad guys and come out on top, then this is not that type of movie. It is a movie where things go from bad to worse, and the end comes about from a final act of desperation to make sure that justice is done. The one thing that I got from reading the bible tonight is that even if somebody seems to have everything, that will not last forever. The thing is that God will bring about their destruction, not us, so to attempt to speed up the inevitable will not solve anything. Here all of the evidence may have been destroyed, the bad guy will have to die sometime, and when he dies he will learn the truth of what life is really all about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay actioner if you don't think too much
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hong Kong action movies in the 80s were made on such short production schedules that calling them 'quickies' is almost flattery. This one is no exception, a serio-comic cop actioner with a crazy plot that is at once simplistic and yet totally unbelievable. The police procedural plot is so silly and slap-dash it makes Crockett and Tubbs look like Holmes and Watson. Famed director Tsui Hark stars as a two-bit forger who, by a series of coincidences, stumbles across a valuable piece of microfilm, then discovers that a dangerous hit man is after it too. Detectives Michelle Yeoh and Cynthia Rothrock team up to follow the microfilm up the criminal food chain, hoping it will lead them, by another series of coincidences, I guess, to the hit man. Or something. I swear, Hong Kong is about the only place where a movie maker would attempt to shoot a murder mystery / police procedural story without bothering to fully work out the plot first... Or bothering to check with a police technical adviser to see how many laws the cops broke in 90 minutes. Anyway, Hark is pretty funny in his scenes as a coward adept at dodging and running away and sticking other people with his problems, and Yeoh and Rothrock kick major butt in their action scenes. If you take the movie on its merits and don't compare it to CSI too closely it makes for pretty decent low brow entertainment. Note that (this film having been shot in 1985) Yeoh and Rothrock - and everybody else - did all of their own stunts and that no wire work was used in the fight scenes, just a little slo-mo to stylize the action. As athletes, they were pretty impressive!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun but could've been better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    henrydeluca
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this '80s Hong Kong action film, Michelle Yeoh and Cynthia Rothrock team up to find a microfilm containing group of villains' illegal activities after a British diplomat has been killed. Unfortunately three thieves have the microfilm and the police need to find it in order to have evidence to make an arrest. Although the film stars Michelle Yeoh and Cynthia Rothrock as kick-ass ladies working as police officers, the story seems to focus more on the three thieves who have the microfilm, which bothered me in a way. The main reason is because I was looking forward to see the chemistry between Yeoh and Rothrock. But instead they are presented as if they are secondary characters. And not only that all of the characters here are one dimensional, which leaves the audience asking themselves questions such as why would Rothrock's character beat up a suspect for answers or why one of the villains is wearing a U.S military- like uniform. Regardless of the film's plot there are some great action sequences, especially the fight in the finale. The stunts shown will make you say out loud "that's gotta hurt!" Remember, we're talking about no CGI, green screen, or wire work!!!!!! Overall I think the film could've been better if the filmmakers worked on character development, a better ending, and focused more on our two female leads' chemistry!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly fun but very much flawed Hong Kong action fare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bloodwank
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, this film could have been so great. I tend to like Hong Kong actioners from the 80's so Police Assassins didn't cause me too much irritation for all its flaws, but its sad that the film is the way it is given its potential. Potential that amounts to this: Michelle Yeoh teamed up with Cynthia Rothrock. Two great ass-kicking ladies, Rothrcok with her genuine martial arts talents and Yeoh a graceful mover with some great training behind her (though she wasn't originally a martial artist), they make for a fine team and the film zings whenever they are together. Regrettably their time together is much less than it should have been, as the film inexplicably chooses to focus on a trio of dimwitted petty criminals who get in over their heads in a bit of dirty corporate dealing. John Sham and Hoi Mang are little more than irritating as the oddly named Strepsil and Asprin, while Tsui Hark (best known as a veteran director) does a bit better as the wheeler dealer forgery expert Panadol, perhaps the only one of the three who actually fits into the film. He puts across his sly and shifty, mischievous role pretty nicely and gets a few decent scenes, and isn't cloying in his comedy or emotions like the other two, who overact, mug and generally detract from affairs. Most of the comedy in this film is "off", the mixture of light and seriousness is even less well handled here than it is in other films of the same stripe. The films other problem is that the plot is pretty inconsequential, the device on which events hinge is never well explained, thus the film lacks suspense, and the arch baddies is never quite villainous enough to be an effective force, though his two head hench-people (Dick Wei and Fat Chung) are appropriately menacing and fine fighters. Also, the film is largely inconsequential in events until the halfway mark, there are fights and the pace is fair, but it all feels contrived and hastily put together. For all this the film isn't too bad in the end, mostly due to some great action and the fine style on display from director Cory Yuen. He knows just when to slow up or slow down a fight, plenty of smart angles and fast paced editing that remains coherent whilst keeping the pace rapid, also fitting in a couple of nifty jump cuts. His choreography ranges from solid in earlier stages to excellent in the rip-snorting finale and even with the aforementioned plot contrivances, when the film gets moving it gets pretty exciting. To sum up the good points, they just about balance out the bad and leave the film ultimately moderately satisfying. It surely isn't great (it took me a few viewings to really warm to it), but if 80's style Hong Kong action is your cup of tea, this film is certainly better than a poke in the eye with a wet stick. A low 6/10 then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mostly lives up to its reputation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gridoon2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Police Assassins" AKA "Yes, Madam!" marked the first action role of the now internationally famous Michelle Yeoh, and established her as one of THE top female stars in her field. When you see the movie, it's easy to understand her success: she moves, shoots, fights and poses with the speed and confidence of a veteran, as well as with the enthusiasm of a rookie. The film also marked the Honk Kong debut of the fierce Cynthia Rothrock, who is generally considered to have done her best work in this part of the world and not later in America. Essentially this is a female buddy-cop film, except that the rivalry between the two women doesn't last as long as in most male examples of the genre, and they soon join forces to get the bad guys. The most notable among those is Dick Wei, the kind of guy who doesn't pull any punches when he fights women (check out his fights with Cynthia Khan in "In The Line Of Duty 3"), which ends up making both him AND the women look good. There are some overextended "slapstick" sequences that don't really fit with the violent style of the movie (particularly those with Tsui Hark), but the action scenes deliver what they promise. *** out of 4.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Dizzying But Fun Ride
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    crossbow0106
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Michelle Yeoh plays a fast moving cop in Hong Kong who is exposed to Dirty Harry type situations in this film which is part of the "In The Line Of Duty" film series. The film is mostly at accelerated speed, and it is the action that carries the scene. The constant fighting and attempted escapes make you forget what is a simple plot about microfilm. Cynthia Rothrock is also in this, so you have two butt kicking cops. The movie loses some steam due to the silliness of some of its characters, but you'll still like the action. It plays in high definition on the Kung Fu Channel, so if you have access this is the way to see it. Michelle Yeoh has, of course, done more compelling work after this, but I think you'll enjoy it, even the violent scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing action scenes that exceeded my expectations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    petep
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So here it is -- Yes, Madam -- Michelle Yeoh's first starring role, back in 1985. I'd been wanting to see this one for a few years. I was a bit worried because the DVD appeared to be a bootleg once it arrived, but it worked fine, so I won't complain. But wow, Yeoh was so amazing in the film. She had won the title of Miss Malaysia just a couple years earlier, for damn good reason, but she took her start in the action genre seriously and trained hard for a few months before shooting began. Sammo Hung himself was the producer (and has a cameo, along with half the industry), and he was looking for two female leads, to make something different from the typical male buddy-cop films. For a co-star they got Cynthia Rothrock, who was making her start in the genre as well. Though she was the real deal as far as martial arts skill. I was interested in the film more for Yeoh but Rothrock certainly held her own. Well, with the action, not the acting, ha ha. Now then, the average American audience might not think much of the movie. It's full of the kind of very odd and stupid HK humor that I've gotten used to. But Yeoh shines in every moment she's on screen, and the action scenes are incredible. In particular the final fights near the end of the film had me as excited as being at a Bulls game. I couldn't believe some of the stuff they were pulling off. My heart goes out to those stunt men!! The actual final minute of the film caught me off guard, though it was realistic. But damn... that ten minutes or so of fighting was among the best I've ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Battling Babes at their best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tony Ryan (tpr007)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A revolutionary a film for kick starting and defining the Battling Babes genre, in the same way 'Zu' was for the fantasy swordplay movies, 'Yes, Madam!' combined the best of Hong Kong action cinema with a fresh, sexy and exciting look. Rarely ever had women played such dominant roles and kicked as much butt as they do here, while still being allowed to show a coy, feminine side. Both Yeoh and Rothrock made their action debuts in this film, and they couldn't have been picked at a better time. The action choreography in HK was entering a new, fast and brutal phase while both girls were at the peak of their physical fitness. The end result is not only the definitive femme-fatale flick, but also one of the finest actioners to leap on to the screen in the mid 80's. The final fight scene alone is more than worth the cost of the DVD and puts Hollywood to shame with its raw power and inventiveness. The best offered in the West at the time was a macho Sigourney Weaver in 'Aliens', but even she wouldn't have been able to touch these girls! Also known as 'In the line of Duty 2' following the later produced 'Royal Warriors' aka 'In the line of Duty' (1986) 'Yes, Madam!' set a new trend in the later 80's whereby attractive women such as Cynthia Khan, Moon Lee, Yukari Oshima and many more were given free reign to dish out the pain, being made to look like the greatest screen fighters ever courtesy of rigorous training from the likes of Dick Wei, Yuen Kwai and Yuen Woo Ping. Even today we are reaping the rewards as female faces, new and old, do battle on the screen in modern classics like 'Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon'. Entertaining cameos from Sammo Hung and Richard Ng as well as great fighting performances from the likes of Chung Fa and Dick Wei makes this a testosterone junkies dream! Ultimately lacking in great cinematography or even much of a plot, the name of the game is to excite the audience in as many ways possible, whether it's with lingering shots of a luscious, young Michelle Yeoh or an animated, head and arm cracking La Rothrock - this movie should not be missed by anyone interested in action - "Hong Kong style".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
