<filme>
 <id>
  84
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111003
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Sob o Dom&iacute;nio dos Aliens
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The Earth is invaded by alien "slugs" that ride on people's backs and control their minds.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Strange aliens land in the Midwest, taking over people's minds in order to spread their dominion. Sam Nivens and Andrew Nivens, aided by Mary Sefton, are part of a government agency who must stop the the aliens before the aliens get to them...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   alien
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   iowa
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   suicide
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   president
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   des moines iowa
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Stuart Orme
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Robert A. Heinlein
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Ted Elliott
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Donald Sutherland
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Eric Thal
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Julie Warner
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adequate sci-fi / action picture.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While "The Puppet Masters" is generally an entertaining movie with a good pace going for it, the simple fact is that it's much too belated an official adaptation of the Robert A. Heinlein novel. We've seen other, similar stories since, including of course "Invasion of the Body Snatchers" (although the Heinlein novel actually preceded the Jack Finney book of "Body Snatchers"). The presentation is definitely competent if not inspired. The creatures themselves are fairly cool, and visuals (specifically, the hive interior) are solid, and the script (credited to Ted Elliott, Terry Rossio, and David S. Goyer) is fairly intelligent, but the direction (by Stuart Orme) is nondescript. The music is generic stuff, as well. It's an alien invasion tale of starfish shaped slugs that land on Earth, attach themselves to the backs of humans, and control their actions. It doesn't take long for an infection (which starts in rural Iowa) to spread and spread. The man in charge of handling the crisis is Andrew Nivens (an amusing Donald Sutherland, who performs with wit and style), who heads up a covert agency that is an offshoot of the C.I.A. and which deals with "scientific intelligence". Also involved is Andrews' special agent son Sam (Eric Thal) and a scientist (the irresistibly cute Julie Warner) who specializes in theorizing about alien anatomy, believe it or not! The story isn't a bad one but just isn't that meaty; I'm told that, as is so often the case, that the book is a superior work of fiction. The filmmakers do their best to keep us interested in the characters, putting each of them in peril. The stars do good work (this wouldn't work as well were it not for Sutherland), and are well supported by a rich variety of top character actors and familiar faces: Keith David, Will Patton, Richard Belzer, Tom Mason, Yaphet Kotto, Gerry Bamman, Sam Anderson, Marshall Bell, Benjamin Mouton, Andrew Robinson, and Dale Dye (some of them, however, get no more than a few lines). Never boring but never that exciting, either, this does fall victim to the "more than one ending" clich&eacute; but does have its good moments too. Best recommended to undemanding fans of the genre. Six out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muppet Pastors
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunate enough to share a name with a brand of dirt-cheap Charles Band movies (but completely disconnected from them) I always figured that The Puppet Masters would be just as schlocky. It ain't art, but it is decent, low-brow, brainless entertainment. A bunch of alien manta-rays land in Iowa in a confusing opening sequence. The authorities arrive and discover that the locals are slowly being turned into mindless slaves to their alien hosts. Sound like the X-Files? It very much does play out like a 3-part episode with virtually the exact same character dynamic and interaction. The tagline for the movie is even 'Trust no one'. It also feels like a John Carpenter movie in some respects (the presence of Keith David, who really ought to be in every movie, only adds to this). And while it's a fairly non-epic movie it does feature some nice anamorphic Panavision photography and a bunch of character actors to keep you entertained in-between the silly plot developments. As well as feeling the X-Files it also comes across as an Invasion of the Body Snatchers rip-off, odd since co-star Donald Sutherland was in one of those movies. Four years later another very similar film called The Faculty also featured mind-controlling alien parasites, as well as the Brain Slugs from Futurama. But apparently it's taken from a novel of the same name by Robert A. Heinlein but with little in common, perhaps thanks to a zillion re-writes. These kinds of movies often have some kind of political subtext, but Puppet Masters embraces its low-brow but clever silliness and ends up a guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unworthy adaptation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heinlein's book is, I gather, pretty good. I'm not a purist and I don't demand that a movie adaptation follow the print version closely, and in fact I haven't read the novel. But this isn't very good. In plot it seems more an overblown version of "The X Files", except that the federal investigative team has more members, so that some can be taken over by the pods. It's hard to imagine Mulder or Scully zombified. In execution and style it's reminiscent of Carpenter's bombastic version of "The Thing." Gloopy organisms coil themselves around people's faces and boomerang from point to point. Or they auger themselves into a victim's back. They "attach themselves to the spinal cord" of the victim, so you can't tell if someone is possessed or not until you have them strip down the back of their shirts and take a look. Julie Warner's examination was the only bright spot in the film. It bears no resemblance whatever to the classic 1950s science fiction film, "The Invasion of the Body Snatchers." That much-imitated original (from Jack Finney's novel) began with a normal, steady state of affairs, grew through suspicion, developed into conviction, and led to action. This begins and ends with action, just in case the viewer might be bored during the first ten minutes of exposition and switch to an energy drink commercial just to watch cartoon figures leap around. The gloppy organisms, ripped off shamelessly and pointlessly from "Alien", are on abundant display. The sloppy, sticky, guts are picked apart, accompanied by a lot of scientific gobbledygook. Donald Sutherland's performance provides the eye of this hurricane of horror. He's quiet and controlled, when almost everyone else is running around berserk. The innards of those parasites are a true mess, and so is the film. I can't imagine that Heinlein, a good writer, produced a book that could be so popular and yet so execrable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Raising Sancho
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Puppet Masters" is a film that in it's first minutes promises to be an interesting and entertaining alien film that will scare you. After 30 minutes, you may change your mind. The beginning is smart, we have action in the first five minutes of running. It's difficult to watch a movie when there are 35345839465 characters, names and names of organizations; I felt very confused and got lost in the mystery many times. Directing is a strong thing, it doesn't seem to be an independent picture. Along with good directing, we have a smart background sound, building a suspenseful atmosphere. Also, this film is very different from most out there, and I can't explain why. It just feels very original and clever-- which, even thought, disappoints. Maybe if they put more story, less action and less screen time, it wouldn't have become this boring. See this only if you like action pictures with lack of story and you will probably enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Sci-Fi...please do this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What we are looking for in Sci-fi is a good story that enables us to join in. We want to be thrilled and have our wonderment, our inquisitiveness fed in large does where we can get it. Enter the Puppet Masters. I would have preferred a better title for this movie, but this one is very accurate and will do. This movie will allow you to see a lesser form of life but equally intelligent in its own way and try to dominate our species playing by our rules and on our playing field. What you will see is how well they go about it methodically making advancements and that is what successful war or invading your enemy is all about. These Alien play to win and we play to lose until we figure out this isn't a play over game if you lose. The acting brings it all close to home and the plot is easy to follow. The story is targeted to any age group and intriguing. To observe Aliens who use their brains instead of their weaponry leaves one frightened. It mentally and emotionally assaults mankind because we know we are the superior being on this planet. For something less in appearance to invade us and succeed is truly frightening not to mention a wake-up call. This was worthy of being a full blown move with a sequel and a prequel potential. I watch it with captions on because I like to hear every word spoken when the Aliens and the humans have a face to to face. Waste no more time reading this review...go watch the movie right now
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The alien take-over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This adaptation of a Robert A. Heinlein novel puts things right into gear when Eric Thal, Julie Warner and the ever-competent Donald Shutterland rush off to Ambrose, Iowa to investigate a registered UFO landing. However, collective-minded alien parasites have already begun to take over, turning humans into puppets to do their bidding. Writing trio Ted Elliott, Terry Rossio & David S. Goyer manage to tie things up fashionably, but also overworked themselves providing just about everything. Being a mixture of sci-fi, horror, thriller, action and drama, it's safe to say the wholesome feels a bit disjoint at places. The animatronic slug-like parasites by Roy Arbogast & Co. are a fine creation and get plenty of screen-time. Ambitious entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining, although sometimes flawed Science-Fiction Thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three top level government agents (Donald Sutherland, Eric Thal and Julie Warner) make a disturbing discovery that extraterrestrial beings have landed on earth and they quickly take over control of the residents in a small midwestern town. The agents find out, they can using their bodies and minds like puppets. While the creatures multiply and spread quickly, the agents have to think fast and destroy these seemingly unstoppable aliens. Directed by Stuart Orme (Best known for directing TV Movies or TV Shows) made an entertaining, science-fiction thriller with an amusing performance by Sutherland as the sardonic lead agent. While Thal and Warner certainly do well in their roles. Since this movie has good creature special make-up effects by Three Time Oscar-Winner:Greg Cannom (Blade, The Curious Case of Benjamin Button, Hannibal). The feature has good production values but somehow director Orme doesn't have much imagination during some of the rather tense sequences and the climax between Sutherland and Thal is a disappointment with cheap visual effects. The movie is certainly on its best in the first two-thirds of the picture. DVD has an fine anamorphic Widescreen (2.35:1) transfer and an good Dolby Surround 2.0 Sound. The DVD doesn't have any special features. "The Puppet Masters" came out in October 1994, it quickly became an box office disappointment and the movie had a lot of imitations before. Which the movie took the edge off and it never really caught any fire. Despite it is based on a novel by Robert A. Heinlein (Starship Troopers). Director Orme certainly wasted some talented actors in small roles like Yaphet Kotto, Richard Belzer, Andrew Robinson and Marshall Bell. Although it is nice to see Keith David (Best known for two John Carpenter movies, "The Thing" and "They Live") in a supporting role. Will Patton seems to be having an great time as the odd-ball scientist. Since the script is pretty good. Written by Ted Elliott (Aladdin, Godzilla "1998", Small Soldiers), Terry Rossio (The Pirates of the Caribbean series, Deja Vu, Shrek) and David S. Goyer (The Blade Trilogy, Dark City, Death Warrant). Although their script was heavily re-written by five screenwriters and the director as well. "The Puppet Masters" today, it is certainly an curio. Although exciting at times with an nice leading performances by Sutherland, Thal and Warner. Which Sutherland is no stranger to this kind of movie, since he was in the superior remake as the lead actor in "Invasion of the Body Snatchers", which it was directed by Philip Kaufman. Perphas some die-hard science fiction fans, it would make an great double feature with "Invasion of the Body Snatchers" and "The Puppet Masters" for one night viewing. Despite some real flaws and an terrible climax, it is still worth viewing. Panavision. (*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not at all bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being one of the key dozen or so science fiction writers of the 20th Century, relatively little of Robert Heinlein's work has been filmed and, with the exception of Starship Troopers (turned on its idealogical head), nothing from the 60s onwards, when his work started to carry more serious subtext. The Puppet Masters, a book from the 50s, is essentially fairly lightweight, albeit the invasion motif is similar to that of much 1950s science fiction in echoing a fear about the spread of communism - indeed, the parasitic slugs in Puppet Masters form a single entity - a commune if you will - and are therefore a fairly obvious analogue for the red menace. The novel was also fairly saucy for its time, with large chunks of the population having to peel down to their skimpies and beyond to prove that their clothing was not hiding the alien slugs. Well, as usual, Hollywood doesn't like to present the naked body to the viewing public, so the protagonists in this film version of Heinlein's story encounter more difficulty than they need to, simply by virtue of everybody keeping their clothes on. Apart from that, it follows the main sequence of events fairly faithfully, albeit updated to be more contemporary. Donald Sutherland is a serviceable "Old Man", even though he is quite different to how I imagined the character from the book (which hardly matters). There are several well-known albeit minor names in the secondary case, but the main leads are taken by Eric Thal and Julie Warner. Neither has had major success before or since (Warner had a lengthy run in Family Law) and, to be perfectly frank, this movie gives a good idea why - they have little charisma, and no chemistry despite the fact that they supposedly fall in love during the film. The story demands lead players who don't come across as insipid, but it doesn't get them. There is relatively little in terms of special effects, but what there is does the job. The major effect is the slugs themselves, and they are pleasingly unpleasant.. There is some offensive - and entirely unnecessary - use of the F-bomb. I don't mind it when it's there for a purpose: here it serves no purpose whatsoever. It doesn't advance the plot or illuminate character, it simply makes an unpleasant comment even more unpleasant, and it could have been omitted entirely without any detrimental effect on the movie. With some promotion, this movie could have been rather more successful than it was, albeit it came on the heels of what might have appeared to be similar epidemic-type stories. Perhaps Heinlein's time in movies is still to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shmobbie
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never read the novel this was movie was based on, or any of his other works for that matter, so I have nothing to compare this film to. I also haven't seen Invasion of the Body Snatchers (shame on me). With that said, I have one question: Why the HELL wouldn't you just invent some sort of kevlar armor that attaches to the back and neck in a comfortable fashion? You would think at least the armed forces dudes would have thought about it.. I mean c'mon boys. Anyway, I thought this was entertaining enough for a boring Tuesday afternoon. I've wanted to see this since when it was released and I was much younger and I'm glad I finally have. Fun concept.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An X-Files Movie in disguise?????
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TahitiLady
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I may be the only one, but I just watched this movie again tonight and it is completely like the X-Files! Does anyone else see this? I had seen it before, but had not seen the connection. But tonight I noticed it. Even the music is similar... Is this a set up for X Files, or what???? As I began to watch it tonight, hubby and I were amazed at how many X-Files references there were - there are all the elements of an X-Files story. We have both read the book - this has little if any resemblance to the book, but if you listen to the characters, and watch the way the story plays out - it is TOTALLY X-Files!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adequate sci-fi / action picture.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While "The Puppet Masters" is generally an entertaining movie with a good pace going for it, the simple fact is that it's much too belated an official adaptation of the Robert A. Heinlein novel. We've seen other, similar stories since, including of course "Invasion of the Body Snatchers" (although the Heinlein novel actually preceded the Jack Finney book of "Body Snatchers"). The presentation is definitely competent if not inspired. The creatures themselves are fairly cool, and visuals (specifically, the hive interior) are solid, and the script (credited to Ted Elliott, Terry Rossio, and David S. Goyer) is fairly intelligent, but the direction (by Stuart Orme) is nondescript. The music is generic stuff, as well. It's an alien invasion tale of starfish shaped slugs that land on Earth, attach themselves to the backs of humans, and control their actions. It doesn't take long for an infection (which starts in rural Iowa) to spread and spread. The man in charge of handling the crisis is Andrew Nivens (an amusing Donald Sutherland, who performs with wit and style), who heads up a covert agency that is an offshoot of the C.I.A. and which deals with "scientific intelligence". Also involved is Andrews' special agent son Sam (Eric Thal) and a scientist (the irresistibly cute Julie Warner) who specializes in theorizing about alien anatomy, believe it or not! The story isn't a bad one but just isn't that meaty; I'm told that, as is so often the case, that the book is a superior work of fiction. The filmmakers do their best to keep us interested in the characters, putting each of them in peril. The stars do good work (this wouldn't work as well were it not for Sutherland), and are well supported by a rich variety of top character actors and familiar faces: Keith David, Will Patton, Richard Belzer, Tom Mason, Yaphet Kotto, Gerry Bamman, Sam Anderson, Marshall Bell, Benjamin Mouton, Andrew Robinson, and Dale Dye (some of them, however, get no more than a few lines). Never boring but never that exciting, either, this does fall victim to the "more than one ending" clich&eacute; but does have its good moments too. Best recommended to undemanding fans of the genre. Six out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muppet Pastors
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunate enough to share a name with a brand of dirt-cheap Charles Band movies (but completely disconnected from them) I always figured that The Puppet Masters would be just as schlocky. It ain't art, but it is decent, low-brow, brainless entertainment. A bunch of alien manta-rays land in Iowa in a confusing opening sequence. The authorities arrive and discover that the locals are slowly being turned into mindless slaves to their alien hosts. Sound like the X-Files? It very much does play out like a 3-part episode with virtually the exact same character dynamic and interaction. The tagline for the movie is even 'Trust no one'. It also feels like a John Carpenter movie in some respects (the presence of Keith David, who really ought to be in every movie, only adds to this). And while it's a fairly non-epic movie it does feature some nice anamorphic Panavision photography and a bunch of character actors to keep you entertained in-between the silly plot developments. As well as feeling the X-Files it also comes across as an Invasion of the Body Snatchers rip-off, odd since co-star Donald Sutherland was in one of those movies. Four years later another very similar film called The Faculty also featured mind-controlling alien parasites, as well as the Brain Slugs from Futurama. But apparently it's taken from a novel of the same name by Robert A. Heinlein but with little in common, perhaps thanks to a zillion re-writes. These kinds of movies often have some kind of political subtext, but Puppet Masters embraces its low-brow but clever silliness and ends up a guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unworthy adaptation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heinlein's book is, I gather, pretty good. I'm not a purist and I don't demand that a movie adaptation follow the print version closely, and in fact I haven't read the novel. But this isn't very good. In plot it seems more an overblown version of "The X Files", except that the federal investigative team has more members, so that some can be taken over by the pods. It's hard to imagine Mulder or Scully zombified. In execution and style it's reminiscent of Carpenter's bombastic version of "The Thing." Gloopy organisms coil themselves around people's faces and boomerang from point to point. Or they auger themselves into a victim's back. They "attach themselves to the spinal cord" of the victim, so you can't tell if someone is possessed or not until you have them strip down the back of their shirts and take a look. Julie Warner's examination was the only bright spot in the film. It bears no resemblance whatever to the classic 1950s science fiction film, "The Invasion of the Body Snatchers." That much-imitated original (from Jack Finney's novel) began with a normal, steady state of affairs, grew through suspicion, developed into conviction, and led to action. This begins and ends with action, just in case the viewer might be bored during the first ten minutes of exposition and switch to an energy drink commercial just to watch cartoon figures leap around. The gloppy organisms, ripped off shamelessly and pointlessly from "Alien", are on abundant display. The sloppy, sticky, guts are picked apart, accompanied by a lot of scientific gobbledygook. Donald Sutherland's performance provides the eye of this hurricane of horror. He's quiet and controlled, when almost everyone else is running around berserk. The innards of those parasites are a true mess, and so is the film. I can't imagine that Heinlein, a good writer, produced a book that could be so popular and yet so execrable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Raising Sancho
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Puppet Masters" is a film that in it's first minutes promises to be an interesting and entertaining alien film that will scare you. After 30 minutes, you may change your mind. The beginning is smart, we have action in the first five minutes of running. It's difficult to watch a movie when there are 35345839465 characters, names and names of organizations; I felt very confused and got lost in the mystery many times. Directing is a strong thing, it doesn't seem to be an independent picture. Along with good directing, we have a smart background sound, building a suspenseful atmosphere. Also, this film is very different from most out there, and I can't explain why. It just feels very original and clever-- which, even thought, disappoints. Maybe if they put more story, less action and less screen time, it wouldn't have become this boring. See this only if you like action pictures with lack of story and you will probably enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Sci-Fi...please do this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What we are looking for in Sci-fi is a good story that enables us to join in. We want to be thrilled and have our wonderment, our inquisitiveness fed in large does where we can get it. Enter the Puppet Masters. I would have preferred a better title for this movie, but this one is very accurate and will do. This movie will allow you to see a lesser form of life but equally intelligent in its own way and try to dominate our species playing by our rules and on our playing field. What you will see is how well they go about it methodically making advancements and that is what successful war or invading your enemy is all about. These Alien play to win and we play to lose until we figure out this isn't a play over game if you lose. The acting brings it all close to home and the plot is easy to follow. The story is targeted to any age group and intriguing. To observe Aliens who use their brains instead of their weaponry leaves one frightened. It mentally and emotionally assaults mankind because we know we are the superior being on this planet. For something less in appearance to invade us and succeed is truly frightening not to mention a wake-up call. This was worthy of being a full blown move with a sequel and a prequel potential. I watch it with captions on because I like to hear every word spoken when the Aliens and the humans have a face to to face. Waste no more time reading this review...go watch the movie right now
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The alien take-over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This adaptation of a Robert A. Heinlein novel puts things right into gear when Eric Thal, Julie Warner and the ever-competent Donald Shutterland rush off to Ambrose, Iowa to investigate a registered UFO landing. However, collective-minded alien parasites have already begun to take over, turning humans into puppets to do their bidding. Writing trio Ted Elliott, Terry Rossio & David S. Goyer manage to tie things up fashionably, but also overworked themselves providing just about everything. Being a mixture of sci-fi, horror, thriller, action and drama, it's safe to say the wholesome feels a bit disjoint at places. The animatronic slug-like parasites by Roy Arbogast & Co. are a fine creation and get plenty of screen-time. Ambitious entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining, although sometimes flawed Science-Fiction Thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three top level government agents (Donald Sutherland, Eric Thal and Julie Warner) make a disturbing discovery that extraterrestrial beings have landed on earth and they quickly take over control of the residents in a small midwestern town. The agents find out, they can using their bodies and minds like puppets. While the creatures multiply and spread quickly, the agents have to think fast and destroy these seemingly unstoppable aliens. Directed by Stuart Orme (Best known for directing TV Movies or TV Shows) made an entertaining, science-fiction thriller with an amusing performance by Sutherland as the sardonic lead agent. While Thal and Warner certainly do well in their roles. Since this movie has good creature special make-up effects by Three Time Oscar-Winner:Greg Cannom (Blade, The Curious Case of Benjamin Button, Hannibal). The feature has good production values but somehow director Orme doesn't have much imagination during some of the rather tense sequences and the climax between Sutherland and Thal is a disappointment with cheap visual effects. The movie is certainly on its best in the first two-thirds of the picture. DVD has an fine anamorphic Widescreen (2.35:1) transfer and an good Dolby Surround 2.0 Sound. The DVD doesn't have any special features. "The Puppet Masters" came out in October 1994, it quickly became an box office disappointment and the movie had a lot of imitations before. Which the movie took the edge off and it never really caught any fire. Despite it is based on a novel by Robert A. Heinlein (Starship Troopers). Director Orme certainly wasted some talented actors in small roles like Yaphet Kotto, Richard Belzer, Andrew Robinson and Marshall Bell. Although it is nice to see Keith David (Best known for two John Carpenter movies, "The Thing" and "They Live") in a supporting role. Will Patton seems to be having an great time as the odd-ball scientist. Since the script is pretty good. Written by Ted Elliott (Aladdin, Godzilla "1998", Small Soldiers), Terry Rossio (The Pirates of the Caribbean series, Deja Vu, Shrek) and David S. Goyer (The Blade Trilogy, Dark City, Death Warrant). Although their script was heavily re-written by five screenwriters and the director as well. "The Puppet Masters" today, it is certainly an curio. Although exciting at times with an nice leading performances by Sutherland, Thal and Warner. Which Sutherland is no stranger to this kind of movie, since he was in the superior remake as the lead actor in "Invasion of the Body Snatchers", which it was directed by Philip Kaufman. Perphas some die-hard science fiction fans, it would make an great double feature with "Invasion of the Body Snatchers" and "The Puppet Masters" for one night viewing. Despite some real flaws and an terrible climax, it is still worth viewing. Panavision. (*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not at all bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being one of the key dozen or so science fiction writers of the 20th Century, relatively little of Robert Heinlein's work has been filmed and, with the exception of Starship Troopers (turned on its idealogical head), nothing from the 60s onwards, when his work started to carry more serious subtext. The Puppet Masters, a book from the 50s, is essentially fairly lightweight, albeit the invasion motif is similar to that of much 1950s science fiction in echoing a fear about the spread of communism - indeed, the parasitic slugs in Puppet Masters form a single entity - a commune if you will - and are therefore a fairly obvious analogue for the red menace. The novel was also fairly saucy for its time, with large chunks of the population having to peel down to their skimpies and beyond to prove that their clothing was not hiding the alien slugs. Well, as usual, Hollywood doesn't like to present the naked body to the viewing public, so the protagonists in this film version of Heinlein's story encounter more difficulty than they need to, simply by virtue of everybody keeping their clothes on. Apart from that, it follows the main sequence of events fairly faithfully, albeit updated to be more contemporary. Donald Sutherland is a serviceable "Old Man", even though he is quite different to how I imagined the character from the book (which hardly matters). There are several well-known albeit minor names in the secondary case, but the main leads are taken by Eric Thal and Julie Warner. Neither has had major success before or since (Warner had a lengthy run in Family Law) and, to be perfectly frank, this movie gives a good idea why - they have little charisma, and no chemistry despite the fact that they supposedly fall in love during the film. The story demands lead players who don't come across as insipid, but it doesn't get them. There is relatively little in terms of special effects, but what there is does the job. The major effect is the slugs themselves, and they are pleasingly unpleasant.. There is some offensive - and entirely unnecessary - use of the F-bomb. I don't mind it when it's there for a purpose: here it serves no purpose whatsoever. It doesn't advance the plot or illuminate character, it simply makes an unpleasant comment even more unpleasant, and it could have been omitted entirely without any detrimental effect on the movie. With some promotion, this movie could have been rather more successful than it was, albeit it came on the heels of what might have appeared to be similar epidemic-type stories. Perhaps Heinlein's time in movies is still to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shmobbie
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never read the novel this was movie was based on, or any of his other works for that matter, so I have nothing to compare this film to. I also haven't seen Invasion of the Body Snatchers (shame on me). With that said, I have one question: Why the HELL wouldn't you just invent some sort of kevlar armor that attaches to the back and neck in a comfortable fashion? You would think at least the armed forces dudes would have thought about it.. I mean c'mon boys. Anyway, I thought this was entertaining enough for a boring Tuesday afternoon. I've wanted to see this since when it was released and I was much younger and I'm glad I finally have. Fun concept.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An X-Files Movie in disguise?????
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TahitiLady
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I may be the only one, but I just watched this movie again tonight and it is completely like the X-Files! Does anyone else see this? I had seen it before, but had not seen the connection. But tonight I noticed it. Even the music is similar... Is this a set up for X Files, or what???? As I began to watch it tonight, hubby and I were amazed at how many X-Files references there were - there are all the elements of an X-Files story. We have both read the book - this has little if any resemblance to the book, but if you listen to the characters, and watch the way the story plays out - it is TOTALLY X-Files!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adequate sci-fi / action picture.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While "The Puppet Masters" is generally an entertaining movie with a good pace going for it, the simple fact is that it's much too belated an official adaptation of the Robert A. Heinlein novel. We've seen other, similar stories since, including of course "Invasion of the Body Snatchers" (although the Heinlein novel actually preceded the Jack Finney book of "Body Snatchers"). The presentation is definitely competent if not inspired. The creatures themselves are fairly cool, and visuals (specifically, the hive interior) are solid, and the script (credited to Ted Elliott, Terry Rossio, and David S. Goyer) is fairly intelligent, but the direction (by Stuart Orme) is nondescript. The music is generic stuff, as well. It's an alien invasion tale of starfish shaped slugs that land on Earth, attach themselves to the backs of humans, and control their actions. It doesn't take long for an infection (which starts in rural Iowa) to spread and spread. The man in charge of handling the crisis is Andrew Nivens (an amusing Donald Sutherland, who performs with wit and style), who heads up a covert agency that is an offshoot of the C.I.A. and which deals with "scientific intelligence". Also involved is Andrews' special agent son Sam (Eric Thal) and a scientist (the irresistibly cute Julie Warner) who specializes in theorizing about alien anatomy, believe it or not! The story isn't a bad one but just isn't that meaty; I'm told that, as is so often the case, that the book is a superior work of fiction. The filmmakers do their best to keep us interested in the characters, putting each of them in peril. The stars do good work (this wouldn't work as well were it not for Sutherland), and are well supported by a rich variety of top character actors and familiar faces: Keith David, Will Patton, Richard Belzer, Tom Mason, Yaphet Kotto, Gerry Bamman, Sam Anderson, Marshall Bell, Benjamin Mouton, Andrew Robinson, and Dale Dye (some of them, however, get no more than a few lines). Never boring but never that exciting, either, this does fall victim to the "more than one ending" clich&eacute; but does have its good moments too. Best recommended to undemanding fans of the genre. Six out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muppet Pastors
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunate enough to share a name with a brand of dirt-cheap Charles Band movies (but completely disconnected from them) I always figured that The Puppet Masters would be just as schlocky. It ain't art, but it is decent, low-brow, brainless entertainment. A bunch of alien manta-rays land in Iowa in a confusing opening sequence. The authorities arrive and discover that the locals are slowly being turned into mindless slaves to their alien hosts. Sound like the X-Files? It very much does play out like a 3-part episode with virtually the exact same character dynamic and interaction. The tagline for the movie is even 'Trust no one'. It also feels like a John Carpenter movie in some respects (the presence of Keith David, who really ought to be in every movie, only adds to this). And while it's a fairly non-epic movie it does feature some nice anamorphic Panavision photography and a bunch of character actors to keep you entertained in-between the silly plot developments. As well as feeling the X-Files it also comes across as an Invasion of the Body Snatchers rip-off, odd since co-star Donald Sutherland was in one of those movies. Four years later another very similar film called The Faculty also featured mind-controlling alien parasites, as well as the Brain Slugs from Futurama. But apparently it's taken from a novel of the same name by Robert A. Heinlein but with little in common, perhaps thanks to a zillion re-writes. These kinds of movies often have some kind of political subtext, but Puppet Masters embraces its low-brow but clever silliness and ends up a guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unworthy adaptation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heinlein's book is, I gather, pretty good. I'm not a purist and I don't demand that a movie adaptation follow the print version closely, and in fact I haven't read the novel. But this isn't very good. In plot it seems more an overblown version of "The X Files", except that the federal investigative team has more members, so that some can be taken over by the pods. It's hard to imagine Mulder or Scully zombified. In execution and style it's reminiscent of Carpenter's bombastic version of "The Thing." Gloopy organisms coil themselves around people's faces and boomerang from point to point. Or they auger themselves into a victim's back. They "attach themselves to the spinal cord" of the victim, so you can't tell if someone is possessed or not until you have them strip down the back of their shirts and take a look. Julie Warner's examination was the only bright spot in the film. It bears no resemblance whatever to the classic 1950s science fiction film, "The Invasion of the Body Snatchers." That much-imitated original (from Jack Finney's novel) began with a normal, steady state of affairs, grew through suspicion, developed into conviction, and led to action. This begins and ends with action, just in case the viewer might be bored during the first ten minutes of exposition and switch to an energy drink commercial just to watch cartoon figures leap around. The gloppy organisms, ripped off shamelessly and pointlessly from "Alien", are on abundant display. The sloppy, sticky, guts are picked apart, accompanied by a lot of scientific gobbledygook. Donald Sutherland's performance provides the eye of this hurricane of horror. He's quiet and controlled, when almost everyone else is running around berserk. The innards of those parasites are a true mess, and so is the film. I can't imagine that Heinlein, a good writer, produced a book that could be so popular and yet so execrable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Raising Sancho
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Puppet Masters" is a film that in it's first minutes promises to be an interesting and entertaining alien film that will scare you. After 30 minutes, you may change your mind. The beginning is smart, we have action in the first five minutes of running. It's difficult to watch a movie when there are 35345839465 characters, names and names of organizations; I felt very confused and got lost in the mystery many times. Directing is a strong thing, it doesn't seem to be an independent picture. Along with good directing, we have a smart background sound, building a suspenseful atmosphere. Also, this film is very different from most out there, and I can't explain why. It just feels very original and clever-- which, even thought, disappoints. Maybe if they put more story, less action and less screen time, it wouldn't have become this boring. See this only if you like action pictures with lack of story and you will probably enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Sci-Fi...please do this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What we are looking for in Sci-fi is a good story that enables us to join in. We want to be thrilled and have our wonderment, our inquisitiveness fed in large does where we can get it. Enter the Puppet Masters. I would have preferred a better title for this movie, but this one is very accurate and will do. This movie will allow you to see a lesser form of life but equally intelligent in its own way and try to dominate our species playing by our rules and on our playing field. What you will see is how well they go about it methodically making advancements and that is what successful war or invading your enemy is all about. These Alien play to win and we play to lose until we figure out this isn't a play over game if you lose. The acting brings it all close to home and the plot is easy to follow. The story is targeted to any age group and intriguing. To observe Aliens who use their brains instead of their weaponry leaves one frightened. It mentally and emotionally assaults mankind because we know we are the superior being on this planet. For something less in appearance to invade us and succeed is truly frightening not to mention a wake-up call. This was worthy of being a full blown move with a sequel and a prequel potential. I watch it with captions on because I like to hear every word spoken when the Aliens and the humans have a face to to face. Waste no more time reading this review...go watch the movie right now
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The alien take-over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This adaptation of a Robert A. Heinlein novel puts things right into gear when Eric Thal, Julie Warner and the ever-competent Donald Shutterland rush off to Ambrose, Iowa to investigate a registered UFO landing. However, collective-minded alien parasites have already begun to take over, turning humans into puppets to do their bidding. Writing trio Ted Elliott, Terry Rossio & David S. Goyer manage to tie things up fashionably, but also overworked themselves providing just about everything. Being a mixture of sci-fi, horror, thriller, action and drama, it's safe to say the wholesome feels a bit disjoint at places. The animatronic slug-like parasites by Roy Arbogast & Co. are a fine creation and get plenty of screen-time. Ambitious entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining, although sometimes flawed Science-Fiction Thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three top level government agents (Donald Sutherland, Eric Thal and Julie Warner) make a disturbing discovery that extraterrestrial beings have landed on earth and they quickly take over control of the residents in a small midwestern town. The agents find out, they can using their bodies and minds like puppets. While the creatures multiply and spread quickly, the agents have to think fast and destroy these seemingly unstoppable aliens. Directed by Stuart Orme (Best known for directing TV Movies or TV Shows) made an entertaining, science-fiction thriller with an amusing performance by Sutherland as the sardonic lead agent. While Thal and Warner certainly do well in their roles. Since this movie has good creature special make-up effects by Three Time Oscar-Winner:Greg Cannom (Blade, The Curious Case of Benjamin Button, Hannibal). The feature has good production values but somehow director Orme doesn't have much imagination during some of the rather tense sequences and the climax between Sutherland and Thal is a disappointment with cheap visual effects. The movie is certainly on its best in the first two-thirds of the picture. DVD has an fine anamorphic Widescreen (2.35:1) transfer and an good Dolby Surround 2.0 Sound. The DVD doesn't have any special features. "The Puppet Masters" came out in October 1994, it quickly became an box office disappointment and the movie had a lot of imitations before. Which the movie took the edge off and it never really caught any fire. Despite it is based on a novel by Robert A. Heinlein (Starship Troopers). Director Orme certainly wasted some talented actors in small roles like Yaphet Kotto, Richard Belzer, Andrew Robinson and Marshall Bell. Although it is nice to see Keith David (Best known for two John Carpenter movies, "The Thing" and "They Live") in a supporting role. Will Patton seems to be having an great time as the odd-ball scientist. Since the script is pretty good. Written by Ted Elliott (Aladdin, Godzilla "1998", Small Soldiers), Terry Rossio (The Pirates of the Caribbean series, Deja Vu, Shrek) and David S. Goyer (The Blade Trilogy, Dark City, Death Warrant). Although their script was heavily re-written by five screenwriters and the director as well. "The Puppet Masters" today, it is certainly an curio. Although exciting at times with an nice leading performances by Sutherland, Thal and Warner. Which Sutherland is no stranger to this kind of movie, since he was in the superior remake as the lead actor in "Invasion of the Body Snatchers", which it was directed by Philip Kaufman. Perphas some die-hard science fiction fans, it would make an great double feature with "Invasion of the Body Snatchers" and "The Puppet Masters" for one night viewing. Despite some real flaws and an terrible climax, it is still worth viewing. Panavision. (*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not at all bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being one of the key dozen or so science fiction writers of the 20th Century, relatively little of Robert Heinlein's work has been filmed and, with the exception of Starship Troopers (turned on its idealogical head), nothing from the 60s onwards, when his work started to carry more serious subtext. The Puppet Masters, a book from the 50s, is essentially fairly lightweight, albeit the invasion motif is similar to that of much 1950s science fiction in echoing a fear about the spread of communism - indeed, the parasitic slugs in Puppet Masters form a single entity - a commune if you will - and are therefore a fairly obvious analogue for the red menace. The novel was also fairly saucy for its time, with large chunks of the population having to peel down to their skimpies and beyond to prove that their clothing was not hiding the alien slugs. Well, as usual, Hollywood doesn't like to present the naked body to the viewing public, so the protagonists in this film version of Heinlein's story encounter more difficulty than they need to, simply by virtue of everybody keeping their clothes on. Apart from that, it follows the main sequence of events fairly faithfully, albeit updated to be more contemporary. Donald Sutherland is a serviceable "Old Man", even though he is quite different to how I imagined the character from the book (which hardly matters). There are several well-known albeit minor names in the secondary case, but the main leads are taken by Eric Thal and Julie Warner. Neither has had major success before or since (Warner had a lengthy run in Family Law) and, to be perfectly frank, this movie gives a good idea why - they have little charisma, and no chemistry despite the fact that they supposedly fall in love during the film. The story demands lead players who don't come across as insipid, but it doesn't get them. There is relatively little in terms of special effects, but what there is does the job. The major effect is the slugs themselves, and they are pleasingly unpleasant.. There is some offensive - and entirely unnecessary - use of the F-bomb. I don't mind it when it's there for a purpose: here it serves no purpose whatsoever. It doesn't advance the plot or illuminate character, it simply makes an unpleasant comment even more unpleasant, and it could have been omitted entirely without any detrimental effect on the movie. With some promotion, this movie could have been rather more successful than it was, albeit it came on the heels of what might have appeared to be similar epidemic-type stories. Perhaps Heinlein's time in movies is still to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shmobbie
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never read the novel this was movie was based on, or any of his other works for that matter, so I have nothing to compare this film to. I also haven't seen Invasion of the Body Snatchers (shame on me). With that said, I have one question: Why the HELL wouldn't you just invent some sort of kevlar armor that attaches to the back and neck in a comfortable fashion? You would think at least the armed forces dudes would have thought about it.. I mean c'mon boys. Anyway, I thought this was entertaining enough for a boring Tuesday afternoon. I've wanted to see this since when it was released and I was much younger and I'm glad I finally have. Fun concept.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An X-Files Movie in disguise?????
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TahitiLady
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I may be the only one, but I just watched this movie again tonight and it is completely like the X-Files! Does anyone else see this? I had seen it before, but had not seen the connection. But tonight I noticed it. Even the music is similar... Is this a set up for X Files, or what???? As I began to watch it tonight, hubby and I were amazed at how many X-Files references there were - there are all the elements of an X-Files story. We have both read the book - this has little if any resemblance to the book, but if you listen to the characters, and watch the way the story plays out - it is TOTALLY X-Files!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adequate sci-fi / action picture.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While "The Puppet Masters" is generally an entertaining movie with a good pace going for it, the simple fact is that it's much too belated an official adaptation of the Robert A. Heinlein novel. We've seen other, similar stories since, including of course "Invasion of the Body Snatchers" (although the Heinlein novel actually preceded the Jack Finney book of "Body Snatchers"). The presentation is definitely competent if not inspired. The creatures themselves are fairly cool, and visuals (specifically, the hive interior) are solid, and the script (credited to Ted Elliott, Terry Rossio, and David S. Goyer) is fairly intelligent, but the direction (by Stuart Orme) is nondescript. The music is generic stuff, as well. It's an alien invasion tale of starfish shaped slugs that land on Earth, attach themselves to the backs of humans, and control their actions. It doesn't take long for an infection (which starts in rural Iowa) to spread and spread. The man in charge of handling the crisis is Andrew Nivens (an amusing Donald Sutherland, who performs with wit and style), who heads up a covert agency that is an offshoot of the C.I.A. and which deals with "scientific intelligence". Also involved is Andrews' special agent son Sam (Eric Thal) and a scientist (the irresistibly cute Julie Warner) who specializes in theorizing about alien anatomy, believe it or not! The story isn't a bad one but just isn't that meaty; I'm told that, as is so often the case, that the book is a superior work of fiction. The filmmakers do their best to keep us interested in the characters, putting each of them in peril. The stars do good work (this wouldn't work as well were it not for Sutherland), and are well supported by a rich variety of top character actors and familiar faces: Keith David, Will Patton, Richard Belzer, Tom Mason, Yaphet Kotto, Gerry Bamman, Sam Anderson, Marshall Bell, Benjamin Mouton, Andrew Robinson, and Dale Dye (some of them, however, get no more than a few lines). Never boring but never that exciting, either, this does fall victim to the "more than one ending" clich&eacute; but does have its good moments too. Best recommended to undemanding fans of the genre. Six out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muppet Pastors
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunate enough to share a name with a brand of dirt-cheap Charles Band movies (but completely disconnected from them) I always figured that The Puppet Masters would be just as schlocky. It ain't art, but it is decent, low-brow, brainless entertainment. A bunch of alien manta-rays land in Iowa in a confusing opening sequence. The authorities arrive and discover that the locals are slowly being turned into mindless slaves to their alien hosts. Sound like the X-Files? It very much does play out like a 3-part episode with virtually the exact same character dynamic and interaction. The tagline for the movie is even 'Trust no one'. It also feels like a John Carpenter movie in some respects (the presence of Keith David, who really ought to be in every movie, only adds to this). And while it's a fairly non-epic movie it does feature some nice anamorphic Panavision photography and a bunch of character actors to keep you entertained in-between the silly plot developments. As well as feeling the X-Files it also comes across as an Invasion of the Body Snatchers rip-off, odd since co-star Donald Sutherland was in one of those movies. Four years later another very similar film called The Faculty also featured mind-controlling alien parasites, as well as the Brain Slugs from Futurama. But apparently it's taken from a novel of the same name by Robert A. Heinlein but with little in common, perhaps thanks to a zillion re-writes. These kinds of movies often have some kind of political subtext, but Puppet Masters embraces its low-brow but clever silliness and ends up a guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unworthy adaptation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heinlein's book is, I gather, pretty good. I'm not a purist and I don't demand that a movie adaptation follow the print version closely, and in fact I haven't read the novel. But this isn't very good. In plot it seems more an overblown version of "The X Files", except that the federal investigative team has more members, so that some can be taken over by the pods. It's hard to imagine Mulder or Scully zombified. In execution and style it's reminiscent of Carpenter's bombastic version of "The Thing." Gloopy organisms coil themselves around people's faces and boomerang from point to point. Or they auger themselves into a victim's back. They "attach themselves to the spinal cord" of the victim, so you can't tell if someone is possessed or not until you have them strip down the back of their shirts and take a look. Julie Warner's examination was the only bright spot in the film. It bears no resemblance whatever to the classic 1950s science fiction film, "The Invasion of the Body Snatchers." That much-imitated original (from Jack Finney's novel) began with a normal, steady state of affairs, grew through suspicion, developed into conviction, and led to action. This begins and ends with action, just in case the viewer might be bored during the first ten minutes of exposition and switch to an energy drink commercial just to watch cartoon figures leap around. The gloppy organisms, ripped off shamelessly and pointlessly from "Alien", are on abundant display. The sloppy, sticky, guts are picked apart, accompanied by a lot of scientific gobbledygook. Donald Sutherland's performance provides the eye of this hurricane of horror. He's quiet and controlled, when almost everyone else is running around berserk. The innards of those parasites are a true mess, and so is the film. I can't imagine that Heinlein, a good writer, produced a book that could be so popular and yet so execrable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Raising Sancho
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Puppet Masters" is a film that in it's first minutes promises to be an interesting and entertaining alien film that will scare you. After 30 minutes, you may change your mind. The beginning is smart, we have action in the first five minutes of running. It's difficult to watch a movie when there are 35345839465 characters, names and names of organizations; I felt very confused and got lost in the mystery many times. Directing is a strong thing, it doesn't seem to be an independent picture. Along with good directing, we have a smart background sound, building a suspenseful atmosphere. Also, this film is very different from most out there, and I can't explain why. It just feels very original and clever-- which, even thought, disappoints. Maybe if they put more story, less action and less screen time, it wouldn't have become this boring. See this only if you like action pictures with lack of story and you will probably enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Sci-Fi...please do this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What we are looking for in Sci-fi is a good story that enables us to join in. We want to be thrilled and have our wonderment, our inquisitiveness fed in large does where we can get it. Enter the Puppet Masters. I would have preferred a better title for this movie, but this one is very accurate and will do. This movie will allow you to see a lesser form of life but equally intelligent in its own way and try to dominate our species playing by our rules and on our playing field. What you will see is how well they go about it methodically making advancements and that is what successful war or invading your enemy is all about. These Alien play to win and we play to lose until we figure out this isn't a play over game if you lose. The acting brings it all close to home and the plot is easy to follow. The story is targeted to any age group and intriguing. To observe Aliens who use their brains instead of their weaponry leaves one frightened. It mentally and emotionally assaults mankind because we know we are the superior being on this planet. For something less in appearance to invade us and succeed is truly frightening not to mention a wake-up call. This was worthy of being a full blown move with a sequel and a prequel potential. I watch it with captions on because I like to hear every word spoken when the Aliens and the humans have a face to to face. Waste no more time reading this review...go watch the movie right now
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The alien take-over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This adaptation of a Robert A. Heinlein novel puts things right into gear when Eric Thal, Julie Warner and the ever-competent Donald Shutterland rush off to Ambrose, Iowa to investigate a registered UFO landing. However, collective-minded alien parasites have already begun to take over, turning humans into puppets to do their bidding. Writing trio Ted Elliott, Terry Rossio & David S. Goyer manage to tie things up fashionably, but also overworked themselves providing just about everything. Being a mixture of sci-fi, horror, thriller, action and drama, it's safe to say the wholesome feels a bit disjoint at places. The animatronic slug-like parasites by Roy Arbogast & Co. are a fine creation and get plenty of screen-time. Ambitious entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining, although sometimes flawed Science-Fiction Thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three top level government agents (Donald Sutherland, Eric Thal and Julie Warner) make a disturbing discovery that extraterrestrial beings have landed on earth and they quickly take over control of the residents in a small midwestern town. The agents find out, they can using their bodies and minds like puppets. While the creatures multiply and spread quickly, the agents have to think fast and destroy these seemingly unstoppable aliens. Directed by Stuart Orme (Best known for directing TV Movies or TV Shows) made an entertaining, science-fiction thriller with an amusing performance by Sutherland as the sardonic lead agent. While Thal and Warner certainly do well in their roles. Since this movie has good creature special make-up effects by Three Time Oscar-Winner:Greg Cannom (Blade, The Curious Case of Benjamin Button, Hannibal). The feature has good production values but somehow director Orme doesn't have much imagination during some of the rather tense sequences and the climax between Sutherland and Thal is a disappointment with cheap visual effects. The movie is certainly on its best in the first two-thirds of the picture. DVD has an fine anamorphic Widescreen (2.35:1) transfer and an good Dolby Surround 2.0 Sound. The DVD doesn't have any special features. "The Puppet Masters" came out in October 1994, it quickly became an box office disappointment and the movie had a lot of imitations before. Which the movie took the edge off and it never really caught any fire. Despite it is based on a novel by Robert A. Heinlein (Starship Troopers). Director Orme certainly wasted some talented actors in small roles like Yaphet Kotto, Richard Belzer, Andrew Robinson and Marshall Bell. Although it is nice to see Keith David (Best known for two John Carpenter movies, "The Thing" and "They Live") in a supporting role. Will Patton seems to be having an great time as the odd-ball scientist. Since the script is pretty good. Written by Ted Elliott (Aladdin, Godzilla "1998", Small Soldiers), Terry Rossio (The Pirates of the Caribbean series, Deja Vu, Shrek) and David S. Goyer (The Blade Trilogy, Dark City, Death Warrant). Although their script was heavily re-written by five screenwriters and the director as well. "The Puppet Masters" today, it is certainly an curio. Although exciting at times with an nice leading performances by Sutherland, Thal and Warner. Which Sutherland is no stranger to this kind of movie, since he was in the superior remake as the lead actor in "Invasion of the Body Snatchers", which it was directed by Philip Kaufman. Perphas some die-hard science fiction fans, it would make an great double feature with "Invasion of the Body Snatchers" and "The Puppet Masters" for one night viewing. Despite some real flaws and an terrible climax, it is still worth viewing. Panavision. (*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not at all bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being one of the key dozen or so science fiction writers of the 20th Century, relatively little of Robert Heinlein's work has been filmed and, with the exception of Starship Troopers (turned on its idealogical head), nothing from the 60s onwards, when his work started to carry more serious subtext. The Puppet Masters, a book from the 50s, is essentially fairly lightweight, albeit the invasion motif is similar to that of much 1950s science fiction in echoing a fear about the spread of communism - indeed, the parasitic slugs in Puppet Masters form a single entity - a commune if you will - and are therefore a fairly obvious analogue for the red menace. The novel was also fairly saucy for its time, with large chunks of the population having to peel down to their skimpies and beyond to prove that their clothing was not hiding the alien slugs. Well, as usual, Hollywood doesn't like to present the naked body to the viewing public, so the protagonists in this film version of Heinlein's story encounter more difficulty than they need to, simply by virtue of everybody keeping their clothes on. Apart from that, it follows the main sequence of events fairly faithfully, albeit updated to be more contemporary. Donald Sutherland is a serviceable "Old Man", even though he is quite different to how I imagined the character from the book (which hardly matters). There are several well-known albeit minor names in the secondary case, but the main leads are taken by Eric Thal and Julie Warner. Neither has had major success before or since (Warner had a lengthy run in Family Law) and, to be perfectly frank, this movie gives a good idea why - they have little charisma, and no chemistry despite the fact that they supposedly fall in love during the film. The story demands lead players who don't come across as insipid, but it doesn't get them. There is relatively little in terms of special effects, but what there is does the job. The major effect is the slugs themselves, and they are pleasingly unpleasant.. There is some offensive - and entirely unnecessary - use of the F-bomb. I don't mind it when it's there for a purpose: here it serves no purpose whatsoever. It doesn't advance the plot or illuminate character, it simply makes an unpleasant comment even more unpleasant, and it could have been omitted entirely without any detrimental effect on the movie. With some promotion, this movie could have been rather more successful than it was, albeit it came on the heels of what might have appeared to be similar epidemic-type stories. Perhaps Heinlein's time in movies is still to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shmobbie
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never read the novel this was movie was based on, or any of his other works for that matter, so I have nothing to compare this film to. I also haven't seen Invasion of the Body Snatchers (shame on me). With that said, I have one question: Why the HELL wouldn't you just invent some sort of kevlar armor that attaches to the back and neck in a comfortable fashion? You would think at least the armed forces dudes would have thought about it.. I mean c'mon boys. Anyway, I thought this was entertaining enough for a boring Tuesday afternoon. I've wanted to see this since when it was released and I was much younger and I'm glad I finally have. Fun concept.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An X-Files Movie in disguise?????
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TahitiLady
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I may be the only one, but I just watched this movie again tonight and it is completely like the X-Files! Does anyone else see this? I had seen it before, but had not seen the connection. But tonight I noticed it. Even the music is similar... Is this a set up for X Files, or what???? As I began to watch it tonight, hubby and I were amazed at how many X-Files references there were - there are all the elements of an X-Files story. We have both read the book - this has little if any resemblance to the book, but if you listen to the characters, and watch the way the story plays out - it is TOTALLY X-Files!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adequate sci-fi / action picture.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While "The Puppet Masters" is generally an entertaining movie with a good pace going for it, the simple fact is that it's much too belated an official adaptation of the Robert A. Heinlein novel. We've seen other, similar stories since, including of course "Invasion of the Body Snatchers" (although the Heinlein novel actually preceded the Jack Finney book of "Body Snatchers"). The presentation is definitely competent if not inspired. The creatures themselves are fairly cool, and visuals (specifically, the hive interior) are solid, and the script (credited to Ted Elliott, Terry Rossio, and David S. Goyer) is fairly intelligent, but the direction (by Stuart Orme) is nondescript. The music is generic stuff, as well. It's an alien invasion tale of starfish shaped slugs that land on Earth, attach themselves to the backs of humans, and control their actions. It doesn't take long for an infection (which starts in rural Iowa) to spread and spread. The man in charge of handling the crisis is Andrew Nivens (an amusing Donald Sutherland, who performs with wit and style), who heads up a covert agency that is an offshoot of the C.I.A. and which deals with "scientific intelligence". Also involved is Andrews' special agent son Sam (Eric Thal) and a scientist (the irresistibly cute Julie Warner) who specializes in theorizing about alien anatomy, believe it or not! The story isn't a bad one but just isn't that meaty; I'm told that, as is so often the case, that the book is a superior work of fiction. The filmmakers do their best to keep us interested in the characters, putting each of them in peril. The stars do good work (this wouldn't work as well were it not for Sutherland), and are well supported by a rich variety of top character actors and familiar faces: Keith David, Will Patton, Richard Belzer, Tom Mason, Yaphet Kotto, Gerry Bamman, Sam Anderson, Marshall Bell, Benjamin Mouton, Andrew Robinson, and Dale Dye (some of them, however, get no more than a few lines). Never boring but never that exciting, either, this does fall victim to the "more than one ending" clich&eacute; but does have its good moments too. Best recommended to undemanding fans of the genre. Six out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muppet Pastors
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunate enough to share a name with a brand of dirt-cheap Charles Band movies (but completely disconnected from them) I always figured that The Puppet Masters would be just as schlocky. It ain't art, but it is decent, low-brow, brainless entertainment. A bunch of alien manta-rays land in Iowa in a confusing opening sequence. The authorities arrive and discover that the locals are slowly being turned into mindless slaves to their alien hosts. Sound like the X-Files? It very much does play out like a 3-part episode with virtually the exact same character dynamic and interaction. The tagline for the movie is even 'Trust no one'. It also feels like a John Carpenter movie in some respects (the presence of Keith David, who really ought to be in every movie, only adds to this). And while it's a fairly non-epic movie it does feature some nice anamorphic Panavision photography and a bunch of character actors to keep you entertained in-between the silly plot developments. As well as feeling the X-Files it also comes across as an Invasion of the Body Snatchers rip-off, odd since co-star Donald Sutherland was in one of those movies. Four years later another very similar film called The Faculty also featured mind-controlling alien parasites, as well as the Brain Slugs from Futurama. But apparently it's taken from a novel of the same name by Robert A. Heinlein but with little in common, perhaps thanks to a zillion re-writes. These kinds of movies often have some kind of political subtext, but Puppet Masters embraces its low-brow but clever silliness and ends up a guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unworthy adaptation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heinlein's book is, I gather, pretty good. I'm not a purist and I don't demand that a movie adaptation follow the print version closely, and in fact I haven't read the novel. But this isn't very good. In plot it seems more an overblown version of "The X Files", except that the federal investigative team has more members, so that some can be taken over by the pods. It's hard to imagine Mulder or Scully zombified. In execution and style it's reminiscent of Carpenter's bombastic version of "The Thing." Gloopy organisms coil themselves around people's faces and boomerang from point to point. Or they auger themselves into a victim's back. They "attach themselves to the spinal cord" of the victim, so you can't tell if someone is possessed or not until you have them strip down the back of their shirts and take a look. Julie Warner's examination was the only bright spot in the film. It bears no resemblance whatever to the classic 1950s science fiction film, "The Invasion of the Body Snatchers." That much-imitated original (from Jack Finney's novel) began with a normal, steady state of affairs, grew through suspicion, developed into conviction, and led to action. This begins and ends with action, just in case the viewer might be bored during the first ten minutes of exposition and switch to an energy drink commercial just to watch cartoon figures leap around. The gloppy organisms, ripped off shamelessly and pointlessly from "Alien", are on abundant display. The sloppy, sticky, guts are picked apart, accompanied by a lot of scientific gobbledygook. Donald Sutherland's performance provides the eye of this hurricane of horror. He's quiet and controlled, when almost everyone else is running around berserk. The innards of those parasites are a true mess, and so is the film. I can't imagine that Heinlein, a good writer, produced a book that could be so popular and yet so execrable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Raising Sancho
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Puppet Masters" is a film that in it's first minutes promises to be an interesting and entertaining alien film that will scare you. After 30 minutes, you may change your mind. The beginning is smart, we have action in the first five minutes of running. It's difficult to watch a movie when there are 35345839465 characters, names and names of organizations; I felt very confused and got lost in the mystery many times. Directing is a strong thing, it doesn't seem to be an independent picture. Along with good directing, we have a smart background sound, building a suspenseful atmosphere. Also, this film is very different from most out there, and I can't explain why. It just feels very original and clever-- which, even thought, disappoints. Maybe if they put more story, less action and less screen time, it wouldn't have become this boring. See this only if you like action pictures with lack of story and you will probably enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Sci-Fi...please do this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What we are looking for in Sci-fi is a good story that enables us to join in. We want to be thrilled and have our wonderment, our inquisitiveness fed in large does where we can get it. Enter the Puppet Masters. I would have preferred a better title for this movie, but this one is very accurate and will do. This movie will allow you to see a lesser form of life but equally intelligent in its own way and try to dominate our species playing by our rules and on our playing field. What you will see is how well they go about it methodically making advancements and that is what successful war or invading your enemy is all about. These Alien play to win and we play to lose until we figure out this isn't a play over game if you lose. The acting brings it all close to home and the plot is easy to follow. The story is targeted to any age group and intriguing. To observe Aliens who use their brains instead of their weaponry leaves one frightened. It mentally and emotionally assaults mankind because we know we are the superior being on this planet. For something less in appearance to invade us and succeed is truly frightening not to mention a wake-up call. This was worthy of being a full blown move with a sequel and a prequel potential. I watch it with captions on because I like to hear every word spoken when the Aliens and the humans have a face to to face. Waste no more time reading this review...go watch the movie right now
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The alien take-over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This adaptation of a Robert A. Heinlein novel puts things right into gear when Eric Thal, Julie Warner and the ever-competent Donald Shutterland rush off to Ambrose, Iowa to investigate a registered UFO landing. However, collective-minded alien parasites have already begun to take over, turning humans into puppets to do their bidding. Writing trio Ted Elliott, Terry Rossio & David S. Goyer manage to tie things up fashionably, but also overworked themselves providing just about everything. Being a mixture of sci-fi, horror, thriller, action and drama, it's safe to say the wholesome feels a bit disjoint at places. The animatronic slug-like parasites by Roy Arbogast & Co. are a fine creation and get plenty of screen-time. Ambitious entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining, although sometimes flawed Science-Fiction Thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three top level government agents (Donald Sutherland, Eric Thal and Julie Warner) make a disturbing discovery that extraterrestrial beings have landed on earth and they quickly take over control of the residents in a small midwestern town. The agents find out, they can using their bodies and minds like puppets. While the creatures multiply and spread quickly, the agents have to think fast and destroy these seemingly unstoppable aliens. Directed by Stuart Orme (Best known for directing TV Movies or TV Shows) made an entertaining, science-fiction thriller with an amusing performance by Sutherland as the sardonic lead agent. While Thal and Warner certainly do well in their roles. Since this movie has good creature special make-up effects by Three Time Oscar-Winner:Greg Cannom (Blade, The Curious Case of Benjamin Button, Hannibal). The feature has good production values but somehow director Orme doesn't have much imagination during some of the rather tense sequences and the climax between Sutherland and Thal is a disappointment with cheap visual effects. The movie is certainly on its best in the first two-thirds of the picture. DVD has an fine anamorphic Widescreen (2.35:1) transfer and an good Dolby Surround 2.0 Sound. The DVD doesn't have any special features. "The Puppet Masters" came out in October 1994, it quickly became an box office disappointment and the movie had a lot of imitations before. Which the movie took the edge off and it never really caught any fire. Despite it is based on a novel by Robert A. Heinlein (Starship Troopers). Director Orme certainly wasted some talented actors in small roles like Yaphet Kotto, Richard Belzer, Andrew Robinson and Marshall Bell. Although it is nice to see Keith David (Best known for two John Carpenter movies, "The Thing" and "They Live") in a supporting role. Will Patton seems to be having an great time as the odd-ball scientist. Since the script is pretty good. Written by Ted Elliott (Aladdin, Godzilla "1998", Small Soldiers), Terry Rossio (The Pirates of the Caribbean series, Deja Vu, Shrek) and David S. Goyer (The Blade Trilogy, Dark City, Death Warrant). Although their script was heavily re-written by five screenwriters and the director as well. "The Puppet Masters" today, it is certainly an curio. Although exciting at times with an nice leading performances by Sutherland, Thal and Warner. Which Sutherland is no stranger to this kind of movie, since he was in the superior remake as the lead actor in "Invasion of the Body Snatchers", which it was directed by Philip Kaufman. Perphas some die-hard science fiction fans, it would make an great double feature with "Invasion of the Body Snatchers" and "The Puppet Masters" for one night viewing. Despite some real flaws and an terrible climax, it is still worth viewing. Panavision. (*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not at all bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being one of the key dozen or so science fiction writers of the 20th Century, relatively little of Robert Heinlein's work has been filmed and, with the exception of Starship Troopers (turned on its idealogical head), nothing from the 60s onwards, when his work started to carry more serious subtext. The Puppet Masters, a book from the 50s, is essentially fairly lightweight, albeit the invasion motif is similar to that of much 1950s science fiction in echoing a fear about the spread of communism - indeed, the parasitic slugs in Puppet Masters form a single entity - a commune if you will - and are therefore a fairly obvious analogue for the red menace. The novel was also fairly saucy for its time, with large chunks of the population having to peel down to their skimpies and beyond to prove that their clothing was not hiding the alien slugs. Well, as usual, Hollywood doesn't like to present the naked body to the viewing public, so the protagonists in this film version of Heinlein's story encounter more difficulty than they need to, simply by virtue of everybody keeping their clothes on. Apart from that, it follows the main sequence of events fairly faithfully, albeit updated to be more contemporary. Donald Sutherland is a serviceable "Old Man", even though he is quite different to how I imagined the character from the book (which hardly matters). There are several well-known albeit minor names in the secondary case, but the main leads are taken by Eric Thal and Julie Warner. Neither has had major success before or since (Warner had a lengthy run in Family Law) and, to be perfectly frank, this movie gives a good idea why - they have little charisma, and no chemistry despite the fact that they supposedly fall in love during the film. The story demands lead players who don't come across as insipid, but it doesn't get them. There is relatively little in terms of special effects, but what there is does the job. The major effect is the slugs themselves, and they are pleasingly unpleasant.. There is some offensive - and entirely unnecessary - use of the F-bomb. I don't mind it when it's there for a purpose: here it serves no purpose whatsoever. It doesn't advance the plot or illuminate character, it simply makes an unpleasant comment even more unpleasant, and it could have been omitted entirely without any detrimental effect on the movie. With some promotion, this movie could have been rather more successful than it was, albeit it came on the heels of what might have appeared to be similar epidemic-type stories. Perhaps Heinlein's time in movies is still to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shmobbie
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never read the novel this was movie was based on, or any of his other works for that matter, so I have nothing to compare this film to. I also haven't seen Invasion of the Body Snatchers (shame on me). With that said, I have one question: Why the HELL wouldn't you just invent some sort of kevlar armor that attaches to the back and neck in a comfortable fashion? You would think at least the armed forces dudes would have thought about it.. I mean c'mon boys. Anyway, I thought this was entertaining enough for a boring Tuesday afternoon. I've wanted to see this since when it was released and I was much younger and I'm glad I finally have. Fun concept.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An X-Files Movie in disguise?????
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TahitiLady
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I may be the only one, but I just watched this movie again tonight and it is completely like the X-Files! Does anyone else see this? I had seen it before, but had not seen the connection. But tonight I noticed it. Even the music is similar... Is this a set up for X Files, or what???? As I began to watch it tonight, hubby and I were amazed at how many X-Files references there were - there are all the elements of an X-Files story. We have both read the book - this has little if any resemblance to the book, but if you listen to the characters, and watch the way the story plays out - it is TOTALLY X-Files!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Adequate sci-fi / action picture.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While "The Puppet Masters" is generally an entertaining movie with a good pace going for it, the simple fact is that it's much too belated an official adaptation of the Robert A. Heinlein novel. We've seen other, similar stories since, including of course "Invasion of the Body Snatchers" (although the Heinlein novel actually preceded the Jack Finney book of "Body Snatchers"). The presentation is definitely competent if not inspired. The creatures themselves are fairly cool, and visuals (specifically, the hive interior) are solid, and the script (credited to Ted Elliott, Terry Rossio, and David S. Goyer) is fairly intelligent, but the direction (by Stuart Orme) is nondescript. The music is generic stuff, as well. It's an alien invasion tale of starfish shaped slugs that land on Earth, attach themselves to the backs of humans, and control their actions. It doesn't take long for an infection (which starts in rural Iowa) to spread and spread. The man in charge of handling the crisis is Andrew Nivens (an amusing Donald Sutherland, who performs with wit and style), who heads up a covert agency that is an offshoot of the C.I.A. and which deals with "scientific intelligence". Also involved is Andrews' special agent son Sam (Eric Thal) and a scientist (the irresistibly cute Julie Warner) who specializes in theorizing about alien anatomy, believe it or not! The story isn't a bad one but just isn't that meaty; I'm told that, as is so often the case, that the book is a superior work of fiction. The filmmakers do their best to keep us interested in the characters, putting each of them in peril. The stars do good work (this wouldn't work as well were it not for Sutherland), and are well supported by a rich variety of top character actors and familiar faces: Keith David, Will Patton, Richard Belzer, Tom Mason, Yaphet Kotto, Gerry Bamman, Sam Anderson, Marshall Bell, Benjamin Mouton, Andrew Robinson, and Dale Dye (some of them, however, get no more than a few lines). Never boring but never that exciting, either, this does fall victim to the "more than one ending" clich&eacute; but does have its good moments too. Best recommended to undemanding fans of the genre. Six out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Muppet Pastors
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunate enough to share a name with a brand of dirt-cheap Charles Band movies (but completely disconnected from them) I always figured that The Puppet Masters would be just as schlocky. It ain't art, but it is decent, low-brow, brainless entertainment. A bunch of alien manta-rays land in Iowa in a confusing opening sequence. The authorities arrive and discover that the locals are slowly being turned into mindless slaves to their alien hosts. Sound like the X-Files? It very much does play out like a 3-part episode with virtually the exact same character dynamic and interaction. The tagline for the movie is even 'Trust no one'. It also feels like a John Carpenter movie in some respects (the presence of Keith David, who really ought to be in every movie, only adds to this). And while it's a fairly non-epic movie it does feature some nice anamorphic Panavision photography and a bunch of character actors to keep you entertained in-between the silly plot developments. As well as feeling the X-Files it also comes across as an Invasion of the Body Snatchers rip-off, odd since co-star Donald Sutherland was in one of those movies. Four years later another very similar film called The Faculty also featured mind-controlling alien parasites, as well as the Brain Slugs from Futurama. But apparently it's taken from a novel of the same name by Robert A. Heinlein but with little in common, perhaps thanks to a zillion re-writes. These kinds of movies often have some kind of political subtext, but Puppet Masters embraces its low-brow but clever silliness and ends up a guilty pleasure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unworthy adaptation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heinlein's book is, I gather, pretty good. I'm not a purist and I don't demand that a movie adaptation follow the print version closely, and in fact I haven't read the novel. But this isn't very good. In plot it seems more an overblown version of "The X Files", except that the federal investigative team has more members, so that some can be taken over by the pods. It's hard to imagine Mulder or Scully zombified. In execution and style it's reminiscent of Carpenter's bombastic version of "The Thing." Gloopy organisms coil themselves around people's faces and boomerang from point to point. Or they auger themselves into a victim's back. They "attach themselves to the spinal cord" of the victim, so you can't tell if someone is possessed or not until you have them strip down the back of their shirts and take a look. Julie Warner's examination was the only bright spot in the film. It bears no resemblance whatever to the classic 1950s science fiction film, "The Invasion of the Body Snatchers." That much-imitated original (from Jack Finney's novel) began with a normal, steady state of affairs, grew through suspicion, developed into conviction, and led to action. This begins and ends with action, just in case the viewer might be bored during the first ten minutes of exposition and switch to an energy drink commercial just to watch cartoon figures leap around. The gloppy organisms, ripped off shamelessly and pointlessly from "Alien", are on abundant display. The sloppy, sticky, guts are picked apart, accompanied by a lot of scientific gobbledygook. Donald Sutherland's performance provides the eye of this hurricane of horror. He's quiet and controlled, when almost everyone else is running around berserk. The innards of those parasites are a true mess, and so is the film. I can't imagine that Heinlein, a good writer, produced a book that could be so popular and yet so execrable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Raising Sancho
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Puppet Masters" is a film that in it's first minutes promises to be an interesting and entertaining alien film that will scare you. After 30 minutes, you may change your mind. The beginning is smart, we have action in the first five minutes of running. It's difficult to watch a movie when there are 35345839465 characters, names and names of organizations; I felt very confused and got lost in the mystery many times. Directing is a strong thing, it doesn't seem to be an independent picture. Along with good directing, we have a smart background sound, building a suspenseful atmosphere. Also, this film is very different from most out there, and I can't explain why. It just feels very original and clever-- which, even thought, disappoints. Maybe if they put more story, less action and less screen time, it wouldn't have become this boring. See this only if you like action pictures with lack of story and you will probably enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding Sci-Fi...please do this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What we are looking for in Sci-fi is a good story that enables us to join in. We want to be thrilled and have our wonderment, our inquisitiveness fed in large does where we can get it. Enter the Puppet Masters. I would have preferred a better title for this movie, but this one is very accurate and will do. This movie will allow you to see a lesser form of life but equally intelligent in its own way and try to dominate our species playing by our rules and on our playing field. What you will see is how well they go about it methodically making advancements and that is what successful war or invading your enemy is all about. These Alien play to win and we play to lose until we figure out this isn't a play over game if you lose. The acting brings it all close to home and the plot is easy to follow. The story is targeted to any age group and intriguing. To observe Aliens who use their brains instead of their weaponry leaves one frightened. It mentally and emotionally assaults mankind because we know we are the superior being on this planet. For something less in appearance to invade us and succeed is truly frightening not to mention a wake-up call. This was worthy of being a full blown move with a sequel and a prequel potential. I watch it with captions on because I like to hear every word spoken when the Aliens and the humans have a face to to face. Waste no more time reading this review...go watch the movie right now
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The alien take-over...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This adaptation of a Robert A. Heinlein novel puts things right into gear when Eric Thal, Julie Warner and the ever-competent Donald Shutterland rush off to Ambrose, Iowa to investigate a registered UFO landing. However, collective-minded alien parasites have already begun to take over, turning humans into puppets to do their bidding. Writing trio Ted Elliott, Terry Rossio & David S. Goyer manage to tie things up fashionably, but also overworked themselves providing just about everything. Being a mixture of sci-fi, horror, thriller, action and drama, it's safe to say the wholesome feels a bit disjoint at places. The animatronic slug-like parasites by Roy Arbogast & Co. are a fine creation and get plenty of screen-time. Ambitious entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Entertaining, although sometimes flawed Science-Fiction Thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three top level government agents (Donald Sutherland, Eric Thal and Julie Warner) make a disturbing discovery that extraterrestrial beings have landed on earth and they quickly take over control of the residents in a small midwestern town. The agents find out, they can using their bodies and minds like puppets. While the creatures multiply and spread quickly, the agents have to think fast and destroy these seemingly unstoppable aliens. Directed by Stuart Orme (Best known for directing TV Movies or TV Shows) made an entertaining, science-fiction thriller with an amusing performance by Sutherland as the sardonic lead agent. While Thal and Warner certainly do well in their roles. Since this movie has good creature special make-up effects by Three Time Oscar-Winner:Greg Cannom (Blade, The Curious Case of Benjamin Button, Hannibal). The feature has good production values but somehow director Orme doesn't have much imagination during some of the rather tense sequences and the climax between Sutherland and Thal is a disappointment with cheap visual effects. The movie is certainly on its best in the first two-thirds of the picture. DVD has an fine anamorphic Widescreen (2.35:1) transfer and an good Dolby Surround 2.0 Sound. The DVD doesn't have any special features. "The Puppet Masters" came out in October 1994, it quickly became an box office disappointment and the movie had a lot of imitations before. Which the movie took the edge off and it never really caught any fire. Despite it is based on a novel by Robert A. Heinlein (Starship Troopers). Director Orme certainly wasted some talented actors in small roles like Yaphet Kotto, Richard Belzer, Andrew Robinson and Marshall Bell. Although it is nice to see Keith David (Best known for two John Carpenter movies, "The Thing" and "They Live") in a supporting role. Will Patton seems to be having an great time as the odd-ball scientist. Since the script is pretty good. Written by Ted Elliott (Aladdin, Godzilla "1998", Small Soldiers), Terry Rossio (The Pirates of the Caribbean series, Deja Vu, Shrek) and David S. Goyer (The Blade Trilogy, Dark City, Death Warrant). Although their script was heavily re-written by five screenwriters and the director as well. "The Puppet Masters" today, it is certainly an curio. Although exciting at times with an nice leading performances by Sutherland, Thal and Warner. Which Sutherland is no stranger to this kind of movie, since he was in the superior remake as the lead actor in "Invasion of the Body Snatchers", which it was directed by Philip Kaufman. Perphas some die-hard science fiction fans, it would make an great double feature with "Invasion of the Body Snatchers" and "The Puppet Masters" for one night viewing. Despite some real flaws and an terrible climax, it is still worth viewing. Panavision. (*** &frac12;/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not at all bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being one of the key dozen or so science fiction writers of the 20th Century, relatively little of Robert Heinlein's work has been filmed and, with the exception of Starship Troopers (turned on its idealogical head), nothing from the 60s onwards, when his work started to carry more serious subtext. The Puppet Masters, a book from the 50s, is essentially fairly lightweight, albeit the invasion motif is similar to that of much 1950s science fiction in echoing a fear about the spread of communism - indeed, the parasitic slugs in Puppet Masters form a single entity - a commune if you will - and are therefore a fairly obvious analogue for the red menace. The novel was also fairly saucy for its time, with large chunks of the population having to peel down to their skimpies and beyond to prove that their clothing was not hiding the alien slugs. Well, as usual, Hollywood doesn't like to present the naked body to the viewing public, so the protagonists in this film version of Heinlein's story encounter more difficulty than they need to, simply by virtue of everybody keeping their clothes on. Apart from that, it follows the main sequence of events fairly faithfully, albeit updated to be more contemporary. Donald Sutherland is a serviceable "Old Man", even though he is quite different to how I imagined the character from the book (which hardly matters). There are several well-known albeit minor names in the secondary case, but the main leads are taken by Eric Thal and Julie Warner. Neither has had major success before or since (Warner had a lengthy run in Family Law) and, to be perfectly frank, this movie gives a good idea why - they have little charisma, and no chemistry despite the fact that they supposedly fall in love during the film. The story demands lead players who don't come across as insipid, but it doesn't get them. There is relatively little in terms of special effects, but what there is does the job. The major effect is the slugs themselves, and they are pleasingly unpleasant.. There is some offensive - and entirely unnecessary - use of the F-bomb. I don't mind it when it's there for a purpose: here it serves no purpose whatsoever. It doesn't advance the plot or illuminate character, it simply makes an unpleasant comment even more unpleasant, and it could have been omitted entirely without any detrimental effect on the movie. With some promotion, this movie could have been rather more successful than it was, albeit it came on the heels of what might have appeared to be similar epidemic-type stories. Perhaps Heinlein's time in movies is still to come.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hmmm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shmobbie
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never read the novel this was movie was based on, or any of his other works for that matter, so I have nothing to compare this film to. I also haven't seen Invasion of the Body Snatchers (shame on me). With that said, I have one question: Why the HELL wouldn't you just invent some sort of kevlar armor that attaches to the back and neck in a comfortable fashion? You would think at least the armed forces dudes would have thought about it.. I mean c'mon boys. Anyway, I thought this was entertaining enough for a boring Tuesday afternoon. I've wanted to see this since when it was released and I was much younger and I'm glad I finally have. Fun concept.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An X-Files Movie in disguise?????
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TahitiLady
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I may be the only one, but I just watched this movie again tonight and it is completely like the X-Files! Does anyone else see this? I had seen it before, but had not seen the connection. But tonight I noticed it. Even the music is similar... Is this a set up for X Files, or what???? As I began to watch it tonight, hubby and I were amazed at how many X-Files references there were - there are all the elements of an X-Files story. We have both read the book - this has little if any resemblance to the book, but if you listen to the characters, and watch the way the story plays out - it is TOTALLY X-Files!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
