<filme>
 <id>
  843
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0053271
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1959
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Felpudo, O C&atilde;o Feiticeiro
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A teenage boy is cursed with periodically turning into an sheepdog.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Through an ancient spell, a boy changes into a sheepdog and back again. It seems to happen at inopportune times and the spell can only be broken by an act of bravery....
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   mailman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   girl next door
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   role reversal
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   slapstick comedy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   little brother
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Charles Barton
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Bill Walsh
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Lillie Hayward
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Fred MacMurray
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jean Hagen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Tommy Kirk
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A flat fantasy that plods along at an insufferably slow pace before sparking into life right at the end, when it's far too late. Tommy Kirk is a kid who finds a magic ring that transforms him into a talking dog; in this furry form he overhears crooks planning a robbery at the local missile plant. If it sounds like one of those daft, seemingly drug-induced Disney capers that inevitably ends in a car chase, that's because it is. Unfortunately it's not much fun bar the hilarious animated credits sequence and odd moment like the dog putting on pajamas, cleaning his teeth and driving a car. It's not enough. Despite the utter stupidity of the film's plot this is stiff, boring and woodenly acted stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird and Funny "Shaggy Dog" Story Of Teen Age Lycanthropy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a hoot for anyone who understands the term " a shaggy dog story" or anyone who knows folklore. first off the term "shaggy dog", means a ridiculous or exaggerated story so even the title is imaginative and clever. anyone who has delved into folklore knows all about stories of lycanthropy or the legend of the Borgia family. all of this mixed into the whole fifties "i was a teen age..." formula. the film is good laughs and not a bad excursion into contemporary folklore. i've always felt that Disney comedies like this are often underrated for their cleverness. i guess because so much of the comedy is played for dumb laughs it's hard to take it all seriously, which you're not supposed to really, because it's Disney you're supposed to enjoy and have fun. this is a great comedy, semi-horror, teen flick that actually holds up well to sophisticated screw ball comedies. a genuine argument can be made for this film that it is one of cinema's better comedies. certainly with all of it's gimmicks and effects, it's very cinematic. one major note here for viewers. this film was originally filmed in glorious B&W and is most effective when viewed in B&W. avoid the horrible colorized, tinted versions which disarm the effectiveness of it's nostalgia and photography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bow! Wow!... It's A Doggy Delight!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I'll be dog-gone. It was my sweet, little, 8 year-old nephew, TeddyBear, who excitedly picked out The Shaggy Dog at the local video store for the two of us to watch together.... And, you know what? I'm glad he did. Regardless of its gaping plot holes and its laughably cheap make-up effects, The Shaggy Dog's script was definitely first-rate, fast-paced, and, generally, a lot of goofy, family-oriented fun-fun-fun. Packed with plenty of hilarious one-liners, slapstick chases and uproarious sight gags, The Shaggy Dog also featured an excellent cast who competently brought this 1950s Comedy right in on the mark. The Shaggy Dog's story centers around the zany experiences of white, suburban teen, Wilby Daniels (a bona-fide geek) who, always at a loss for words around the girls, suddenly finds himself in a very hairy situation when the unknown powers of an antique "magical" ring transforms him into (of all things) an Old English Sheepdog. (You go figure) Check it out. You'll be dog-gone glad that you did.... Arf! Arf!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and amusing entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I re-watched this film as I often do with my childhood favourites. I loved The Shaggy Dog as a child, and at 18 I still do. But I wasn't so taken with the spy subplot, thinking it went on for too long and took up too much time in the narrative. Also, the film feels a little too long. However, despite how silly some of it it never fails to be amusing and charming, which is more than good enough for me. The film's production values are decent and hold up fairly well, while Paul J.Smith's score is jaunty and dynamic. The script is snappy as well and the story doesn't fall into the trap of being too predictable complete with a number of very entertaining scenes especially the pursuit in the police car, hectic it may be but also entertaining. The direction is pretty good too, as is the acting. Fred MacMurray is likable with some fun acting chops, while Jean Hagen shows some great comic timing. The real star though is Tommy Kirk, who is just great here. All in all, a fun, charming and amusing movie. 8/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An early live action Disney movie with its share of flaws, but also plenty of heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw lots of Disney animated films from different eras as a kid, back in the '90s, but never heard of this particular live action flick from Walt Disney Productions. I remember when the remake starring Tim Allen came out in 2006 and I saw a trailer for it, but I didn't know that film was a remake at the time. I still haven't seen that version, and have known for sometime now that it's not all that popular, but now I have finally seen the original 1959 version of "The Shaggy Dog", with a cast featuring Fred MacMurray and several cast members of "The Mickey Mouse Club". I didn't think this movie would be amazing family entertainment, since it doesn't seem to have that kind of reputation, but I was expecting it to be a 7/10 for me, which it is. Wilby Daniels is a teenager who likes to conduct experiments in the basement, but his father, Wilson, does not like this, and after Wilby accidentally launches a missile from the basement, Wilson tells him to clear out all his experiments. A new family moves into the neighbourhood, and Wilby and his friend, Buzz Miller, soon meet the daughter of the family, Franceska Andrassy. They also meet the family's sheep dog. Wilby, Buzz, and Franceska go to the museum together, but Wilby is separated from the other two. He meets Professor Plumcutt, a man he used to know, who tells him about his beliefs in ancient magic, including shape-shifting. Wilby ends up accidentally bringing home a mystical ring, which turns him into the Andrassy dog! This is not a good thing, since his father hates dogs! He sneaks out to tell Plumcutt what has happened, and learns from him that he is now under a spell, which will turn him back and forth from human to dog, and the only way to break this spell is through a selfless act of heroism! As a comedy, this 1959 live action Disney flick is far from consistent, but I did laugh a number of times, starting around the beginning when Wilby has his missile in the basement and accidentally launches it from there, obviously putting holes in every floor above! More laughs come after Wilby turns into a dog, including the scenes where Officer Hanson hears the teenager talk to him while in dog form. I didn't usually laugh that hard, but those parts were definitely exceptions, and were not the only ones! The acting in "The Shaggy Dog" is mostly not that impressive, and the plot isn't the most interesting, but in both cases, I've certainly seen worse. The dance sequence is maybe a bit tedious, and during parts like that, it was somewhat of a struggle for me to stay into it, but eventually, that changed, as the story gets better and the suspense builds up! For the rest of the film, I had no trouble staying into it, even if it wears out its welcome just a BIT towards the end. So, while by no means a masterpiece, this original "Shaggy Dog" probably still has enough to please the family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A shaggy dog tail of a film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Over the last few days,I've been in the mood of watching a fun family film.As I went looking at my DVDs,I spotted a film that my dad had given to me a while ago with Fred MacMurray-who I hugely enjoyed seeing in the excellent Absent-Minded Professor starring in. The plot: After having gotten back from being left behind at a local museum by his "best friend" and a new next door neighbour (who he secretly has a crush on)Wilby Daniels discovers that a strange looking ancient ring has ended up in one of his jean pockets.When he reads out the inscription on the ring,he turns into his neighbours dog!!.Due to his father saying that he will shoot any dog that comes into the house (this is because he had a lot of trouble with dogs when he was a postman.) Because of this,Wilby decides to stay with the newly-arrived neighbours.Whilst there,Daniels discovers that the neighbours are not as sweet as they seem... View on the film: Whilst the last half an hour of the film has a very entertaining Mad Mad Mad Mad World-style chase,an odd thing about the screenplay by Bill Walsh and Lillie Hayward,is that they offer no explanation as to how the neighbours dog returns when Wilby turns back into a human.Also,perhaps due to the films age,the ending (where Wilby seems pretty happy to hear that the girl he had a crush on is being sent back and questioned by the CIA!.) gives the movie's ending a surprisingly nasty taste. Although he is not given as bigger role as I would have liked,Fred MacMurray gives a good performance as Wilson Daniels,who has trouble dealing with all the crazy chaos around him.Tommy Kirk also gives a very strong performance as Wilby,by showing all the frustrations that he has to try and manage,because of his transformation. Final view on the film: A fun film for the whole family,with very good performances from MacMurray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shaggy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one had me laughing so hard,, i seriously cannot remember laughing so hard at a movie in a long long time,, for starters,, the look on the cop's face throughout the movie was priceless. Fred MacMurray was great a the dad,, as he had all of those years on My Three Sons. Anette Funicello was also pretty darn good in this,, i loved the dog driving through town and waving at the police officers, as he went by,, then you got the dog telling his dad that he really is his son,, and the shaking the hand bit,, just put me on the floor laughing,, i kinda wish that Hollywood would make something more like this in the future,, even if it's only once a year,, go black and white,, get back to old school, this movie was just a pure heartfelt joy to watch, and i think that everyone should at least watch this once for some good natured laughter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really funny and entertaining late 50's Disney live action classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cranky mailman Wilson Daniels (a delightfully charming portrayal by Fred MacMurray) has a vehement disdain for dogs. Things get hairy (both literally and figuratively) when his likable misfit son Wilby (a wonderfully amiable performance by Tommy Kirk) gets stricken by a magical ring that causes him to transform into a big shaggy sheepdog. Wilby has to perform an act of heroism by thwarting an international spy ring so he can break the spell. Director Charles Bartun, working from a witty and good-natured script by Bill Walsh and Lillie Haward, relates the zany plot at a constant zippy pace, maintains a pleasant and frothy tone throughout, and stages the slapstick gags with praiseworthy brio (amusing comic highlights include the dog disrupting a swanky dance party, a hapless patrolman's sidesplitting constant run-ins with the talking pooch, and a marvelously wacky last reel car chase). Moreover, the characters are well-developed, sympathetic, and above all even pretty believable as everyday folks who find themselves caught up in a fantastic situation. Extra kudos are in order for the uniformly sound acting from a tip-top cast: MacMurray and Kirk shine in the lead roles, with fine support from Jean Hagen as Wilson's doting wife Freeda, Kevin Corcoran as Wilby's mischievous little squirt kid brother Moochie, Tim Considine as Wilby's hip pal Buzz Miller, Roberta Shore as fetching French hottie Franceska Andrassy, Annette Funicello as the sweet and adorable Allison D'Allessio, Cecil Kellaway as the jolly Professor Plumcutt, and Strother Martin as no-count criminal Thurm. Sam the dog is simply amazing as the titular canine. Legendary voice actor Paul Frees provides the narration and even has an uncredited minor part as disbelieving psychiatrist Dr. J.W. Galvin. The theme song is an absolute groovy gas. Edward Colman's crisp black and white cinematography makes neat occasional use of fades and dissolves. Endearing family fare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i liked it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    sure,it may seem cheesy by todays' standards,but it's good clean fun for the whole family,for the most part.really young children might be a bit scared from a few scenes,but other than that,it's fun for everyone.i chuckled quite a bit t some of the comedic bits,and i also thought the story was interesting.it's not just about the Shaggy Dog.there's another story in there as well.some of the facial expressions and reactions may seem a bit hokey and overdone,but so what.that was how they acted back then. if i recall correctly,this was the first motion picture made by Disney.i wouldn't say the comedic parts are laugh out loud,rolling in the aisles funny.,but they were certainly amusing.you could do a lot worse with 102 minutes or so.my vote for The Shaggy Dog: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly comedy is dated stuff that looks more like a made-for-TV movie than a feature length hit...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Doyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Times have certainly changed. Here we have a Disney live action feature film that looks and sounds more like a TV sit-com (and a below par one at that), and yet it grossed $8,000,000 at the box-office at a time when any film that grossed more than a few million was considered a box-office hit. At least FRED MacMURRAY does a professional job as the bumbling father of TOMMY KIRK and KEVIN CORCORAN, a dog-hater with a shotgun who gets itchy around the collar if a dog is even remotely close to his territory. He provides some genuine chuckles with his comic touch on a role that could well have seemed anything but sympathetic. The boys do OK too, especially Kevin Corcoran as the younger brother who always wanted a dog and promises to take good care of his brother who has magically transformed into one. The plot is pretty threadbare but it does provide some very amusing moments--such as the one where Tommy Kirk gets into his pajamas and brushes his teeth while in the guise of the shaggy dog. The transmutation has taken place because he read aloud the inscription on a ring that had once belonged to the Borgias and whose Latin words were meant to change the sayer into a dog. What weakens the story is the whole spy subplot which has him overhearing the spies while a dog and then reverting to his own body before he can get away from their presence. All of this leads to a hectic chase that has the baffled police force falling all over themselves to catch a shaggy dog driving a stolen police car. It's silly stuff and never overcomes the feel of a lame sitcom from the innocent '50s, complete with people like ANNETTE FUNICELLO, TIM CONSIDINE, JEAN HAGEN (a far cry from her "Singin' in the Rain" dumb blonde), and JAMES WESTERFIELD as the policeman who can't believe his own eyes. It passes the time pleasantly enough but you have to be willing to view it in the context of its '50s era innocence. And contrary to what some here believe, this was not Disney's first live action film--not by a long shot. However, it was one of the few to make a bundle at the box-office for some unknown reason and gave a boost to the sagging career of Fred MacMurray at a time when his film career was on the skids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A flat fantasy that plods along at an insufferably slow pace before sparking into life right at the end, when it's far too late. Tommy Kirk is a kid who finds a magic ring that transforms him into a talking dog; in this furry form he overhears crooks planning a robbery at the local missile plant. If it sounds like one of those daft, seemingly drug-induced Disney capers that inevitably ends in a car chase, that's because it is. Unfortunately it's not much fun bar the hilarious animated credits sequence and odd moment like the dog putting on pajamas, cleaning his teeth and driving a car. It's not enough. Despite the utter stupidity of the film's plot this is stiff, boring and woodenly acted stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird and Funny "Shaggy Dog" Story Of Teen Age Lycanthropy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a hoot for anyone who understands the term " a shaggy dog story" or anyone who knows folklore. first off the term "shaggy dog", means a ridiculous or exaggerated story so even the title is imaginative and clever. anyone who has delved into folklore knows all about stories of lycanthropy or the legend of the Borgia family. all of this mixed into the whole fifties "i was a teen age..." formula. the film is good laughs and not a bad excursion into contemporary folklore. i've always felt that Disney comedies like this are often underrated for their cleverness. i guess because so much of the comedy is played for dumb laughs it's hard to take it all seriously, which you're not supposed to really, because it's Disney you're supposed to enjoy and have fun. this is a great comedy, semi-horror, teen flick that actually holds up well to sophisticated screw ball comedies. a genuine argument can be made for this film that it is one of cinema's better comedies. certainly with all of it's gimmicks and effects, it's very cinematic. one major note here for viewers. this film was originally filmed in glorious B&W and is most effective when viewed in B&W. avoid the horrible colorized, tinted versions which disarm the effectiveness of it's nostalgia and photography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bow! Wow!... It's A Doggy Delight!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I'll be dog-gone. It was my sweet, little, 8 year-old nephew, TeddyBear, who excitedly picked out The Shaggy Dog at the local video store for the two of us to watch together.... And, you know what? I'm glad he did. Regardless of its gaping plot holes and its laughably cheap make-up effects, The Shaggy Dog's script was definitely first-rate, fast-paced, and, generally, a lot of goofy, family-oriented fun-fun-fun. Packed with plenty of hilarious one-liners, slapstick chases and uproarious sight gags, The Shaggy Dog also featured an excellent cast who competently brought this 1950s Comedy right in on the mark. The Shaggy Dog's story centers around the zany experiences of white, suburban teen, Wilby Daniels (a bona-fide geek) who, always at a loss for words around the girls, suddenly finds himself in a very hairy situation when the unknown powers of an antique "magical" ring transforms him into (of all things) an Old English Sheepdog. (You go figure) Check it out. You'll be dog-gone glad that you did.... Arf! Arf!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and amusing entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I re-watched this film as I often do with my childhood favourites. I loved The Shaggy Dog as a child, and at 18 I still do. But I wasn't so taken with the spy subplot, thinking it went on for too long and took up too much time in the narrative. Also, the film feels a little too long. However, despite how silly some of it it never fails to be amusing and charming, which is more than good enough for me. The film's production values are decent and hold up fairly well, while Paul J.Smith's score is jaunty and dynamic. The script is snappy as well and the story doesn't fall into the trap of being too predictable complete with a number of very entertaining scenes especially the pursuit in the police car, hectic it may be but also entertaining. The direction is pretty good too, as is the acting. Fred MacMurray is likable with some fun acting chops, while Jean Hagen shows some great comic timing. The real star though is Tommy Kirk, who is just great here. All in all, a fun, charming and amusing movie. 8/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An early live action Disney movie with its share of flaws, but also plenty of heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw lots of Disney animated films from different eras as a kid, back in the '90s, but never heard of this particular live action flick from Walt Disney Productions. I remember when the remake starring Tim Allen came out in 2006 and I saw a trailer for it, but I didn't know that film was a remake at the time. I still haven't seen that version, and have known for sometime now that it's not all that popular, but now I have finally seen the original 1959 version of "The Shaggy Dog", with a cast featuring Fred MacMurray and several cast members of "The Mickey Mouse Club". I didn't think this movie would be amazing family entertainment, since it doesn't seem to have that kind of reputation, but I was expecting it to be a 7/10 for me, which it is. Wilby Daniels is a teenager who likes to conduct experiments in the basement, but his father, Wilson, does not like this, and after Wilby accidentally launches a missile from the basement, Wilson tells him to clear out all his experiments. A new family moves into the neighbourhood, and Wilby and his friend, Buzz Miller, soon meet the daughter of the family, Franceska Andrassy. They also meet the family's sheep dog. Wilby, Buzz, and Franceska go to the museum together, but Wilby is separated from the other two. He meets Professor Plumcutt, a man he used to know, who tells him about his beliefs in ancient magic, including shape-shifting. Wilby ends up accidentally bringing home a mystical ring, which turns him into the Andrassy dog! This is not a good thing, since his father hates dogs! He sneaks out to tell Plumcutt what has happened, and learns from him that he is now under a spell, which will turn him back and forth from human to dog, and the only way to break this spell is through a selfless act of heroism! As a comedy, this 1959 live action Disney flick is far from consistent, but I did laugh a number of times, starting around the beginning when Wilby has his missile in the basement and accidentally launches it from there, obviously putting holes in every floor above! More laughs come after Wilby turns into a dog, including the scenes where Officer Hanson hears the teenager talk to him while in dog form. I didn't usually laugh that hard, but those parts were definitely exceptions, and were not the only ones! The acting in "The Shaggy Dog" is mostly not that impressive, and the plot isn't the most interesting, but in both cases, I've certainly seen worse. The dance sequence is maybe a bit tedious, and during parts like that, it was somewhat of a struggle for me to stay into it, but eventually, that changed, as the story gets better and the suspense builds up! For the rest of the film, I had no trouble staying into it, even if it wears out its welcome just a BIT towards the end. So, while by no means a masterpiece, this original "Shaggy Dog" probably still has enough to please the family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A shaggy dog tail of a film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Over the last few days,I've been in the mood of watching a fun family film.As I went looking at my DVDs,I spotted a film that my dad had given to me a while ago with Fred MacMurray-who I hugely enjoyed seeing in the excellent Absent-Minded Professor starring in. The plot: After having gotten back from being left behind at a local museum by his "best friend" and a new next door neighbour (who he secretly has a crush on)Wilby Daniels discovers that a strange looking ancient ring has ended up in one of his jean pockets.When he reads out the inscription on the ring,he turns into his neighbours dog!!.Due to his father saying that he will shoot any dog that comes into the house (this is because he had a lot of trouble with dogs when he was a postman.) Because of this,Wilby decides to stay with the newly-arrived neighbours.Whilst there,Daniels discovers that the neighbours are not as sweet as they seem... View on the film: Whilst the last half an hour of the film has a very entertaining Mad Mad Mad Mad World-style chase,an odd thing about the screenplay by Bill Walsh and Lillie Hayward,is that they offer no explanation as to how the neighbours dog returns when Wilby turns back into a human.Also,perhaps due to the films age,the ending (where Wilby seems pretty happy to hear that the girl he had a crush on is being sent back and questioned by the CIA!.) gives the movie's ending a surprisingly nasty taste. Although he is not given as bigger role as I would have liked,Fred MacMurray gives a good performance as Wilson Daniels,who has trouble dealing with all the crazy chaos around him.Tommy Kirk also gives a very strong performance as Wilby,by showing all the frustrations that he has to try and manage,because of his transformation. Final view on the film: A fun film for the whole family,with very good performances from MacMurray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shaggy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one had me laughing so hard,, i seriously cannot remember laughing so hard at a movie in a long long time,, for starters,, the look on the cop's face throughout the movie was priceless. Fred MacMurray was great a the dad,, as he had all of those years on My Three Sons. Anette Funicello was also pretty darn good in this,, i loved the dog driving through town and waving at the police officers, as he went by,, then you got the dog telling his dad that he really is his son,, and the shaking the hand bit,, just put me on the floor laughing,, i kinda wish that Hollywood would make something more like this in the future,, even if it's only once a year,, go black and white,, get back to old school, this movie was just a pure heartfelt joy to watch, and i think that everyone should at least watch this once for some good natured laughter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really funny and entertaining late 50's Disney live action classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cranky mailman Wilson Daniels (a delightfully charming portrayal by Fred MacMurray) has a vehement disdain for dogs. Things get hairy (both literally and figuratively) when his likable misfit son Wilby (a wonderfully amiable performance by Tommy Kirk) gets stricken by a magical ring that causes him to transform into a big shaggy sheepdog. Wilby has to perform an act of heroism by thwarting an international spy ring so he can break the spell. Director Charles Bartun, working from a witty and good-natured script by Bill Walsh and Lillie Haward, relates the zany plot at a constant zippy pace, maintains a pleasant and frothy tone throughout, and stages the slapstick gags with praiseworthy brio (amusing comic highlights include the dog disrupting a swanky dance party, a hapless patrolman's sidesplitting constant run-ins with the talking pooch, and a marvelously wacky last reel car chase). Moreover, the characters are well-developed, sympathetic, and above all even pretty believable as everyday folks who find themselves caught up in a fantastic situation. Extra kudos are in order for the uniformly sound acting from a tip-top cast: MacMurray and Kirk shine in the lead roles, with fine support from Jean Hagen as Wilson's doting wife Freeda, Kevin Corcoran as Wilby's mischievous little squirt kid brother Moochie, Tim Considine as Wilby's hip pal Buzz Miller, Roberta Shore as fetching French hottie Franceska Andrassy, Annette Funicello as the sweet and adorable Allison D'Allessio, Cecil Kellaway as the jolly Professor Plumcutt, and Strother Martin as no-count criminal Thurm. Sam the dog is simply amazing as the titular canine. Legendary voice actor Paul Frees provides the narration and even has an uncredited minor part as disbelieving psychiatrist Dr. J.W. Galvin. The theme song is an absolute groovy gas. Edward Colman's crisp black and white cinematography makes neat occasional use of fades and dissolves. Endearing family fare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i liked it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    sure,it may seem cheesy by todays' standards,but it's good clean fun for the whole family,for the most part.really young children might be a bit scared from a few scenes,but other than that,it's fun for everyone.i chuckled quite a bit t some of the comedic bits,and i also thought the story was interesting.it's not just about the Shaggy Dog.there's another story in there as well.some of the facial expressions and reactions may seem a bit hokey and overdone,but so what.that was how they acted back then. if i recall correctly,this was the first motion picture made by Disney.i wouldn't say the comedic parts are laugh out loud,rolling in the aisles funny.,but they were certainly amusing.you could do a lot worse with 102 minutes or so.my vote for The Shaggy Dog: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly comedy is dated stuff that looks more like a made-for-TV movie than a feature length hit...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Doyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Times have certainly changed. Here we have a Disney live action feature film that looks and sounds more like a TV sit-com (and a below par one at that), and yet it grossed $8,000,000 at the box-office at a time when any film that grossed more than a few million was considered a box-office hit. At least FRED MacMURRAY does a professional job as the bumbling father of TOMMY KIRK and KEVIN CORCORAN, a dog-hater with a shotgun who gets itchy around the collar if a dog is even remotely close to his territory. He provides some genuine chuckles with his comic touch on a role that could well have seemed anything but sympathetic. The boys do OK too, especially Kevin Corcoran as the younger brother who always wanted a dog and promises to take good care of his brother who has magically transformed into one. The plot is pretty threadbare but it does provide some very amusing moments--such as the one where Tommy Kirk gets into his pajamas and brushes his teeth while in the guise of the shaggy dog. The transmutation has taken place because he read aloud the inscription on a ring that had once belonged to the Borgias and whose Latin words were meant to change the sayer into a dog. What weakens the story is the whole spy subplot which has him overhearing the spies while a dog and then reverting to his own body before he can get away from their presence. All of this leads to a hectic chase that has the baffled police force falling all over themselves to catch a shaggy dog driving a stolen police car. It's silly stuff and never overcomes the feel of a lame sitcom from the innocent '50s, complete with people like ANNETTE FUNICELLO, TIM CONSIDINE, JEAN HAGEN (a far cry from her "Singin' in the Rain" dumb blonde), and JAMES WESTERFIELD as the policeman who can't believe his own eyes. It passes the time pleasantly enough but you have to be willing to view it in the context of its '50s era innocence. And contrary to what some here believe, this was not Disney's first live action film--not by a long shot. However, it was one of the few to make a bundle at the box-office for some unknown reason and gave a boost to the sagging career of Fred MacMurray at a time when his film career was on the skids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A flat fantasy that plods along at an insufferably slow pace before sparking into life right at the end, when it's far too late. Tommy Kirk is a kid who finds a magic ring that transforms him into a talking dog; in this furry form he overhears crooks planning a robbery at the local missile plant. If it sounds like one of those daft, seemingly drug-induced Disney capers that inevitably ends in a car chase, that's because it is. Unfortunately it's not much fun bar the hilarious animated credits sequence and odd moment like the dog putting on pajamas, cleaning his teeth and driving a car. It's not enough. Despite the utter stupidity of the film's plot this is stiff, boring and woodenly acted stuff.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird and Funny "Shaggy Dog" Story Of Teen Age Lycanthropy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnstonjames
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is a hoot for anyone who understands the term " a shaggy dog story" or anyone who knows folklore. first off the term "shaggy dog", means a ridiculous or exaggerated story so even the title is imaginative and clever. anyone who has delved into folklore knows all about stories of lycanthropy or the legend of the Borgia family. all of this mixed into the whole fifties "i was a teen age..." formula. the film is good laughs and not a bad excursion into contemporary folklore. i've always felt that Disney comedies like this are often underrated for their cleverness. i guess because so much of the comedy is played for dumb laughs it's hard to take it all seriously, which you're not supposed to really, because it's Disney you're supposed to enjoy and have fun. this is a great comedy, semi-horror, teen flick that actually holds up well to sophisticated screw ball comedies. a genuine argument can be made for this film that it is one of cinema's better comedies. certainly with all of it's gimmicks and effects, it's very cinematic. one major note here for viewers. this film was originally filmed in glorious B&W and is most effective when viewed in B&W. avoid the horrible colorized, tinted versions which disarm the effectiveness of it's nostalgia and photography.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bow! Wow!... It's A Doggy Delight!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I'll be dog-gone. It was my sweet, little, 8 year-old nephew, TeddyBear, who excitedly picked out The Shaggy Dog at the local video store for the two of us to watch together.... And, you know what? I'm glad he did. Regardless of its gaping plot holes and its laughably cheap make-up effects, The Shaggy Dog's script was definitely first-rate, fast-paced, and, generally, a lot of goofy, family-oriented fun-fun-fun. Packed with plenty of hilarious one-liners, slapstick chases and uproarious sight gags, The Shaggy Dog also featured an excellent cast who competently brought this 1950s Comedy right in on the mark. The Shaggy Dog's story centers around the zany experiences of white, suburban teen, Wilby Daniels (a bona-fide geek) who, always at a loss for words around the girls, suddenly finds himself in a very hairy situation when the unknown powers of an antique "magical" ring transforms him into (of all things) an Old English Sheepdog. (You go figure) Check it out. You'll be dog-gone glad that you did.... Arf! Arf!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and amusing entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I re-watched this film as I often do with my childhood favourites. I loved The Shaggy Dog as a child, and at 18 I still do. But I wasn't so taken with the spy subplot, thinking it went on for too long and took up too much time in the narrative. Also, the film feels a little too long. However, despite how silly some of it it never fails to be amusing and charming, which is more than good enough for me. The film's production values are decent and hold up fairly well, while Paul J.Smith's score is jaunty and dynamic. The script is snappy as well and the story doesn't fall into the trap of being too predictable complete with a number of very entertaining scenes especially the pursuit in the police car, hectic it may be but also entertaining. The direction is pretty good too, as is the acting. Fred MacMurray is likable with some fun acting chops, while Jean Hagen shows some great comic timing. The real star though is Tommy Kirk, who is just great here. All in all, a fun, charming and amusing movie. 8/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An early live action Disney movie with its share of flaws, but also plenty of heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw lots of Disney animated films from different eras as a kid, back in the '90s, but never heard of this particular live action flick from Walt Disney Productions. I remember when the remake starring Tim Allen came out in 2006 and I saw a trailer for it, but I didn't know that film was a remake at the time. I still haven't seen that version, and have known for sometime now that it's not all that popular, but now I have finally seen the original 1959 version of "The Shaggy Dog", with a cast featuring Fred MacMurray and several cast members of "The Mickey Mouse Club". I didn't think this movie would be amazing family entertainment, since it doesn't seem to have that kind of reputation, but I was expecting it to be a 7/10 for me, which it is. Wilby Daniels is a teenager who likes to conduct experiments in the basement, but his father, Wilson, does not like this, and after Wilby accidentally launches a missile from the basement, Wilson tells him to clear out all his experiments. A new family moves into the neighbourhood, and Wilby and his friend, Buzz Miller, soon meet the daughter of the family, Franceska Andrassy. They also meet the family's sheep dog. Wilby, Buzz, and Franceska go to the museum together, but Wilby is separated from the other two. He meets Professor Plumcutt, a man he used to know, who tells him about his beliefs in ancient magic, including shape-shifting. Wilby ends up accidentally bringing home a mystical ring, which turns him into the Andrassy dog! This is not a good thing, since his father hates dogs! He sneaks out to tell Plumcutt what has happened, and learns from him that he is now under a spell, which will turn him back and forth from human to dog, and the only way to break this spell is through a selfless act of heroism! As a comedy, this 1959 live action Disney flick is far from consistent, but I did laugh a number of times, starting around the beginning when Wilby has his missile in the basement and accidentally launches it from there, obviously putting holes in every floor above! More laughs come after Wilby turns into a dog, including the scenes where Officer Hanson hears the teenager talk to him while in dog form. I didn't usually laugh that hard, but those parts were definitely exceptions, and were not the only ones! The acting in "The Shaggy Dog" is mostly not that impressive, and the plot isn't the most interesting, but in both cases, I've certainly seen worse. The dance sequence is maybe a bit tedious, and during parts like that, it was somewhat of a struggle for me to stay into it, but eventually, that changed, as the story gets better and the suspense builds up! For the rest of the film, I had no trouble staying into it, even if it wears out its welcome just a BIT towards the end. So, while by no means a masterpiece, this original "Shaggy Dog" probably still has enough to please the family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A shaggy dog tail of a film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    morrison-dylan-fan
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Over the last few days,I've been in the mood of watching a fun family film.As I went looking at my DVDs,I spotted a film that my dad had given to me a while ago with Fred MacMurray-who I hugely enjoyed seeing in the excellent Absent-Minded Professor starring in. The plot: After having gotten back from being left behind at a local museum by his "best friend" and a new next door neighbour (who he secretly has a crush on)Wilby Daniels discovers that a strange looking ancient ring has ended up in one of his jean pockets.When he reads out the inscription on the ring,he turns into his neighbours dog!!.Due to his father saying that he will shoot any dog that comes into the house (this is because he had a lot of trouble with dogs when he was a postman.) Because of this,Wilby decides to stay with the newly-arrived neighbours.Whilst there,Daniels discovers that the neighbours are not as sweet as they seem... View on the film: Whilst the last half an hour of the film has a very entertaining Mad Mad Mad Mad World-style chase,an odd thing about the screenplay by Bill Walsh and Lillie Hayward,is that they offer no explanation as to how the neighbours dog returns when Wilby turns back into a human.Also,perhaps due to the films age,the ending (where Wilby seems pretty happy to hear that the girl he had a crush on is being sent back and questioned by the CIA!.) gives the movie's ending a surprisingly nasty taste. Although he is not given as bigger role as I would have liked,Fred MacMurray gives a good performance as Wilson Daniels,who has trouble dealing with all the crazy chaos around him.Tommy Kirk also gives a very strong performance as Wilby,by showing all the frustrations that he has to try and manage,because of his transformation. Final view on the film: A fun film for the whole family,with very good performances from MacMurray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shaggy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This one had me laughing so hard,, i seriously cannot remember laughing so hard at a movie in a long long time,, for starters,, the look on the cop's face throughout the movie was priceless. Fred MacMurray was great a the dad,, as he had all of those years on My Three Sons. Anette Funicello was also pretty darn good in this,, i loved the dog driving through town and waving at the police officers, as he went by,, then you got the dog telling his dad that he really is his son,, and the shaking the hand bit,, just put me on the floor laughing,, i kinda wish that Hollywood would make something more like this in the future,, even if it's only once a year,, go black and white,, get back to old school, this movie was just a pure heartfelt joy to watch, and i think that everyone should at least watch this once for some good natured laughter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really funny and entertaining late 50's Disney live action classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Woodyanders (Woodyanders@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cranky mailman Wilson Daniels (a delightfully charming portrayal by Fred MacMurray) has a vehement disdain for dogs. Things get hairy (both literally and figuratively) when his likable misfit son Wilby (a wonderfully amiable performance by Tommy Kirk) gets stricken by a magical ring that causes him to transform into a big shaggy sheepdog. Wilby has to perform an act of heroism by thwarting an international spy ring so he can break the spell. Director Charles Bartun, working from a witty and good-natured script by Bill Walsh and Lillie Haward, relates the zany plot at a constant zippy pace, maintains a pleasant and frothy tone throughout, and stages the slapstick gags with praiseworthy brio (amusing comic highlights include the dog disrupting a swanky dance party, a hapless patrolman's sidesplitting constant run-ins with the talking pooch, and a marvelously wacky last reel car chase). Moreover, the characters are well-developed, sympathetic, and above all even pretty believable as everyday folks who find themselves caught up in a fantastic situation. Extra kudos are in order for the uniformly sound acting from a tip-top cast: MacMurray and Kirk shine in the lead roles, with fine support from Jean Hagen as Wilson's doting wife Freeda, Kevin Corcoran as Wilby's mischievous little squirt kid brother Moochie, Tim Considine as Wilby's hip pal Buzz Miller, Roberta Shore as fetching French hottie Franceska Andrassy, Annette Funicello as the sweet and adorable Allison D'Allessio, Cecil Kellaway as the jolly Professor Plumcutt, and Strother Martin as no-count criminal Thurm. Sam the dog is simply amazing as the titular canine. Legendary voice actor Paul Frees provides the narration and even has an uncredited minor part as disbelieving psychiatrist Dr. J.W. Galvin. The theme song is an absolute groovy gas. Edward Colman's crisp black and white cinematography makes neat occasional use of fades and dissolves. Endearing family fare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i liked it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    sure,it may seem cheesy by todays' standards,but it's good clean fun for the whole family,for the most part.really young children might be a bit scared from a few scenes,but other than that,it's fun for everyone.i chuckled quite a bit t some of the comedic bits,and i also thought the story was interesting.it's not just about the Shaggy Dog.there's another story in there as well.some of the facial expressions and reactions may seem a bit hokey and overdone,but so what.that was how they acted back then. if i recall correctly,this was the first motion picture made by Disney.i wouldn't say the comedic parts are laugh out loud,rolling in the aisles funny.,but they were certainly amusing.you could do a lot worse with 102 minutes or so.my vote for The Shaggy Dog: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly comedy is dated stuff that looks more like a made-for-TV movie than a feature length hit...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Doyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Times have certainly changed. Here we have a Disney live action feature film that looks and sounds more like a TV sit-com (and a below par one at that), and yet it grossed $8,000,000 at the box-office at a time when any film that grossed more than a few million was considered a box-office hit. At least FRED MacMURRAY does a professional job as the bumbling father of TOMMY KIRK and KEVIN CORCORAN, a dog-hater with a shotgun who gets itchy around the collar if a dog is even remotely close to his territory. He provides some genuine chuckles with his comic touch on a role that could well have seemed anything but sympathetic. The boys do OK too, especially Kevin Corcoran as the younger brother who always wanted a dog and promises to take good care of his brother who has magically transformed into one. The plot is pretty threadbare but it does provide some very amusing moments--such as the one where Tommy Kirk gets into his pajamas and brushes his teeth while in the guise of the shaggy dog. The transmutation has taken place because he read aloud the inscription on a ring that had once belonged to the Borgias and whose Latin words were meant to change the sayer into a dog. What weakens the story is the whole spy subplot which has him overhearing the spies while a dog and then reverting to his own body before he can get away from their presence. All of this leads to a hectic chase that has the baffled police force falling all over themselves to catch a shaggy dog driving a stolen police car. It's silly stuff and never overcomes the feel of a lame sitcom from the innocent '50s, complete with people like ANNETTE FUNICELLO, TIM CONSIDINE, JEAN HAGEN (a far cry from her "Singin' in the Rain" dumb blonde), and JAMES WESTERFIELD as the policeman who can't believe his own eyes. It passes the time pleasantly enough but you have to be willing to view it in the context of its '50s era innocence. And contrary to what some here believe, this was not Disney's first live action film--not by a long shot. However, it was one of the few to make a bundle at the box-office for some unknown reason and gave a boost to the sagging career of Fred MacMurray at a time when his film career was on the skids.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
