<filme>
 <id>
  844
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116361
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Freeway - Sem Sa&iacute;da
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A twisted take on 'Little Red Riding Hood' with a teenage juvenile delinquent on the run from a social worker traveling to her grandmother's house and being hounded by a charming, but sadistic, serial killer/pedophile.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Little Red Riding Hood for the 1990's: After her mom and step-dad are arrested, 15-year-old Vanessa Lutz decides that instead of once again being put into a foster home, she'd rather go and search for the grandmother she's never met, and live with her. "On the way to grandma's house," (actually a trailer park) Vanessa's car breaks down, and she's picked up from the side of the road by Bob Wolverton, a counselor at a school for troubled boys. Bob slowly earns Vanessa's trust, and eventually convinces her to talk about her sexual abuse at the hands of her stepfather. When Vanessa realizes that Bob is enjoying what she's saying, she realizes that he's "The I-5 Killer," from the news. She tries to get out of his truck, but the inside door handle has been removed...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   freeway
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   little red riding hood
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   school
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   prostitution
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Matthew Bright
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Matthew Bright
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Reese Witherspoon
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kiefer Sutherland
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Bokeem Woodbine
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Varied, violent, funny and furious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So there's me thinking I'm taking a break from my obscure exploitation movies and I find myself sat before this beauty. Made in 1996, which doesn't seem so long ago, but it's before Keiffer Sutherland settled into the 24 TV series and before Reese Witherspoon had even made Election, and while they have both gone on to much bigger if not better things, director Bright has not. Well, I don't know what possessed him to imagine he was going to make too many Hollywood friends with this mighty chunk of wild and anti-establishment, two fingered spout of anger, but it is enormous fun to watch. Also, as with so much exploitative cinema it seems to tell far more truths than your average 'serious' movie. Sutherland is effective but Witherspoon amazing, I had forgotten how tremendous she could be. Varied, violent, funny and furious, this is worth a watch anytime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanquinn-52-789942
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely brilliant film in so many different respects. At it's most basic it's a modern take on Robin Hood, but it can be enjoyed on many different levels. There are several just plain brilliant performances. This is first film that I watched Reece Witherspoon in that really showed me her depth and stretched her ability as an actress, and she was only 18 years old! She's strong, powerful, empathetic and like-able as the wayward teen looking for her grandmother. Keifer Sutherland also has a strong role, with some of my other favorite performances being from Britany Murphy as a completely transformed and nearly unrecognizable pyromaniac lesbian delinquent. Another great performance is Michael T. Weiss (from the TV series Pretender) as a complete crack-head, and Brook Shields as the wife of Keifer Sutherland's character. This is not a film for children, despite it being based on a children's tale, but if you approach it with an open mind I think you'll really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reese As You've Never Seen Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reese Witherspoon made this riveting thriller before she became everybody's favorite sweetheart. The "Legally Blond" star plays a foul-mouthed, illiterate teenager named Vanessa Lutz who hitches a ride with an older man after her car breaks down on the freeway. He offers her a lift as far as Los Angeles and even takes her out to dinner. Later, he turns out to be a notorious California highway serial killer who has been making headlines. Kiefer Sutherland is thoroughly obnoxious as Bob Wolverton, a bespectacled boys counselor who gets more than he bargained for after he picks up Vanessa, cuts off her ponytail, and threatens to rape her corpse. She whips out a small, Spanish-made automatic pistol that her boyfriend, Chopper (Bokeem Woodbine) gave her moments before he died in a drive-by shooting. Vanessa lands in jail but she does not stick long before she breaks out and joins a group of Hispanic girls who pull tricks on the side. All Vanessa wants to do is go to Stockton, California, so she can live with her grandmother rather than wind up in another horrible foster home.The dialogue brims with profanity and the subject matter is very unsavory. Witherspoon gives a dynamic performance. If you think that Witherspoon is cast against the grain, wait until you see a grown-up Brooke Shields who plays the wife of the serial killer. "Freeway" is an unforgettable dark comedy that doesn't pull any of its punches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is still one of Reese's best roles ever, and not a dull moment ever . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know, it may seem ridiculous to some, but actually, even after all these years (now well into 2012), this is still a film to watch, and no one could have delivered the key role more perfectly than Reese Witherspoon. She is simply spectacularly spot on with her characterization of the theme and culture that is her character here. The story is a bit hard edged for some, but sadly, not entirely outside the realms of reality in the current world. Do characters like hers in this film really exist as portrayed? Absolutely yes. Do characters like that portrayed by Sutherland, the predatory pedophile sociopath who appears to be so acceptably "normal" to the outside world? Absolutely yes, as recent history has shown only too clearly. On the surface this may have appeared to be a sort of whacky, creepy crime thriller, but actually, if one actually takes the time to watch this film, there is much more to this than the ad copy may have suggested at the time. It is still currently viable, to this very day . . . has stood the test of time. And it is absolutely one of Reese's best ever performances. Sadly, her more recent work has sort of flattened out into much less risky, complex roles, but hey, a great actress she is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suggests a better story than it delivers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is one of those films that are okay but still manage to be a little disappointing because it's so damned apparent that it could have been much better. It's perfectly clear where the story is going early on, yet it still takes forever to get there. When it finally arrives, writer/director Matthew Bright throws a great left turn into the plot and sets up a potentially fascinating second half of the movie. That never materializes because Bright ignores almost all of the possibilities suggested by his great idea so he can relentlessly focus on a main character who is too impervious to care about. Vanessa Lutz (Reese Witherspoon) is the 15 year old, illiterate spawn of poor white city trash. Her drug addict stepfather (Michael T. Weiss) molests her and her at-best-borderline crazy mother (Amanda Plummer) turns tricks on the street in the parking lot outside the motel room where they all live. When they get arrested, Vanessa tries to flee to the grandmother she's never met. Along the way, she runs into Bob Wolverton (Keifer Sutherland) a counselor for troubled youth who offers her a lift and some help with Vanessa's beyond screwed up life. If I tell you there's a mention at the start of the film of a serial killer targeting young girls in Vanessa's town, can you guess where her and Bob's relationship is headed? That is where it goes, though writer/director Bright waits a long time to get it there and then shamelessly foreshadows it right before it happens, as though anyone watching this movie didn't see it coming. But then he takes what you expect and completely upends it, leaving you without any clue where Freeway is going next but anxious to find out. That feeling doesn't last long because writer/director Bright takes almost all of the interesting directions his story could go and reduces them to comic relief so he can put Vanessa through her paces in an afterschool special that has no moral or "message to grow on", unless that moral is "bad things also happen to bad people". It's only when Freeway needs an ending that writer/director Bright abruptly picks up some of the potential he's cast aside and tries to cobble together a big finish. I'm not sure the origins of this motion picture, but what it turned out to be was a starring vehicle for the young Reese Witherspoon that went nowhere. Not because she isn't cute as all get out and doesn't do a fine job here. It's because Vanessa dominates the whole show and is a sociopath but unfortunately, she's not one of those intriguing and grandiose sociopaths. She's one of those petty, boring sociopaths who turn up in police stations every day. The movie takes great pains to spell out all the terrible things that were done to Vanessa but none of it seems to have had any effect on her. Vanessa has no depth or inner life and cruises through her horrible existence like a shark looking for the next fat seal to eat. That might not have been a problem if Freeway had become the kind of thriller suggested by writer/director Bright's very clever left turn. In plot dominated tales, it's not always necessary for characters to be relatable or even all that interesting. By essentially becoming a study of a two-dimensional character, though, the film only highlights the lack of connection the viewer can have with Vanessa. Witherspoon is good here, as is Keifer Sutherland and Brooke Shields. Brittany Murphy has an odd role as a scarred paint-huffer and Dan Hedaya and Wolfgang Bodison are fine as two detectives, though the movie can't keep straight which one of them is supposed to be the good cop and which the bad cop. In most respects, Freeway is perfectly acceptable entertainment, with reasonably good writing, directing and acting. I can't shake the feeling that it could easily have been more than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wait... So This Movie Was Released in the West?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Bridge (joebridge@bigpond.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this movie, and as soon as it started with the bizarre, embarrassingly bad "Red Riding Hood" opening credits and horrid cheap-sounding soundtrack, I was certain it was some sort of fake "knock-off" video, especially as someone gave me this copy as sold in Indonesia. The ending credits were really bad and fake-looking as well, so maybe both were replaced in the Indonesian version, not sure, but it also is so bad throughout, perhaps the entire movie was replaced? While watching this, my friends and I were almost certain the actor credits were fake and that it was filmed by a group of amateur film-makers (as it was so utterly badly made - I was certain it was made in Indonesia or other Foreign country and was meant to make fun of the West), until Keifer Sutherland showed up and we were fairly certain it was him. Was this a straight-to-video movie? It was just so badly made and badly acted even for a dark comedy. Just because it is a comedy doesn't mean you have to act as if you are playing around with the script and not saying the lines in any way that makes sense. The acting was so disturbingly over-the-top bad, the accents annoying and ridiculous throughout (sounded mostly like hillbillies from the more isolated areas of Kentucky - yet supposedly was taking place in California), and the actors themselves looking so awful in every way possible (even Brooke Shields looked as if they used CGI to warp her body into something not quite human in that weird sailor outfit - again unless our copy was tampered with), I'm certain this was MEANT to be a farce/comedy, especially with the ludicrous climax regarding the actual Little Red Riding Hood story - which kind of added insult to injury - how could any writer be THAT ridiculous? Obviously it wasn't meant to be crime drama or anything like that, even though the premise suggested it was drama. It does have an overwhelming "quickly made television movie" and "print every first take" feel. So it appears that this movie (or a version of it) WAS released in the USA (not sure about here in Australia) after all? I'm still fairly certain our copy was tampered with (especially the ridiculous looking and sounding opening and ending credits - that were in static-ridden Foreign-sounding music and in mono - which wouldn't meet even the lowest standards these days), as nothing could be that badly made and be released. Most of us thought that it was one of those "experimental" films that was made especially for places like Indonesia and never placed directly in the actors' credits, and which wasn't released elsewhere, but seeing the information on IMDb is quite stunning in its implications about the general populace... Unbelievable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outrageously Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only in the 1990's that you had a enormous stream of twisted, violent, dark films with awkward funny moments, and writers and directors got away with it, although some of them haven't lived up to higher expectations with the noble exception of Coen brothers. Far away from being intelligent like Coen's films "Freeway" comes to amaze us with bringing the story of Little Red Riding Hood in a different environment with many violent and funny situations. Reese Witherspoon plays the troubled Vanessa, a girl whose mother and stepfather were arrested, and she doesn't want to go to foster care or similar, deciding instead on going to her grandmother's house, the only place she can go. This Little Red Riding Hood won't bring cookies to grandma, and she's not so innocent like the old tale, here's a girl with lots of problems and lots of anger too after meeting her Big Bad Wolf, Bob a friendly psycho killer (Kiefer Sutherland) who picks her up on the road after her car broke. What comes after it's a hilarious and twisted story about two figures that don't know how to get rid of each other, in a plot that involves murders, juvenile prison for girls, a funny trial, punchlines in the wrong time to make us laugh all the time. It's not for everyone's tastes, it's certainly that not everyone will find the story funny as a comedy instead of a ridiculous way as the plot might suggest. It's full of surprises, very uncompromising and has some interesting performance from Witherspoon as the talking/smart/violent/Christian girl who manages to survive the whole ride meeting creepy characters on the way, and a nice performance from Kiefer playing the friendly guy who ends up being a killer trapped in his own evilness, after the girl shoot him several times, and this guy for some reason doesn't die but keeps living a painful life after. The scenes with both in the car, talking about her problems and he's playing the good listener was very good, and sometimes I wish that the whole movie would be focused on them doing this because it was interesting so these two change to each other the way they act, talk and all, but then we would have a dramatic feature, something that this film is not. How come one stumble upon this film? Simple! Of 5 films credited on IMDb you'll see in 4 random titles the suggestion for this film, and I gotta recognize that the promotion is a little bit over-the-top but it made me curious to watch it, and it turned out to be a great film. One year in a crusade after "Freeway" I finally watched, enjoyed, it got me laughing and surprised despite a few clich&eacute;s here and there. If you can see humor in bizarre situations that in ordinary life wouldn't be funny then this film is for you! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wash your mouth out with soap Little Red Riding Hood !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgonite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is a black comic take on Little Red Riding Hood. Reese Witherspoon plays a rather sweet and innocent looking young woman off to find her grandmother. Kiefer Sutherland plays a psychological serial killer, although not a fully paid up one but the free or Lite version. The film's strengths are the performance by Witherspoon who brings the character to life, and the screenplay which is funny in the extreme. Indeed I would be surprised if Witherspoon had not been nominated for an award in the role. Freeway is not a very politically correct film and is all the more enjoyable for it! This aspect of it could cause offence and as such has probably hindered it's publicity. Pros - Twisted, Dark, Comic Tale Cons - None come to mind Overall - Baddass
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    captaintrps
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible. I spent the majority of the time holding down the fast forward button on my remote. Reese W. does well despite the horrible film that this is. Keifer S. should just stay retired or go in hiding or wherever he was before this came out. Reese has to regret doing this film. Very predictable, with no plot or storyline that you're average movie buff couldn't come up with. I don't see where this has anything to do with the little red riding hood story. They forced that association onto this film. This is not worth watching at all. The weekend opening gross tells the story. Don't waste your time, or spoil your thoughts that Reese W. is fun to watch on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark, disgusting and utterly wonderful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is written and directed by Matthew Bright. It stars Reese Witherspoon, Kiefer Sutherland, Dan Hedaya, Wolfgang Bodison, Brooke Shields & Brittany Murphy. Plot is darkly based around the Little Red Riding Hood fairy tale and sees young runaway Vanessa Lutz (Witherspoon) hit the road after her parents are arrested. Setting off to visit her grandmother she agrees to a lift from the kind and well spoken Bob Wolverton (Sutherland), only to find that he's not as nice as she first thought. He in turn is in for a big surprise himself since Vanessa is more than capable of looking after herself. Twisted and richly humorous, Matthew Bright's movie oozes originality and quite frankly deserves to be better appreciated: never mind better known! Going into it for a first time completely oblivious to its structure will arguably aid the experience. Suffice to say that the less known about it prior to viewing it the better. All I have to say is that it's violent, sweary and contains very sexually explicit dialogue, so if those things are likely to offend then perhaps stay away from it. But what if I offer up that those things are dealt with a satirical bent? That the tough scenes, and some of them are very tough, are basis to a caustic narrative about social hypocrisy and the often stupidity of the law? Interested? You should be, because once viewed you're unlikely to forget it. It's no surprise to see Oliver Stone's name etched onto the production credits, since this very much feels like a dirty second cousin to his Natural Born Killers. I'd argue that here we have the better acted film with Witherspoon and Sutherland giving virtuoso performances: with admirable support coming from the likes of Bodison, Shields and Murphy. One of the most undervalued film's of the 90s? You bet it is! 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Varied, violent, funny and furious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So there's me thinking I'm taking a break from my obscure exploitation movies and I find myself sat before this beauty. Made in 1996, which doesn't seem so long ago, but it's before Keiffer Sutherland settled into the 24 TV series and before Reese Witherspoon had even made Election, and while they have both gone on to much bigger if not better things, director Bright has not. Well, I don't know what possessed him to imagine he was going to make too many Hollywood friends with this mighty chunk of wild and anti-establishment, two fingered spout of anger, but it is enormous fun to watch. Also, as with so much exploitative cinema it seems to tell far more truths than your average 'serious' movie. Sutherland is effective but Witherspoon amazing, I had forgotten how tremendous she could be. Varied, violent, funny and furious, this is worth a watch anytime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanquinn-52-789942
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely brilliant film in so many different respects. At it's most basic it's a modern take on Robin Hood, but it can be enjoyed on many different levels. There are several just plain brilliant performances. This is first film that I watched Reece Witherspoon in that really showed me her depth and stretched her ability as an actress, and she was only 18 years old! She's strong, powerful, empathetic and like-able as the wayward teen looking for her grandmother. Keifer Sutherland also has a strong role, with some of my other favorite performances being from Britany Murphy as a completely transformed and nearly unrecognizable pyromaniac lesbian delinquent. Another great performance is Michael T. Weiss (from the TV series Pretender) as a complete crack-head, and Brook Shields as the wife of Keifer Sutherland's character. This is not a film for children, despite it being based on a children's tale, but if you approach it with an open mind I think you'll really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reese As You've Never Seen Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reese Witherspoon made this riveting thriller before she became everybody's favorite sweetheart. The "Legally Blond" star plays a foul-mouthed, illiterate teenager named Vanessa Lutz who hitches a ride with an older man after her car breaks down on the freeway. He offers her a lift as far as Los Angeles and even takes her out to dinner. Later, he turns out to be a notorious California highway serial killer who has been making headlines. Kiefer Sutherland is thoroughly obnoxious as Bob Wolverton, a bespectacled boys counselor who gets more than he bargained for after he picks up Vanessa, cuts off her ponytail, and threatens to rape her corpse. She whips out a small, Spanish-made automatic pistol that her boyfriend, Chopper (Bokeem Woodbine) gave her moments before he died in a drive-by shooting. Vanessa lands in jail but she does not stick long before she breaks out and joins a group of Hispanic girls who pull tricks on the side. All Vanessa wants to do is go to Stockton, California, so she can live with her grandmother rather than wind up in another horrible foster home.The dialogue brims with profanity and the subject matter is very unsavory. Witherspoon gives a dynamic performance. If you think that Witherspoon is cast against the grain, wait until you see a grown-up Brooke Shields who plays the wife of the serial killer. "Freeway" is an unforgettable dark comedy that doesn't pull any of its punches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is still one of Reese's best roles ever, and not a dull moment ever . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know, it may seem ridiculous to some, but actually, even after all these years (now well into 2012), this is still a film to watch, and no one could have delivered the key role more perfectly than Reese Witherspoon. She is simply spectacularly spot on with her characterization of the theme and culture that is her character here. The story is a bit hard edged for some, but sadly, not entirely outside the realms of reality in the current world. Do characters like hers in this film really exist as portrayed? Absolutely yes. Do characters like that portrayed by Sutherland, the predatory pedophile sociopath who appears to be so acceptably "normal" to the outside world? Absolutely yes, as recent history has shown only too clearly. On the surface this may have appeared to be a sort of whacky, creepy crime thriller, but actually, if one actually takes the time to watch this film, there is much more to this than the ad copy may have suggested at the time. It is still currently viable, to this very day . . . has stood the test of time. And it is absolutely one of Reese's best ever performances. Sadly, her more recent work has sort of flattened out into much less risky, complex roles, but hey, a great actress she is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suggests a better story than it delivers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is one of those films that are okay but still manage to be a little disappointing because it's so damned apparent that it could have been much better. It's perfectly clear where the story is going early on, yet it still takes forever to get there. When it finally arrives, writer/director Matthew Bright throws a great left turn into the plot and sets up a potentially fascinating second half of the movie. That never materializes because Bright ignores almost all of the possibilities suggested by his great idea so he can relentlessly focus on a main character who is too impervious to care about. Vanessa Lutz (Reese Witherspoon) is the 15 year old, illiterate spawn of poor white city trash. Her drug addict stepfather (Michael T. Weiss) molests her and her at-best-borderline crazy mother (Amanda Plummer) turns tricks on the street in the parking lot outside the motel room where they all live. When they get arrested, Vanessa tries to flee to the grandmother she's never met. Along the way, she runs into Bob Wolverton (Keifer Sutherland) a counselor for troubled youth who offers her a lift and some help with Vanessa's beyond screwed up life. If I tell you there's a mention at the start of the film of a serial killer targeting young girls in Vanessa's town, can you guess where her and Bob's relationship is headed? That is where it goes, though writer/director Bright waits a long time to get it there and then shamelessly foreshadows it right before it happens, as though anyone watching this movie didn't see it coming. But then he takes what you expect and completely upends it, leaving you without any clue where Freeway is going next but anxious to find out. That feeling doesn't last long because writer/director Bright takes almost all of the interesting directions his story could go and reduces them to comic relief so he can put Vanessa through her paces in an afterschool special that has no moral or "message to grow on", unless that moral is "bad things also happen to bad people". It's only when Freeway needs an ending that writer/director Bright abruptly picks up some of the potential he's cast aside and tries to cobble together a big finish. I'm not sure the origins of this motion picture, but what it turned out to be was a starring vehicle for the young Reese Witherspoon that went nowhere. Not because she isn't cute as all get out and doesn't do a fine job here. It's because Vanessa dominates the whole show and is a sociopath but unfortunately, she's not one of those intriguing and grandiose sociopaths. She's one of those petty, boring sociopaths who turn up in police stations every day. The movie takes great pains to spell out all the terrible things that were done to Vanessa but none of it seems to have had any effect on her. Vanessa has no depth or inner life and cruises through her horrible existence like a shark looking for the next fat seal to eat. That might not have been a problem if Freeway had become the kind of thriller suggested by writer/director Bright's very clever left turn. In plot dominated tales, it's not always necessary for characters to be relatable or even all that interesting. By essentially becoming a study of a two-dimensional character, though, the film only highlights the lack of connection the viewer can have with Vanessa. Witherspoon is good here, as is Keifer Sutherland and Brooke Shields. Brittany Murphy has an odd role as a scarred paint-huffer and Dan Hedaya and Wolfgang Bodison are fine as two detectives, though the movie can't keep straight which one of them is supposed to be the good cop and which the bad cop. In most respects, Freeway is perfectly acceptable entertainment, with reasonably good writing, directing and acting. I can't shake the feeling that it could easily have been more than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wait... So This Movie Was Released in the West?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Bridge (joebridge@bigpond.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this movie, and as soon as it started with the bizarre, embarrassingly bad "Red Riding Hood" opening credits and horrid cheap-sounding soundtrack, I was certain it was some sort of fake "knock-off" video, especially as someone gave me this copy as sold in Indonesia. The ending credits were really bad and fake-looking as well, so maybe both were replaced in the Indonesian version, not sure, but it also is so bad throughout, perhaps the entire movie was replaced? While watching this, my friends and I were almost certain the actor credits were fake and that it was filmed by a group of amateur film-makers (as it was so utterly badly made - I was certain it was made in Indonesia or other Foreign country and was meant to make fun of the West), until Keifer Sutherland showed up and we were fairly certain it was him. Was this a straight-to-video movie? It was just so badly made and badly acted even for a dark comedy. Just because it is a comedy doesn't mean you have to act as if you are playing around with the script and not saying the lines in any way that makes sense. The acting was so disturbingly over-the-top bad, the accents annoying and ridiculous throughout (sounded mostly like hillbillies from the more isolated areas of Kentucky - yet supposedly was taking place in California), and the actors themselves looking so awful in every way possible (even Brooke Shields looked as if they used CGI to warp her body into something not quite human in that weird sailor outfit - again unless our copy was tampered with), I'm certain this was MEANT to be a farce/comedy, especially with the ludicrous climax regarding the actual Little Red Riding Hood story - which kind of added insult to injury - how could any writer be THAT ridiculous? Obviously it wasn't meant to be crime drama or anything like that, even though the premise suggested it was drama. It does have an overwhelming "quickly made television movie" and "print every first take" feel. So it appears that this movie (or a version of it) WAS released in the USA (not sure about here in Australia) after all? I'm still fairly certain our copy was tampered with (especially the ridiculous looking and sounding opening and ending credits - that were in static-ridden Foreign-sounding music and in mono - which wouldn't meet even the lowest standards these days), as nothing could be that badly made and be released. Most of us thought that it was one of those "experimental" films that was made especially for places like Indonesia and never placed directly in the actors' credits, and which wasn't released elsewhere, but seeing the information on IMDb is quite stunning in its implications about the general populace... Unbelievable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outrageously Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only in the 1990's that you had a enormous stream of twisted, violent, dark films with awkward funny moments, and writers and directors got away with it, although some of them haven't lived up to higher expectations with the noble exception of Coen brothers. Far away from being intelligent like Coen's films "Freeway" comes to amaze us with bringing the story of Little Red Riding Hood in a different environment with many violent and funny situations. Reese Witherspoon plays the troubled Vanessa, a girl whose mother and stepfather were arrested, and she doesn't want to go to foster care or similar, deciding instead on going to her grandmother's house, the only place she can go. This Little Red Riding Hood won't bring cookies to grandma, and she's not so innocent like the old tale, here's a girl with lots of problems and lots of anger too after meeting her Big Bad Wolf, Bob a friendly psycho killer (Kiefer Sutherland) who picks her up on the road after her car broke. What comes after it's a hilarious and twisted story about two figures that don't know how to get rid of each other, in a plot that involves murders, juvenile prison for girls, a funny trial, punchlines in the wrong time to make us laugh all the time. It's not for everyone's tastes, it's certainly that not everyone will find the story funny as a comedy instead of a ridiculous way as the plot might suggest. It's full of surprises, very uncompromising and has some interesting performance from Witherspoon as the talking/smart/violent/Christian girl who manages to survive the whole ride meeting creepy characters on the way, and a nice performance from Kiefer playing the friendly guy who ends up being a killer trapped in his own evilness, after the girl shoot him several times, and this guy for some reason doesn't die but keeps living a painful life after. The scenes with both in the car, talking about her problems and he's playing the good listener was very good, and sometimes I wish that the whole movie would be focused on them doing this because it was interesting so these two change to each other the way they act, talk and all, but then we would have a dramatic feature, something that this film is not. How come one stumble upon this film? Simple! Of 5 films credited on IMDb you'll see in 4 random titles the suggestion for this film, and I gotta recognize that the promotion is a little bit over-the-top but it made me curious to watch it, and it turned out to be a great film. One year in a crusade after "Freeway" I finally watched, enjoyed, it got me laughing and surprised despite a few clich&eacute;s here and there. If you can see humor in bizarre situations that in ordinary life wouldn't be funny then this film is for you! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wash your mouth out with soap Little Red Riding Hood !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgonite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is a black comic take on Little Red Riding Hood. Reese Witherspoon plays a rather sweet and innocent looking young woman off to find her grandmother. Kiefer Sutherland plays a psychological serial killer, although not a fully paid up one but the free or Lite version. The film's strengths are the performance by Witherspoon who brings the character to life, and the screenplay which is funny in the extreme. Indeed I would be surprised if Witherspoon had not been nominated for an award in the role. Freeway is not a very politically correct film and is all the more enjoyable for it! This aspect of it could cause offence and as such has probably hindered it's publicity. Pros - Twisted, Dark, Comic Tale Cons - None come to mind Overall - Baddass
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    captaintrps
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible. I spent the majority of the time holding down the fast forward button on my remote. Reese W. does well despite the horrible film that this is. Keifer S. should just stay retired or go in hiding or wherever he was before this came out. Reese has to regret doing this film. Very predictable, with no plot or storyline that you're average movie buff couldn't come up with. I don't see where this has anything to do with the little red riding hood story. They forced that association onto this film. This is not worth watching at all. The weekend opening gross tells the story. Don't waste your time, or spoil your thoughts that Reese W. is fun to watch on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark, disgusting and utterly wonderful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is written and directed by Matthew Bright. It stars Reese Witherspoon, Kiefer Sutherland, Dan Hedaya, Wolfgang Bodison, Brooke Shields & Brittany Murphy. Plot is darkly based around the Little Red Riding Hood fairy tale and sees young runaway Vanessa Lutz (Witherspoon) hit the road after her parents are arrested. Setting off to visit her grandmother she agrees to a lift from the kind and well spoken Bob Wolverton (Sutherland), only to find that he's not as nice as she first thought. He in turn is in for a big surprise himself since Vanessa is more than capable of looking after herself. Twisted and richly humorous, Matthew Bright's movie oozes originality and quite frankly deserves to be better appreciated: never mind better known! Going into it for a first time completely oblivious to its structure will arguably aid the experience. Suffice to say that the less known about it prior to viewing it the better. All I have to say is that it's violent, sweary and contains very sexually explicit dialogue, so if those things are likely to offend then perhaps stay away from it. But what if I offer up that those things are dealt with a satirical bent? That the tough scenes, and some of them are very tough, are basis to a caustic narrative about social hypocrisy and the often stupidity of the law? Interested? You should be, because once viewed you're unlikely to forget it. It's no surprise to see Oliver Stone's name etched onto the production credits, since this very much feels like a dirty second cousin to his Natural Born Killers. I'd argue that here we have the better acted film with Witherspoon and Sutherland giving virtuoso performances: with admirable support coming from the likes of Bodison, Shields and Murphy. One of the most undervalued film's of the 90s? You bet it is! 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Varied, violent, funny and furious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So there's me thinking I'm taking a break from my obscure exploitation movies and I find myself sat before this beauty. Made in 1996, which doesn't seem so long ago, but it's before Keiffer Sutherland settled into the 24 TV series and before Reese Witherspoon had even made Election, and while they have both gone on to much bigger if not better things, director Bright has not. Well, I don't know what possessed him to imagine he was going to make too many Hollywood friends with this mighty chunk of wild and anti-establishment, two fingered spout of anger, but it is enormous fun to watch. Also, as with so much exploitative cinema it seems to tell far more truths than your average 'serious' movie. Sutherland is effective but Witherspoon amazing, I had forgotten how tremendous she could be. Varied, violent, funny and furious, this is worth a watch anytime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanquinn-52-789942
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely brilliant film in so many different respects. At it's most basic it's a modern take on Robin Hood, but it can be enjoyed on many different levels. There are several just plain brilliant performances. This is first film that I watched Reece Witherspoon in that really showed me her depth and stretched her ability as an actress, and she was only 18 years old! She's strong, powerful, empathetic and like-able as the wayward teen looking for her grandmother. Keifer Sutherland also has a strong role, with some of my other favorite performances being from Britany Murphy as a completely transformed and nearly unrecognizable pyromaniac lesbian delinquent. Another great performance is Michael T. Weiss (from the TV series Pretender) as a complete crack-head, and Brook Shields as the wife of Keifer Sutherland's character. This is not a film for children, despite it being based on a children's tale, but if you approach it with an open mind I think you'll really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reese As You've Never Seen Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reese Witherspoon made this riveting thriller before she became everybody's favorite sweetheart. The "Legally Blond" star plays a foul-mouthed, illiterate teenager named Vanessa Lutz who hitches a ride with an older man after her car breaks down on the freeway. He offers her a lift as far as Los Angeles and even takes her out to dinner. Later, he turns out to be a notorious California highway serial killer who has been making headlines. Kiefer Sutherland is thoroughly obnoxious as Bob Wolverton, a bespectacled boys counselor who gets more than he bargained for after he picks up Vanessa, cuts off her ponytail, and threatens to rape her corpse. She whips out a small, Spanish-made automatic pistol that her boyfriend, Chopper (Bokeem Woodbine) gave her moments before he died in a drive-by shooting. Vanessa lands in jail but she does not stick long before she breaks out and joins a group of Hispanic girls who pull tricks on the side. All Vanessa wants to do is go to Stockton, California, so she can live with her grandmother rather than wind up in another horrible foster home.The dialogue brims with profanity and the subject matter is very unsavory. Witherspoon gives a dynamic performance. If you think that Witherspoon is cast against the grain, wait until you see a grown-up Brooke Shields who plays the wife of the serial killer. "Freeway" is an unforgettable dark comedy that doesn't pull any of its punches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is still one of Reese's best roles ever, and not a dull moment ever . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know, it may seem ridiculous to some, but actually, even after all these years (now well into 2012), this is still a film to watch, and no one could have delivered the key role more perfectly than Reese Witherspoon. She is simply spectacularly spot on with her characterization of the theme and culture that is her character here. The story is a bit hard edged for some, but sadly, not entirely outside the realms of reality in the current world. Do characters like hers in this film really exist as portrayed? Absolutely yes. Do characters like that portrayed by Sutherland, the predatory pedophile sociopath who appears to be so acceptably "normal" to the outside world? Absolutely yes, as recent history has shown only too clearly. On the surface this may have appeared to be a sort of whacky, creepy crime thriller, but actually, if one actually takes the time to watch this film, there is much more to this than the ad copy may have suggested at the time. It is still currently viable, to this very day . . . has stood the test of time. And it is absolutely one of Reese's best ever performances. Sadly, her more recent work has sort of flattened out into much less risky, complex roles, but hey, a great actress she is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suggests a better story than it delivers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is one of those films that are okay but still manage to be a little disappointing because it's so damned apparent that it could have been much better. It's perfectly clear where the story is going early on, yet it still takes forever to get there. When it finally arrives, writer/director Matthew Bright throws a great left turn into the plot and sets up a potentially fascinating second half of the movie. That never materializes because Bright ignores almost all of the possibilities suggested by his great idea so he can relentlessly focus on a main character who is too impervious to care about. Vanessa Lutz (Reese Witherspoon) is the 15 year old, illiterate spawn of poor white city trash. Her drug addict stepfather (Michael T. Weiss) molests her and her at-best-borderline crazy mother (Amanda Plummer) turns tricks on the street in the parking lot outside the motel room where they all live. When they get arrested, Vanessa tries to flee to the grandmother she's never met. Along the way, she runs into Bob Wolverton (Keifer Sutherland) a counselor for troubled youth who offers her a lift and some help with Vanessa's beyond screwed up life. If I tell you there's a mention at the start of the film of a serial killer targeting young girls in Vanessa's town, can you guess where her and Bob's relationship is headed? That is where it goes, though writer/director Bright waits a long time to get it there and then shamelessly foreshadows it right before it happens, as though anyone watching this movie didn't see it coming. But then he takes what you expect and completely upends it, leaving you without any clue where Freeway is going next but anxious to find out. That feeling doesn't last long because writer/director Bright takes almost all of the interesting directions his story could go and reduces them to comic relief so he can put Vanessa through her paces in an afterschool special that has no moral or "message to grow on", unless that moral is "bad things also happen to bad people". It's only when Freeway needs an ending that writer/director Bright abruptly picks up some of the potential he's cast aside and tries to cobble together a big finish. I'm not sure the origins of this motion picture, but what it turned out to be was a starring vehicle for the young Reese Witherspoon that went nowhere. Not because she isn't cute as all get out and doesn't do a fine job here. It's because Vanessa dominates the whole show and is a sociopath but unfortunately, she's not one of those intriguing and grandiose sociopaths. She's one of those petty, boring sociopaths who turn up in police stations every day. The movie takes great pains to spell out all the terrible things that were done to Vanessa but none of it seems to have had any effect on her. Vanessa has no depth or inner life and cruises through her horrible existence like a shark looking for the next fat seal to eat. That might not have been a problem if Freeway had become the kind of thriller suggested by writer/director Bright's very clever left turn. In plot dominated tales, it's not always necessary for characters to be relatable or even all that interesting. By essentially becoming a study of a two-dimensional character, though, the film only highlights the lack of connection the viewer can have with Vanessa. Witherspoon is good here, as is Keifer Sutherland and Brooke Shields. Brittany Murphy has an odd role as a scarred paint-huffer and Dan Hedaya and Wolfgang Bodison are fine as two detectives, though the movie can't keep straight which one of them is supposed to be the good cop and which the bad cop. In most respects, Freeway is perfectly acceptable entertainment, with reasonably good writing, directing and acting. I can't shake the feeling that it could easily have been more than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wait... So This Movie Was Released in the West?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Bridge (joebridge@bigpond.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this movie, and as soon as it started with the bizarre, embarrassingly bad "Red Riding Hood" opening credits and horrid cheap-sounding soundtrack, I was certain it was some sort of fake "knock-off" video, especially as someone gave me this copy as sold in Indonesia. The ending credits were really bad and fake-looking as well, so maybe both were replaced in the Indonesian version, not sure, but it also is so bad throughout, perhaps the entire movie was replaced? While watching this, my friends and I were almost certain the actor credits were fake and that it was filmed by a group of amateur film-makers (as it was so utterly badly made - I was certain it was made in Indonesia or other Foreign country and was meant to make fun of the West), until Keifer Sutherland showed up and we were fairly certain it was him. Was this a straight-to-video movie? It was just so badly made and badly acted even for a dark comedy. Just because it is a comedy doesn't mean you have to act as if you are playing around with the script and not saying the lines in any way that makes sense. The acting was so disturbingly over-the-top bad, the accents annoying and ridiculous throughout (sounded mostly like hillbillies from the more isolated areas of Kentucky - yet supposedly was taking place in California), and the actors themselves looking so awful in every way possible (even Brooke Shields looked as if they used CGI to warp her body into something not quite human in that weird sailor outfit - again unless our copy was tampered with), I'm certain this was MEANT to be a farce/comedy, especially with the ludicrous climax regarding the actual Little Red Riding Hood story - which kind of added insult to injury - how could any writer be THAT ridiculous? Obviously it wasn't meant to be crime drama or anything like that, even though the premise suggested it was drama. It does have an overwhelming "quickly made television movie" and "print every first take" feel. So it appears that this movie (or a version of it) WAS released in the USA (not sure about here in Australia) after all? I'm still fairly certain our copy was tampered with (especially the ridiculous looking and sounding opening and ending credits - that were in static-ridden Foreign-sounding music and in mono - which wouldn't meet even the lowest standards these days), as nothing could be that badly made and be released. Most of us thought that it was one of those "experimental" films that was made especially for places like Indonesia and never placed directly in the actors' credits, and which wasn't released elsewhere, but seeing the information on IMDb is quite stunning in its implications about the general populace... Unbelievable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outrageously Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only in the 1990's that you had a enormous stream of twisted, violent, dark films with awkward funny moments, and writers and directors got away with it, although some of them haven't lived up to higher expectations with the noble exception of Coen brothers. Far away from being intelligent like Coen's films "Freeway" comes to amaze us with bringing the story of Little Red Riding Hood in a different environment with many violent and funny situations. Reese Witherspoon plays the troubled Vanessa, a girl whose mother and stepfather were arrested, and she doesn't want to go to foster care or similar, deciding instead on going to her grandmother's house, the only place she can go. This Little Red Riding Hood won't bring cookies to grandma, and she's not so innocent like the old tale, here's a girl with lots of problems and lots of anger too after meeting her Big Bad Wolf, Bob a friendly psycho killer (Kiefer Sutherland) who picks her up on the road after her car broke. What comes after it's a hilarious and twisted story about two figures that don't know how to get rid of each other, in a plot that involves murders, juvenile prison for girls, a funny trial, punchlines in the wrong time to make us laugh all the time. It's not for everyone's tastes, it's certainly that not everyone will find the story funny as a comedy instead of a ridiculous way as the plot might suggest. It's full of surprises, very uncompromising and has some interesting performance from Witherspoon as the talking/smart/violent/Christian girl who manages to survive the whole ride meeting creepy characters on the way, and a nice performance from Kiefer playing the friendly guy who ends up being a killer trapped in his own evilness, after the girl shoot him several times, and this guy for some reason doesn't die but keeps living a painful life after. The scenes with both in the car, talking about her problems and he's playing the good listener was very good, and sometimes I wish that the whole movie would be focused on them doing this because it was interesting so these two change to each other the way they act, talk and all, but then we would have a dramatic feature, something that this film is not. How come one stumble upon this film? Simple! Of 5 films credited on IMDb you'll see in 4 random titles the suggestion for this film, and I gotta recognize that the promotion is a little bit over-the-top but it made me curious to watch it, and it turned out to be a great film. One year in a crusade after "Freeway" I finally watched, enjoyed, it got me laughing and surprised despite a few clich&eacute;s here and there. If you can see humor in bizarre situations that in ordinary life wouldn't be funny then this film is for you! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wash your mouth out with soap Little Red Riding Hood !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgonite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is a black comic take on Little Red Riding Hood. Reese Witherspoon plays a rather sweet and innocent looking young woman off to find her grandmother. Kiefer Sutherland plays a psychological serial killer, although not a fully paid up one but the free or Lite version. The film's strengths are the performance by Witherspoon who brings the character to life, and the screenplay which is funny in the extreme. Indeed I would be surprised if Witherspoon had not been nominated for an award in the role. Freeway is not a very politically correct film and is all the more enjoyable for it! This aspect of it could cause offence and as such has probably hindered it's publicity. Pros - Twisted, Dark, Comic Tale Cons - None come to mind Overall - Baddass
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    captaintrps
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible. I spent the majority of the time holding down the fast forward button on my remote. Reese W. does well despite the horrible film that this is. Keifer S. should just stay retired or go in hiding or wherever he was before this came out. Reese has to regret doing this film. Very predictable, with no plot or storyline that you're average movie buff couldn't come up with. I don't see where this has anything to do with the little red riding hood story. They forced that association onto this film. This is not worth watching at all. The weekend opening gross tells the story. Don't waste your time, or spoil your thoughts that Reese W. is fun to watch on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark, disgusting and utterly wonderful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is written and directed by Matthew Bright. It stars Reese Witherspoon, Kiefer Sutherland, Dan Hedaya, Wolfgang Bodison, Brooke Shields & Brittany Murphy. Plot is darkly based around the Little Red Riding Hood fairy tale and sees young runaway Vanessa Lutz (Witherspoon) hit the road after her parents are arrested. Setting off to visit her grandmother she agrees to a lift from the kind and well spoken Bob Wolverton (Sutherland), only to find that he's not as nice as she first thought. He in turn is in for a big surprise himself since Vanessa is more than capable of looking after herself. Twisted and richly humorous, Matthew Bright's movie oozes originality and quite frankly deserves to be better appreciated: never mind better known! Going into it for a first time completely oblivious to its structure will arguably aid the experience. Suffice to say that the less known about it prior to viewing it the better. All I have to say is that it's violent, sweary and contains very sexually explicit dialogue, so if those things are likely to offend then perhaps stay away from it. But what if I offer up that those things are dealt with a satirical bent? That the tough scenes, and some of them are very tough, are basis to a caustic narrative about social hypocrisy and the often stupidity of the law? Interested? You should be, because once viewed you're unlikely to forget it. It's no surprise to see Oliver Stone's name etched onto the production credits, since this very much feels like a dirty second cousin to his Natural Born Killers. I'd argue that here we have the better acted film with Witherspoon and Sutherland giving virtuoso performances: with admirable support coming from the likes of Bodison, Shields and Murphy. One of the most undervalued film's of the 90s? You bet it is! 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Varied, violent, funny and furious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So there's me thinking I'm taking a break from my obscure exploitation movies and I find myself sat before this beauty. Made in 1996, which doesn't seem so long ago, but it's before Keiffer Sutherland settled into the 24 TV series and before Reese Witherspoon had even made Election, and while they have both gone on to much bigger if not better things, director Bright has not. Well, I don't know what possessed him to imagine he was going to make too many Hollywood friends with this mighty chunk of wild and anti-establishment, two fingered spout of anger, but it is enormous fun to watch. Also, as with so much exploitative cinema it seems to tell far more truths than your average 'serious' movie. Sutherland is effective but Witherspoon amazing, I had forgotten how tremendous she could be. Varied, violent, funny and furious, this is worth a watch anytime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanquinn-52-789942
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely brilliant film in so many different respects. At it's most basic it's a modern take on Robin Hood, but it can be enjoyed on many different levels. There are several just plain brilliant performances. This is first film that I watched Reece Witherspoon in that really showed me her depth and stretched her ability as an actress, and she was only 18 years old! She's strong, powerful, empathetic and like-able as the wayward teen looking for her grandmother. Keifer Sutherland also has a strong role, with some of my other favorite performances being from Britany Murphy as a completely transformed and nearly unrecognizable pyromaniac lesbian delinquent. Another great performance is Michael T. Weiss (from the TV series Pretender) as a complete crack-head, and Brook Shields as the wife of Keifer Sutherland's character. This is not a film for children, despite it being based on a children's tale, but if you approach it with an open mind I think you'll really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reese As You've Never Seen Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reese Witherspoon made this riveting thriller before she became everybody's favorite sweetheart. The "Legally Blond" star plays a foul-mouthed, illiterate teenager named Vanessa Lutz who hitches a ride with an older man after her car breaks down on the freeway. He offers her a lift as far as Los Angeles and even takes her out to dinner. Later, he turns out to be a notorious California highway serial killer who has been making headlines. Kiefer Sutherland is thoroughly obnoxious as Bob Wolverton, a bespectacled boys counselor who gets more than he bargained for after he picks up Vanessa, cuts off her ponytail, and threatens to rape her corpse. She whips out a small, Spanish-made automatic pistol that her boyfriend, Chopper (Bokeem Woodbine) gave her moments before he died in a drive-by shooting. Vanessa lands in jail but she does not stick long before she breaks out and joins a group of Hispanic girls who pull tricks on the side. All Vanessa wants to do is go to Stockton, California, so she can live with her grandmother rather than wind up in another horrible foster home.The dialogue brims with profanity and the subject matter is very unsavory. Witherspoon gives a dynamic performance. If you think that Witherspoon is cast against the grain, wait until you see a grown-up Brooke Shields who plays the wife of the serial killer. "Freeway" is an unforgettable dark comedy that doesn't pull any of its punches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is still one of Reese's best roles ever, and not a dull moment ever . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know, it may seem ridiculous to some, but actually, even after all these years (now well into 2012), this is still a film to watch, and no one could have delivered the key role more perfectly than Reese Witherspoon. She is simply spectacularly spot on with her characterization of the theme and culture that is her character here. The story is a bit hard edged for some, but sadly, not entirely outside the realms of reality in the current world. Do characters like hers in this film really exist as portrayed? Absolutely yes. Do characters like that portrayed by Sutherland, the predatory pedophile sociopath who appears to be so acceptably "normal" to the outside world? Absolutely yes, as recent history has shown only too clearly. On the surface this may have appeared to be a sort of whacky, creepy crime thriller, but actually, if one actually takes the time to watch this film, there is much more to this than the ad copy may have suggested at the time. It is still currently viable, to this very day . . . has stood the test of time. And it is absolutely one of Reese's best ever performances. Sadly, her more recent work has sort of flattened out into much less risky, complex roles, but hey, a great actress she is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suggests a better story than it delivers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is one of those films that are okay but still manage to be a little disappointing because it's so damned apparent that it could have been much better. It's perfectly clear where the story is going early on, yet it still takes forever to get there. When it finally arrives, writer/director Matthew Bright throws a great left turn into the plot and sets up a potentially fascinating second half of the movie. That never materializes because Bright ignores almost all of the possibilities suggested by his great idea so he can relentlessly focus on a main character who is too impervious to care about. Vanessa Lutz (Reese Witherspoon) is the 15 year old, illiterate spawn of poor white city trash. Her drug addict stepfather (Michael T. Weiss) molests her and her at-best-borderline crazy mother (Amanda Plummer) turns tricks on the street in the parking lot outside the motel room where they all live. When they get arrested, Vanessa tries to flee to the grandmother she's never met. Along the way, she runs into Bob Wolverton (Keifer Sutherland) a counselor for troubled youth who offers her a lift and some help with Vanessa's beyond screwed up life. If I tell you there's a mention at the start of the film of a serial killer targeting young girls in Vanessa's town, can you guess where her and Bob's relationship is headed? That is where it goes, though writer/director Bright waits a long time to get it there and then shamelessly foreshadows it right before it happens, as though anyone watching this movie didn't see it coming. But then he takes what you expect and completely upends it, leaving you without any clue where Freeway is going next but anxious to find out. That feeling doesn't last long because writer/director Bright takes almost all of the interesting directions his story could go and reduces them to comic relief so he can put Vanessa through her paces in an afterschool special that has no moral or "message to grow on", unless that moral is "bad things also happen to bad people". It's only when Freeway needs an ending that writer/director Bright abruptly picks up some of the potential he's cast aside and tries to cobble together a big finish. I'm not sure the origins of this motion picture, but what it turned out to be was a starring vehicle for the young Reese Witherspoon that went nowhere. Not because she isn't cute as all get out and doesn't do a fine job here. It's because Vanessa dominates the whole show and is a sociopath but unfortunately, she's not one of those intriguing and grandiose sociopaths. She's one of those petty, boring sociopaths who turn up in police stations every day. The movie takes great pains to spell out all the terrible things that were done to Vanessa but none of it seems to have had any effect on her. Vanessa has no depth or inner life and cruises through her horrible existence like a shark looking for the next fat seal to eat. That might not have been a problem if Freeway had become the kind of thriller suggested by writer/director Bright's very clever left turn. In plot dominated tales, it's not always necessary for characters to be relatable or even all that interesting. By essentially becoming a study of a two-dimensional character, though, the film only highlights the lack of connection the viewer can have with Vanessa. Witherspoon is good here, as is Keifer Sutherland and Brooke Shields. Brittany Murphy has an odd role as a scarred paint-huffer and Dan Hedaya and Wolfgang Bodison are fine as two detectives, though the movie can't keep straight which one of them is supposed to be the good cop and which the bad cop. In most respects, Freeway is perfectly acceptable entertainment, with reasonably good writing, directing and acting. I can't shake the feeling that it could easily have been more than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wait... So This Movie Was Released in the West?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Bridge (joebridge@bigpond.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this movie, and as soon as it started with the bizarre, embarrassingly bad "Red Riding Hood" opening credits and horrid cheap-sounding soundtrack, I was certain it was some sort of fake "knock-off" video, especially as someone gave me this copy as sold in Indonesia. The ending credits were really bad and fake-looking as well, so maybe both were replaced in the Indonesian version, not sure, but it also is so bad throughout, perhaps the entire movie was replaced? While watching this, my friends and I were almost certain the actor credits were fake and that it was filmed by a group of amateur film-makers (as it was so utterly badly made - I was certain it was made in Indonesia or other Foreign country and was meant to make fun of the West), until Keifer Sutherland showed up and we were fairly certain it was him. Was this a straight-to-video movie? It was just so badly made and badly acted even for a dark comedy. Just because it is a comedy doesn't mean you have to act as if you are playing around with the script and not saying the lines in any way that makes sense. The acting was so disturbingly over-the-top bad, the accents annoying and ridiculous throughout (sounded mostly like hillbillies from the more isolated areas of Kentucky - yet supposedly was taking place in California), and the actors themselves looking so awful in every way possible (even Brooke Shields looked as if they used CGI to warp her body into something not quite human in that weird sailor outfit - again unless our copy was tampered with), I'm certain this was MEANT to be a farce/comedy, especially with the ludicrous climax regarding the actual Little Red Riding Hood story - which kind of added insult to injury - how could any writer be THAT ridiculous? Obviously it wasn't meant to be crime drama or anything like that, even though the premise suggested it was drama. It does have an overwhelming "quickly made television movie" and "print every first take" feel. So it appears that this movie (or a version of it) WAS released in the USA (not sure about here in Australia) after all? I'm still fairly certain our copy was tampered with (especially the ridiculous looking and sounding opening and ending credits - that were in static-ridden Foreign-sounding music and in mono - which wouldn't meet even the lowest standards these days), as nothing could be that badly made and be released. Most of us thought that it was one of those "experimental" films that was made especially for places like Indonesia and never placed directly in the actors' credits, and which wasn't released elsewhere, but seeing the information on IMDb is quite stunning in its implications about the general populace... Unbelievable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outrageously Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only in the 1990's that you had a enormous stream of twisted, violent, dark films with awkward funny moments, and writers and directors got away with it, although some of them haven't lived up to higher expectations with the noble exception of Coen brothers. Far away from being intelligent like Coen's films "Freeway" comes to amaze us with bringing the story of Little Red Riding Hood in a different environment with many violent and funny situations. Reese Witherspoon plays the troubled Vanessa, a girl whose mother and stepfather were arrested, and she doesn't want to go to foster care or similar, deciding instead on going to her grandmother's house, the only place she can go. This Little Red Riding Hood won't bring cookies to grandma, and she's not so innocent like the old tale, here's a girl with lots of problems and lots of anger too after meeting her Big Bad Wolf, Bob a friendly psycho killer (Kiefer Sutherland) who picks her up on the road after her car broke. What comes after it's a hilarious and twisted story about two figures that don't know how to get rid of each other, in a plot that involves murders, juvenile prison for girls, a funny trial, punchlines in the wrong time to make us laugh all the time. It's not for everyone's tastes, it's certainly that not everyone will find the story funny as a comedy instead of a ridiculous way as the plot might suggest. It's full of surprises, very uncompromising and has some interesting performance from Witherspoon as the talking/smart/violent/Christian girl who manages to survive the whole ride meeting creepy characters on the way, and a nice performance from Kiefer playing the friendly guy who ends up being a killer trapped in his own evilness, after the girl shoot him several times, and this guy for some reason doesn't die but keeps living a painful life after. The scenes with both in the car, talking about her problems and he's playing the good listener was very good, and sometimes I wish that the whole movie would be focused on them doing this because it was interesting so these two change to each other the way they act, talk and all, but then we would have a dramatic feature, something that this film is not. How come one stumble upon this film? Simple! Of 5 films credited on IMDb you'll see in 4 random titles the suggestion for this film, and I gotta recognize that the promotion is a little bit over-the-top but it made me curious to watch it, and it turned out to be a great film. One year in a crusade after "Freeway" I finally watched, enjoyed, it got me laughing and surprised despite a few clich&eacute;s here and there. If you can see humor in bizarre situations that in ordinary life wouldn't be funny then this film is for you! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wash your mouth out with soap Little Red Riding Hood !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgonite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is a black comic take on Little Red Riding Hood. Reese Witherspoon plays a rather sweet and innocent looking young woman off to find her grandmother. Kiefer Sutherland plays a psychological serial killer, although not a fully paid up one but the free or Lite version. The film's strengths are the performance by Witherspoon who brings the character to life, and the screenplay which is funny in the extreme. Indeed I would be surprised if Witherspoon had not been nominated for an award in the role. Freeway is not a very politically correct film and is all the more enjoyable for it! This aspect of it could cause offence and as such has probably hindered it's publicity. Pros - Twisted, Dark, Comic Tale Cons - None come to mind Overall - Baddass
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    captaintrps
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible. I spent the majority of the time holding down the fast forward button on my remote. Reese W. does well despite the horrible film that this is. Keifer S. should just stay retired or go in hiding or wherever he was before this came out. Reese has to regret doing this film. Very predictable, with no plot or storyline that you're average movie buff couldn't come up with. I don't see where this has anything to do with the little red riding hood story. They forced that association onto this film. This is not worth watching at all. The weekend opening gross tells the story. Don't waste your time, or spoil your thoughts that Reese W. is fun to watch on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark, disgusting and utterly wonderful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is written and directed by Matthew Bright. It stars Reese Witherspoon, Kiefer Sutherland, Dan Hedaya, Wolfgang Bodison, Brooke Shields & Brittany Murphy. Plot is darkly based around the Little Red Riding Hood fairy tale and sees young runaway Vanessa Lutz (Witherspoon) hit the road after her parents are arrested. Setting off to visit her grandmother she agrees to a lift from the kind and well spoken Bob Wolverton (Sutherland), only to find that he's not as nice as she first thought. He in turn is in for a big surprise himself since Vanessa is more than capable of looking after herself. Twisted and richly humorous, Matthew Bright's movie oozes originality and quite frankly deserves to be better appreciated: never mind better known! Going into it for a first time completely oblivious to its structure will arguably aid the experience. Suffice to say that the less known about it prior to viewing it the better. All I have to say is that it's violent, sweary and contains very sexually explicit dialogue, so if those things are likely to offend then perhaps stay away from it. But what if I offer up that those things are dealt with a satirical bent? That the tough scenes, and some of them are very tough, are basis to a caustic narrative about social hypocrisy and the often stupidity of the law? Interested? You should be, because once viewed you're unlikely to forget it. It's no surprise to see Oliver Stone's name etched onto the production credits, since this very much feels like a dirty second cousin to his Natural Born Killers. I'd argue that here we have the better acted film with Witherspoon and Sutherland giving virtuoso performances: with admirable support coming from the likes of Bodison, Shields and Murphy. One of the most undervalued film's of the 90s? You bet it is! 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Varied, violent, funny and furious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So there's me thinking I'm taking a break from my obscure exploitation movies and I find myself sat before this beauty. Made in 1996, which doesn't seem so long ago, but it's before Keiffer Sutherland settled into the 24 TV series and before Reese Witherspoon had even made Election, and while they have both gone on to much bigger if not better things, director Bright has not. Well, I don't know what possessed him to imagine he was going to make too many Hollywood friends with this mighty chunk of wild and anti-establishment, two fingered spout of anger, but it is enormous fun to watch. Also, as with so much exploitative cinema it seems to tell far more truths than your average 'serious' movie. Sutherland is effective but Witherspoon amazing, I had forgotten how tremendous she could be. Varied, violent, funny and furious, this is worth a watch anytime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanquinn-52-789942
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely brilliant film in so many different respects. At it's most basic it's a modern take on Robin Hood, but it can be enjoyed on many different levels. There are several just plain brilliant performances. This is first film that I watched Reece Witherspoon in that really showed me her depth and stretched her ability as an actress, and she was only 18 years old! She's strong, powerful, empathetic and like-able as the wayward teen looking for her grandmother. Keifer Sutherland also has a strong role, with some of my other favorite performances being from Britany Murphy as a completely transformed and nearly unrecognizable pyromaniac lesbian delinquent. Another great performance is Michael T. Weiss (from the TV series Pretender) as a complete crack-head, and Brook Shields as the wife of Keifer Sutherland's character. This is not a film for children, despite it being based on a children's tale, but if you approach it with an open mind I think you'll really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reese As You've Never Seen Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reese Witherspoon made this riveting thriller before she became everybody's favorite sweetheart. The "Legally Blond" star plays a foul-mouthed, illiterate teenager named Vanessa Lutz who hitches a ride with an older man after her car breaks down on the freeway. He offers her a lift as far as Los Angeles and even takes her out to dinner. Later, he turns out to be a notorious California highway serial killer who has been making headlines. Kiefer Sutherland is thoroughly obnoxious as Bob Wolverton, a bespectacled boys counselor who gets more than he bargained for after he picks up Vanessa, cuts off her ponytail, and threatens to rape her corpse. She whips out a small, Spanish-made automatic pistol that her boyfriend, Chopper (Bokeem Woodbine) gave her moments before he died in a drive-by shooting. Vanessa lands in jail but she does not stick long before she breaks out and joins a group of Hispanic girls who pull tricks on the side. All Vanessa wants to do is go to Stockton, California, so she can live with her grandmother rather than wind up in another horrible foster home.The dialogue brims with profanity and the subject matter is very unsavory. Witherspoon gives a dynamic performance. If you think that Witherspoon is cast against the grain, wait until you see a grown-up Brooke Shields who plays the wife of the serial killer. "Freeway" is an unforgettable dark comedy that doesn't pull any of its punches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is still one of Reese's best roles ever, and not a dull moment ever . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know, it may seem ridiculous to some, but actually, even after all these years (now well into 2012), this is still a film to watch, and no one could have delivered the key role more perfectly than Reese Witherspoon. She is simply spectacularly spot on with her characterization of the theme and culture that is her character here. The story is a bit hard edged for some, but sadly, not entirely outside the realms of reality in the current world. Do characters like hers in this film really exist as portrayed? Absolutely yes. Do characters like that portrayed by Sutherland, the predatory pedophile sociopath who appears to be so acceptably "normal" to the outside world? Absolutely yes, as recent history has shown only too clearly. On the surface this may have appeared to be a sort of whacky, creepy crime thriller, but actually, if one actually takes the time to watch this film, there is much more to this than the ad copy may have suggested at the time. It is still currently viable, to this very day . . . has stood the test of time. And it is absolutely one of Reese's best ever performances. Sadly, her more recent work has sort of flattened out into much less risky, complex roles, but hey, a great actress she is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suggests a better story than it delivers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is one of those films that are okay but still manage to be a little disappointing because it's so damned apparent that it could have been much better. It's perfectly clear where the story is going early on, yet it still takes forever to get there. When it finally arrives, writer/director Matthew Bright throws a great left turn into the plot and sets up a potentially fascinating second half of the movie. That never materializes because Bright ignores almost all of the possibilities suggested by his great idea so he can relentlessly focus on a main character who is too impervious to care about. Vanessa Lutz (Reese Witherspoon) is the 15 year old, illiterate spawn of poor white city trash. Her drug addict stepfather (Michael T. Weiss) molests her and her at-best-borderline crazy mother (Amanda Plummer) turns tricks on the street in the parking lot outside the motel room where they all live. When they get arrested, Vanessa tries to flee to the grandmother she's never met. Along the way, she runs into Bob Wolverton (Keifer Sutherland) a counselor for troubled youth who offers her a lift and some help with Vanessa's beyond screwed up life. If I tell you there's a mention at the start of the film of a serial killer targeting young girls in Vanessa's town, can you guess where her and Bob's relationship is headed? That is where it goes, though writer/director Bright waits a long time to get it there and then shamelessly foreshadows it right before it happens, as though anyone watching this movie didn't see it coming. But then he takes what you expect and completely upends it, leaving you without any clue where Freeway is going next but anxious to find out. That feeling doesn't last long because writer/director Bright takes almost all of the interesting directions his story could go and reduces them to comic relief so he can put Vanessa through her paces in an afterschool special that has no moral or "message to grow on", unless that moral is "bad things also happen to bad people". It's only when Freeway needs an ending that writer/director Bright abruptly picks up some of the potential he's cast aside and tries to cobble together a big finish. I'm not sure the origins of this motion picture, but what it turned out to be was a starring vehicle for the young Reese Witherspoon that went nowhere. Not because she isn't cute as all get out and doesn't do a fine job here. It's because Vanessa dominates the whole show and is a sociopath but unfortunately, she's not one of those intriguing and grandiose sociopaths. She's one of those petty, boring sociopaths who turn up in police stations every day. The movie takes great pains to spell out all the terrible things that were done to Vanessa but none of it seems to have had any effect on her. Vanessa has no depth or inner life and cruises through her horrible existence like a shark looking for the next fat seal to eat. That might not have been a problem if Freeway had become the kind of thriller suggested by writer/director Bright's very clever left turn. In plot dominated tales, it's not always necessary for characters to be relatable or even all that interesting. By essentially becoming a study of a two-dimensional character, though, the film only highlights the lack of connection the viewer can have with Vanessa. Witherspoon is good here, as is Keifer Sutherland and Brooke Shields. Brittany Murphy has an odd role as a scarred paint-huffer and Dan Hedaya and Wolfgang Bodison are fine as two detectives, though the movie can't keep straight which one of them is supposed to be the good cop and which the bad cop. In most respects, Freeway is perfectly acceptable entertainment, with reasonably good writing, directing and acting. I can't shake the feeling that it could easily have been more than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wait... So This Movie Was Released in the West?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Bridge (joebridge@bigpond.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this movie, and as soon as it started with the bizarre, embarrassingly bad "Red Riding Hood" opening credits and horrid cheap-sounding soundtrack, I was certain it was some sort of fake "knock-off" video, especially as someone gave me this copy as sold in Indonesia. The ending credits were really bad and fake-looking as well, so maybe both were replaced in the Indonesian version, not sure, but it also is so bad throughout, perhaps the entire movie was replaced? While watching this, my friends and I were almost certain the actor credits were fake and that it was filmed by a group of amateur film-makers (as it was so utterly badly made - I was certain it was made in Indonesia or other Foreign country and was meant to make fun of the West), until Keifer Sutherland showed up and we were fairly certain it was him. Was this a straight-to-video movie? It was just so badly made and badly acted even for a dark comedy. Just because it is a comedy doesn't mean you have to act as if you are playing around with the script and not saying the lines in any way that makes sense. The acting was so disturbingly over-the-top bad, the accents annoying and ridiculous throughout (sounded mostly like hillbillies from the more isolated areas of Kentucky - yet supposedly was taking place in California), and the actors themselves looking so awful in every way possible (even Brooke Shields looked as if they used CGI to warp her body into something not quite human in that weird sailor outfit - again unless our copy was tampered with), I'm certain this was MEANT to be a farce/comedy, especially with the ludicrous climax regarding the actual Little Red Riding Hood story - which kind of added insult to injury - how could any writer be THAT ridiculous? Obviously it wasn't meant to be crime drama or anything like that, even though the premise suggested it was drama. It does have an overwhelming "quickly made television movie" and "print every first take" feel. So it appears that this movie (or a version of it) WAS released in the USA (not sure about here in Australia) after all? I'm still fairly certain our copy was tampered with (especially the ridiculous looking and sounding opening and ending credits - that were in static-ridden Foreign-sounding music and in mono - which wouldn't meet even the lowest standards these days), as nothing could be that badly made and be released. Most of us thought that it was one of those "experimental" films that was made especially for places like Indonesia and never placed directly in the actors' credits, and which wasn't released elsewhere, but seeing the information on IMDb is quite stunning in its implications about the general populace... Unbelievable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outrageously Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only in the 1990's that you had a enormous stream of twisted, violent, dark films with awkward funny moments, and writers and directors got away with it, although some of them haven't lived up to higher expectations with the noble exception of Coen brothers. Far away from being intelligent like Coen's films "Freeway" comes to amaze us with bringing the story of Little Red Riding Hood in a different environment with many violent and funny situations. Reese Witherspoon plays the troubled Vanessa, a girl whose mother and stepfather were arrested, and she doesn't want to go to foster care or similar, deciding instead on going to her grandmother's house, the only place she can go. This Little Red Riding Hood won't bring cookies to grandma, and she's not so innocent like the old tale, here's a girl with lots of problems and lots of anger too after meeting her Big Bad Wolf, Bob a friendly psycho killer (Kiefer Sutherland) who picks her up on the road after her car broke. What comes after it's a hilarious and twisted story about two figures that don't know how to get rid of each other, in a plot that involves murders, juvenile prison for girls, a funny trial, punchlines in the wrong time to make us laugh all the time. It's not for everyone's tastes, it's certainly that not everyone will find the story funny as a comedy instead of a ridiculous way as the plot might suggest. It's full of surprises, very uncompromising and has some interesting performance from Witherspoon as the talking/smart/violent/Christian girl who manages to survive the whole ride meeting creepy characters on the way, and a nice performance from Kiefer playing the friendly guy who ends up being a killer trapped in his own evilness, after the girl shoot him several times, and this guy for some reason doesn't die but keeps living a painful life after. The scenes with both in the car, talking about her problems and he's playing the good listener was very good, and sometimes I wish that the whole movie would be focused on them doing this because it was interesting so these two change to each other the way they act, talk and all, but then we would have a dramatic feature, something that this film is not. How come one stumble upon this film? Simple! Of 5 films credited on IMDb you'll see in 4 random titles the suggestion for this film, and I gotta recognize that the promotion is a little bit over-the-top but it made me curious to watch it, and it turned out to be a great film. One year in a crusade after "Freeway" I finally watched, enjoyed, it got me laughing and surprised despite a few clich&eacute;s here and there. If you can see humor in bizarre situations that in ordinary life wouldn't be funny then this film is for you! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wash your mouth out with soap Little Red Riding Hood !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgonite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is a black comic take on Little Red Riding Hood. Reese Witherspoon plays a rather sweet and innocent looking young woman off to find her grandmother. Kiefer Sutherland plays a psychological serial killer, although not a fully paid up one but the free or Lite version. The film's strengths are the performance by Witherspoon who brings the character to life, and the screenplay which is funny in the extreme. Indeed I would be surprised if Witherspoon had not been nominated for an award in the role. Freeway is not a very politically correct film and is all the more enjoyable for it! This aspect of it could cause offence and as such has probably hindered it's publicity. Pros - Twisted, Dark, Comic Tale Cons - None come to mind Overall - Baddass
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    captaintrps
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible. I spent the majority of the time holding down the fast forward button on my remote. Reese W. does well despite the horrible film that this is. Keifer S. should just stay retired or go in hiding or wherever he was before this came out. Reese has to regret doing this film. Very predictable, with no plot or storyline that you're average movie buff couldn't come up with. I don't see where this has anything to do with the little red riding hood story. They forced that association onto this film. This is not worth watching at all. The weekend opening gross tells the story. Don't waste your time, or spoil your thoughts that Reese W. is fun to watch on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark, disgusting and utterly wonderful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is written and directed by Matthew Bright. It stars Reese Witherspoon, Kiefer Sutherland, Dan Hedaya, Wolfgang Bodison, Brooke Shields & Brittany Murphy. Plot is darkly based around the Little Red Riding Hood fairy tale and sees young runaway Vanessa Lutz (Witherspoon) hit the road after her parents are arrested. Setting off to visit her grandmother she agrees to a lift from the kind and well spoken Bob Wolverton (Sutherland), only to find that he's not as nice as she first thought. He in turn is in for a big surprise himself since Vanessa is more than capable of looking after herself. Twisted and richly humorous, Matthew Bright's movie oozes originality and quite frankly deserves to be better appreciated: never mind better known! Going into it for a first time completely oblivious to its structure will arguably aid the experience. Suffice to say that the less known about it prior to viewing it the better. All I have to say is that it's violent, sweary and contains very sexually explicit dialogue, so if those things are likely to offend then perhaps stay away from it. But what if I offer up that those things are dealt with a satirical bent? That the tough scenes, and some of them are very tough, are basis to a caustic narrative about social hypocrisy and the often stupidity of the law? Interested? You should be, because once viewed you're unlikely to forget it. It's no surprise to see Oliver Stone's name etched onto the production credits, since this very much feels like a dirty second cousin to his Natural Born Killers. I'd argue that here we have the better acted film with Witherspoon and Sutherland giving virtuoso performances: with admirable support coming from the likes of Bodison, Shields and Murphy. One of the most undervalued film's of the 90s? You bet it is! 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Varied, violent, funny and furious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So there's me thinking I'm taking a break from my obscure exploitation movies and I find myself sat before this beauty. Made in 1996, which doesn't seem so long ago, but it's before Keiffer Sutherland settled into the 24 TV series and before Reese Witherspoon had even made Election, and while they have both gone on to much bigger if not better things, director Bright has not. Well, I don't know what possessed him to imagine he was going to make too many Hollywood friends with this mighty chunk of wild and anti-establishment, two fingered spout of anger, but it is enormous fun to watch. Also, as with so much exploitative cinema it seems to tell far more truths than your average 'serious' movie. Sutherland is effective but Witherspoon amazing, I had forgotten how tremendous she could be. Varied, violent, funny and furious, this is worth a watch anytime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanquinn-52-789942
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely brilliant film in so many different respects. At it's most basic it's a modern take on Robin Hood, but it can be enjoyed on many different levels. There are several just plain brilliant performances. This is first film that I watched Reece Witherspoon in that really showed me her depth and stretched her ability as an actress, and she was only 18 years old! She's strong, powerful, empathetic and like-able as the wayward teen looking for her grandmother. Keifer Sutherland also has a strong role, with some of my other favorite performances being from Britany Murphy as a completely transformed and nearly unrecognizable pyromaniac lesbian delinquent. Another great performance is Michael T. Weiss (from the TV series Pretender) as a complete crack-head, and Brook Shields as the wife of Keifer Sutherland's character. This is not a film for children, despite it being based on a children's tale, but if you approach it with an open mind I think you'll really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reese As You've Never Seen Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reese Witherspoon made this riveting thriller before she became everybody's favorite sweetheart. The "Legally Blond" star plays a foul-mouthed, illiterate teenager named Vanessa Lutz who hitches a ride with an older man after her car breaks down on the freeway. He offers her a lift as far as Los Angeles and even takes her out to dinner. Later, he turns out to be a notorious California highway serial killer who has been making headlines. Kiefer Sutherland is thoroughly obnoxious as Bob Wolverton, a bespectacled boys counselor who gets more than he bargained for after he picks up Vanessa, cuts off her ponytail, and threatens to rape her corpse. She whips out a small, Spanish-made automatic pistol that her boyfriend, Chopper (Bokeem Woodbine) gave her moments before he died in a drive-by shooting. Vanessa lands in jail but she does not stick long before she breaks out and joins a group of Hispanic girls who pull tricks on the side. All Vanessa wants to do is go to Stockton, California, so she can live with her grandmother rather than wind up in another horrible foster home.The dialogue brims with profanity and the subject matter is very unsavory. Witherspoon gives a dynamic performance. If you think that Witherspoon is cast against the grain, wait until you see a grown-up Brooke Shields who plays the wife of the serial killer. "Freeway" is an unforgettable dark comedy that doesn't pull any of its punches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is still one of Reese's best roles ever, and not a dull moment ever . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know, it may seem ridiculous to some, but actually, even after all these years (now well into 2012), this is still a film to watch, and no one could have delivered the key role more perfectly than Reese Witherspoon. She is simply spectacularly spot on with her characterization of the theme and culture that is her character here. The story is a bit hard edged for some, but sadly, not entirely outside the realms of reality in the current world. Do characters like hers in this film really exist as portrayed? Absolutely yes. Do characters like that portrayed by Sutherland, the predatory pedophile sociopath who appears to be so acceptably "normal" to the outside world? Absolutely yes, as recent history has shown only too clearly. On the surface this may have appeared to be a sort of whacky, creepy crime thriller, but actually, if one actually takes the time to watch this film, there is much more to this than the ad copy may have suggested at the time. It is still currently viable, to this very day . . . has stood the test of time. And it is absolutely one of Reese's best ever performances. Sadly, her more recent work has sort of flattened out into much less risky, complex roles, but hey, a great actress she is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suggests a better story than it delivers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is one of those films that are okay but still manage to be a little disappointing because it's so damned apparent that it could have been much better. It's perfectly clear where the story is going early on, yet it still takes forever to get there. When it finally arrives, writer/director Matthew Bright throws a great left turn into the plot and sets up a potentially fascinating second half of the movie. That never materializes because Bright ignores almost all of the possibilities suggested by his great idea so he can relentlessly focus on a main character who is too impervious to care about. Vanessa Lutz (Reese Witherspoon) is the 15 year old, illiterate spawn of poor white city trash. Her drug addict stepfather (Michael T. Weiss) molests her and her at-best-borderline crazy mother (Amanda Plummer) turns tricks on the street in the parking lot outside the motel room where they all live. When they get arrested, Vanessa tries to flee to the grandmother she's never met. Along the way, she runs into Bob Wolverton (Keifer Sutherland) a counselor for troubled youth who offers her a lift and some help with Vanessa's beyond screwed up life. If I tell you there's a mention at the start of the film of a serial killer targeting young girls in Vanessa's town, can you guess where her and Bob's relationship is headed? That is where it goes, though writer/director Bright waits a long time to get it there and then shamelessly foreshadows it right before it happens, as though anyone watching this movie didn't see it coming. But then he takes what you expect and completely upends it, leaving you without any clue where Freeway is going next but anxious to find out. That feeling doesn't last long because writer/director Bright takes almost all of the interesting directions his story could go and reduces them to comic relief so he can put Vanessa through her paces in an afterschool special that has no moral or "message to grow on", unless that moral is "bad things also happen to bad people". It's only when Freeway needs an ending that writer/director Bright abruptly picks up some of the potential he's cast aside and tries to cobble together a big finish. I'm not sure the origins of this motion picture, but what it turned out to be was a starring vehicle for the young Reese Witherspoon that went nowhere. Not because she isn't cute as all get out and doesn't do a fine job here. It's because Vanessa dominates the whole show and is a sociopath but unfortunately, she's not one of those intriguing and grandiose sociopaths. She's one of those petty, boring sociopaths who turn up in police stations every day. The movie takes great pains to spell out all the terrible things that were done to Vanessa but none of it seems to have had any effect on her. Vanessa has no depth or inner life and cruises through her horrible existence like a shark looking for the next fat seal to eat. That might not have been a problem if Freeway had become the kind of thriller suggested by writer/director Bright's very clever left turn. In plot dominated tales, it's not always necessary for characters to be relatable or even all that interesting. By essentially becoming a study of a two-dimensional character, though, the film only highlights the lack of connection the viewer can have with Vanessa. Witherspoon is good here, as is Keifer Sutherland and Brooke Shields. Brittany Murphy has an odd role as a scarred paint-huffer and Dan Hedaya and Wolfgang Bodison are fine as two detectives, though the movie can't keep straight which one of them is supposed to be the good cop and which the bad cop. In most respects, Freeway is perfectly acceptable entertainment, with reasonably good writing, directing and acting. I can't shake the feeling that it could easily have been more than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wait... So This Movie Was Released in the West?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Bridge (joebridge@bigpond.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this movie, and as soon as it started with the bizarre, embarrassingly bad "Red Riding Hood" opening credits and horrid cheap-sounding soundtrack, I was certain it was some sort of fake "knock-off" video, especially as someone gave me this copy as sold in Indonesia. The ending credits were really bad and fake-looking as well, so maybe both were replaced in the Indonesian version, not sure, but it also is so bad throughout, perhaps the entire movie was replaced? While watching this, my friends and I were almost certain the actor credits were fake and that it was filmed by a group of amateur film-makers (as it was so utterly badly made - I was certain it was made in Indonesia or other Foreign country and was meant to make fun of the West), until Keifer Sutherland showed up and we were fairly certain it was him. Was this a straight-to-video movie? It was just so badly made and badly acted even for a dark comedy. Just because it is a comedy doesn't mean you have to act as if you are playing around with the script and not saying the lines in any way that makes sense. The acting was so disturbingly over-the-top bad, the accents annoying and ridiculous throughout (sounded mostly like hillbillies from the more isolated areas of Kentucky - yet supposedly was taking place in California), and the actors themselves looking so awful in every way possible (even Brooke Shields looked as if they used CGI to warp her body into something not quite human in that weird sailor outfit - again unless our copy was tampered with), I'm certain this was MEANT to be a farce/comedy, especially with the ludicrous climax regarding the actual Little Red Riding Hood story - which kind of added insult to injury - how could any writer be THAT ridiculous? Obviously it wasn't meant to be crime drama or anything like that, even though the premise suggested it was drama. It does have an overwhelming "quickly made television movie" and "print every first take" feel. So it appears that this movie (or a version of it) WAS released in the USA (not sure about here in Australia) after all? I'm still fairly certain our copy was tampered with (especially the ridiculous looking and sounding opening and ending credits - that were in static-ridden Foreign-sounding music and in mono - which wouldn't meet even the lowest standards these days), as nothing could be that badly made and be released. Most of us thought that it was one of those "experimental" films that was made especially for places like Indonesia and never placed directly in the actors' credits, and which wasn't released elsewhere, but seeing the information on IMDb is quite stunning in its implications about the general populace... Unbelievable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outrageously Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only in the 1990's that you had a enormous stream of twisted, violent, dark films with awkward funny moments, and writers and directors got away with it, although some of them haven't lived up to higher expectations with the noble exception of Coen brothers. Far away from being intelligent like Coen's films "Freeway" comes to amaze us with bringing the story of Little Red Riding Hood in a different environment with many violent and funny situations. Reese Witherspoon plays the troubled Vanessa, a girl whose mother and stepfather were arrested, and she doesn't want to go to foster care or similar, deciding instead on going to her grandmother's house, the only place she can go. This Little Red Riding Hood won't bring cookies to grandma, and she's not so innocent like the old tale, here's a girl with lots of problems and lots of anger too after meeting her Big Bad Wolf, Bob a friendly psycho killer (Kiefer Sutherland) who picks her up on the road after her car broke. What comes after it's a hilarious and twisted story about two figures that don't know how to get rid of each other, in a plot that involves murders, juvenile prison for girls, a funny trial, punchlines in the wrong time to make us laugh all the time. It's not for everyone's tastes, it's certainly that not everyone will find the story funny as a comedy instead of a ridiculous way as the plot might suggest. It's full of surprises, very uncompromising and has some interesting performance from Witherspoon as the talking/smart/violent/Christian girl who manages to survive the whole ride meeting creepy characters on the way, and a nice performance from Kiefer playing the friendly guy who ends up being a killer trapped in his own evilness, after the girl shoot him several times, and this guy for some reason doesn't die but keeps living a painful life after. The scenes with both in the car, talking about her problems and he's playing the good listener was very good, and sometimes I wish that the whole movie would be focused on them doing this because it was interesting so these two change to each other the way they act, talk and all, but then we would have a dramatic feature, something that this film is not. How come one stumble upon this film? Simple! Of 5 films credited on IMDb you'll see in 4 random titles the suggestion for this film, and I gotta recognize that the promotion is a little bit over-the-top but it made me curious to watch it, and it turned out to be a great film. One year in a crusade after "Freeway" I finally watched, enjoyed, it got me laughing and surprised despite a few clich&eacute;s here and there. If you can see humor in bizarre situations that in ordinary life wouldn't be funny then this film is for you! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wash your mouth out with soap Little Red Riding Hood !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgonite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is a black comic take on Little Red Riding Hood. Reese Witherspoon plays a rather sweet and innocent looking young woman off to find her grandmother. Kiefer Sutherland plays a psychological serial killer, although not a fully paid up one but the free or Lite version. The film's strengths are the performance by Witherspoon who brings the character to life, and the screenplay which is funny in the extreme. Indeed I would be surprised if Witherspoon had not been nominated for an award in the role. Freeway is not a very politically correct film and is all the more enjoyable for it! This aspect of it could cause offence and as such has probably hindered it's publicity. Pros - Twisted, Dark, Comic Tale Cons - None come to mind Overall - Baddass
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    captaintrps
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible. I spent the majority of the time holding down the fast forward button on my remote. Reese W. does well despite the horrible film that this is. Keifer S. should just stay retired or go in hiding or wherever he was before this came out. Reese has to regret doing this film. Very predictable, with no plot or storyline that you're average movie buff couldn't come up with. I don't see where this has anything to do with the little red riding hood story. They forced that association onto this film. This is not worth watching at all. The weekend opening gross tells the story. Don't waste your time, or spoil your thoughts that Reese W. is fun to watch on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark, disgusting and utterly wonderful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is written and directed by Matthew Bright. It stars Reese Witherspoon, Kiefer Sutherland, Dan Hedaya, Wolfgang Bodison, Brooke Shields & Brittany Murphy. Plot is darkly based around the Little Red Riding Hood fairy tale and sees young runaway Vanessa Lutz (Witherspoon) hit the road after her parents are arrested. Setting off to visit her grandmother she agrees to a lift from the kind and well spoken Bob Wolverton (Sutherland), only to find that he's not as nice as she first thought. He in turn is in for a big surprise himself since Vanessa is more than capable of looking after herself. Twisted and richly humorous, Matthew Bright's movie oozes originality and quite frankly deserves to be better appreciated: never mind better known! Going into it for a first time completely oblivious to its structure will arguably aid the experience. Suffice to say that the less known about it prior to viewing it the better. All I have to say is that it's violent, sweary and contains very sexually explicit dialogue, so if those things are likely to offend then perhaps stay away from it. But what if I offer up that those things are dealt with a satirical bent? That the tough scenes, and some of them are very tough, are basis to a caustic narrative about social hypocrisy and the often stupidity of the law? Interested? You should be, because once viewed you're unlikely to forget it. It's no surprise to see Oliver Stone's name etched onto the production credits, since this very much feels like a dirty second cousin to his Natural Born Killers. I'd argue that here we have the better acted film with Witherspoon and Sutherland giving virtuoso performances: with admirable support coming from the likes of Bodison, Shields and Murphy. One of the most undervalued film's of the 90s? You bet it is! 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Varied, violent, funny and furious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So there's me thinking I'm taking a break from my obscure exploitation movies and I find myself sat before this beauty. Made in 1996, which doesn't seem so long ago, but it's before Keiffer Sutherland settled into the 24 TV series and before Reese Witherspoon had even made Election, and while they have both gone on to much bigger if not better things, director Bright has not. Well, I don't know what possessed him to imagine he was going to make too many Hollywood friends with this mighty chunk of wild and anti-establishment, two fingered spout of anger, but it is enormous fun to watch. Also, as with so much exploitative cinema it seems to tell far more truths than your average 'serious' movie. Sutherland is effective but Witherspoon amazing, I had forgotten how tremendous she could be. Varied, violent, funny and furious, this is worth a watch anytime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanquinn-52-789942
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely brilliant film in so many different respects. At it's most basic it's a modern take on Robin Hood, but it can be enjoyed on many different levels. There are several just plain brilliant performances. This is first film that I watched Reece Witherspoon in that really showed me her depth and stretched her ability as an actress, and she was only 18 years old! She's strong, powerful, empathetic and like-able as the wayward teen looking for her grandmother. Keifer Sutherland also has a strong role, with some of my other favorite performances being from Britany Murphy as a completely transformed and nearly unrecognizable pyromaniac lesbian delinquent. Another great performance is Michael T. Weiss (from the TV series Pretender) as a complete crack-head, and Brook Shields as the wife of Keifer Sutherland's character. This is not a film for children, despite it being based on a children's tale, but if you approach it with an open mind I think you'll really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reese As You've Never Seen Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reese Witherspoon made this riveting thriller before she became everybody's favorite sweetheart. The "Legally Blond" star plays a foul-mouthed, illiterate teenager named Vanessa Lutz who hitches a ride with an older man after her car breaks down on the freeway. He offers her a lift as far as Los Angeles and even takes her out to dinner. Later, he turns out to be a notorious California highway serial killer who has been making headlines. Kiefer Sutherland is thoroughly obnoxious as Bob Wolverton, a bespectacled boys counselor who gets more than he bargained for after he picks up Vanessa, cuts off her ponytail, and threatens to rape her corpse. She whips out a small, Spanish-made automatic pistol that her boyfriend, Chopper (Bokeem Woodbine) gave her moments before he died in a drive-by shooting. Vanessa lands in jail but she does not stick long before she breaks out and joins a group of Hispanic girls who pull tricks on the side. All Vanessa wants to do is go to Stockton, California, so she can live with her grandmother rather than wind up in another horrible foster home.The dialogue brims with profanity and the subject matter is very unsavory. Witherspoon gives a dynamic performance. If you think that Witherspoon is cast against the grain, wait until you see a grown-up Brooke Shields who plays the wife of the serial killer. "Freeway" is an unforgettable dark comedy that doesn't pull any of its punches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is still one of Reese's best roles ever, and not a dull moment ever . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know, it may seem ridiculous to some, but actually, even after all these years (now well into 2012), this is still a film to watch, and no one could have delivered the key role more perfectly than Reese Witherspoon. She is simply spectacularly spot on with her characterization of the theme and culture that is her character here. The story is a bit hard edged for some, but sadly, not entirely outside the realms of reality in the current world. Do characters like hers in this film really exist as portrayed? Absolutely yes. Do characters like that portrayed by Sutherland, the predatory pedophile sociopath who appears to be so acceptably "normal" to the outside world? Absolutely yes, as recent history has shown only too clearly. On the surface this may have appeared to be a sort of whacky, creepy crime thriller, but actually, if one actually takes the time to watch this film, there is much more to this than the ad copy may have suggested at the time. It is still currently viable, to this very day . . . has stood the test of time. And it is absolutely one of Reese's best ever performances. Sadly, her more recent work has sort of flattened out into much less risky, complex roles, but hey, a great actress she is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suggests a better story than it delivers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is one of those films that are okay but still manage to be a little disappointing because it's so damned apparent that it could have been much better. It's perfectly clear where the story is going early on, yet it still takes forever to get there. When it finally arrives, writer/director Matthew Bright throws a great left turn into the plot and sets up a potentially fascinating second half of the movie. That never materializes because Bright ignores almost all of the possibilities suggested by his great idea so he can relentlessly focus on a main character who is too impervious to care about. Vanessa Lutz (Reese Witherspoon) is the 15 year old, illiterate spawn of poor white city trash. Her drug addict stepfather (Michael T. Weiss) molests her and her at-best-borderline crazy mother (Amanda Plummer) turns tricks on the street in the parking lot outside the motel room where they all live. When they get arrested, Vanessa tries to flee to the grandmother she's never met. Along the way, she runs into Bob Wolverton (Keifer Sutherland) a counselor for troubled youth who offers her a lift and some help with Vanessa's beyond screwed up life. If I tell you there's a mention at the start of the film of a serial killer targeting young girls in Vanessa's town, can you guess where her and Bob's relationship is headed? That is where it goes, though writer/director Bright waits a long time to get it there and then shamelessly foreshadows it right before it happens, as though anyone watching this movie didn't see it coming. But then he takes what you expect and completely upends it, leaving you without any clue where Freeway is going next but anxious to find out. That feeling doesn't last long because writer/director Bright takes almost all of the interesting directions his story could go and reduces them to comic relief so he can put Vanessa through her paces in an afterschool special that has no moral or "message to grow on", unless that moral is "bad things also happen to bad people". It's only when Freeway needs an ending that writer/director Bright abruptly picks up some of the potential he's cast aside and tries to cobble together a big finish. I'm not sure the origins of this motion picture, but what it turned out to be was a starring vehicle for the young Reese Witherspoon that went nowhere. Not because she isn't cute as all get out and doesn't do a fine job here. It's because Vanessa dominates the whole show and is a sociopath but unfortunately, she's not one of those intriguing and grandiose sociopaths. She's one of those petty, boring sociopaths who turn up in police stations every day. The movie takes great pains to spell out all the terrible things that were done to Vanessa but none of it seems to have had any effect on her. Vanessa has no depth or inner life and cruises through her horrible existence like a shark looking for the next fat seal to eat. That might not have been a problem if Freeway had become the kind of thriller suggested by writer/director Bright's very clever left turn. In plot dominated tales, it's not always necessary for characters to be relatable or even all that interesting. By essentially becoming a study of a two-dimensional character, though, the film only highlights the lack of connection the viewer can have with Vanessa. Witherspoon is good here, as is Keifer Sutherland and Brooke Shields. Brittany Murphy has an odd role as a scarred paint-huffer and Dan Hedaya and Wolfgang Bodison are fine as two detectives, though the movie can't keep straight which one of them is supposed to be the good cop and which the bad cop. In most respects, Freeway is perfectly acceptable entertainment, with reasonably good writing, directing and acting. I can't shake the feeling that it could easily have been more than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wait... So This Movie Was Released in the West?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Bridge (joebridge@bigpond.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this movie, and as soon as it started with the bizarre, embarrassingly bad "Red Riding Hood" opening credits and horrid cheap-sounding soundtrack, I was certain it was some sort of fake "knock-off" video, especially as someone gave me this copy as sold in Indonesia. The ending credits were really bad and fake-looking as well, so maybe both were replaced in the Indonesian version, not sure, but it also is so bad throughout, perhaps the entire movie was replaced? While watching this, my friends and I were almost certain the actor credits were fake and that it was filmed by a group of amateur film-makers (as it was so utterly badly made - I was certain it was made in Indonesia or other Foreign country and was meant to make fun of the West), until Keifer Sutherland showed up and we were fairly certain it was him. Was this a straight-to-video movie? It was just so badly made and badly acted even for a dark comedy. Just because it is a comedy doesn't mean you have to act as if you are playing around with the script and not saying the lines in any way that makes sense. The acting was so disturbingly over-the-top bad, the accents annoying and ridiculous throughout (sounded mostly like hillbillies from the more isolated areas of Kentucky - yet supposedly was taking place in California), and the actors themselves looking so awful in every way possible (even Brooke Shields looked as if they used CGI to warp her body into something not quite human in that weird sailor outfit - again unless our copy was tampered with), I'm certain this was MEANT to be a farce/comedy, especially with the ludicrous climax regarding the actual Little Red Riding Hood story - which kind of added insult to injury - how could any writer be THAT ridiculous? Obviously it wasn't meant to be crime drama or anything like that, even though the premise suggested it was drama. It does have an overwhelming "quickly made television movie" and "print every first take" feel. So it appears that this movie (or a version of it) WAS released in the USA (not sure about here in Australia) after all? I'm still fairly certain our copy was tampered with (especially the ridiculous looking and sounding opening and ending credits - that were in static-ridden Foreign-sounding music and in mono - which wouldn't meet even the lowest standards these days), as nothing could be that badly made and be released. Most of us thought that it was one of those "experimental" films that was made especially for places like Indonesia and never placed directly in the actors' credits, and which wasn't released elsewhere, but seeing the information on IMDb is quite stunning in its implications about the general populace... Unbelievable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outrageously Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only in the 1990's that you had a enormous stream of twisted, violent, dark films with awkward funny moments, and writers and directors got away with it, although some of them haven't lived up to higher expectations with the noble exception of Coen brothers. Far away from being intelligent like Coen's films "Freeway" comes to amaze us with bringing the story of Little Red Riding Hood in a different environment with many violent and funny situations. Reese Witherspoon plays the troubled Vanessa, a girl whose mother and stepfather were arrested, and she doesn't want to go to foster care or similar, deciding instead on going to her grandmother's house, the only place she can go. This Little Red Riding Hood won't bring cookies to grandma, and she's not so innocent like the old tale, here's a girl with lots of problems and lots of anger too after meeting her Big Bad Wolf, Bob a friendly psycho killer (Kiefer Sutherland) who picks her up on the road after her car broke. What comes after it's a hilarious and twisted story about two figures that don't know how to get rid of each other, in a plot that involves murders, juvenile prison for girls, a funny trial, punchlines in the wrong time to make us laugh all the time. It's not for everyone's tastes, it's certainly that not everyone will find the story funny as a comedy instead of a ridiculous way as the plot might suggest. It's full of surprises, very uncompromising and has some interesting performance from Witherspoon as the talking/smart/violent/Christian girl who manages to survive the whole ride meeting creepy characters on the way, and a nice performance from Kiefer playing the friendly guy who ends up being a killer trapped in his own evilness, after the girl shoot him several times, and this guy for some reason doesn't die but keeps living a painful life after. The scenes with both in the car, talking about her problems and he's playing the good listener was very good, and sometimes I wish that the whole movie would be focused on them doing this because it was interesting so these two change to each other the way they act, talk and all, but then we would have a dramatic feature, something that this film is not. How come one stumble upon this film? Simple! Of 5 films credited on IMDb you'll see in 4 random titles the suggestion for this film, and I gotta recognize that the promotion is a little bit over-the-top but it made me curious to watch it, and it turned out to be a great film. One year in a crusade after "Freeway" I finally watched, enjoyed, it got me laughing and surprised despite a few clich&eacute;s here and there. If you can see humor in bizarre situations that in ordinary life wouldn't be funny then this film is for you! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wash your mouth out with soap Little Red Riding Hood !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgonite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is a black comic take on Little Red Riding Hood. Reese Witherspoon plays a rather sweet and innocent looking young woman off to find her grandmother. Kiefer Sutherland plays a psychological serial killer, although not a fully paid up one but the free or Lite version. The film's strengths are the performance by Witherspoon who brings the character to life, and the screenplay which is funny in the extreme. Indeed I would be surprised if Witherspoon had not been nominated for an award in the role. Freeway is not a very politically correct film and is all the more enjoyable for it! This aspect of it could cause offence and as such has probably hindered it's publicity. Pros - Twisted, Dark, Comic Tale Cons - None come to mind Overall - Baddass
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    captaintrps
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible. I spent the majority of the time holding down the fast forward button on my remote. Reese W. does well despite the horrible film that this is. Keifer S. should just stay retired or go in hiding or wherever he was before this came out. Reese has to regret doing this film. Very predictable, with no plot or storyline that you're average movie buff couldn't come up with. I don't see where this has anything to do with the little red riding hood story. They forced that association onto this film. This is not worth watching at all. The weekend opening gross tells the story. Don't waste your time, or spoil your thoughts that Reese W. is fun to watch on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark, disgusting and utterly wonderful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is written and directed by Matthew Bright. It stars Reese Witherspoon, Kiefer Sutherland, Dan Hedaya, Wolfgang Bodison, Brooke Shields & Brittany Murphy. Plot is darkly based around the Little Red Riding Hood fairy tale and sees young runaway Vanessa Lutz (Witherspoon) hit the road after her parents are arrested. Setting off to visit her grandmother she agrees to a lift from the kind and well spoken Bob Wolverton (Sutherland), only to find that he's not as nice as she first thought. He in turn is in for a big surprise himself since Vanessa is more than capable of looking after herself. Twisted and richly humorous, Matthew Bright's movie oozes originality and quite frankly deserves to be better appreciated: never mind better known! Going into it for a first time completely oblivious to its structure will arguably aid the experience. Suffice to say that the less known about it prior to viewing it the better. All I have to say is that it's violent, sweary and contains very sexually explicit dialogue, so if those things are likely to offend then perhaps stay away from it. But what if I offer up that those things are dealt with a satirical bent? That the tough scenes, and some of them are very tough, are basis to a caustic narrative about social hypocrisy and the often stupidity of the law? Interested? You should be, because once viewed you're unlikely to forget it. It's no surprise to see Oliver Stone's name etched onto the production credits, since this very much feels like a dirty second cousin to his Natural Born Killers. I'd argue that here we have the better acted film with Witherspoon and Sutherland giving virtuoso performances: with admirable support coming from the likes of Bodison, Shields and Murphy. One of the most undervalued film's of the 90s? You bet it is! 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Varied, violent, funny and furious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So there's me thinking I'm taking a break from my obscure exploitation movies and I find myself sat before this beauty. Made in 1996, which doesn't seem so long ago, but it's before Keiffer Sutherland settled into the 24 TV series and before Reese Witherspoon had even made Election, and while they have both gone on to much bigger if not better things, director Bright has not. Well, I don't know what possessed him to imagine he was going to make too many Hollywood friends with this mighty chunk of wild and anti-establishment, two fingered spout of anger, but it is enormous fun to watch. Also, as with so much exploitative cinema it seems to tell far more truths than your average 'serious' movie. Sutherland is effective but Witherspoon amazing, I had forgotten how tremendous she could be. Varied, violent, funny and furious, this is worth a watch anytime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanquinn-52-789942
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely brilliant film in so many different respects. At it's most basic it's a modern take on Robin Hood, but it can be enjoyed on many different levels. There are several just plain brilliant performances. This is first film that I watched Reece Witherspoon in that really showed me her depth and stretched her ability as an actress, and she was only 18 years old! She's strong, powerful, empathetic and like-able as the wayward teen looking for her grandmother. Keifer Sutherland also has a strong role, with some of my other favorite performances being from Britany Murphy as a completely transformed and nearly unrecognizable pyromaniac lesbian delinquent. Another great performance is Michael T. Weiss (from the TV series Pretender) as a complete crack-head, and Brook Shields as the wife of Keifer Sutherland's character. This is not a film for children, despite it being based on a children's tale, but if you approach it with an open mind I think you'll really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reese As You've Never Seen Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reese Witherspoon made this riveting thriller before she became everybody's favorite sweetheart. The "Legally Blond" star plays a foul-mouthed, illiterate teenager named Vanessa Lutz who hitches a ride with an older man after her car breaks down on the freeway. He offers her a lift as far as Los Angeles and even takes her out to dinner. Later, he turns out to be a notorious California highway serial killer who has been making headlines. Kiefer Sutherland is thoroughly obnoxious as Bob Wolverton, a bespectacled boys counselor who gets more than he bargained for after he picks up Vanessa, cuts off her ponytail, and threatens to rape her corpse. She whips out a small, Spanish-made automatic pistol that her boyfriend, Chopper (Bokeem Woodbine) gave her moments before he died in a drive-by shooting. Vanessa lands in jail but she does not stick long before she breaks out and joins a group of Hispanic girls who pull tricks on the side. All Vanessa wants to do is go to Stockton, California, so she can live with her grandmother rather than wind up in another horrible foster home.The dialogue brims with profanity and the subject matter is very unsavory. Witherspoon gives a dynamic performance. If you think that Witherspoon is cast against the grain, wait until you see a grown-up Brooke Shields who plays the wife of the serial killer. "Freeway" is an unforgettable dark comedy that doesn't pull any of its punches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is still one of Reese's best roles ever, and not a dull moment ever . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know, it may seem ridiculous to some, but actually, even after all these years (now well into 2012), this is still a film to watch, and no one could have delivered the key role more perfectly than Reese Witherspoon. She is simply spectacularly spot on with her characterization of the theme and culture that is her character here. The story is a bit hard edged for some, but sadly, not entirely outside the realms of reality in the current world. Do characters like hers in this film really exist as portrayed? Absolutely yes. Do characters like that portrayed by Sutherland, the predatory pedophile sociopath who appears to be so acceptably "normal" to the outside world? Absolutely yes, as recent history has shown only too clearly. On the surface this may have appeared to be a sort of whacky, creepy crime thriller, but actually, if one actually takes the time to watch this film, there is much more to this than the ad copy may have suggested at the time. It is still currently viable, to this very day . . . has stood the test of time. And it is absolutely one of Reese's best ever performances. Sadly, her more recent work has sort of flattened out into much less risky, complex roles, but hey, a great actress she is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suggests a better story than it delivers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is one of those films that are okay but still manage to be a little disappointing because it's so damned apparent that it could have been much better. It's perfectly clear where the story is going early on, yet it still takes forever to get there. When it finally arrives, writer/director Matthew Bright throws a great left turn into the plot and sets up a potentially fascinating second half of the movie. That never materializes because Bright ignores almost all of the possibilities suggested by his great idea so he can relentlessly focus on a main character who is too impervious to care about. Vanessa Lutz (Reese Witherspoon) is the 15 year old, illiterate spawn of poor white city trash. Her drug addict stepfather (Michael T. Weiss) molests her and her at-best-borderline crazy mother (Amanda Plummer) turns tricks on the street in the parking lot outside the motel room where they all live. When they get arrested, Vanessa tries to flee to the grandmother she's never met. Along the way, she runs into Bob Wolverton (Keifer Sutherland) a counselor for troubled youth who offers her a lift and some help with Vanessa's beyond screwed up life. If I tell you there's a mention at the start of the film of a serial killer targeting young girls in Vanessa's town, can you guess where her and Bob's relationship is headed? That is where it goes, though writer/director Bright waits a long time to get it there and then shamelessly foreshadows it right before it happens, as though anyone watching this movie didn't see it coming. But then he takes what you expect and completely upends it, leaving you without any clue where Freeway is going next but anxious to find out. That feeling doesn't last long because writer/director Bright takes almost all of the interesting directions his story could go and reduces them to comic relief so he can put Vanessa through her paces in an afterschool special that has no moral or "message to grow on", unless that moral is "bad things also happen to bad people". It's only when Freeway needs an ending that writer/director Bright abruptly picks up some of the potential he's cast aside and tries to cobble together a big finish. I'm not sure the origins of this motion picture, but what it turned out to be was a starring vehicle for the young Reese Witherspoon that went nowhere. Not because she isn't cute as all get out and doesn't do a fine job here. It's because Vanessa dominates the whole show and is a sociopath but unfortunately, she's not one of those intriguing and grandiose sociopaths. She's one of those petty, boring sociopaths who turn up in police stations every day. The movie takes great pains to spell out all the terrible things that were done to Vanessa but none of it seems to have had any effect on her. Vanessa has no depth or inner life and cruises through her horrible existence like a shark looking for the next fat seal to eat. That might not have been a problem if Freeway had become the kind of thriller suggested by writer/director Bright's very clever left turn. In plot dominated tales, it's not always necessary for characters to be relatable or even all that interesting. By essentially becoming a study of a two-dimensional character, though, the film only highlights the lack of connection the viewer can have with Vanessa. Witherspoon is good here, as is Keifer Sutherland and Brooke Shields. Brittany Murphy has an odd role as a scarred paint-huffer and Dan Hedaya and Wolfgang Bodison are fine as two detectives, though the movie can't keep straight which one of them is supposed to be the good cop and which the bad cop. In most respects, Freeway is perfectly acceptable entertainment, with reasonably good writing, directing and acting. I can't shake the feeling that it could easily have been more than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wait... So This Movie Was Released in the West?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Bridge (joebridge@bigpond.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this movie, and as soon as it started with the bizarre, embarrassingly bad "Red Riding Hood" opening credits and horrid cheap-sounding soundtrack, I was certain it was some sort of fake "knock-off" video, especially as someone gave me this copy as sold in Indonesia. The ending credits were really bad and fake-looking as well, so maybe both were replaced in the Indonesian version, not sure, but it also is so bad throughout, perhaps the entire movie was replaced? While watching this, my friends and I were almost certain the actor credits were fake and that it was filmed by a group of amateur film-makers (as it was so utterly badly made - I was certain it was made in Indonesia or other Foreign country and was meant to make fun of the West), until Keifer Sutherland showed up and we were fairly certain it was him. Was this a straight-to-video movie? It was just so badly made and badly acted even for a dark comedy. Just because it is a comedy doesn't mean you have to act as if you are playing around with the script and not saying the lines in any way that makes sense. The acting was so disturbingly over-the-top bad, the accents annoying and ridiculous throughout (sounded mostly like hillbillies from the more isolated areas of Kentucky - yet supposedly was taking place in California), and the actors themselves looking so awful in every way possible (even Brooke Shields looked as if they used CGI to warp her body into something not quite human in that weird sailor outfit - again unless our copy was tampered with), I'm certain this was MEANT to be a farce/comedy, especially with the ludicrous climax regarding the actual Little Red Riding Hood story - which kind of added insult to injury - how could any writer be THAT ridiculous? Obviously it wasn't meant to be crime drama or anything like that, even though the premise suggested it was drama. It does have an overwhelming "quickly made television movie" and "print every first take" feel. So it appears that this movie (or a version of it) WAS released in the USA (not sure about here in Australia) after all? I'm still fairly certain our copy was tampered with (especially the ridiculous looking and sounding opening and ending credits - that were in static-ridden Foreign-sounding music and in mono - which wouldn't meet even the lowest standards these days), as nothing could be that badly made and be released. Most of us thought that it was one of those "experimental" films that was made especially for places like Indonesia and never placed directly in the actors' credits, and which wasn't released elsewhere, but seeing the information on IMDb is quite stunning in its implications about the general populace... Unbelievable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outrageously Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only in the 1990's that you had a enormous stream of twisted, violent, dark films with awkward funny moments, and writers and directors got away with it, although some of them haven't lived up to higher expectations with the noble exception of Coen brothers. Far away from being intelligent like Coen's films "Freeway" comes to amaze us with bringing the story of Little Red Riding Hood in a different environment with many violent and funny situations. Reese Witherspoon plays the troubled Vanessa, a girl whose mother and stepfather were arrested, and she doesn't want to go to foster care or similar, deciding instead on going to her grandmother's house, the only place she can go. This Little Red Riding Hood won't bring cookies to grandma, and she's not so innocent like the old tale, here's a girl with lots of problems and lots of anger too after meeting her Big Bad Wolf, Bob a friendly psycho killer (Kiefer Sutherland) who picks her up on the road after her car broke. What comes after it's a hilarious and twisted story about two figures that don't know how to get rid of each other, in a plot that involves murders, juvenile prison for girls, a funny trial, punchlines in the wrong time to make us laugh all the time. It's not for everyone's tastes, it's certainly that not everyone will find the story funny as a comedy instead of a ridiculous way as the plot might suggest. It's full of surprises, very uncompromising and has some interesting performance from Witherspoon as the talking/smart/violent/Christian girl who manages to survive the whole ride meeting creepy characters on the way, and a nice performance from Kiefer playing the friendly guy who ends up being a killer trapped in his own evilness, after the girl shoot him several times, and this guy for some reason doesn't die but keeps living a painful life after. The scenes with both in the car, talking about her problems and he's playing the good listener was very good, and sometimes I wish that the whole movie would be focused on them doing this because it was interesting so these two change to each other the way they act, talk and all, but then we would have a dramatic feature, something that this film is not. How come one stumble upon this film? Simple! Of 5 films credited on IMDb you'll see in 4 random titles the suggestion for this film, and I gotta recognize that the promotion is a little bit over-the-top but it made me curious to watch it, and it turned out to be a great film. One year in a crusade after "Freeway" I finally watched, enjoyed, it got me laughing and surprised despite a few clich&eacute;s here and there. If you can see humor in bizarre situations that in ordinary life wouldn't be funny then this film is for you! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wash your mouth out with soap Little Red Riding Hood !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgonite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is a black comic take on Little Red Riding Hood. Reese Witherspoon plays a rather sweet and innocent looking young woman off to find her grandmother. Kiefer Sutherland plays a psychological serial killer, although not a fully paid up one but the free or Lite version. The film's strengths are the performance by Witherspoon who brings the character to life, and the screenplay which is funny in the extreme. Indeed I would be surprised if Witherspoon had not been nominated for an award in the role. Freeway is not a very politically correct film and is all the more enjoyable for it! This aspect of it could cause offence and as such has probably hindered it's publicity. Pros - Twisted, Dark, Comic Tale Cons - None come to mind Overall - Baddass
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    captaintrps
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible. I spent the majority of the time holding down the fast forward button on my remote. Reese W. does well despite the horrible film that this is. Keifer S. should just stay retired or go in hiding or wherever he was before this came out. Reese has to regret doing this film. Very predictable, with no plot or storyline that you're average movie buff couldn't come up with. I don't see where this has anything to do with the little red riding hood story. They forced that association onto this film. This is not worth watching at all. The weekend opening gross tells the story. Don't waste your time, or spoil your thoughts that Reese W. is fun to watch on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark, disgusting and utterly wonderful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is written and directed by Matthew Bright. It stars Reese Witherspoon, Kiefer Sutherland, Dan Hedaya, Wolfgang Bodison, Brooke Shields & Brittany Murphy. Plot is darkly based around the Little Red Riding Hood fairy tale and sees young runaway Vanessa Lutz (Witherspoon) hit the road after her parents are arrested. Setting off to visit her grandmother she agrees to a lift from the kind and well spoken Bob Wolverton (Sutherland), only to find that he's not as nice as she first thought. He in turn is in for a big surprise himself since Vanessa is more than capable of looking after herself. Twisted and richly humorous, Matthew Bright's movie oozes originality and quite frankly deserves to be better appreciated: never mind better known! Going into it for a first time completely oblivious to its structure will arguably aid the experience. Suffice to say that the less known about it prior to viewing it the better. All I have to say is that it's violent, sweary and contains very sexually explicit dialogue, so if those things are likely to offend then perhaps stay away from it. But what if I offer up that those things are dealt with a satirical bent? That the tough scenes, and some of them are very tough, are basis to a caustic narrative about social hypocrisy and the often stupidity of the law? Interested? You should be, because once viewed you're unlikely to forget it. It's no surprise to see Oliver Stone's name etched onto the production credits, since this very much feels like a dirty second cousin to his Natural Born Killers. I'd argue that here we have the better acted film with Witherspoon and Sutherland giving virtuoso performances: with admirable support coming from the likes of Bodison, Shields and Murphy. One of the most undervalued film's of the 90s? You bet it is! 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Varied, violent, funny and furious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So there's me thinking I'm taking a break from my obscure exploitation movies and I find myself sat before this beauty. Made in 1996, which doesn't seem so long ago, but it's before Keiffer Sutherland settled into the 24 TV series and before Reese Witherspoon had even made Election, and while they have both gone on to much bigger if not better things, director Bright has not. Well, I don't know what possessed him to imagine he was going to make too many Hollywood friends with this mighty chunk of wild and anti-establishment, two fingered spout of anger, but it is enormous fun to watch. Also, as with so much exploitative cinema it seems to tell far more truths than your average 'serious' movie. Sutherland is effective but Witherspoon amazing, I had forgotten how tremendous she could be. Varied, violent, funny and furious, this is worth a watch anytime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanquinn-52-789942
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely brilliant film in so many different respects. At it's most basic it's a modern take on Robin Hood, but it can be enjoyed on many different levels. There are several just plain brilliant performances. This is first film that I watched Reece Witherspoon in that really showed me her depth and stretched her ability as an actress, and she was only 18 years old! She's strong, powerful, empathetic and like-able as the wayward teen looking for her grandmother. Keifer Sutherland also has a strong role, with some of my other favorite performances being from Britany Murphy as a completely transformed and nearly unrecognizable pyromaniac lesbian delinquent. Another great performance is Michael T. Weiss (from the TV series Pretender) as a complete crack-head, and Brook Shields as the wife of Keifer Sutherland's character. This is not a film for children, despite it being based on a children's tale, but if you approach it with an open mind I think you'll really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reese As You've Never Seen Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reese Witherspoon made this riveting thriller before she became everybody's favorite sweetheart. The "Legally Blond" star plays a foul-mouthed, illiterate teenager named Vanessa Lutz who hitches a ride with an older man after her car breaks down on the freeway. He offers her a lift as far as Los Angeles and even takes her out to dinner. Later, he turns out to be a notorious California highway serial killer who has been making headlines. Kiefer Sutherland is thoroughly obnoxious as Bob Wolverton, a bespectacled boys counselor who gets more than he bargained for after he picks up Vanessa, cuts off her ponytail, and threatens to rape her corpse. She whips out a small, Spanish-made automatic pistol that her boyfriend, Chopper (Bokeem Woodbine) gave her moments before he died in a drive-by shooting. Vanessa lands in jail but she does not stick long before she breaks out and joins a group of Hispanic girls who pull tricks on the side. All Vanessa wants to do is go to Stockton, California, so she can live with her grandmother rather than wind up in another horrible foster home.The dialogue brims with profanity and the subject matter is very unsavory. Witherspoon gives a dynamic performance. If you think that Witherspoon is cast against the grain, wait until you see a grown-up Brooke Shields who plays the wife of the serial killer. "Freeway" is an unforgettable dark comedy that doesn't pull any of its punches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is still one of Reese's best roles ever, and not a dull moment ever . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know, it may seem ridiculous to some, but actually, even after all these years (now well into 2012), this is still a film to watch, and no one could have delivered the key role more perfectly than Reese Witherspoon. She is simply spectacularly spot on with her characterization of the theme and culture that is her character here. The story is a bit hard edged for some, but sadly, not entirely outside the realms of reality in the current world. Do characters like hers in this film really exist as portrayed? Absolutely yes. Do characters like that portrayed by Sutherland, the predatory pedophile sociopath who appears to be so acceptably "normal" to the outside world? Absolutely yes, as recent history has shown only too clearly. On the surface this may have appeared to be a sort of whacky, creepy crime thriller, but actually, if one actually takes the time to watch this film, there is much more to this than the ad copy may have suggested at the time. It is still currently viable, to this very day . . . has stood the test of time. And it is absolutely one of Reese's best ever performances. Sadly, her more recent work has sort of flattened out into much less risky, complex roles, but hey, a great actress she is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suggests a better story than it delivers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is one of those films that are okay but still manage to be a little disappointing because it's so damned apparent that it could have been much better. It's perfectly clear where the story is going early on, yet it still takes forever to get there. When it finally arrives, writer/director Matthew Bright throws a great left turn into the plot and sets up a potentially fascinating second half of the movie. That never materializes because Bright ignores almost all of the possibilities suggested by his great idea so he can relentlessly focus on a main character who is too impervious to care about. Vanessa Lutz (Reese Witherspoon) is the 15 year old, illiterate spawn of poor white city trash. Her drug addict stepfather (Michael T. Weiss) molests her and her at-best-borderline crazy mother (Amanda Plummer) turns tricks on the street in the parking lot outside the motel room where they all live. When they get arrested, Vanessa tries to flee to the grandmother she's never met. Along the way, she runs into Bob Wolverton (Keifer Sutherland) a counselor for troubled youth who offers her a lift and some help with Vanessa's beyond screwed up life. If I tell you there's a mention at the start of the film of a serial killer targeting young girls in Vanessa's town, can you guess where her and Bob's relationship is headed? That is where it goes, though writer/director Bright waits a long time to get it there and then shamelessly foreshadows it right before it happens, as though anyone watching this movie didn't see it coming. But then he takes what you expect and completely upends it, leaving you without any clue where Freeway is going next but anxious to find out. That feeling doesn't last long because writer/director Bright takes almost all of the interesting directions his story could go and reduces them to comic relief so he can put Vanessa through her paces in an afterschool special that has no moral or "message to grow on", unless that moral is "bad things also happen to bad people". It's only when Freeway needs an ending that writer/director Bright abruptly picks up some of the potential he's cast aside and tries to cobble together a big finish. I'm not sure the origins of this motion picture, but what it turned out to be was a starring vehicle for the young Reese Witherspoon that went nowhere. Not because she isn't cute as all get out and doesn't do a fine job here. It's because Vanessa dominates the whole show and is a sociopath but unfortunately, she's not one of those intriguing and grandiose sociopaths. She's one of those petty, boring sociopaths who turn up in police stations every day. The movie takes great pains to spell out all the terrible things that were done to Vanessa but none of it seems to have had any effect on her. Vanessa has no depth or inner life and cruises through her horrible existence like a shark looking for the next fat seal to eat. That might not have been a problem if Freeway had become the kind of thriller suggested by writer/director Bright's very clever left turn. In plot dominated tales, it's not always necessary for characters to be relatable or even all that interesting. By essentially becoming a study of a two-dimensional character, though, the film only highlights the lack of connection the viewer can have with Vanessa. Witherspoon is good here, as is Keifer Sutherland and Brooke Shields. Brittany Murphy has an odd role as a scarred paint-huffer and Dan Hedaya and Wolfgang Bodison are fine as two detectives, though the movie can't keep straight which one of them is supposed to be the good cop and which the bad cop. In most respects, Freeway is perfectly acceptable entertainment, with reasonably good writing, directing and acting. I can't shake the feeling that it could easily have been more than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wait... So This Movie Was Released in the West?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Bridge (joebridge@bigpond.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this movie, and as soon as it started with the bizarre, embarrassingly bad "Red Riding Hood" opening credits and horrid cheap-sounding soundtrack, I was certain it was some sort of fake "knock-off" video, especially as someone gave me this copy as sold in Indonesia. The ending credits were really bad and fake-looking as well, so maybe both were replaced in the Indonesian version, not sure, but it also is so bad throughout, perhaps the entire movie was replaced? While watching this, my friends and I were almost certain the actor credits were fake and that it was filmed by a group of amateur film-makers (as it was so utterly badly made - I was certain it was made in Indonesia or other Foreign country and was meant to make fun of the West), until Keifer Sutherland showed up and we were fairly certain it was him. Was this a straight-to-video movie? It was just so badly made and badly acted even for a dark comedy. Just because it is a comedy doesn't mean you have to act as if you are playing around with the script and not saying the lines in any way that makes sense. The acting was so disturbingly over-the-top bad, the accents annoying and ridiculous throughout (sounded mostly like hillbillies from the more isolated areas of Kentucky - yet supposedly was taking place in California), and the actors themselves looking so awful in every way possible (even Brooke Shields looked as if they used CGI to warp her body into something not quite human in that weird sailor outfit - again unless our copy was tampered with), I'm certain this was MEANT to be a farce/comedy, especially with the ludicrous climax regarding the actual Little Red Riding Hood story - which kind of added insult to injury - how could any writer be THAT ridiculous? Obviously it wasn't meant to be crime drama or anything like that, even though the premise suggested it was drama. It does have an overwhelming "quickly made television movie" and "print every first take" feel. So it appears that this movie (or a version of it) WAS released in the USA (not sure about here in Australia) after all? I'm still fairly certain our copy was tampered with (especially the ridiculous looking and sounding opening and ending credits - that were in static-ridden Foreign-sounding music and in mono - which wouldn't meet even the lowest standards these days), as nothing could be that badly made and be released. Most of us thought that it was one of those "experimental" films that was made especially for places like Indonesia and never placed directly in the actors' credits, and which wasn't released elsewhere, but seeing the information on IMDb is quite stunning in its implications about the general populace... Unbelievable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outrageously Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only in the 1990's that you had a enormous stream of twisted, violent, dark films with awkward funny moments, and writers and directors got away with it, although some of them haven't lived up to higher expectations with the noble exception of Coen brothers. Far away from being intelligent like Coen's films "Freeway" comes to amaze us with bringing the story of Little Red Riding Hood in a different environment with many violent and funny situations. Reese Witherspoon plays the troubled Vanessa, a girl whose mother and stepfather were arrested, and she doesn't want to go to foster care or similar, deciding instead on going to her grandmother's house, the only place she can go. This Little Red Riding Hood won't bring cookies to grandma, and she's not so innocent like the old tale, here's a girl with lots of problems and lots of anger too after meeting her Big Bad Wolf, Bob a friendly psycho killer (Kiefer Sutherland) who picks her up on the road after her car broke. What comes after it's a hilarious and twisted story about two figures that don't know how to get rid of each other, in a plot that involves murders, juvenile prison for girls, a funny trial, punchlines in the wrong time to make us laugh all the time. It's not for everyone's tastes, it's certainly that not everyone will find the story funny as a comedy instead of a ridiculous way as the plot might suggest. It's full of surprises, very uncompromising and has some interesting performance from Witherspoon as the talking/smart/violent/Christian girl who manages to survive the whole ride meeting creepy characters on the way, and a nice performance from Kiefer playing the friendly guy who ends up being a killer trapped in his own evilness, after the girl shoot him several times, and this guy for some reason doesn't die but keeps living a painful life after. The scenes with both in the car, talking about her problems and he's playing the good listener was very good, and sometimes I wish that the whole movie would be focused on them doing this because it was interesting so these two change to each other the way they act, talk and all, but then we would have a dramatic feature, something that this film is not. How come one stumble upon this film? Simple! Of 5 films credited on IMDb you'll see in 4 random titles the suggestion for this film, and I gotta recognize that the promotion is a little bit over-the-top but it made me curious to watch it, and it turned out to be a great film. One year in a crusade after "Freeway" I finally watched, enjoyed, it got me laughing and surprised despite a few clich&eacute;s here and there. If you can see humor in bizarre situations that in ordinary life wouldn't be funny then this film is for you! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wash your mouth out with soap Little Red Riding Hood !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgonite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is a black comic take on Little Red Riding Hood. Reese Witherspoon plays a rather sweet and innocent looking young woman off to find her grandmother. Kiefer Sutherland plays a psychological serial killer, although not a fully paid up one but the free or Lite version. The film's strengths are the performance by Witherspoon who brings the character to life, and the screenplay which is funny in the extreme. Indeed I would be surprised if Witherspoon had not been nominated for an award in the role. Freeway is not a very politically correct film and is all the more enjoyable for it! This aspect of it could cause offence and as such has probably hindered it's publicity. Pros - Twisted, Dark, Comic Tale Cons - None come to mind Overall - Baddass
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    captaintrps
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible. I spent the majority of the time holding down the fast forward button on my remote. Reese W. does well despite the horrible film that this is. Keifer S. should just stay retired or go in hiding or wherever he was before this came out. Reese has to regret doing this film. Very predictable, with no plot or storyline that you're average movie buff couldn't come up with. I don't see where this has anything to do with the little red riding hood story. They forced that association onto this film. This is not worth watching at all. The weekend opening gross tells the story. Don't waste your time, or spoil your thoughts that Reese W. is fun to watch on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark, disgusting and utterly wonderful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is written and directed by Matthew Bright. It stars Reese Witherspoon, Kiefer Sutherland, Dan Hedaya, Wolfgang Bodison, Brooke Shields & Brittany Murphy. Plot is darkly based around the Little Red Riding Hood fairy tale and sees young runaway Vanessa Lutz (Witherspoon) hit the road after her parents are arrested. Setting off to visit her grandmother she agrees to a lift from the kind and well spoken Bob Wolverton (Sutherland), only to find that he's not as nice as she first thought. He in turn is in for a big surprise himself since Vanessa is more than capable of looking after herself. Twisted and richly humorous, Matthew Bright's movie oozes originality and quite frankly deserves to be better appreciated: never mind better known! Going into it for a first time completely oblivious to its structure will arguably aid the experience. Suffice to say that the less known about it prior to viewing it the better. All I have to say is that it's violent, sweary and contains very sexually explicit dialogue, so if those things are likely to offend then perhaps stay away from it. But what if I offer up that those things are dealt with a satirical bent? That the tough scenes, and some of them are very tough, are basis to a caustic narrative about social hypocrisy and the often stupidity of the law? Interested? You should be, because once viewed you're unlikely to forget it. It's no surprise to see Oliver Stone's name etched onto the production credits, since this very much feels like a dirty second cousin to his Natural Born Killers. I'd argue that here we have the better acted film with Witherspoon and Sutherland giving virtuoso performances: with admirable support coming from the likes of Bodison, Shields and Murphy. One of the most undervalued film's of the 90s? You bet it is! 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Varied, violent, funny and furious
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    christopher-underwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So there's me thinking I'm taking a break from my obscure exploitation movies and I find myself sat before this beauty. Made in 1996, which doesn't seem so long ago, but it's before Keiffer Sutherland settled into the 24 TV series and before Reese Witherspoon had even made Election, and while they have both gone on to much bigger if not better things, director Bright has not. Well, I don't know what possessed him to imagine he was going to make too many Hollywood friends with this mighty chunk of wild and anti-establishment, two fingered spout of anger, but it is enormous fun to watch. Also, as with so much exploitative cinema it seems to tell far more truths than your average 'serious' movie. Sutherland is effective but Witherspoon amazing, I had forgotten how tremendous she could be. Varied, violent, funny and furious, this is worth a watch anytime.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite films of all time.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stanquinn-52-789942
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An absolutely brilliant film in so many different respects. At it's most basic it's a modern take on Robin Hood, but it can be enjoyed on many different levels. There are several just plain brilliant performances. This is first film that I watched Reece Witherspoon in that really showed me her depth and stretched her ability as an actress, and she was only 18 years old! She's strong, powerful, empathetic and like-able as the wayward teen looking for her grandmother. Keifer Sutherland also has a strong role, with some of my other favorite performances being from Britany Murphy as a completely transformed and nearly unrecognizable pyromaniac lesbian delinquent. Another great performance is Michael T. Weiss (from the TV series Pretender) as a complete crack-head, and Brook Shields as the wife of Keifer Sutherland's character. This is not a film for children, despite it being based on a children's tale, but if you approach it with an open mind I think you'll really enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reese As You've Never Seen Her
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Reese Witherspoon made this riveting thriller before she became everybody's favorite sweetheart. The "Legally Blond" star plays a foul-mouthed, illiterate teenager named Vanessa Lutz who hitches a ride with an older man after her car breaks down on the freeway. He offers her a lift as far as Los Angeles and even takes her out to dinner. Later, he turns out to be a notorious California highway serial killer who has been making headlines. Kiefer Sutherland is thoroughly obnoxious as Bob Wolverton, a bespectacled boys counselor who gets more than he bargained for after he picks up Vanessa, cuts off her ponytail, and threatens to rape her corpse. She whips out a small, Spanish-made automatic pistol that her boyfriend, Chopper (Bokeem Woodbine) gave her moments before he died in a drive-by shooting. Vanessa lands in jail but she does not stick long before she breaks out and joins a group of Hispanic girls who pull tricks on the side. All Vanessa wants to do is go to Stockton, California, so she can live with her grandmother rather than wind up in another horrible foster home.The dialogue brims with profanity and the subject matter is very unsavory. Witherspoon gives a dynamic performance. If you think that Witherspoon is cast against the grain, wait until you see a grown-up Brooke Shields who plays the wife of the serial killer. "Freeway" is an unforgettable dark comedy that doesn't pull any of its punches!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is still one of Reese's best roles ever, and not a dull moment ever . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know, it may seem ridiculous to some, but actually, even after all these years (now well into 2012), this is still a film to watch, and no one could have delivered the key role more perfectly than Reese Witherspoon. She is simply spectacularly spot on with her characterization of the theme and culture that is her character here. The story is a bit hard edged for some, but sadly, not entirely outside the realms of reality in the current world. Do characters like hers in this film really exist as portrayed? Absolutely yes. Do characters like that portrayed by Sutherland, the predatory pedophile sociopath who appears to be so acceptably "normal" to the outside world? Absolutely yes, as recent history has shown only too clearly. On the surface this may have appeared to be a sort of whacky, creepy crime thriller, but actually, if one actually takes the time to watch this film, there is much more to this than the ad copy may have suggested at the time. It is still currently viable, to this very day . . . has stood the test of time. And it is absolutely one of Reese's best ever performances. Sadly, her more recent work has sort of flattened out into much less risky, complex roles, but hey, a great actress she is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Suggests a better story than it delivers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is one of those films that are okay but still manage to be a little disappointing because it's so damned apparent that it could have been much better. It's perfectly clear where the story is going early on, yet it still takes forever to get there. When it finally arrives, writer/director Matthew Bright throws a great left turn into the plot and sets up a potentially fascinating second half of the movie. That never materializes because Bright ignores almost all of the possibilities suggested by his great idea so he can relentlessly focus on a main character who is too impervious to care about. Vanessa Lutz (Reese Witherspoon) is the 15 year old, illiterate spawn of poor white city trash. Her drug addict stepfather (Michael T. Weiss) molests her and her at-best-borderline crazy mother (Amanda Plummer) turns tricks on the street in the parking lot outside the motel room where they all live. When they get arrested, Vanessa tries to flee to the grandmother she's never met. Along the way, she runs into Bob Wolverton (Keifer Sutherland) a counselor for troubled youth who offers her a lift and some help with Vanessa's beyond screwed up life. If I tell you there's a mention at the start of the film of a serial killer targeting young girls in Vanessa's town, can you guess where her and Bob's relationship is headed? That is where it goes, though writer/director Bright waits a long time to get it there and then shamelessly foreshadows it right before it happens, as though anyone watching this movie didn't see it coming. But then he takes what you expect and completely upends it, leaving you without any clue where Freeway is going next but anxious to find out. That feeling doesn't last long because writer/director Bright takes almost all of the interesting directions his story could go and reduces them to comic relief so he can put Vanessa through her paces in an afterschool special that has no moral or "message to grow on", unless that moral is "bad things also happen to bad people". It's only when Freeway needs an ending that writer/director Bright abruptly picks up some of the potential he's cast aside and tries to cobble together a big finish. I'm not sure the origins of this motion picture, but what it turned out to be was a starring vehicle for the young Reese Witherspoon that went nowhere. Not because she isn't cute as all get out and doesn't do a fine job here. It's because Vanessa dominates the whole show and is a sociopath but unfortunately, she's not one of those intriguing and grandiose sociopaths. She's one of those petty, boring sociopaths who turn up in police stations every day. The movie takes great pains to spell out all the terrible things that were done to Vanessa but none of it seems to have had any effect on her. Vanessa has no depth or inner life and cruises through her horrible existence like a shark looking for the next fat seal to eat. That might not have been a problem if Freeway had become the kind of thriller suggested by writer/director Bright's very clever left turn. In plot dominated tales, it's not always necessary for characters to be relatable or even all that interesting. By essentially becoming a study of a two-dimensional character, though, the film only highlights the lack of connection the viewer can have with Vanessa. Witherspoon is good here, as is Keifer Sutherland and Brooke Shields. Brittany Murphy has an odd role as a scarred paint-huffer and Dan Hedaya and Wolfgang Bodison are fine as two detectives, though the movie can't keep straight which one of them is supposed to be the good cop and which the bad cop. In most respects, Freeway is perfectly acceptable entertainment, with reasonably good writing, directing and acting. I can't shake the feeling that it could easily have been more than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wait... So This Movie Was Released in the West?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Bridge (joebridge@bigpond.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just saw this movie, and as soon as it started with the bizarre, embarrassingly bad "Red Riding Hood" opening credits and horrid cheap-sounding soundtrack, I was certain it was some sort of fake "knock-off" video, especially as someone gave me this copy as sold in Indonesia. The ending credits were really bad and fake-looking as well, so maybe both were replaced in the Indonesian version, not sure, but it also is so bad throughout, perhaps the entire movie was replaced? While watching this, my friends and I were almost certain the actor credits were fake and that it was filmed by a group of amateur film-makers (as it was so utterly badly made - I was certain it was made in Indonesia or other Foreign country and was meant to make fun of the West), until Keifer Sutherland showed up and we were fairly certain it was him. Was this a straight-to-video movie? It was just so badly made and badly acted even for a dark comedy. Just because it is a comedy doesn't mean you have to act as if you are playing around with the script and not saying the lines in any way that makes sense. The acting was so disturbingly over-the-top bad, the accents annoying and ridiculous throughout (sounded mostly like hillbillies from the more isolated areas of Kentucky - yet supposedly was taking place in California), and the actors themselves looking so awful in every way possible (even Brooke Shields looked as if they used CGI to warp her body into something not quite human in that weird sailor outfit - again unless our copy was tampered with), I'm certain this was MEANT to be a farce/comedy, especially with the ludicrous climax regarding the actual Little Red Riding Hood story - which kind of added insult to injury - how could any writer be THAT ridiculous? Obviously it wasn't meant to be crime drama or anything like that, even though the premise suggested it was drama. It does have an overwhelming "quickly made television movie" and "print every first take" feel. So it appears that this movie (or a version of it) WAS released in the USA (not sure about here in Australia) after all? I'm still fairly certain our copy was tampered with (especially the ridiculous looking and sounding opening and ending credits - that were in static-ridden Foreign-sounding music and in mono - which wouldn't meet even the lowest standards these days), as nothing could be that badly made and be released. Most of us thought that it was one of those "experimental" films that was made especially for places like Indonesia and never placed directly in the actors' credits, and which wasn't released elsewhere, but seeing the information on IMDb is quite stunning in its implications about the general populace... Unbelievable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outrageously Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Only in the 1990's that you had a enormous stream of twisted, violent, dark films with awkward funny moments, and writers and directors got away with it, although some of them haven't lived up to higher expectations with the noble exception of Coen brothers. Far away from being intelligent like Coen's films "Freeway" comes to amaze us with bringing the story of Little Red Riding Hood in a different environment with many violent and funny situations. Reese Witherspoon plays the troubled Vanessa, a girl whose mother and stepfather were arrested, and she doesn't want to go to foster care or similar, deciding instead on going to her grandmother's house, the only place she can go. This Little Red Riding Hood won't bring cookies to grandma, and she's not so innocent like the old tale, here's a girl with lots of problems and lots of anger too after meeting her Big Bad Wolf, Bob a friendly psycho killer (Kiefer Sutherland) who picks her up on the road after her car broke. What comes after it's a hilarious and twisted story about two figures that don't know how to get rid of each other, in a plot that involves murders, juvenile prison for girls, a funny trial, punchlines in the wrong time to make us laugh all the time. It's not for everyone's tastes, it's certainly that not everyone will find the story funny as a comedy instead of a ridiculous way as the plot might suggest. It's full of surprises, very uncompromising and has some interesting performance from Witherspoon as the talking/smart/violent/Christian girl who manages to survive the whole ride meeting creepy characters on the way, and a nice performance from Kiefer playing the friendly guy who ends up being a killer trapped in his own evilness, after the girl shoot him several times, and this guy for some reason doesn't die but keeps living a painful life after. The scenes with both in the car, talking about her problems and he's playing the good listener was very good, and sometimes I wish that the whole movie would be focused on them doing this because it was interesting so these two change to each other the way they act, talk and all, but then we would have a dramatic feature, something that this film is not. How come one stumble upon this film? Simple! Of 5 films credited on IMDb you'll see in 4 random titles the suggestion for this film, and I gotta recognize that the promotion is a little bit over-the-top but it made me curious to watch it, and it turned out to be a great film. One year in a crusade after "Freeway" I finally watched, enjoyed, it got me laughing and surprised despite a few clich&eacute;s here and there. If you can see humor in bizarre situations that in ordinary life wouldn't be funny then this film is for you! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wash your mouth out with soap Little Red Riding Hood !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gorgonite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is a black comic take on Little Red Riding Hood. Reese Witherspoon plays a rather sweet and innocent looking young woman off to find her grandmother. Kiefer Sutherland plays a psychological serial killer, although not a fully paid up one but the free or Lite version. The film's strengths are the performance by Witherspoon who brings the character to life, and the screenplay which is funny in the extreme. Indeed I would be surprised if Witherspoon had not been nominated for an award in the role. Freeway is not a very politically correct film and is all the more enjoyable for it! This aspect of it could cause offence and as such has probably hindered it's publicity. Pros - Twisted, Dark, Comic Tale Cons - None come to mind Overall - Baddass
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just horrible
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    captaintrps
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is horrible. I spent the majority of the time holding down the fast forward button on my remote. Reese W. does well despite the horrible film that this is. Keifer S. should just stay retired or go in hiding or wherever he was before this came out. Reese has to regret doing this film. Very predictable, with no plot or storyline that you're average movie buff couldn't come up with. I don't see where this has anything to do with the little red riding hood story. They forced that association onto this film. This is not worth watching at all. The weekend opening gross tells the story. Don't waste your time, or spoil your thoughts that Reese W. is fun to watch on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark, disgusting and utterly wonderful.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freeway is written and directed by Matthew Bright. It stars Reese Witherspoon, Kiefer Sutherland, Dan Hedaya, Wolfgang Bodison, Brooke Shields & Brittany Murphy. Plot is darkly based around the Little Red Riding Hood fairy tale and sees young runaway Vanessa Lutz (Witherspoon) hit the road after her parents are arrested. Setting off to visit her grandmother she agrees to a lift from the kind and well spoken Bob Wolverton (Sutherland), only to find that he's not as nice as she first thought. He in turn is in for a big surprise himself since Vanessa is more than capable of looking after herself. Twisted and richly humorous, Matthew Bright's movie oozes originality and quite frankly deserves to be better appreciated: never mind better known! Going into it for a first time completely oblivious to its structure will arguably aid the experience. Suffice to say that the less known about it prior to viewing it the better. All I have to say is that it's violent, sweary and contains very sexually explicit dialogue, so if those things are likely to offend then perhaps stay away from it. But what if I offer up that those things are dealt with a satirical bent? That the tough scenes, and some of them are very tough, are basis to a caustic narrative about social hypocrisy and the often stupidity of the law? Interested? You should be, because once viewed you're unlikely to forget it. It's no surprise to see Oliver Stone's name etched onto the production credits, since this very much feels like a dirty second cousin to his Natural Born Killers. I'd argue that here we have the better acted film with Witherspoon and Sutherland giving virtuoso performances: with admirable support coming from the likes of Bodison, Shields and Murphy. One of the most undervalued film's of the 90s? You bet it is! 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
