<filme>
 <id>
  845
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117887
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  The Wonders - O Sonho N&atilde;o Acabou
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A Pennsylvania band scores a hit in 1964 and rides the star-making machinery as long as it can, with lots of help from its manager.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Recounts a fable of a pop rock band formed a year after the Beatles took America by storm in early 1964. Jazz aficionado Guy Patterson, unhappily toiling in the family appliance store, is recruited into the band the Oneders (later renamed the Wonders) after regular drummer Chad breaks his arm. After Guy injects a four/four rock beat into lead singer Jimmy's ballad, the song's undeniable pop power flings the Wonders into a brief whirlwind of success, telling the tale of many American bands who attempted to grab the brass ring of rock and roll in the wake of the British Invasion.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   band
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pennsylvania
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   song
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   appliance store
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jazz
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Tom Hanks
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Tom Hanks
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Tom Hanks
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Liv Tyler
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Charlize Theron
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun musical romp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have said, it's an homage to a simpler time. Love the small visual nods to "A Hard Day's Night" with the boys running through the simulation of the states. Also the hint of the same thing that happened to Lennon with the 'he's engaged' posting on the monitor. Of course, Lennon was actually engaged, if not already married! I truly don't get tired of this film. Just a feel-good movie. Also liked everything I read about how Hanks insisted that the actors learn to play their instruments well enough to look good in the film. Some of them practiced several hours a day. It's fun to see his wife pop in as a waitress where there's good jazz. Such a seemingly fun woman - but what else would you expect from Tom Hanks' wife? No, it didn't win any awards. But it's a 'keeper'. Watch it. Such fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nostalgic look back at the 1960s, when I was a beginning college student.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this movie a number of years ago but didn't remember much about it, so I saw it again today on DVD from my public library. I was a college Freshman in 1963/64, when the Beatles were first gaining popularity on this side of the pond, and this movie fairly accurately recreates that period, the way people dressed, and how teenagers reacted when seeing their pop idols live in concert. The story grabs hold of a theme I am very fond of pondering, both in real life and in fiction stories. That theme is the relative randomness of our lives, the things that happen, and then how we react to those random events. If we look at random events in our own lives, we can see how certain unexpected things shaped who we are today. In this movie a group of high school friends like to make music, one of them writes songs and is the featured singer. He has written "That Thing You Do" and they are about to perform it in a local small-potatoes contest. But the drummer, horsing around by showing the bass player how to jump over parking meters, falls and breaks his arm right before the contest. Now that is the "random event", and it leads them to ask another guy in town, who is a good drummer, to sit in for that one gig, so that they will still have a chance to win the competition. Then comes the rest of the influence of that "random event", the drummer own his own (this is important) decides to beat out a much faster tempo. It is this faster tempo that makes "That Thing You Do" a hit with the audience, attracts the attention of an agent, gets them a record, gets them a contract, puts them on tour, and has their hit rise towards the top of the charts. If their original drummer had not broken his arm, they would have just remained an ordinary band. Well as the story progresses they experience all the growing pains of sudden fame, and conflicting priorities among the members of the group. Tom Hanks directed, has a part as a record label agent, and he even wrote many of the songs. Tom Everett Scott who was in his mid-20s is very good as the replacement drummer, Guy Patterson. Liv Tyler, still a teenager was Faye Dolan who ended up traveling with the band. Her boyfriend was Johnathon Schaech as Jimmy who wrote the song and sang lead vocals. Steve Zahn was the crazy member Lenny, and Ethan Embry, also a teenager, was T. B. Player the unreliable bass player. Another teenager just starting her career was Charlize Theron as Tina in a fairly small part, as a flaky girlfriend who dumps Guy after an appointment with a handsome dentist. Plus young Giovanni Ribisi as Chad , the original drummer who breaks his arm. All in all a fairly pleasant movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You've heard of the "Jersey Boys", Well, here come the "Erie Boys!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yay! Somebody made a movie set in my home town! Historically made famous by early American battles in the infancy of our country, Erie PA is also famous for where a certain overweight US President got stuck in a bathtub, and where a comic named Bob Hope wed his lovely bride, Delores. But for Tom Hanks (here the filmmaker in addition to actor), he uses Erie as the setting for a boy's band which suddenly rises to fame and go through all of the stereotypical star-making egos where many lessons are learned. Fans of 60's rock music will love this for its accurate description of the times, through the music, fashions, beehive hairdo's and those crazy home decors usually found in the old Green Stamps catalogs. Erie residents may not recognize State Street in the few street scenes (with the exception of the still standing facade of the old Boston Store), but mentions of Mercyhurst College and radio/TV station WJET (their ABC affiliate-Channel 24 during my youth), plus constant reminders as the boys go on the road that they are Erie natives, the film becomes a hallmark card to a beautiful city that sometimes takes a ribbing but in truth is actually one of the top tourist attractions in Pennsylvania. Hanks gives an enthusiastic performance as the manager of the band who is determined to rise them to fame. If Detroit can have their Dreamgirls, then Erie is more than allowed to have their Laker Boys! While the real 1960's produced a lot of schlocky rock & roll movies (mainly through some Sam Katzman produced musicals made at Columbia studios or those silly American International Frankie/Annette "Beach Party" movies), this is a loving salute to all the glitz from the movies and television shows of this era, with a bit of "Bye Bye Birdie" and "Hairspray" thrown in. As for the energetic title song, I really was shocked to learn that it was written for the movie, not an actual hit from that era.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stands the test of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie no matters how many times you've seen it always remains an enjoyable movie to watch with some great actors. Tom Hanks definitely makes a great showing in his directorial debut. The story focuses on a local Scranton, PA band that goes from obscurity to being a fast rising band. When the original drummer of the band hurts his hand before playing a gig they bring in Guy to replace him and his participation in the band changes the trajectory of the band. Eventually they get signed to Tom Hanks character who works for a big label called Playtone Records. Things are going good for a bit touring the country doing concerts. But then they get called to Hollywood and end up doing a bunch of pointless appearances. After awhile tension builds in the band and they end up breaking up, ultimately the band ends up being nothing more then a 1 hit wonder.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The O-Needers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That Thing You Do! Is written and directed by Tom Hanks who also co-stars with Tom Everett Scott, Liv Tyler, Steve Zahn, Johnathon Schaech and Ethan Embry. Film is set in the summer of 1964 and tells of the story of American one hit wonder band, The Wonders. Who after scoring big with their catchy debut single That Thing That You Do, hope to blaze the hits trail like the British Beatles. But with success comes lifestyle changes, and inevitably cracks start to appear in the group dynamic. Utterly charming in places, and propelled by an irritatingly catchy theme tune, Tom Hanks' directing debut is enjoyable while it's on, if ultimately it's very predictable fare. It lacks bite for the dramatic threads, but the characterisations are strong, the period detail is spot on (Hanks clearly utilising his memory banks) and there's nothing to complain about in the acting. However, the trajectory of the story stays on such a safe formulaic road, with not a snippet of villainy or hardship to be found, that it's hard to genuinely root for this band to succeed. We like them, we like their song, but it's all made so easy for them, while there's also a distinct lack of humour to be found along the way. When the band starts to implode, ask yourself if you really care or not? Safe is the key word, Hanks has played it safe, it's inoffensive stuff and impossible to dislike, and there should be the odd tingle of warmth coursing through your body. But you have to be in a safe sort of mood to forgive it its lack of guts, or at the very least, adventure. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bravo, Tom Hanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie doesn't so much have a plot as a trajectory. Nevertheless, it is better to see it yourself than to know where it is going. Suffice it to say that it is about a rock band, and how its members, friends and family respond to its success. As such, it is in the slice-of-life genre. Given its nearly 2 and a half hour length on the directors cut that I saw, and recommend, it works remarkably well. After awhile, I wondered if something would happen, some disaster or twist of fate, some bad guy to thicken the plot, and noticed the movie was rather long. But I wasn't bored at all, and was enjoying seeing the story unfold. In the end, the length was just right. Also, I am not a rock fan, so I was a bit skeptical. It didn't matter. In the wrong hands, this could have turned into Partridge Family cornball. But it is solid. To all this, Tom Hanks deserves the credit as writer, director, and low- key star, who appears late in the movie. It's a first class job. Not an earth shaking masterpiece, but a well-crafted, thoroughly enjoyable movie. I am a stickler for anachronisms in movies like this. This is a period piece set in Erie, Pennsylvania, circa 1964. The Sixties was a fluid time, where the culture changed every two years; 1964 was different from 1960, 1962, 1966 and 1968. The fact that one of the band members enlists in the Marines, without any mention of Vietnam, is a good measure of the mood and innocence of 1964, versus 1966, when the war had become politicized. America was at its best around this time, and it was all downhill from there. The movie captured the spirit of this window of time. Tom Hanks was 8 at the time, so he could not rely solely on memory, and must have done some historical research to fully understand the period. Whoever was in charge of props did a fantastic job of assembling lots of appliances, radios, recording gear and lots of cars. This is a movie that got it right. I loved when Skitch handed out pocket transistor radios to everyone in the band - back then an AM radio would have cost about $10 to $15, very expensive at the time, about $50 or more in today's dollars. The only anachronism I found was when Skitch tells a customer the appliance is available in avocado. Avocado was a notoriously common kitchen appliance color in the 1970s; I see it was introduced by GE in 1966, but became a tidal wave around 1968-1970. It was one of those fashion things, a late Dating Game chic, when all of a sudden everything was avocado green (or harvest gold), color coordinated so people could have an entire kitchen of avocado, lucky you!. And then avocado, predictably, disappeared. I found a post, "The Death of Avocado" that observed it was a mistake to put a trendy color on a long-life appliance, which looked obnoxious after coordinating avocado room decor disappeared. No kidding. I was just a kid at the time, but I could see that coming. See how sensitive the cultural timeline is for the Sixties? Actually, I would say what most people think of as the Sixties began around 1963-64, with the Beatles and the period of this film, and lasted till Nixon's resignation in 1974 (although some place the beginning of change at 1959). After that, the years unfolded in a homogeneous miasma, distinguished mainly by the gradual introduction of new technology, like the VCR, the Walkman and cordless phone sizes. That an appliance color was the only missed stitch in the movie indicates just how good it was! The acting all round was excellent. There were no caricatures, even with the doorman at the LA hotel, who had some real depth to his role. And, although I read here there were pro musicians actually dubbing the music, the actors were totally convincing that they were the ones making the music. "That Thing You Do" fits most closely the mold of "Breaking Away," which also featured a cast of talented young actors, and a skeptical, practical father representing the secure, dull path. Both are about life, dreams and fallibility. They both offer a lesson for young people. And in both, in the end, they turn a corner and life goes on. This is an enjoyable, memorable and thoughtful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny seize the day and forget about the rest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr Jacques COULARDEAU
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a comedy about real young people from the Rock 'n Roll planet in the early 1960s. It's funny but also typically American. There are so many sharks going around looking for young teenage would-be rock stars that it is impossible not to be noticed by one, one day, not to become some one overnight and not to dissolved as soon as the top is reached. To stay at the top is really difficult. A band in those days, and in the USA, was the normal way for anyone who wanted to do some music on the stage to go around but bands did not last long. Everyone is not the Beatles or the Rolling Stones, you know. This is the story of the short-lived Wonders and yet the four boys and the one girl who were there at the first public appearance in the boonies, all eventually did something with their skin and their brains, if they had any, both skin and brains. Today that adventure still exists in the USA but it has also taken names like Myspace music, Youtube, Daily Motion and some others. Permanence of course is nothing in that business in 99% of the cases, but chance is also essential for those who have something in their veins. A career is often 50% talent and 50% chance, some would say opportunity. But the film is funny, though so banal that it should be a warning to anyone who wants to imitate these young teenagers. As the old Paxton would say: look after your money, women and a few other things of that type. Yesterday is a sure thing that existed but tomorrow is as brittle as an egg shell in front of a bulldozer. And the world is full of bulldozers crushing many eggshells down into the ground and powder. Dust to dust mind you. Dr Jacques COULARDEAU, University Paris 1 Pantheon Sorbonne, University Paris 8 Saint Denis, University Paris 12 Cr&eacute;teil, CEGID
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breezy period piece wrapped around a catchy song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this movie advertised in the theaters back in 1996, I rolled my eyes in great disdain. For one thing the advertising banner - "In every life there comes a time when that dream you dream becomes that thing you do" hit me the wrong way. After all, 95% of us never wind up doing the dream we dream...there is no WHEN in our lives for this event. Plus, I just figured it was an attempt by Tom Hanks to go highbrow via a directorial debut after those back-to-back Academy Awards. When I finally got around to seeing the film I really loved it. The first half is very upbeat as the band gets started out. They truly are the "One-ders", just like many other bands of the Beatles' transitional era. They wrote and performed one song that got them national attention, and then couldn't follow up with anything else. That's too bad, because the band does get one lucky break after another at the start. The guy in the camper that shoves a bowl of stew and a contract in front of them and tells them to "trust me" could have had them signing anything. They got lucky that he was legitimate and really did intend to get the record on the air and not steal it from them. That's what makes the disintegration of the band at the end so sad. One by one, they just walk away from their dream. To me, if the movie had any flaw, it was this - the band members just acted like the whole thing was one big amusement park ride rather than a once-in-a-lifetime life changing opportunity. Finally, I also loved all of the authentic looking stage designs. The home appliance store really brought back memories. These type of family owned appliance stores were all over the place back in the 1960's before the big box stores gradually made them extinct. Plus, the appliances being sold looked just like what was available in 1964 right down to the brand names and the styles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ingenious! One Of The Best Movies Of 1996!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie only a few years ago, and I can say that I was not disappointed in any way, shape, or form! In my point of view, this is ingenious! I remember that when I was done watching this movie for the first time, I just wanted to watch it all over again, because I just plain loved it! I mean that I loved this movie, and when I mean that I loved it, I loved it! This movie is honestly one of the best movies of the 1990's, as well as one of the best movies of 1996! This movie is totally and completely remarkable from beginning to end, from the very beginning of this movie to the very end of this movie, it is totally and completely remarkable! I honestly have nothing to say about this movie that is against it, because I was not disappointed with it at all! And once more, I thought that this movie was perfect, not only as a musical movie, but as a movie movie! This is also another movie that is a must see, because it just can't get any better than this, not kidding, it really can't get any better! While I loved the movie as a whole, I especially loved the songs and the music! In fact, I own the soundtrack to this film, as well as the film itself! This movie has got some of the best songs of any film that I have honestly ever heard, because they are extraordinary! And because I own the soundtrack and the film, I can watch this movie and listen to the songs at any time that I feel like doing it! I don't regret seeing this movie, because it blew me away! So all in all, this is another movie that scores a ten out of ten on my scale! If you haven't seen this movie yet, see it, because like I was, you are going to be blown away! I am not joking with you, this movie really is that great of a film, I mean that it is something that you are going to love from the very minute that you start watching it! Mark my words: You've got to watch this movie, it is totally and completely fabulous and extraordinary! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do that thing I do!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sukhitha Jayathilake
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Huge cast. Many popular stars today maybe at the start of their carrier. Liv Tylor and Charlice Theron. OMG they literally look like dolls. Specially Charlice. And two of my favorites, Steve Zahn and Giovanni Ribisi. It's a movie about a small town band trying to make it out in the big time. Well It's just a simple journey every band has to go through so to speak. Basically as I see it It's all just four guys playing there only hit single throughout the movie like a thousand times? Does tend to make you sick even! The reason I don't get that much of a kick out of this movie is maybe because I'm not 50. People tom Hanks' age must get to drive down the memory lane watching this one. Too bad I can't feel it. Well BTW If you think about it, This movie is pretty gay. The modern equivalent to this movie would be a movie about the Jonas brothers. Only they are still popular. But Still Liv Tyler makes it watchable. I wanted to see more Charlice Theron. She must have been an amateur then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun musical romp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have said, it's an homage to a simpler time. Love the small visual nods to "A Hard Day's Night" with the boys running through the simulation of the states. Also the hint of the same thing that happened to Lennon with the 'he's engaged' posting on the monitor. Of course, Lennon was actually engaged, if not already married! I truly don't get tired of this film. Just a feel-good movie. Also liked everything I read about how Hanks insisted that the actors learn to play their instruments well enough to look good in the film. Some of them practiced several hours a day. It's fun to see his wife pop in as a waitress where there's good jazz. Such a seemingly fun woman - but what else would you expect from Tom Hanks' wife? No, it didn't win any awards. But it's a 'keeper'. Watch it. Such fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nostalgic look back at the 1960s, when I was a beginning college student.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this movie a number of years ago but didn't remember much about it, so I saw it again today on DVD from my public library. I was a college Freshman in 1963/64, when the Beatles were first gaining popularity on this side of the pond, and this movie fairly accurately recreates that period, the way people dressed, and how teenagers reacted when seeing their pop idols live in concert. The story grabs hold of a theme I am very fond of pondering, both in real life and in fiction stories. That theme is the relative randomness of our lives, the things that happen, and then how we react to those random events. If we look at random events in our own lives, we can see how certain unexpected things shaped who we are today. In this movie a group of high school friends like to make music, one of them writes songs and is the featured singer. He has written "That Thing You Do" and they are about to perform it in a local small-potatoes contest. But the drummer, horsing around by showing the bass player how to jump over parking meters, falls and breaks his arm right before the contest. Now that is the "random event", and it leads them to ask another guy in town, who is a good drummer, to sit in for that one gig, so that they will still have a chance to win the competition. Then comes the rest of the influence of that "random event", the drummer own his own (this is important) decides to beat out a much faster tempo. It is this faster tempo that makes "That Thing You Do" a hit with the audience, attracts the attention of an agent, gets them a record, gets them a contract, puts them on tour, and has their hit rise towards the top of the charts. If their original drummer had not broken his arm, they would have just remained an ordinary band. Well as the story progresses they experience all the growing pains of sudden fame, and conflicting priorities among the members of the group. Tom Hanks directed, has a part as a record label agent, and he even wrote many of the songs. Tom Everett Scott who was in his mid-20s is very good as the replacement drummer, Guy Patterson. Liv Tyler, still a teenager was Faye Dolan who ended up traveling with the band. Her boyfriend was Johnathon Schaech as Jimmy who wrote the song and sang lead vocals. Steve Zahn was the crazy member Lenny, and Ethan Embry, also a teenager, was T. B. Player the unreliable bass player. Another teenager just starting her career was Charlize Theron as Tina in a fairly small part, as a flaky girlfriend who dumps Guy after an appointment with a handsome dentist. Plus young Giovanni Ribisi as Chad , the original drummer who breaks his arm. All in all a fairly pleasant movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You've heard of the "Jersey Boys", Well, here come the "Erie Boys!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yay! Somebody made a movie set in my home town! Historically made famous by early American battles in the infancy of our country, Erie PA is also famous for where a certain overweight US President got stuck in a bathtub, and where a comic named Bob Hope wed his lovely bride, Delores. But for Tom Hanks (here the filmmaker in addition to actor), he uses Erie as the setting for a boy's band which suddenly rises to fame and go through all of the stereotypical star-making egos where many lessons are learned. Fans of 60's rock music will love this for its accurate description of the times, through the music, fashions, beehive hairdo's and those crazy home decors usually found in the old Green Stamps catalogs. Erie residents may not recognize State Street in the few street scenes (with the exception of the still standing facade of the old Boston Store), but mentions of Mercyhurst College and radio/TV station WJET (their ABC affiliate-Channel 24 during my youth), plus constant reminders as the boys go on the road that they are Erie natives, the film becomes a hallmark card to a beautiful city that sometimes takes a ribbing but in truth is actually one of the top tourist attractions in Pennsylvania. Hanks gives an enthusiastic performance as the manager of the band who is determined to rise them to fame. If Detroit can have their Dreamgirls, then Erie is more than allowed to have their Laker Boys! While the real 1960's produced a lot of schlocky rock & roll movies (mainly through some Sam Katzman produced musicals made at Columbia studios or those silly American International Frankie/Annette "Beach Party" movies), this is a loving salute to all the glitz from the movies and television shows of this era, with a bit of "Bye Bye Birdie" and "Hairspray" thrown in. As for the energetic title song, I really was shocked to learn that it was written for the movie, not an actual hit from that era.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stands the test of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie no matters how many times you've seen it always remains an enjoyable movie to watch with some great actors. Tom Hanks definitely makes a great showing in his directorial debut. The story focuses on a local Scranton, PA band that goes from obscurity to being a fast rising band. When the original drummer of the band hurts his hand before playing a gig they bring in Guy to replace him and his participation in the band changes the trajectory of the band. Eventually they get signed to Tom Hanks character who works for a big label called Playtone Records. Things are going good for a bit touring the country doing concerts. But then they get called to Hollywood and end up doing a bunch of pointless appearances. After awhile tension builds in the band and they end up breaking up, ultimately the band ends up being nothing more then a 1 hit wonder.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The O-Needers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That Thing You Do! Is written and directed by Tom Hanks who also co-stars with Tom Everett Scott, Liv Tyler, Steve Zahn, Johnathon Schaech and Ethan Embry. Film is set in the summer of 1964 and tells of the story of American one hit wonder band, The Wonders. Who after scoring big with their catchy debut single That Thing That You Do, hope to blaze the hits trail like the British Beatles. But with success comes lifestyle changes, and inevitably cracks start to appear in the group dynamic. Utterly charming in places, and propelled by an irritatingly catchy theme tune, Tom Hanks' directing debut is enjoyable while it's on, if ultimately it's very predictable fare. It lacks bite for the dramatic threads, but the characterisations are strong, the period detail is spot on (Hanks clearly utilising his memory banks) and there's nothing to complain about in the acting. However, the trajectory of the story stays on such a safe formulaic road, with not a snippet of villainy or hardship to be found, that it's hard to genuinely root for this band to succeed. We like them, we like their song, but it's all made so easy for them, while there's also a distinct lack of humour to be found along the way. When the band starts to implode, ask yourself if you really care or not? Safe is the key word, Hanks has played it safe, it's inoffensive stuff and impossible to dislike, and there should be the odd tingle of warmth coursing through your body. But you have to be in a safe sort of mood to forgive it its lack of guts, or at the very least, adventure. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bravo, Tom Hanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie doesn't so much have a plot as a trajectory. Nevertheless, it is better to see it yourself than to know where it is going. Suffice it to say that it is about a rock band, and how its members, friends and family respond to its success. As such, it is in the slice-of-life genre. Given its nearly 2 and a half hour length on the directors cut that I saw, and recommend, it works remarkably well. After awhile, I wondered if something would happen, some disaster or twist of fate, some bad guy to thicken the plot, and noticed the movie was rather long. But I wasn't bored at all, and was enjoying seeing the story unfold. In the end, the length was just right. Also, I am not a rock fan, so I was a bit skeptical. It didn't matter. In the wrong hands, this could have turned into Partridge Family cornball. But it is solid. To all this, Tom Hanks deserves the credit as writer, director, and low- key star, who appears late in the movie. It's a first class job. Not an earth shaking masterpiece, but a well-crafted, thoroughly enjoyable movie. I am a stickler for anachronisms in movies like this. This is a period piece set in Erie, Pennsylvania, circa 1964. The Sixties was a fluid time, where the culture changed every two years; 1964 was different from 1960, 1962, 1966 and 1968. The fact that one of the band members enlists in the Marines, without any mention of Vietnam, is a good measure of the mood and innocence of 1964, versus 1966, when the war had become politicized. America was at its best around this time, and it was all downhill from there. The movie captured the spirit of this window of time. Tom Hanks was 8 at the time, so he could not rely solely on memory, and must have done some historical research to fully understand the period. Whoever was in charge of props did a fantastic job of assembling lots of appliances, radios, recording gear and lots of cars. This is a movie that got it right. I loved when Skitch handed out pocket transistor radios to everyone in the band - back then an AM radio would have cost about $10 to $15, very expensive at the time, about $50 or more in today's dollars. The only anachronism I found was when Skitch tells a customer the appliance is available in avocado. Avocado was a notoriously common kitchen appliance color in the 1970s; I see it was introduced by GE in 1966, but became a tidal wave around 1968-1970. It was one of those fashion things, a late Dating Game chic, when all of a sudden everything was avocado green (or harvest gold), color coordinated so people could have an entire kitchen of avocado, lucky you!. And then avocado, predictably, disappeared. I found a post, "The Death of Avocado" that observed it was a mistake to put a trendy color on a long-life appliance, which looked obnoxious after coordinating avocado room decor disappeared. No kidding. I was just a kid at the time, but I could see that coming. See how sensitive the cultural timeline is for the Sixties? Actually, I would say what most people think of as the Sixties began around 1963-64, with the Beatles and the period of this film, and lasted till Nixon's resignation in 1974 (although some place the beginning of change at 1959). After that, the years unfolded in a homogeneous miasma, distinguished mainly by the gradual introduction of new technology, like the VCR, the Walkman and cordless phone sizes. That an appliance color was the only missed stitch in the movie indicates just how good it was! The acting all round was excellent. There were no caricatures, even with the doorman at the LA hotel, who had some real depth to his role. And, although I read here there were pro musicians actually dubbing the music, the actors were totally convincing that they were the ones making the music. "That Thing You Do" fits most closely the mold of "Breaking Away," which also featured a cast of talented young actors, and a skeptical, practical father representing the secure, dull path. Both are about life, dreams and fallibility. They both offer a lesson for young people. And in both, in the end, they turn a corner and life goes on. This is an enjoyable, memorable and thoughtful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny seize the day and forget about the rest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr Jacques COULARDEAU
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a comedy about real young people from the Rock 'n Roll planet in the early 1960s. It's funny but also typically American. There are so many sharks going around looking for young teenage would-be rock stars that it is impossible not to be noticed by one, one day, not to become some one overnight and not to dissolved as soon as the top is reached. To stay at the top is really difficult. A band in those days, and in the USA, was the normal way for anyone who wanted to do some music on the stage to go around but bands did not last long. Everyone is not the Beatles or the Rolling Stones, you know. This is the story of the short-lived Wonders and yet the four boys and the one girl who were there at the first public appearance in the boonies, all eventually did something with their skin and their brains, if they had any, both skin and brains. Today that adventure still exists in the USA but it has also taken names like Myspace music, Youtube, Daily Motion and some others. Permanence of course is nothing in that business in 99% of the cases, but chance is also essential for those who have something in their veins. A career is often 50% talent and 50% chance, some would say opportunity. But the film is funny, though so banal that it should be a warning to anyone who wants to imitate these young teenagers. As the old Paxton would say: look after your money, women and a few other things of that type. Yesterday is a sure thing that existed but tomorrow is as brittle as an egg shell in front of a bulldozer. And the world is full of bulldozers crushing many eggshells down into the ground and powder. Dust to dust mind you. Dr Jacques COULARDEAU, University Paris 1 Pantheon Sorbonne, University Paris 8 Saint Denis, University Paris 12 Cr&eacute;teil, CEGID
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breezy period piece wrapped around a catchy song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this movie advertised in the theaters back in 1996, I rolled my eyes in great disdain. For one thing the advertising banner - "In every life there comes a time when that dream you dream becomes that thing you do" hit me the wrong way. After all, 95% of us never wind up doing the dream we dream...there is no WHEN in our lives for this event. Plus, I just figured it was an attempt by Tom Hanks to go highbrow via a directorial debut after those back-to-back Academy Awards. When I finally got around to seeing the film I really loved it. The first half is very upbeat as the band gets started out. They truly are the "One-ders", just like many other bands of the Beatles' transitional era. They wrote and performed one song that got them national attention, and then couldn't follow up with anything else. That's too bad, because the band does get one lucky break after another at the start. The guy in the camper that shoves a bowl of stew and a contract in front of them and tells them to "trust me" could have had them signing anything. They got lucky that he was legitimate and really did intend to get the record on the air and not steal it from them. That's what makes the disintegration of the band at the end so sad. One by one, they just walk away from their dream. To me, if the movie had any flaw, it was this - the band members just acted like the whole thing was one big amusement park ride rather than a once-in-a-lifetime life changing opportunity. Finally, I also loved all of the authentic looking stage designs. The home appliance store really brought back memories. These type of family owned appliance stores were all over the place back in the 1960's before the big box stores gradually made them extinct. Plus, the appliances being sold looked just like what was available in 1964 right down to the brand names and the styles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ingenious! One Of The Best Movies Of 1996!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie only a few years ago, and I can say that I was not disappointed in any way, shape, or form! In my point of view, this is ingenious! I remember that when I was done watching this movie for the first time, I just wanted to watch it all over again, because I just plain loved it! I mean that I loved this movie, and when I mean that I loved it, I loved it! This movie is honestly one of the best movies of the 1990's, as well as one of the best movies of 1996! This movie is totally and completely remarkable from beginning to end, from the very beginning of this movie to the very end of this movie, it is totally and completely remarkable! I honestly have nothing to say about this movie that is against it, because I was not disappointed with it at all! And once more, I thought that this movie was perfect, not only as a musical movie, but as a movie movie! This is also another movie that is a must see, because it just can't get any better than this, not kidding, it really can't get any better! While I loved the movie as a whole, I especially loved the songs and the music! In fact, I own the soundtrack to this film, as well as the film itself! This movie has got some of the best songs of any film that I have honestly ever heard, because they are extraordinary! And because I own the soundtrack and the film, I can watch this movie and listen to the songs at any time that I feel like doing it! I don't regret seeing this movie, because it blew me away! So all in all, this is another movie that scores a ten out of ten on my scale! If you haven't seen this movie yet, see it, because like I was, you are going to be blown away! I am not joking with you, this movie really is that great of a film, I mean that it is something that you are going to love from the very minute that you start watching it! Mark my words: You've got to watch this movie, it is totally and completely fabulous and extraordinary! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do that thing I do!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sukhitha Jayathilake
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Huge cast. Many popular stars today maybe at the start of their carrier. Liv Tylor and Charlice Theron. OMG they literally look like dolls. Specially Charlice. And two of my favorites, Steve Zahn and Giovanni Ribisi. It's a movie about a small town band trying to make it out in the big time. Well It's just a simple journey every band has to go through so to speak. Basically as I see it It's all just four guys playing there only hit single throughout the movie like a thousand times? Does tend to make you sick even! The reason I don't get that much of a kick out of this movie is maybe because I'm not 50. People tom Hanks' age must get to drive down the memory lane watching this one. Too bad I can't feel it. Well BTW If you think about it, This movie is pretty gay. The modern equivalent to this movie would be a movie about the Jonas brothers. Only they are still popular. But Still Liv Tyler makes it watchable. I wanted to see more Charlice Theron. She must have been an amateur then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun musical romp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have said, it's an homage to a simpler time. Love the small visual nods to "A Hard Day's Night" with the boys running through the simulation of the states. Also the hint of the same thing that happened to Lennon with the 'he's engaged' posting on the monitor. Of course, Lennon was actually engaged, if not already married! I truly don't get tired of this film. Just a feel-good movie. Also liked everything I read about how Hanks insisted that the actors learn to play their instruments well enough to look good in the film. Some of them practiced several hours a day. It's fun to see his wife pop in as a waitress where there's good jazz. Such a seemingly fun woman - but what else would you expect from Tom Hanks' wife? No, it didn't win any awards. But it's a 'keeper'. Watch it. Such fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nostalgic look back at the 1960s, when I was a beginning college student.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this movie a number of years ago but didn't remember much about it, so I saw it again today on DVD from my public library. I was a college Freshman in 1963/64, when the Beatles were first gaining popularity on this side of the pond, and this movie fairly accurately recreates that period, the way people dressed, and how teenagers reacted when seeing their pop idols live in concert. The story grabs hold of a theme I am very fond of pondering, both in real life and in fiction stories. That theme is the relative randomness of our lives, the things that happen, and then how we react to those random events. If we look at random events in our own lives, we can see how certain unexpected things shaped who we are today. In this movie a group of high school friends like to make music, one of them writes songs and is the featured singer. He has written "That Thing You Do" and they are about to perform it in a local small-potatoes contest. But the drummer, horsing around by showing the bass player how to jump over parking meters, falls and breaks his arm right before the contest. Now that is the "random event", and it leads them to ask another guy in town, who is a good drummer, to sit in for that one gig, so that they will still have a chance to win the competition. Then comes the rest of the influence of that "random event", the drummer own his own (this is important) decides to beat out a much faster tempo. It is this faster tempo that makes "That Thing You Do" a hit with the audience, attracts the attention of an agent, gets them a record, gets them a contract, puts them on tour, and has their hit rise towards the top of the charts. If their original drummer had not broken his arm, they would have just remained an ordinary band. Well as the story progresses they experience all the growing pains of sudden fame, and conflicting priorities among the members of the group. Tom Hanks directed, has a part as a record label agent, and he even wrote many of the songs. Tom Everett Scott who was in his mid-20s is very good as the replacement drummer, Guy Patterson. Liv Tyler, still a teenager was Faye Dolan who ended up traveling with the band. Her boyfriend was Johnathon Schaech as Jimmy who wrote the song and sang lead vocals. Steve Zahn was the crazy member Lenny, and Ethan Embry, also a teenager, was T. B. Player the unreliable bass player. Another teenager just starting her career was Charlize Theron as Tina in a fairly small part, as a flaky girlfriend who dumps Guy after an appointment with a handsome dentist. Plus young Giovanni Ribisi as Chad , the original drummer who breaks his arm. All in all a fairly pleasant movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You've heard of the "Jersey Boys", Well, here come the "Erie Boys!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yay! Somebody made a movie set in my home town! Historically made famous by early American battles in the infancy of our country, Erie PA is also famous for where a certain overweight US President got stuck in a bathtub, and where a comic named Bob Hope wed his lovely bride, Delores. But for Tom Hanks (here the filmmaker in addition to actor), he uses Erie as the setting for a boy's band which suddenly rises to fame and go through all of the stereotypical star-making egos where many lessons are learned. Fans of 60's rock music will love this for its accurate description of the times, through the music, fashions, beehive hairdo's and those crazy home decors usually found in the old Green Stamps catalogs. Erie residents may not recognize State Street in the few street scenes (with the exception of the still standing facade of the old Boston Store), but mentions of Mercyhurst College and radio/TV station WJET (their ABC affiliate-Channel 24 during my youth), plus constant reminders as the boys go on the road that they are Erie natives, the film becomes a hallmark card to a beautiful city that sometimes takes a ribbing but in truth is actually one of the top tourist attractions in Pennsylvania. Hanks gives an enthusiastic performance as the manager of the band who is determined to rise them to fame. If Detroit can have their Dreamgirls, then Erie is more than allowed to have their Laker Boys! While the real 1960's produced a lot of schlocky rock & roll movies (mainly through some Sam Katzman produced musicals made at Columbia studios or those silly American International Frankie/Annette "Beach Party" movies), this is a loving salute to all the glitz from the movies and television shows of this era, with a bit of "Bye Bye Birdie" and "Hairspray" thrown in. As for the energetic title song, I really was shocked to learn that it was written for the movie, not an actual hit from that era.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stands the test of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie no matters how many times you've seen it always remains an enjoyable movie to watch with some great actors. Tom Hanks definitely makes a great showing in his directorial debut. The story focuses on a local Scranton, PA band that goes from obscurity to being a fast rising band. When the original drummer of the band hurts his hand before playing a gig they bring in Guy to replace him and his participation in the band changes the trajectory of the band. Eventually they get signed to Tom Hanks character who works for a big label called Playtone Records. Things are going good for a bit touring the country doing concerts. But then they get called to Hollywood and end up doing a bunch of pointless appearances. After awhile tension builds in the band and they end up breaking up, ultimately the band ends up being nothing more then a 1 hit wonder.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The O-Needers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That Thing You Do! Is written and directed by Tom Hanks who also co-stars with Tom Everett Scott, Liv Tyler, Steve Zahn, Johnathon Schaech and Ethan Embry. Film is set in the summer of 1964 and tells of the story of American one hit wonder band, The Wonders. Who after scoring big with their catchy debut single That Thing That You Do, hope to blaze the hits trail like the British Beatles. But with success comes lifestyle changes, and inevitably cracks start to appear in the group dynamic. Utterly charming in places, and propelled by an irritatingly catchy theme tune, Tom Hanks' directing debut is enjoyable while it's on, if ultimately it's very predictable fare. It lacks bite for the dramatic threads, but the characterisations are strong, the period detail is spot on (Hanks clearly utilising his memory banks) and there's nothing to complain about in the acting. However, the trajectory of the story stays on such a safe formulaic road, with not a snippet of villainy or hardship to be found, that it's hard to genuinely root for this band to succeed. We like them, we like their song, but it's all made so easy for them, while there's also a distinct lack of humour to be found along the way. When the band starts to implode, ask yourself if you really care or not? Safe is the key word, Hanks has played it safe, it's inoffensive stuff and impossible to dislike, and there should be the odd tingle of warmth coursing through your body. But you have to be in a safe sort of mood to forgive it its lack of guts, or at the very least, adventure. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bravo, Tom Hanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie doesn't so much have a plot as a trajectory. Nevertheless, it is better to see it yourself than to know where it is going. Suffice it to say that it is about a rock band, and how its members, friends and family respond to its success. As such, it is in the slice-of-life genre. Given its nearly 2 and a half hour length on the directors cut that I saw, and recommend, it works remarkably well. After awhile, I wondered if something would happen, some disaster or twist of fate, some bad guy to thicken the plot, and noticed the movie was rather long. But I wasn't bored at all, and was enjoying seeing the story unfold. In the end, the length was just right. Also, I am not a rock fan, so I was a bit skeptical. It didn't matter. In the wrong hands, this could have turned into Partridge Family cornball. But it is solid. To all this, Tom Hanks deserves the credit as writer, director, and low- key star, who appears late in the movie. It's a first class job. Not an earth shaking masterpiece, but a well-crafted, thoroughly enjoyable movie. I am a stickler for anachronisms in movies like this. This is a period piece set in Erie, Pennsylvania, circa 1964. The Sixties was a fluid time, where the culture changed every two years; 1964 was different from 1960, 1962, 1966 and 1968. The fact that one of the band members enlists in the Marines, without any mention of Vietnam, is a good measure of the mood and innocence of 1964, versus 1966, when the war had become politicized. America was at its best around this time, and it was all downhill from there. The movie captured the spirit of this window of time. Tom Hanks was 8 at the time, so he could not rely solely on memory, and must have done some historical research to fully understand the period. Whoever was in charge of props did a fantastic job of assembling lots of appliances, radios, recording gear and lots of cars. This is a movie that got it right. I loved when Skitch handed out pocket transistor radios to everyone in the band - back then an AM radio would have cost about $10 to $15, very expensive at the time, about $50 or more in today's dollars. The only anachronism I found was when Skitch tells a customer the appliance is available in avocado. Avocado was a notoriously common kitchen appliance color in the 1970s; I see it was introduced by GE in 1966, but became a tidal wave around 1968-1970. It was one of those fashion things, a late Dating Game chic, when all of a sudden everything was avocado green (or harvest gold), color coordinated so people could have an entire kitchen of avocado, lucky you!. And then avocado, predictably, disappeared. I found a post, "The Death of Avocado" that observed it was a mistake to put a trendy color on a long-life appliance, which looked obnoxious after coordinating avocado room decor disappeared. No kidding. I was just a kid at the time, but I could see that coming. See how sensitive the cultural timeline is for the Sixties? Actually, I would say what most people think of as the Sixties began around 1963-64, with the Beatles and the period of this film, and lasted till Nixon's resignation in 1974 (although some place the beginning of change at 1959). After that, the years unfolded in a homogeneous miasma, distinguished mainly by the gradual introduction of new technology, like the VCR, the Walkman and cordless phone sizes. That an appliance color was the only missed stitch in the movie indicates just how good it was! The acting all round was excellent. There were no caricatures, even with the doorman at the LA hotel, who had some real depth to his role. And, although I read here there were pro musicians actually dubbing the music, the actors were totally convincing that they were the ones making the music. "That Thing You Do" fits most closely the mold of "Breaking Away," which also featured a cast of talented young actors, and a skeptical, practical father representing the secure, dull path. Both are about life, dreams and fallibility. They both offer a lesson for young people. And in both, in the end, they turn a corner and life goes on. This is an enjoyable, memorable and thoughtful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny seize the day and forget about the rest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr Jacques COULARDEAU
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a comedy about real young people from the Rock 'n Roll planet in the early 1960s. It's funny but also typically American. There are so many sharks going around looking for young teenage would-be rock stars that it is impossible not to be noticed by one, one day, not to become some one overnight and not to dissolved as soon as the top is reached. To stay at the top is really difficult. A band in those days, and in the USA, was the normal way for anyone who wanted to do some music on the stage to go around but bands did not last long. Everyone is not the Beatles or the Rolling Stones, you know. This is the story of the short-lived Wonders and yet the four boys and the one girl who were there at the first public appearance in the boonies, all eventually did something with their skin and their brains, if they had any, both skin and brains. Today that adventure still exists in the USA but it has also taken names like Myspace music, Youtube, Daily Motion and some others. Permanence of course is nothing in that business in 99% of the cases, but chance is also essential for those who have something in their veins. A career is often 50% talent and 50% chance, some would say opportunity. But the film is funny, though so banal that it should be a warning to anyone who wants to imitate these young teenagers. As the old Paxton would say: look after your money, women and a few other things of that type. Yesterday is a sure thing that existed but tomorrow is as brittle as an egg shell in front of a bulldozer. And the world is full of bulldozers crushing many eggshells down into the ground and powder. Dust to dust mind you. Dr Jacques COULARDEAU, University Paris 1 Pantheon Sorbonne, University Paris 8 Saint Denis, University Paris 12 Cr&eacute;teil, CEGID
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breezy period piece wrapped around a catchy song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this movie advertised in the theaters back in 1996, I rolled my eyes in great disdain. For one thing the advertising banner - "In every life there comes a time when that dream you dream becomes that thing you do" hit me the wrong way. After all, 95% of us never wind up doing the dream we dream...there is no WHEN in our lives for this event. Plus, I just figured it was an attempt by Tom Hanks to go highbrow via a directorial debut after those back-to-back Academy Awards. When I finally got around to seeing the film I really loved it. The first half is very upbeat as the band gets started out. They truly are the "One-ders", just like many other bands of the Beatles' transitional era. They wrote and performed one song that got them national attention, and then couldn't follow up with anything else. That's too bad, because the band does get one lucky break after another at the start. The guy in the camper that shoves a bowl of stew and a contract in front of them and tells them to "trust me" could have had them signing anything. They got lucky that he was legitimate and really did intend to get the record on the air and not steal it from them. That's what makes the disintegration of the band at the end so sad. One by one, they just walk away from their dream. To me, if the movie had any flaw, it was this - the band members just acted like the whole thing was one big amusement park ride rather than a once-in-a-lifetime life changing opportunity. Finally, I also loved all of the authentic looking stage designs. The home appliance store really brought back memories. These type of family owned appliance stores were all over the place back in the 1960's before the big box stores gradually made them extinct. Plus, the appliances being sold looked just like what was available in 1964 right down to the brand names and the styles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ingenious! One Of The Best Movies Of 1996!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie only a few years ago, and I can say that I was not disappointed in any way, shape, or form! In my point of view, this is ingenious! I remember that when I was done watching this movie for the first time, I just wanted to watch it all over again, because I just plain loved it! I mean that I loved this movie, and when I mean that I loved it, I loved it! This movie is honestly one of the best movies of the 1990's, as well as one of the best movies of 1996! This movie is totally and completely remarkable from beginning to end, from the very beginning of this movie to the very end of this movie, it is totally and completely remarkable! I honestly have nothing to say about this movie that is against it, because I was not disappointed with it at all! And once more, I thought that this movie was perfect, not only as a musical movie, but as a movie movie! This is also another movie that is a must see, because it just can't get any better than this, not kidding, it really can't get any better! While I loved the movie as a whole, I especially loved the songs and the music! In fact, I own the soundtrack to this film, as well as the film itself! This movie has got some of the best songs of any film that I have honestly ever heard, because they are extraordinary! And because I own the soundtrack and the film, I can watch this movie and listen to the songs at any time that I feel like doing it! I don't regret seeing this movie, because it blew me away! So all in all, this is another movie that scores a ten out of ten on my scale! If you haven't seen this movie yet, see it, because like I was, you are going to be blown away! I am not joking with you, this movie really is that great of a film, I mean that it is something that you are going to love from the very minute that you start watching it! Mark my words: You've got to watch this movie, it is totally and completely fabulous and extraordinary! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do that thing I do!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sukhitha Jayathilake
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Huge cast. Many popular stars today maybe at the start of their carrier. Liv Tylor and Charlice Theron. OMG they literally look like dolls. Specially Charlice. And two of my favorites, Steve Zahn and Giovanni Ribisi. It's a movie about a small town band trying to make it out in the big time. Well It's just a simple journey every band has to go through so to speak. Basically as I see it It's all just four guys playing there only hit single throughout the movie like a thousand times? Does tend to make you sick even! The reason I don't get that much of a kick out of this movie is maybe because I'm not 50. People tom Hanks' age must get to drive down the memory lane watching this one. Too bad I can't feel it. Well BTW If you think about it, This movie is pretty gay. The modern equivalent to this movie would be a movie about the Jonas brothers. Only they are still popular. But Still Liv Tyler makes it watchable. I wanted to see more Charlice Theron. She must have been an amateur then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun musical romp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have said, it's an homage to a simpler time. Love the small visual nods to "A Hard Day's Night" with the boys running through the simulation of the states. Also the hint of the same thing that happened to Lennon with the 'he's engaged' posting on the monitor. Of course, Lennon was actually engaged, if not already married! I truly don't get tired of this film. Just a feel-good movie. Also liked everything I read about how Hanks insisted that the actors learn to play their instruments well enough to look good in the film. Some of them practiced several hours a day. It's fun to see his wife pop in as a waitress where there's good jazz. Such a seemingly fun woman - but what else would you expect from Tom Hanks' wife? No, it didn't win any awards. But it's a 'keeper'. Watch it. Such fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nostalgic look back at the 1960s, when I was a beginning college student.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this movie a number of years ago but didn't remember much about it, so I saw it again today on DVD from my public library. I was a college Freshman in 1963/64, when the Beatles were first gaining popularity on this side of the pond, and this movie fairly accurately recreates that period, the way people dressed, and how teenagers reacted when seeing their pop idols live in concert. The story grabs hold of a theme I am very fond of pondering, both in real life and in fiction stories. That theme is the relative randomness of our lives, the things that happen, and then how we react to those random events. If we look at random events in our own lives, we can see how certain unexpected things shaped who we are today. In this movie a group of high school friends like to make music, one of them writes songs and is the featured singer. He has written "That Thing You Do" and they are about to perform it in a local small-potatoes contest. But the drummer, horsing around by showing the bass player how to jump over parking meters, falls and breaks his arm right before the contest. Now that is the "random event", and it leads them to ask another guy in town, who is a good drummer, to sit in for that one gig, so that they will still have a chance to win the competition. Then comes the rest of the influence of that "random event", the drummer own his own (this is important) decides to beat out a much faster tempo. It is this faster tempo that makes "That Thing You Do" a hit with the audience, attracts the attention of an agent, gets them a record, gets them a contract, puts them on tour, and has their hit rise towards the top of the charts. If their original drummer had not broken his arm, they would have just remained an ordinary band. Well as the story progresses they experience all the growing pains of sudden fame, and conflicting priorities among the members of the group. Tom Hanks directed, has a part as a record label agent, and he even wrote many of the songs. Tom Everett Scott who was in his mid-20s is very good as the replacement drummer, Guy Patterson. Liv Tyler, still a teenager was Faye Dolan who ended up traveling with the band. Her boyfriend was Johnathon Schaech as Jimmy who wrote the song and sang lead vocals. Steve Zahn was the crazy member Lenny, and Ethan Embry, also a teenager, was T. B. Player the unreliable bass player. Another teenager just starting her career was Charlize Theron as Tina in a fairly small part, as a flaky girlfriend who dumps Guy after an appointment with a handsome dentist. Plus young Giovanni Ribisi as Chad , the original drummer who breaks his arm. All in all a fairly pleasant movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You've heard of the "Jersey Boys", Well, here come the "Erie Boys!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yay! Somebody made a movie set in my home town! Historically made famous by early American battles in the infancy of our country, Erie PA is also famous for where a certain overweight US President got stuck in a bathtub, and where a comic named Bob Hope wed his lovely bride, Delores. But for Tom Hanks (here the filmmaker in addition to actor), he uses Erie as the setting for a boy's band which suddenly rises to fame and go through all of the stereotypical star-making egos where many lessons are learned. Fans of 60's rock music will love this for its accurate description of the times, through the music, fashions, beehive hairdo's and those crazy home decors usually found in the old Green Stamps catalogs. Erie residents may not recognize State Street in the few street scenes (with the exception of the still standing facade of the old Boston Store), but mentions of Mercyhurst College and radio/TV station WJET (their ABC affiliate-Channel 24 during my youth), plus constant reminders as the boys go on the road that they are Erie natives, the film becomes a hallmark card to a beautiful city that sometimes takes a ribbing but in truth is actually one of the top tourist attractions in Pennsylvania. Hanks gives an enthusiastic performance as the manager of the band who is determined to rise them to fame. If Detroit can have their Dreamgirls, then Erie is more than allowed to have their Laker Boys! While the real 1960's produced a lot of schlocky rock & roll movies (mainly through some Sam Katzman produced musicals made at Columbia studios or those silly American International Frankie/Annette "Beach Party" movies), this is a loving salute to all the glitz from the movies and television shows of this era, with a bit of "Bye Bye Birdie" and "Hairspray" thrown in. As for the energetic title song, I really was shocked to learn that it was written for the movie, not an actual hit from that era.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stands the test of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie no matters how many times you've seen it always remains an enjoyable movie to watch with some great actors. Tom Hanks definitely makes a great showing in his directorial debut. The story focuses on a local Scranton, PA band that goes from obscurity to being a fast rising band. When the original drummer of the band hurts his hand before playing a gig they bring in Guy to replace him and his participation in the band changes the trajectory of the band. Eventually they get signed to Tom Hanks character who works for a big label called Playtone Records. Things are going good for a bit touring the country doing concerts. But then they get called to Hollywood and end up doing a bunch of pointless appearances. After awhile tension builds in the band and they end up breaking up, ultimately the band ends up being nothing more then a 1 hit wonder.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The O-Needers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That Thing You Do! Is written and directed by Tom Hanks who also co-stars with Tom Everett Scott, Liv Tyler, Steve Zahn, Johnathon Schaech and Ethan Embry. Film is set in the summer of 1964 and tells of the story of American one hit wonder band, The Wonders. Who after scoring big with their catchy debut single That Thing That You Do, hope to blaze the hits trail like the British Beatles. But with success comes lifestyle changes, and inevitably cracks start to appear in the group dynamic. Utterly charming in places, and propelled by an irritatingly catchy theme tune, Tom Hanks' directing debut is enjoyable while it's on, if ultimately it's very predictable fare. It lacks bite for the dramatic threads, but the characterisations are strong, the period detail is spot on (Hanks clearly utilising his memory banks) and there's nothing to complain about in the acting. However, the trajectory of the story stays on such a safe formulaic road, with not a snippet of villainy or hardship to be found, that it's hard to genuinely root for this band to succeed. We like them, we like their song, but it's all made so easy for them, while there's also a distinct lack of humour to be found along the way. When the band starts to implode, ask yourself if you really care or not? Safe is the key word, Hanks has played it safe, it's inoffensive stuff and impossible to dislike, and there should be the odd tingle of warmth coursing through your body. But you have to be in a safe sort of mood to forgive it its lack of guts, or at the very least, adventure. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bravo, Tom Hanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie doesn't so much have a plot as a trajectory. Nevertheless, it is better to see it yourself than to know where it is going. Suffice it to say that it is about a rock band, and how its members, friends and family respond to its success. As such, it is in the slice-of-life genre. Given its nearly 2 and a half hour length on the directors cut that I saw, and recommend, it works remarkably well. After awhile, I wondered if something would happen, some disaster or twist of fate, some bad guy to thicken the plot, and noticed the movie was rather long. But I wasn't bored at all, and was enjoying seeing the story unfold. In the end, the length was just right. Also, I am not a rock fan, so I was a bit skeptical. It didn't matter. In the wrong hands, this could have turned into Partridge Family cornball. But it is solid. To all this, Tom Hanks deserves the credit as writer, director, and low- key star, who appears late in the movie. It's a first class job. Not an earth shaking masterpiece, but a well-crafted, thoroughly enjoyable movie. I am a stickler for anachronisms in movies like this. This is a period piece set in Erie, Pennsylvania, circa 1964. The Sixties was a fluid time, where the culture changed every two years; 1964 was different from 1960, 1962, 1966 and 1968. The fact that one of the band members enlists in the Marines, without any mention of Vietnam, is a good measure of the mood and innocence of 1964, versus 1966, when the war had become politicized. America was at its best around this time, and it was all downhill from there. The movie captured the spirit of this window of time. Tom Hanks was 8 at the time, so he could not rely solely on memory, and must have done some historical research to fully understand the period. Whoever was in charge of props did a fantastic job of assembling lots of appliances, radios, recording gear and lots of cars. This is a movie that got it right. I loved when Skitch handed out pocket transistor radios to everyone in the band - back then an AM radio would have cost about $10 to $15, very expensive at the time, about $50 or more in today's dollars. The only anachronism I found was when Skitch tells a customer the appliance is available in avocado. Avocado was a notoriously common kitchen appliance color in the 1970s; I see it was introduced by GE in 1966, but became a tidal wave around 1968-1970. It was one of those fashion things, a late Dating Game chic, when all of a sudden everything was avocado green (or harvest gold), color coordinated so people could have an entire kitchen of avocado, lucky you!. And then avocado, predictably, disappeared. I found a post, "The Death of Avocado" that observed it was a mistake to put a trendy color on a long-life appliance, which looked obnoxious after coordinating avocado room decor disappeared. No kidding. I was just a kid at the time, but I could see that coming. See how sensitive the cultural timeline is for the Sixties? Actually, I would say what most people think of as the Sixties began around 1963-64, with the Beatles and the period of this film, and lasted till Nixon's resignation in 1974 (although some place the beginning of change at 1959). After that, the years unfolded in a homogeneous miasma, distinguished mainly by the gradual introduction of new technology, like the VCR, the Walkman and cordless phone sizes. That an appliance color was the only missed stitch in the movie indicates just how good it was! The acting all round was excellent. There were no caricatures, even with the doorman at the LA hotel, who had some real depth to his role. And, although I read here there were pro musicians actually dubbing the music, the actors were totally convincing that they were the ones making the music. "That Thing You Do" fits most closely the mold of "Breaking Away," which also featured a cast of talented young actors, and a skeptical, practical father representing the secure, dull path. Both are about life, dreams and fallibility. They both offer a lesson for young people. And in both, in the end, they turn a corner and life goes on. This is an enjoyable, memorable and thoughtful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny seize the day and forget about the rest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr Jacques COULARDEAU
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a comedy about real young people from the Rock 'n Roll planet in the early 1960s. It's funny but also typically American. There are so many sharks going around looking for young teenage would-be rock stars that it is impossible not to be noticed by one, one day, not to become some one overnight and not to dissolved as soon as the top is reached. To stay at the top is really difficult. A band in those days, and in the USA, was the normal way for anyone who wanted to do some music on the stage to go around but bands did not last long. Everyone is not the Beatles or the Rolling Stones, you know. This is the story of the short-lived Wonders and yet the four boys and the one girl who were there at the first public appearance in the boonies, all eventually did something with their skin and their brains, if they had any, both skin and brains. Today that adventure still exists in the USA but it has also taken names like Myspace music, Youtube, Daily Motion and some others. Permanence of course is nothing in that business in 99% of the cases, but chance is also essential for those who have something in their veins. A career is often 50% talent and 50% chance, some would say opportunity. But the film is funny, though so banal that it should be a warning to anyone who wants to imitate these young teenagers. As the old Paxton would say: look after your money, women and a few other things of that type. Yesterday is a sure thing that existed but tomorrow is as brittle as an egg shell in front of a bulldozer. And the world is full of bulldozers crushing many eggshells down into the ground and powder. Dust to dust mind you. Dr Jacques COULARDEAU, University Paris 1 Pantheon Sorbonne, University Paris 8 Saint Denis, University Paris 12 Cr&eacute;teil, CEGID
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breezy period piece wrapped around a catchy song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this movie advertised in the theaters back in 1996, I rolled my eyes in great disdain. For one thing the advertising banner - "In every life there comes a time when that dream you dream becomes that thing you do" hit me the wrong way. After all, 95% of us never wind up doing the dream we dream...there is no WHEN in our lives for this event. Plus, I just figured it was an attempt by Tom Hanks to go highbrow via a directorial debut after those back-to-back Academy Awards. When I finally got around to seeing the film I really loved it. The first half is very upbeat as the band gets started out. They truly are the "One-ders", just like many other bands of the Beatles' transitional era. They wrote and performed one song that got them national attention, and then couldn't follow up with anything else. That's too bad, because the band does get one lucky break after another at the start. The guy in the camper that shoves a bowl of stew and a contract in front of them and tells them to "trust me" could have had them signing anything. They got lucky that he was legitimate and really did intend to get the record on the air and not steal it from them. That's what makes the disintegration of the band at the end so sad. One by one, they just walk away from their dream. To me, if the movie had any flaw, it was this - the band members just acted like the whole thing was one big amusement park ride rather than a once-in-a-lifetime life changing opportunity. Finally, I also loved all of the authentic looking stage designs. The home appliance store really brought back memories. These type of family owned appliance stores were all over the place back in the 1960's before the big box stores gradually made them extinct. Plus, the appliances being sold looked just like what was available in 1964 right down to the brand names and the styles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ingenious! One Of The Best Movies Of 1996!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie only a few years ago, and I can say that I was not disappointed in any way, shape, or form! In my point of view, this is ingenious! I remember that when I was done watching this movie for the first time, I just wanted to watch it all over again, because I just plain loved it! I mean that I loved this movie, and when I mean that I loved it, I loved it! This movie is honestly one of the best movies of the 1990's, as well as one of the best movies of 1996! This movie is totally and completely remarkable from beginning to end, from the very beginning of this movie to the very end of this movie, it is totally and completely remarkable! I honestly have nothing to say about this movie that is against it, because I was not disappointed with it at all! And once more, I thought that this movie was perfect, not only as a musical movie, but as a movie movie! This is also another movie that is a must see, because it just can't get any better than this, not kidding, it really can't get any better! While I loved the movie as a whole, I especially loved the songs and the music! In fact, I own the soundtrack to this film, as well as the film itself! This movie has got some of the best songs of any film that I have honestly ever heard, because they are extraordinary! And because I own the soundtrack and the film, I can watch this movie and listen to the songs at any time that I feel like doing it! I don't regret seeing this movie, because it blew me away! So all in all, this is another movie that scores a ten out of ten on my scale! If you haven't seen this movie yet, see it, because like I was, you are going to be blown away! I am not joking with you, this movie really is that great of a film, I mean that it is something that you are going to love from the very minute that you start watching it! Mark my words: You've got to watch this movie, it is totally and completely fabulous and extraordinary! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do that thing I do!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sukhitha Jayathilake
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Huge cast. Many popular stars today maybe at the start of their carrier. Liv Tylor and Charlice Theron. OMG they literally look like dolls. Specially Charlice. And two of my favorites, Steve Zahn and Giovanni Ribisi. It's a movie about a small town band trying to make it out in the big time. Well It's just a simple journey every band has to go through so to speak. Basically as I see it It's all just four guys playing there only hit single throughout the movie like a thousand times? Does tend to make you sick even! The reason I don't get that much of a kick out of this movie is maybe because I'm not 50. People tom Hanks' age must get to drive down the memory lane watching this one. Too bad I can't feel it. Well BTW If you think about it, This movie is pretty gay. The modern equivalent to this movie would be a movie about the Jonas brothers. Only they are still popular. But Still Liv Tyler makes it watchable. I wanted to see more Charlice Theron. She must have been an amateur then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun musical romp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have said, it's an homage to a simpler time. Love the small visual nods to "A Hard Day's Night" with the boys running through the simulation of the states. Also the hint of the same thing that happened to Lennon with the 'he's engaged' posting on the monitor. Of course, Lennon was actually engaged, if not already married! I truly don't get tired of this film. Just a feel-good movie. Also liked everything I read about how Hanks insisted that the actors learn to play their instruments well enough to look good in the film. Some of them practiced several hours a day. It's fun to see his wife pop in as a waitress where there's good jazz. Such a seemingly fun woman - but what else would you expect from Tom Hanks' wife? No, it didn't win any awards. But it's a 'keeper'. Watch it. Such fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nostalgic look back at the 1960s, when I was a beginning college student.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this movie a number of years ago but didn't remember much about it, so I saw it again today on DVD from my public library. I was a college Freshman in 1963/64, when the Beatles were first gaining popularity on this side of the pond, and this movie fairly accurately recreates that period, the way people dressed, and how teenagers reacted when seeing their pop idols live in concert. The story grabs hold of a theme I am very fond of pondering, both in real life and in fiction stories. That theme is the relative randomness of our lives, the things that happen, and then how we react to those random events. If we look at random events in our own lives, we can see how certain unexpected things shaped who we are today. In this movie a group of high school friends like to make music, one of them writes songs and is the featured singer. He has written "That Thing You Do" and they are about to perform it in a local small-potatoes contest. But the drummer, horsing around by showing the bass player how to jump over parking meters, falls and breaks his arm right before the contest. Now that is the "random event", and it leads them to ask another guy in town, who is a good drummer, to sit in for that one gig, so that they will still have a chance to win the competition. Then comes the rest of the influence of that "random event", the drummer own his own (this is important) decides to beat out a much faster tempo. It is this faster tempo that makes "That Thing You Do" a hit with the audience, attracts the attention of an agent, gets them a record, gets them a contract, puts them on tour, and has their hit rise towards the top of the charts. If their original drummer had not broken his arm, they would have just remained an ordinary band. Well as the story progresses they experience all the growing pains of sudden fame, and conflicting priorities among the members of the group. Tom Hanks directed, has a part as a record label agent, and he even wrote many of the songs. Tom Everett Scott who was in his mid-20s is very good as the replacement drummer, Guy Patterson. Liv Tyler, still a teenager was Faye Dolan who ended up traveling with the band. Her boyfriend was Johnathon Schaech as Jimmy who wrote the song and sang lead vocals. Steve Zahn was the crazy member Lenny, and Ethan Embry, also a teenager, was T. B. Player the unreliable bass player. Another teenager just starting her career was Charlize Theron as Tina in a fairly small part, as a flaky girlfriend who dumps Guy after an appointment with a handsome dentist. Plus young Giovanni Ribisi as Chad , the original drummer who breaks his arm. All in all a fairly pleasant movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You've heard of the "Jersey Boys", Well, here come the "Erie Boys!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yay! Somebody made a movie set in my home town! Historically made famous by early American battles in the infancy of our country, Erie PA is also famous for where a certain overweight US President got stuck in a bathtub, and where a comic named Bob Hope wed his lovely bride, Delores. But for Tom Hanks (here the filmmaker in addition to actor), he uses Erie as the setting for a boy's band which suddenly rises to fame and go through all of the stereotypical star-making egos where many lessons are learned. Fans of 60's rock music will love this for its accurate description of the times, through the music, fashions, beehive hairdo's and those crazy home decors usually found in the old Green Stamps catalogs. Erie residents may not recognize State Street in the few street scenes (with the exception of the still standing facade of the old Boston Store), but mentions of Mercyhurst College and radio/TV station WJET (their ABC affiliate-Channel 24 during my youth), plus constant reminders as the boys go on the road that they are Erie natives, the film becomes a hallmark card to a beautiful city that sometimes takes a ribbing but in truth is actually one of the top tourist attractions in Pennsylvania. Hanks gives an enthusiastic performance as the manager of the band who is determined to rise them to fame. If Detroit can have their Dreamgirls, then Erie is more than allowed to have their Laker Boys! While the real 1960's produced a lot of schlocky rock & roll movies (mainly through some Sam Katzman produced musicals made at Columbia studios or those silly American International Frankie/Annette "Beach Party" movies), this is a loving salute to all the glitz from the movies and television shows of this era, with a bit of "Bye Bye Birdie" and "Hairspray" thrown in. As for the energetic title song, I really was shocked to learn that it was written for the movie, not an actual hit from that era.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stands the test of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie no matters how many times you've seen it always remains an enjoyable movie to watch with some great actors. Tom Hanks definitely makes a great showing in his directorial debut. The story focuses on a local Scranton, PA band that goes from obscurity to being a fast rising band. When the original drummer of the band hurts his hand before playing a gig they bring in Guy to replace him and his participation in the band changes the trajectory of the band. Eventually they get signed to Tom Hanks character who works for a big label called Playtone Records. Things are going good for a bit touring the country doing concerts. But then they get called to Hollywood and end up doing a bunch of pointless appearances. After awhile tension builds in the band and they end up breaking up, ultimately the band ends up being nothing more then a 1 hit wonder.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The O-Needers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That Thing You Do! Is written and directed by Tom Hanks who also co-stars with Tom Everett Scott, Liv Tyler, Steve Zahn, Johnathon Schaech and Ethan Embry. Film is set in the summer of 1964 and tells of the story of American one hit wonder band, The Wonders. Who after scoring big with their catchy debut single That Thing That You Do, hope to blaze the hits trail like the British Beatles. But with success comes lifestyle changes, and inevitably cracks start to appear in the group dynamic. Utterly charming in places, and propelled by an irritatingly catchy theme tune, Tom Hanks' directing debut is enjoyable while it's on, if ultimately it's very predictable fare. It lacks bite for the dramatic threads, but the characterisations are strong, the period detail is spot on (Hanks clearly utilising his memory banks) and there's nothing to complain about in the acting. However, the trajectory of the story stays on such a safe formulaic road, with not a snippet of villainy or hardship to be found, that it's hard to genuinely root for this band to succeed. We like them, we like their song, but it's all made so easy for them, while there's also a distinct lack of humour to be found along the way. When the band starts to implode, ask yourself if you really care or not? Safe is the key word, Hanks has played it safe, it's inoffensive stuff and impossible to dislike, and there should be the odd tingle of warmth coursing through your body. But you have to be in a safe sort of mood to forgive it its lack of guts, or at the very least, adventure. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bravo, Tom Hanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie doesn't so much have a plot as a trajectory. Nevertheless, it is better to see it yourself than to know where it is going. Suffice it to say that it is about a rock band, and how its members, friends and family respond to its success. As such, it is in the slice-of-life genre. Given its nearly 2 and a half hour length on the directors cut that I saw, and recommend, it works remarkably well. After awhile, I wondered if something would happen, some disaster or twist of fate, some bad guy to thicken the plot, and noticed the movie was rather long. But I wasn't bored at all, and was enjoying seeing the story unfold. In the end, the length was just right. Also, I am not a rock fan, so I was a bit skeptical. It didn't matter. In the wrong hands, this could have turned into Partridge Family cornball. But it is solid. To all this, Tom Hanks deserves the credit as writer, director, and low- key star, who appears late in the movie. It's a first class job. Not an earth shaking masterpiece, but a well-crafted, thoroughly enjoyable movie. I am a stickler for anachronisms in movies like this. This is a period piece set in Erie, Pennsylvania, circa 1964. The Sixties was a fluid time, where the culture changed every two years; 1964 was different from 1960, 1962, 1966 and 1968. The fact that one of the band members enlists in the Marines, without any mention of Vietnam, is a good measure of the mood and innocence of 1964, versus 1966, when the war had become politicized. America was at its best around this time, and it was all downhill from there. The movie captured the spirit of this window of time. Tom Hanks was 8 at the time, so he could not rely solely on memory, and must have done some historical research to fully understand the period. Whoever was in charge of props did a fantastic job of assembling lots of appliances, radios, recording gear and lots of cars. This is a movie that got it right. I loved when Skitch handed out pocket transistor radios to everyone in the band - back then an AM radio would have cost about $10 to $15, very expensive at the time, about $50 or more in today's dollars. The only anachronism I found was when Skitch tells a customer the appliance is available in avocado. Avocado was a notoriously common kitchen appliance color in the 1970s; I see it was introduced by GE in 1966, but became a tidal wave around 1968-1970. It was one of those fashion things, a late Dating Game chic, when all of a sudden everything was avocado green (or harvest gold), color coordinated so people could have an entire kitchen of avocado, lucky you!. And then avocado, predictably, disappeared. I found a post, "The Death of Avocado" that observed it was a mistake to put a trendy color on a long-life appliance, which looked obnoxious after coordinating avocado room decor disappeared. No kidding. I was just a kid at the time, but I could see that coming. See how sensitive the cultural timeline is for the Sixties? Actually, I would say what most people think of as the Sixties began around 1963-64, with the Beatles and the period of this film, and lasted till Nixon's resignation in 1974 (although some place the beginning of change at 1959). After that, the years unfolded in a homogeneous miasma, distinguished mainly by the gradual introduction of new technology, like the VCR, the Walkman and cordless phone sizes. That an appliance color was the only missed stitch in the movie indicates just how good it was! The acting all round was excellent. There were no caricatures, even with the doorman at the LA hotel, who had some real depth to his role. And, although I read here there were pro musicians actually dubbing the music, the actors were totally convincing that they were the ones making the music. "That Thing You Do" fits most closely the mold of "Breaking Away," which also featured a cast of talented young actors, and a skeptical, practical father representing the secure, dull path. Both are about life, dreams and fallibility. They both offer a lesson for young people. And in both, in the end, they turn a corner and life goes on. This is an enjoyable, memorable and thoughtful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny seize the day and forget about the rest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr Jacques COULARDEAU
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a comedy about real young people from the Rock 'n Roll planet in the early 1960s. It's funny but also typically American. There are so many sharks going around looking for young teenage would-be rock stars that it is impossible not to be noticed by one, one day, not to become some one overnight and not to dissolved as soon as the top is reached. To stay at the top is really difficult. A band in those days, and in the USA, was the normal way for anyone who wanted to do some music on the stage to go around but bands did not last long. Everyone is not the Beatles or the Rolling Stones, you know. This is the story of the short-lived Wonders and yet the four boys and the one girl who were there at the first public appearance in the boonies, all eventually did something with their skin and their brains, if they had any, both skin and brains. Today that adventure still exists in the USA but it has also taken names like Myspace music, Youtube, Daily Motion and some others. Permanence of course is nothing in that business in 99% of the cases, but chance is also essential for those who have something in their veins. A career is often 50% talent and 50% chance, some would say opportunity. But the film is funny, though so banal that it should be a warning to anyone who wants to imitate these young teenagers. As the old Paxton would say: look after your money, women and a few other things of that type. Yesterday is a sure thing that existed but tomorrow is as brittle as an egg shell in front of a bulldozer. And the world is full of bulldozers crushing many eggshells down into the ground and powder. Dust to dust mind you. Dr Jacques COULARDEAU, University Paris 1 Pantheon Sorbonne, University Paris 8 Saint Denis, University Paris 12 Cr&eacute;teil, CEGID
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breezy period piece wrapped around a catchy song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this movie advertised in the theaters back in 1996, I rolled my eyes in great disdain. For one thing the advertising banner - "In every life there comes a time when that dream you dream becomes that thing you do" hit me the wrong way. After all, 95% of us never wind up doing the dream we dream...there is no WHEN in our lives for this event. Plus, I just figured it was an attempt by Tom Hanks to go highbrow via a directorial debut after those back-to-back Academy Awards. When I finally got around to seeing the film I really loved it. The first half is very upbeat as the band gets started out. They truly are the "One-ders", just like many other bands of the Beatles' transitional era. They wrote and performed one song that got them national attention, and then couldn't follow up with anything else. That's too bad, because the band does get one lucky break after another at the start. The guy in the camper that shoves a bowl of stew and a contract in front of them and tells them to "trust me" could have had them signing anything. They got lucky that he was legitimate and really did intend to get the record on the air and not steal it from them. That's what makes the disintegration of the band at the end so sad. One by one, they just walk away from their dream. To me, if the movie had any flaw, it was this - the band members just acted like the whole thing was one big amusement park ride rather than a once-in-a-lifetime life changing opportunity. Finally, I also loved all of the authentic looking stage designs. The home appliance store really brought back memories. These type of family owned appliance stores were all over the place back in the 1960's before the big box stores gradually made them extinct. Plus, the appliances being sold looked just like what was available in 1964 right down to the brand names and the styles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ingenious! One Of The Best Movies Of 1996!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie only a few years ago, and I can say that I was not disappointed in any way, shape, or form! In my point of view, this is ingenious! I remember that when I was done watching this movie for the first time, I just wanted to watch it all over again, because I just plain loved it! I mean that I loved this movie, and when I mean that I loved it, I loved it! This movie is honestly one of the best movies of the 1990's, as well as one of the best movies of 1996! This movie is totally and completely remarkable from beginning to end, from the very beginning of this movie to the very end of this movie, it is totally and completely remarkable! I honestly have nothing to say about this movie that is against it, because I was not disappointed with it at all! And once more, I thought that this movie was perfect, not only as a musical movie, but as a movie movie! This is also another movie that is a must see, because it just can't get any better than this, not kidding, it really can't get any better! While I loved the movie as a whole, I especially loved the songs and the music! In fact, I own the soundtrack to this film, as well as the film itself! This movie has got some of the best songs of any film that I have honestly ever heard, because they are extraordinary! And because I own the soundtrack and the film, I can watch this movie and listen to the songs at any time that I feel like doing it! I don't regret seeing this movie, because it blew me away! So all in all, this is another movie that scores a ten out of ten on my scale! If you haven't seen this movie yet, see it, because like I was, you are going to be blown away! I am not joking with you, this movie really is that great of a film, I mean that it is something that you are going to love from the very minute that you start watching it! Mark my words: You've got to watch this movie, it is totally and completely fabulous and extraordinary! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do that thing I do!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sukhitha Jayathilake
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Huge cast. Many popular stars today maybe at the start of their carrier. Liv Tylor and Charlice Theron. OMG they literally look like dolls. Specially Charlice. And two of my favorites, Steve Zahn and Giovanni Ribisi. It's a movie about a small town band trying to make it out in the big time. Well It's just a simple journey every band has to go through so to speak. Basically as I see it It's all just four guys playing there only hit single throughout the movie like a thousand times? Does tend to make you sick even! The reason I don't get that much of a kick out of this movie is maybe because I'm not 50. People tom Hanks' age must get to drive down the memory lane watching this one. Too bad I can't feel it. Well BTW If you think about it, This movie is pretty gay. The modern equivalent to this movie would be a movie about the Jonas brothers. Only they are still popular. But Still Liv Tyler makes it watchable. I wanted to see more Charlice Theron. She must have been an amateur then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun musical romp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have said, it's an homage to a simpler time. Love the small visual nods to "A Hard Day's Night" with the boys running through the simulation of the states. Also the hint of the same thing that happened to Lennon with the 'he's engaged' posting on the monitor. Of course, Lennon was actually engaged, if not already married! I truly don't get tired of this film. Just a feel-good movie. Also liked everything I read about how Hanks insisted that the actors learn to play their instruments well enough to look good in the film. Some of them practiced several hours a day. It's fun to see his wife pop in as a waitress where there's good jazz. Such a seemingly fun woman - but what else would you expect from Tom Hanks' wife? No, it didn't win any awards. But it's a 'keeper'. Watch it. Such fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nostalgic look back at the 1960s, when I was a beginning college student.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this movie a number of years ago but didn't remember much about it, so I saw it again today on DVD from my public library. I was a college Freshman in 1963/64, when the Beatles were first gaining popularity on this side of the pond, and this movie fairly accurately recreates that period, the way people dressed, and how teenagers reacted when seeing their pop idols live in concert. The story grabs hold of a theme I am very fond of pondering, both in real life and in fiction stories. That theme is the relative randomness of our lives, the things that happen, and then how we react to those random events. If we look at random events in our own lives, we can see how certain unexpected things shaped who we are today. In this movie a group of high school friends like to make music, one of them writes songs and is the featured singer. He has written "That Thing You Do" and they are about to perform it in a local small-potatoes contest. But the drummer, horsing around by showing the bass player how to jump over parking meters, falls and breaks his arm right before the contest. Now that is the "random event", and it leads them to ask another guy in town, who is a good drummer, to sit in for that one gig, so that they will still have a chance to win the competition. Then comes the rest of the influence of that "random event", the drummer own his own (this is important) decides to beat out a much faster tempo. It is this faster tempo that makes "That Thing You Do" a hit with the audience, attracts the attention of an agent, gets them a record, gets them a contract, puts them on tour, and has their hit rise towards the top of the charts. If their original drummer had not broken his arm, they would have just remained an ordinary band. Well as the story progresses they experience all the growing pains of sudden fame, and conflicting priorities among the members of the group. Tom Hanks directed, has a part as a record label agent, and he even wrote many of the songs. Tom Everett Scott who was in his mid-20s is very good as the replacement drummer, Guy Patterson. Liv Tyler, still a teenager was Faye Dolan who ended up traveling with the band. Her boyfriend was Johnathon Schaech as Jimmy who wrote the song and sang lead vocals. Steve Zahn was the crazy member Lenny, and Ethan Embry, also a teenager, was T. B. Player the unreliable bass player. Another teenager just starting her career was Charlize Theron as Tina in a fairly small part, as a flaky girlfriend who dumps Guy after an appointment with a handsome dentist. Plus young Giovanni Ribisi as Chad , the original drummer who breaks his arm. All in all a fairly pleasant movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You've heard of the "Jersey Boys", Well, here come the "Erie Boys!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yay! Somebody made a movie set in my home town! Historically made famous by early American battles in the infancy of our country, Erie PA is also famous for where a certain overweight US President got stuck in a bathtub, and where a comic named Bob Hope wed his lovely bride, Delores. But for Tom Hanks (here the filmmaker in addition to actor), he uses Erie as the setting for a boy's band which suddenly rises to fame and go through all of the stereotypical star-making egos where many lessons are learned. Fans of 60's rock music will love this for its accurate description of the times, through the music, fashions, beehive hairdo's and those crazy home decors usually found in the old Green Stamps catalogs. Erie residents may not recognize State Street in the few street scenes (with the exception of the still standing facade of the old Boston Store), but mentions of Mercyhurst College and radio/TV station WJET (their ABC affiliate-Channel 24 during my youth), plus constant reminders as the boys go on the road that they are Erie natives, the film becomes a hallmark card to a beautiful city that sometimes takes a ribbing but in truth is actually one of the top tourist attractions in Pennsylvania. Hanks gives an enthusiastic performance as the manager of the band who is determined to rise them to fame. If Detroit can have their Dreamgirls, then Erie is more than allowed to have their Laker Boys! While the real 1960's produced a lot of schlocky rock & roll movies (mainly through some Sam Katzman produced musicals made at Columbia studios or those silly American International Frankie/Annette "Beach Party" movies), this is a loving salute to all the glitz from the movies and television shows of this era, with a bit of "Bye Bye Birdie" and "Hairspray" thrown in. As for the energetic title song, I really was shocked to learn that it was written for the movie, not an actual hit from that era.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stands the test of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie no matters how many times you've seen it always remains an enjoyable movie to watch with some great actors. Tom Hanks definitely makes a great showing in his directorial debut. The story focuses on a local Scranton, PA band that goes from obscurity to being a fast rising band. When the original drummer of the band hurts his hand before playing a gig they bring in Guy to replace him and his participation in the band changes the trajectory of the band. Eventually they get signed to Tom Hanks character who works for a big label called Playtone Records. Things are going good for a bit touring the country doing concerts. But then they get called to Hollywood and end up doing a bunch of pointless appearances. After awhile tension builds in the band and they end up breaking up, ultimately the band ends up being nothing more then a 1 hit wonder.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The O-Needers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That Thing You Do! Is written and directed by Tom Hanks who also co-stars with Tom Everett Scott, Liv Tyler, Steve Zahn, Johnathon Schaech and Ethan Embry. Film is set in the summer of 1964 and tells of the story of American one hit wonder band, The Wonders. Who after scoring big with their catchy debut single That Thing That You Do, hope to blaze the hits trail like the British Beatles. But with success comes lifestyle changes, and inevitably cracks start to appear in the group dynamic. Utterly charming in places, and propelled by an irritatingly catchy theme tune, Tom Hanks' directing debut is enjoyable while it's on, if ultimately it's very predictable fare. It lacks bite for the dramatic threads, but the characterisations are strong, the period detail is spot on (Hanks clearly utilising his memory banks) and there's nothing to complain about in the acting. However, the trajectory of the story stays on such a safe formulaic road, with not a snippet of villainy or hardship to be found, that it's hard to genuinely root for this band to succeed. We like them, we like their song, but it's all made so easy for them, while there's also a distinct lack of humour to be found along the way. When the band starts to implode, ask yourself if you really care or not? Safe is the key word, Hanks has played it safe, it's inoffensive stuff and impossible to dislike, and there should be the odd tingle of warmth coursing through your body. But you have to be in a safe sort of mood to forgive it its lack of guts, or at the very least, adventure. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bravo, Tom Hanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie doesn't so much have a plot as a trajectory. Nevertheless, it is better to see it yourself than to know where it is going. Suffice it to say that it is about a rock band, and how its members, friends and family respond to its success. As such, it is in the slice-of-life genre. Given its nearly 2 and a half hour length on the directors cut that I saw, and recommend, it works remarkably well. After awhile, I wondered if something would happen, some disaster or twist of fate, some bad guy to thicken the plot, and noticed the movie was rather long. But I wasn't bored at all, and was enjoying seeing the story unfold. In the end, the length was just right. Also, I am not a rock fan, so I was a bit skeptical. It didn't matter. In the wrong hands, this could have turned into Partridge Family cornball. But it is solid. To all this, Tom Hanks deserves the credit as writer, director, and low- key star, who appears late in the movie. It's a first class job. Not an earth shaking masterpiece, but a well-crafted, thoroughly enjoyable movie. I am a stickler for anachronisms in movies like this. This is a period piece set in Erie, Pennsylvania, circa 1964. The Sixties was a fluid time, where the culture changed every two years; 1964 was different from 1960, 1962, 1966 and 1968. The fact that one of the band members enlists in the Marines, without any mention of Vietnam, is a good measure of the mood and innocence of 1964, versus 1966, when the war had become politicized. America was at its best around this time, and it was all downhill from there. The movie captured the spirit of this window of time. Tom Hanks was 8 at the time, so he could not rely solely on memory, and must have done some historical research to fully understand the period. Whoever was in charge of props did a fantastic job of assembling lots of appliances, radios, recording gear and lots of cars. This is a movie that got it right. I loved when Skitch handed out pocket transistor radios to everyone in the band - back then an AM radio would have cost about $10 to $15, very expensive at the time, about $50 or more in today's dollars. The only anachronism I found was when Skitch tells a customer the appliance is available in avocado. Avocado was a notoriously common kitchen appliance color in the 1970s; I see it was introduced by GE in 1966, but became a tidal wave around 1968-1970. It was one of those fashion things, a late Dating Game chic, when all of a sudden everything was avocado green (or harvest gold), color coordinated so people could have an entire kitchen of avocado, lucky you!. And then avocado, predictably, disappeared. I found a post, "The Death of Avocado" that observed it was a mistake to put a trendy color on a long-life appliance, which looked obnoxious after coordinating avocado room decor disappeared. No kidding. I was just a kid at the time, but I could see that coming. See how sensitive the cultural timeline is for the Sixties? Actually, I would say what most people think of as the Sixties began around 1963-64, with the Beatles and the period of this film, and lasted till Nixon's resignation in 1974 (although some place the beginning of change at 1959). After that, the years unfolded in a homogeneous miasma, distinguished mainly by the gradual introduction of new technology, like the VCR, the Walkman and cordless phone sizes. That an appliance color was the only missed stitch in the movie indicates just how good it was! The acting all round was excellent. There were no caricatures, even with the doorman at the LA hotel, who had some real depth to his role. And, although I read here there were pro musicians actually dubbing the music, the actors were totally convincing that they were the ones making the music. "That Thing You Do" fits most closely the mold of "Breaking Away," which also featured a cast of talented young actors, and a skeptical, practical father representing the secure, dull path. Both are about life, dreams and fallibility. They both offer a lesson for young people. And in both, in the end, they turn a corner and life goes on. This is an enjoyable, memorable and thoughtful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny seize the day and forget about the rest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr Jacques COULARDEAU
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a comedy about real young people from the Rock 'n Roll planet in the early 1960s. It's funny but also typically American. There are so many sharks going around looking for young teenage would-be rock stars that it is impossible not to be noticed by one, one day, not to become some one overnight and not to dissolved as soon as the top is reached. To stay at the top is really difficult. A band in those days, and in the USA, was the normal way for anyone who wanted to do some music on the stage to go around but bands did not last long. Everyone is not the Beatles or the Rolling Stones, you know. This is the story of the short-lived Wonders and yet the four boys and the one girl who were there at the first public appearance in the boonies, all eventually did something with their skin and their brains, if they had any, both skin and brains. Today that adventure still exists in the USA but it has also taken names like Myspace music, Youtube, Daily Motion and some others. Permanence of course is nothing in that business in 99% of the cases, but chance is also essential for those who have something in their veins. A career is often 50% talent and 50% chance, some would say opportunity. But the film is funny, though so banal that it should be a warning to anyone who wants to imitate these young teenagers. As the old Paxton would say: look after your money, women and a few other things of that type. Yesterday is a sure thing that existed but tomorrow is as brittle as an egg shell in front of a bulldozer. And the world is full of bulldozers crushing many eggshells down into the ground and powder. Dust to dust mind you. Dr Jacques COULARDEAU, University Paris 1 Pantheon Sorbonne, University Paris 8 Saint Denis, University Paris 12 Cr&eacute;teil, CEGID
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breezy period piece wrapped around a catchy song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this movie advertised in the theaters back in 1996, I rolled my eyes in great disdain. For one thing the advertising banner - "In every life there comes a time when that dream you dream becomes that thing you do" hit me the wrong way. After all, 95% of us never wind up doing the dream we dream...there is no WHEN in our lives for this event. Plus, I just figured it was an attempt by Tom Hanks to go highbrow via a directorial debut after those back-to-back Academy Awards. When I finally got around to seeing the film I really loved it. The first half is very upbeat as the band gets started out. They truly are the "One-ders", just like many other bands of the Beatles' transitional era. They wrote and performed one song that got them national attention, and then couldn't follow up with anything else. That's too bad, because the band does get one lucky break after another at the start. The guy in the camper that shoves a bowl of stew and a contract in front of them and tells them to "trust me" could have had them signing anything. They got lucky that he was legitimate and really did intend to get the record on the air and not steal it from them. That's what makes the disintegration of the band at the end so sad. One by one, they just walk away from their dream. To me, if the movie had any flaw, it was this - the band members just acted like the whole thing was one big amusement park ride rather than a once-in-a-lifetime life changing opportunity. Finally, I also loved all of the authentic looking stage designs. The home appliance store really brought back memories. These type of family owned appliance stores were all over the place back in the 1960's before the big box stores gradually made them extinct. Plus, the appliances being sold looked just like what was available in 1964 right down to the brand names and the styles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ingenious! One Of The Best Movies Of 1996!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie only a few years ago, and I can say that I was not disappointed in any way, shape, or form! In my point of view, this is ingenious! I remember that when I was done watching this movie for the first time, I just wanted to watch it all over again, because I just plain loved it! I mean that I loved this movie, and when I mean that I loved it, I loved it! This movie is honestly one of the best movies of the 1990's, as well as one of the best movies of 1996! This movie is totally and completely remarkable from beginning to end, from the very beginning of this movie to the very end of this movie, it is totally and completely remarkable! I honestly have nothing to say about this movie that is against it, because I was not disappointed with it at all! And once more, I thought that this movie was perfect, not only as a musical movie, but as a movie movie! This is also another movie that is a must see, because it just can't get any better than this, not kidding, it really can't get any better! While I loved the movie as a whole, I especially loved the songs and the music! In fact, I own the soundtrack to this film, as well as the film itself! This movie has got some of the best songs of any film that I have honestly ever heard, because they are extraordinary! And because I own the soundtrack and the film, I can watch this movie and listen to the songs at any time that I feel like doing it! I don't regret seeing this movie, because it blew me away! So all in all, this is another movie that scores a ten out of ten on my scale! If you haven't seen this movie yet, see it, because like I was, you are going to be blown away! I am not joking with you, this movie really is that great of a film, I mean that it is something that you are going to love from the very minute that you start watching it! Mark my words: You've got to watch this movie, it is totally and completely fabulous and extraordinary! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do that thing I do!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sukhitha Jayathilake
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Huge cast. Many popular stars today maybe at the start of their carrier. Liv Tylor and Charlice Theron. OMG they literally look like dolls. Specially Charlice. And two of my favorites, Steve Zahn and Giovanni Ribisi. It's a movie about a small town band trying to make it out in the big time. Well It's just a simple journey every band has to go through so to speak. Basically as I see it It's all just four guys playing there only hit single throughout the movie like a thousand times? Does tend to make you sick even! The reason I don't get that much of a kick out of this movie is maybe because I'm not 50. People tom Hanks' age must get to drive down the memory lane watching this one. Too bad I can't feel it. Well BTW If you think about it, This movie is pretty gay. The modern equivalent to this movie would be a movie about the Jonas brothers. Only they are still popular. But Still Liv Tyler makes it watchable. I wanted to see more Charlice Theron. She must have been an amateur then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun musical romp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have said, it's an homage to a simpler time. Love the small visual nods to "A Hard Day's Night" with the boys running through the simulation of the states. Also the hint of the same thing that happened to Lennon with the 'he's engaged' posting on the monitor. Of course, Lennon was actually engaged, if not already married! I truly don't get tired of this film. Just a feel-good movie. Also liked everything I read about how Hanks insisted that the actors learn to play their instruments well enough to look good in the film. Some of them practiced several hours a day. It's fun to see his wife pop in as a waitress where there's good jazz. Such a seemingly fun woman - but what else would you expect from Tom Hanks' wife? No, it didn't win any awards. But it's a 'keeper'. Watch it. Such fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nostalgic look back at the 1960s, when I was a beginning college student.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this movie a number of years ago but didn't remember much about it, so I saw it again today on DVD from my public library. I was a college Freshman in 1963/64, when the Beatles were first gaining popularity on this side of the pond, and this movie fairly accurately recreates that period, the way people dressed, and how teenagers reacted when seeing their pop idols live in concert. The story grabs hold of a theme I am very fond of pondering, both in real life and in fiction stories. That theme is the relative randomness of our lives, the things that happen, and then how we react to those random events. If we look at random events in our own lives, we can see how certain unexpected things shaped who we are today. In this movie a group of high school friends like to make music, one of them writes songs and is the featured singer. He has written "That Thing You Do" and they are about to perform it in a local small-potatoes contest. But the drummer, horsing around by showing the bass player how to jump over parking meters, falls and breaks his arm right before the contest. Now that is the "random event", and it leads them to ask another guy in town, who is a good drummer, to sit in for that one gig, so that they will still have a chance to win the competition. Then comes the rest of the influence of that "random event", the drummer own his own (this is important) decides to beat out a much faster tempo. It is this faster tempo that makes "That Thing You Do" a hit with the audience, attracts the attention of an agent, gets them a record, gets them a contract, puts them on tour, and has their hit rise towards the top of the charts. If their original drummer had not broken his arm, they would have just remained an ordinary band. Well as the story progresses they experience all the growing pains of sudden fame, and conflicting priorities among the members of the group. Tom Hanks directed, has a part as a record label agent, and he even wrote many of the songs. Tom Everett Scott who was in his mid-20s is very good as the replacement drummer, Guy Patterson. Liv Tyler, still a teenager was Faye Dolan who ended up traveling with the band. Her boyfriend was Johnathon Schaech as Jimmy who wrote the song and sang lead vocals. Steve Zahn was the crazy member Lenny, and Ethan Embry, also a teenager, was T. B. Player the unreliable bass player. Another teenager just starting her career was Charlize Theron as Tina in a fairly small part, as a flaky girlfriend who dumps Guy after an appointment with a handsome dentist. Plus young Giovanni Ribisi as Chad , the original drummer who breaks his arm. All in all a fairly pleasant movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You've heard of the "Jersey Boys", Well, here come the "Erie Boys!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yay! Somebody made a movie set in my home town! Historically made famous by early American battles in the infancy of our country, Erie PA is also famous for where a certain overweight US President got stuck in a bathtub, and where a comic named Bob Hope wed his lovely bride, Delores. But for Tom Hanks (here the filmmaker in addition to actor), he uses Erie as the setting for a boy's band which suddenly rises to fame and go through all of the stereotypical star-making egos where many lessons are learned. Fans of 60's rock music will love this for its accurate description of the times, through the music, fashions, beehive hairdo's and those crazy home decors usually found in the old Green Stamps catalogs. Erie residents may not recognize State Street in the few street scenes (with the exception of the still standing facade of the old Boston Store), but mentions of Mercyhurst College and radio/TV station WJET (their ABC affiliate-Channel 24 during my youth), plus constant reminders as the boys go on the road that they are Erie natives, the film becomes a hallmark card to a beautiful city that sometimes takes a ribbing but in truth is actually one of the top tourist attractions in Pennsylvania. Hanks gives an enthusiastic performance as the manager of the band who is determined to rise them to fame. If Detroit can have their Dreamgirls, then Erie is more than allowed to have their Laker Boys! While the real 1960's produced a lot of schlocky rock & roll movies (mainly through some Sam Katzman produced musicals made at Columbia studios or those silly American International Frankie/Annette "Beach Party" movies), this is a loving salute to all the glitz from the movies and television shows of this era, with a bit of "Bye Bye Birdie" and "Hairspray" thrown in. As for the energetic title song, I really was shocked to learn that it was written for the movie, not an actual hit from that era.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stands the test of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie no matters how many times you've seen it always remains an enjoyable movie to watch with some great actors. Tom Hanks definitely makes a great showing in his directorial debut. The story focuses on a local Scranton, PA band that goes from obscurity to being a fast rising band. When the original drummer of the band hurts his hand before playing a gig they bring in Guy to replace him and his participation in the band changes the trajectory of the band. Eventually they get signed to Tom Hanks character who works for a big label called Playtone Records. Things are going good for a bit touring the country doing concerts. But then they get called to Hollywood and end up doing a bunch of pointless appearances. After awhile tension builds in the band and they end up breaking up, ultimately the band ends up being nothing more then a 1 hit wonder.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The O-Needers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That Thing You Do! Is written and directed by Tom Hanks who also co-stars with Tom Everett Scott, Liv Tyler, Steve Zahn, Johnathon Schaech and Ethan Embry. Film is set in the summer of 1964 and tells of the story of American one hit wonder band, The Wonders. Who after scoring big with their catchy debut single That Thing That You Do, hope to blaze the hits trail like the British Beatles. But with success comes lifestyle changes, and inevitably cracks start to appear in the group dynamic. Utterly charming in places, and propelled by an irritatingly catchy theme tune, Tom Hanks' directing debut is enjoyable while it's on, if ultimately it's very predictable fare. It lacks bite for the dramatic threads, but the characterisations are strong, the period detail is spot on (Hanks clearly utilising his memory banks) and there's nothing to complain about in the acting. However, the trajectory of the story stays on such a safe formulaic road, with not a snippet of villainy or hardship to be found, that it's hard to genuinely root for this band to succeed. We like them, we like their song, but it's all made so easy for them, while there's also a distinct lack of humour to be found along the way. When the band starts to implode, ask yourself if you really care or not? Safe is the key word, Hanks has played it safe, it's inoffensive stuff and impossible to dislike, and there should be the odd tingle of warmth coursing through your body. But you have to be in a safe sort of mood to forgive it its lack of guts, or at the very least, adventure. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bravo, Tom Hanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie doesn't so much have a plot as a trajectory. Nevertheless, it is better to see it yourself than to know where it is going. Suffice it to say that it is about a rock band, and how its members, friends and family respond to its success. As such, it is in the slice-of-life genre. Given its nearly 2 and a half hour length on the directors cut that I saw, and recommend, it works remarkably well. After awhile, I wondered if something would happen, some disaster or twist of fate, some bad guy to thicken the plot, and noticed the movie was rather long. But I wasn't bored at all, and was enjoying seeing the story unfold. In the end, the length was just right. Also, I am not a rock fan, so I was a bit skeptical. It didn't matter. In the wrong hands, this could have turned into Partridge Family cornball. But it is solid. To all this, Tom Hanks deserves the credit as writer, director, and low- key star, who appears late in the movie. It's a first class job. Not an earth shaking masterpiece, but a well-crafted, thoroughly enjoyable movie. I am a stickler for anachronisms in movies like this. This is a period piece set in Erie, Pennsylvania, circa 1964. The Sixties was a fluid time, where the culture changed every two years; 1964 was different from 1960, 1962, 1966 and 1968. The fact that one of the band members enlists in the Marines, without any mention of Vietnam, is a good measure of the mood and innocence of 1964, versus 1966, when the war had become politicized. America was at its best around this time, and it was all downhill from there. The movie captured the spirit of this window of time. Tom Hanks was 8 at the time, so he could not rely solely on memory, and must have done some historical research to fully understand the period. Whoever was in charge of props did a fantastic job of assembling lots of appliances, radios, recording gear and lots of cars. This is a movie that got it right. I loved when Skitch handed out pocket transistor radios to everyone in the band - back then an AM radio would have cost about $10 to $15, very expensive at the time, about $50 or more in today's dollars. The only anachronism I found was when Skitch tells a customer the appliance is available in avocado. Avocado was a notoriously common kitchen appliance color in the 1970s; I see it was introduced by GE in 1966, but became a tidal wave around 1968-1970. It was one of those fashion things, a late Dating Game chic, when all of a sudden everything was avocado green (or harvest gold), color coordinated so people could have an entire kitchen of avocado, lucky you!. And then avocado, predictably, disappeared. I found a post, "The Death of Avocado" that observed it was a mistake to put a trendy color on a long-life appliance, which looked obnoxious after coordinating avocado room decor disappeared. No kidding. I was just a kid at the time, but I could see that coming. See how sensitive the cultural timeline is for the Sixties? Actually, I would say what most people think of as the Sixties began around 1963-64, with the Beatles and the period of this film, and lasted till Nixon's resignation in 1974 (although some place the beginning of change at 1959). After that, the years unfolded in a homogeneous miasma, distinguished mainly by the gradual introduction of new technology, like the VCR, the Walkman and cordless phone sizes. That an appliance color was the only missed stitch in the movie indicates just how good it was! The acting all round was excellent. There were no caricatures, even with the doorman at the LA hotel, who had some real depth to his role. And, although I read here there were pro musicians actually dubbing the music, the actors were totally convincing that they were the ones making the music. "That Thing You Do" fits most closely the mold of "Breaking Away," which also featured a cast of talented young actors, and a skeptical, practical father representing the secure, dull path. Both are about life, dreams and fallibility. They both offer a lesson for young people. And in both, in the end, they turn a corner and life goes on. This is an enjoyable, memorable and thoughtful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny seize the day and forget about the rest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr Jacques COULARDEAU
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a comedy about real young people from the Rock 'n Roll planet in the early 1960s. It's funny but also typically American. There are so many sharks going around looking for young teenage would-be rock stars that it is impossible not to be noticed by one, one day, not to become some one overnight and not to dissolved as soon as the top is reached. To stay at the top is really difficult. A band in those days, and in the USA, was the normal way for anyone who wanted to do some music on the stage to go around but bands did not last long. Everyone is not the Beatles or the Rolling Stones, you know. This is the story of the short-lived Wonders and yet the four boys and the one girl who were there at the first public appearance in the boonies, all eventually did something with their skin and their brains, if they had any, both skin and brains. Today that adventure still exists in the USA but it has also taken names like Myspace music, Youtube, Daily Motion and some others. Permanence of course is nothing in that business in 99% of the cases, but chance is also essential for those who have something in their veins. A career is often 50% talent and 50% chance, some would say opportunity. But the film is funny, though so banal that it should be a warning to anyone who wants to imitate these young teenagers. As the old Paxton would say: look after your money, women and a few other things of that type. Yesterday is a sure thing that existed but tomorrow is as brittle as an egg shell in front of a bulldozer. And the world is full of bulldozers crushing many eggshells down into the ground and powder. Dust to dust mind you. Dr Jacques COULARDEAU, University Paris 1 Pantheon Sorbonne, University Paris 8 Saint Denis, University Paris 12 Cr&eacute;teil, CEGID
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breezy period piece wrapped around a catchy song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this movie advertised in the theaters back in 1996, I rolled my eyes in great disdain. For one thing the advertising banner - "In every life there comes a time when that dream you dream becomes that thing you do" hit me the wrong way. After all, 95% of us never wind up doing the dream we dream...there is no WHEN in our lives for this event. Plus, I just figured it was an attempt by Tom Hanks to go highbrow via a directorial debut after those back-to-back Academy Awards. When I finally got around to seeing the film I really loved it. The first half is very upbeat as the band gets started out. They truly are the "One-ders", just like many other bands of the Beatles' transitional era. They wrote and performed one song that got them national attention, and then couldn't follow up with anything else. That's too bad, because the band does get one lucky break after another at the start. The guy in the camper that shoves a bowl of stew and a contract in front of them and tells them to "trust me" could have had them signing anything. They got lucky that he was legitimate and really did intend to get the record on the air and not steal it from them. That's what makes the disintegration of the band at the end so sad. One by one, they just walk away from their dream. To me, if the movie had any flaw, it was this - the band members just acted like the whole thing was one big amusement park ride rather than a once-in-a-lifetime life changing opportunity. Finally, I also loved all of the authentic looking stage designs. The home appliance store really brought back memories. These type of family owned appliance stores were all over the place back in the 1960's before the big box stores gradually made them extinct. Plus, the appliances being sold looked just like what was available in 1964 right down to the brand names and the styles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ingenious! One Of The Best Movies Of 1996!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie only a few years ago, and I can say that I was not disappointed in any way, shape, or form! In my point of view, this is ingenious! I remember that when I was done watching this movie for the first time, I just wanted to watch it all over again, because I just plain loved it! I mean that I loved this movie, and when I mean that I loved it, I loved it! This movie is honestly one of the best movies of the 1990's, as well as one of the best movies of 1996! This movie is totally and completely remarkable from beginning to end, from the very beginning of this movie to the very end of this movie, it is totally and completely remarkable! I honestly have nothing to say about this movie that is against it, because I was not disappointed with it at all! And once more, I thought that this movie was perfect, not only as a musical movie, but as a movie movie! This is also another movie that is a must see, because it just can't get any better than this, not kidding, it really can't get any better! While I loved the movie as a whole, I especially loved the songs and the music! In fact, I own the soundtrack to this film, as well as the film itself! This movie has got some of the best songs of any film that I have honestly ever heard, because they are extraordinary! And because I own the soundtrack and the film, I can watch this movie and listen to the songs at any time that I feel like doing it! I don't regret seeing this movie, because it blew me away! So all in all, this is another movie that scores a ten out of ten on my scale! If you haven't seen this movie yet, see it, because like I was, you are going to be blown away! I am not joking with you, this movie really is that great of a film, I mean that it is something that you are going to love from the very minute that you start watching it! Mark my words: You've got to watch this movie, it is totally and completely fabulous and extraordinary! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do that thing I do!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sukhitha Jayathilake
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Huge cast. Many popular stars today maybe at the start of their carrier. Liv Tylor and Charlice Theron. OMG they literally look like dolls. Specially Charlice. And two of my favorites, Steve Zahn and Giovanni Ribisi. It's a movie about a small town band trying to make it out in the big time. Well It's just a simple journey every band has to go through so to speak. Basically as I see it It's all just four guys playing there only hit single throughout the movie like a thousand times? Does tend to make you sick even! The reason I don't get that much of a kick out of this movie is maybe because I'm not 50. People tom Hanks' age must get to drive down the memory lane watching this one. Too bad I can't feel it. Well BTW If you think about it, This movie is pretty gay. The modern equivalent to this movie would be a movie about the Jonas brothers. Only they are still popular. But Still Liv Tyler makes it watchable. I wanted to see more Charlice Theron. She must have been an amateur then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun musical romp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have said, it's an homage to a simpler time. Love the small visual nods to "A Hard Day's Night" with the boys running through the simulation of the states. Also the hint of the same thing that happened to Lennon with the 'he's engaged' posting on the monitor. Of course, Lennon was actually engaged, if not already married! I truly don't get tired of this film. Just a feel-good movie. Also liked everything I read about how Hanks insisted that the actors learn to play their instruments well enough to look good in the film. Some of them practiced several hours a day. It's fun to see his wife pop in as a waitress where there's good jazz. Such a seemingly fun woman - but what else would you expect from Tom Hanks' wife? No, it didn't win any awards. But it's a 'keeper'. Watch it. Such fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nostalgic look back at the 1960s, when I was a beginning college student.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this movie a number of years ago but didn't remember much about it, so I saw it again today on DVD from my public library. I was a college Freshman in 1963/64, when the Beatles were first gaining popularity on this side of the pond, and this movie fairly accurately recreates that period, the way people dressed, and how teenagers reacted when seeing their pop idols live in concert. The story grabs hold of a theme I am very fond of pondering, both in real life and in fiction stories. That theme is the relative randomness of our lives, the things that happen, and then how we react to those random events. If we look at random events in our own lives, we can see how certain unexpected things shaped who we are today. In this movie a group of high school friends like to make music, one of them writes songs and is the featured singer. He has written "That Thing You Do" and they are about to perform it in a local small-potatoes contest. But the drummer, horsing around by showing the bass player how to jump over parking meters, falls and breaks his arm right before the contest. Now that is the "random event", and it leads them to ask another guy in town, who is a good drummer, to sit in for that one gig, so that they will still have a chance to win the competition. Then comes the rest of the influence of that "random event", the drummer own his own (this is important) decides to beat out a much faster tempo. It is this faster tempo that makes "That Thing You Do" a hit with the audience, attracts the attention of an agent, gets them a record, gets them a contract, puts them on tour, and has their hit rise towards the top of the charts. If their original drummer had not broken his arm, they would have just remained an ordinary band. Well as the story progresses they experience all the growing pains of sudden fame, and conflicting priorities among the members of the group. Tom Hanks directed, has a part as a record label agent, and he even wrote many of the songs. Tom Everett Scott who was in his mid-20s is very good as the replacement drummer, Guy Patterson. Liv Tyler, still a teenager was Faye Dolan who ended up traveling with the band. Her boyfriend was Johnathon Schaech as Jimmy who wrote the song and sang lead vocals. Steve Zahn was the crazy member Lenny, and Ethan Embry, also a teenager, was T. B. Player the unreliable bass player. Another teenager just starting her career was Charlize Theron as Tina in a fairly small part, as a flaky girlfriend who dumps Guy after an appointment with a handsome dentist. Plus young Giovanni Ribisi as Chad , the original drummer who breaks his arm. All in all a fairly pleasant movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You've heard of the "Jersey Boys", Well, here come the "Erie Boys!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yay! Somebody made a movie set in my home town! Historically made famous by early American battles in the infancy of our country, Erie PA is also famous for where a certain overweight US President got stuck in a bathtub, and where a comic named Bob Hope wed his lovely bride, Delores. But for Tom Hanks (here the filmmaker in addition to actor), he uses Erie as the setting for a boy's band which suddenly rises to fame and go through all of the stereotypical star-making egos where many lessons are learned. Fans of 60's rock music will love this for its accurate description of the times, through the music, fashions, beehive hairdo's and those crazy home decors usually found in the old Green Stamps catalogs. Erie residents may not recognize State Street in the few street scenes (with the exception of the still standing facade of the old Boston Store), but mentions of Mercyhurst College and radio/TV station WJET (their ABC affiliate-Channel 24 during my youth), plus constant reminders as the boys go on the road that they are Erie natives, the film becomes a hallmark card to a beautiful city that sometimes takes a ribbing but in truth is actually one of the top tourist attractions in Pennsylvania. Hanks gives an enthusiastic performance as the manager of the band who is determined to rise them to fame. If Detroit can have their Dreamgirls, then Erie is more than allowed to have their Laker Boys! While the real 1960's produced a lot of schlocky rock & roll movies (mainly through some Sam Katzman produced musicals made at Columbia studios or those silly American International Frankie/Annette "Beach Party" movies), this is a loving salute to all the glitz from the movies and television shows of this era, with a bit of "Bye Bye Birdie" and "Hairspray" thrown in. As for the energetic title song, I really was shocked to learn that it was written for the movie, not an actual hit from that era.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stands the test of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie no matters how many times you've seen it always remains an enjoyable movie to watch with some great actors. Tom Hanks definitely makes a great showing in his directorial debut. The story focuses on a local Scranton, PA band that goes from obscurity to being a fast rising band. When the original drummer of the band hurts his hand before playing a gig they bring in Guy to replace him and his participation in the band changes the trajectory of the band. Eventually they get signed to Tom Hanks character who works for a big label called Playtone Records. Things are going good for a bit touring the country doing concerts. But then they get called to Hollywood and end up doing a bunch of pointless appearances. After awhile tension builds in the band and they end up breaking up, ultimately the band ends up being nothing more then a 1 hit wonder.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The O-Needers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That Thing You Do! Is written and directed by Tom Hanks who also co-stars with Tom Everett Scott, Liv Tyler, Steve Zahn, Johnathon Schaech and Ethan Embry. Film is set in the summer of 1964 and tells of the story of American one hit wonder band, The Wonders. Who after scoring big with their catchy debut single That Thing That You Do, hope to blaze the hits trail like the British Beatles. But with success comes lifestyle changes, and inevitably cracks start to appear in the group dynamic. Utterly charming in places, and propelled by an irritatingly catchy theme tune, Tom Hanks' directing debut is enjoyable while it's on, if ultimately it's very predictable fare. It lacks bite for the dramatic threads, but the characterisations are strong, the period detail is spot on (Hanks clearly utilising his memory banks) and there's nothing to complain about in the acting. However, the trajectory of the story stays on such a safe formulaic road, with not a snippet of villainy or hardship to be found, that it's hard to genuinely root for this band to succeed. We like them, we like their song, but it's all made so easy for them, while there's also a distinct lack of humour to be found along the way. When the band starts to implode, ask yourself if you really care or not? Safe is the key word, Hanks has played it safe, it's inoffensive stuff and impossible to dislike, and there should be the odd tingle of warmth coursing through your body. But you have to be in a safe sort of mood to forgive it its lack of guts, or at the very least, adventure. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bravo, Tom Hanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie doesn't so much have a plot as a trajectory. Nevertheless, it is better to see it yourself than to know where it is going. Suffice it to say that it is about a rock band, and how its members, friends and family respond to its success. As such, it is in the slice-of-life genre. Given its nearly 2 and a half hour length on the directors cut that I saw, and recommend, it works remarkably well. After awhile, I wondered if something would happen, some disaster or twist of fate, some bad guy to thicken the plot, and noticed the movie was rather long. But I wasn't bored at all, and was enjoying seeing the story unfold. In the end, the length was just right. Also, I am not a rock fan, so I was a bit skeptical. It didn't matter. In the wrong hands, this could have turned into Partridge Family cornball. But it is solid. To all this, Tom Hanks deserves the credit as writer, director, and low- key star, who appears late in the movie. It's a first class job. Not an earth shaking masterpiece, but a well-crafted, thoroughly enjoyable movie. I am a stickler for anachronisms in movies like this. This is a period piece set in Erie, Pennsylvania, circa 1964. The Sixties was a fluid time, where the culture changed every two years; 1964 was different from 1960, 1962, 1966 and 1968. The fact that one of the band members enlists in the Marines, without any mention of Vietnam, is a good measure of the mood and innocence of 1964, versus 1966, when the war had become politicized. America was at its best around this time, and it was all downhill from there. The movie captured the spirit of this window of time. Tom Hanks was 8 at the time, so he could not rely solely on memory, and must have done some historical research to fully understand the period. Whoever was in charge of props did a fantastic job of assembling lots of appliances, radios, recording gear and lots of cars. This is a movie that got it right. I loved when Skitch handed out pocket transistor radios to everyone in the band - back then an AM radio would have cost about $10 to $15, very expensive at the time, about $50 or more in today's dollars. The only anachronism I found was when Skitch tells a customer the appliance is available in avocado. Avocado was a notoriously common kitchen appliance color in the 1970s; I see it was introduced by GE in 1966, but became a tidal wave around 1968-1970. It was one of those fashion things, a late Dating Game chic, when all of a sudden everything was avocado green (or harvest gold), color coordinated so people could have an entire kitchen of avocado, lucky you!. And then avocado, predictably, disappeared. I found a post, "The Death of Avocado" that observed it was a mistake to put a trendy color on a long-life appliance, which looked obnoxious after coordinating avocado room decor disappeared. No kidding. I was just a kid at the time, but I could see that coming. See how sensitive the cultural timeline is for the Sixties? Actually, I would say what most people think of as the Sixties began around 1963-64, with the Beatles and the period of this film, and lasted till Nixon's resignation in 1974 (although some place the beginning of change at 1959). After that, the years unfolded in a homogeneous miasma, distinguished mainly by the gradual introduction of new technology, like the VCR, the Walkman and cordless phone sizes. That an appliance color was the only missed stitch in the movie indicates just how good it was! The acting all round was excellent. There were no caricatures, even with the doorman at the LA hotel, who had some real depth to his role. And, although I read here there were pro musicians actually dubbing the music, the actors were totally convincing that they were the ones making the music. "That Thing You Do" fits most closely the mold of "Breaking Away," which also featured a cast of talented young actors, and a skeptical, practical father representing the secure, dull path. Both are about life, dreams and fallibility. They both offer a lesson for young people. And in both, in the end, they turn a corner and life goes on. This is an enjoyable, memorable and thoughtful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny seize the day and forget about the rest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr Jacques COULARDEAU
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a comedy about real young people from the Rock 'n Roll planet in the early 1960s. It's funny but also typically American. There are so many sharks going around looking for young teenage would-be rock stars that it is impossible not to be noticed by one, one day, not to become some one overnight and not to dissolved as soon as the top is reached. To stay at the top is really difficult. A band in those days, and in the USA, was the normal way for anyone who wanted to do some music on the stage to go around but bands did not last long. Everyone is not the Beatles or the Rolling Stones, you know. This is the story of the short-lived Wonders and yet the four boys and the one girl who were there at the first public appearance in the boonies, all eventually did something with their skin and their brains, if they had any, both skin and brains. Today that adventure still exists in the USA but it has also taken names like Myspace music, Youtube, Daily Motion and some others. Permanence of course is nothing in that business in 99% of the cases, but chance is also essential for those who have something in their veins. A career is often 50% talent and 50% chance, some would say opportunity. But the film is funny, though so banal that it should be a warning to anyone who wants to imitate these young teenagers. As the old Paxton would say: look after your money, women and a few other things of that type. Yesterday is a sure thing that existed but tomorrow is as brittle as an egg shell in front of a bulldozer. And the world is full of bulldozers crushing many eggshells down into the ground and powder. Dust to dust mind you. Dr Jacques COULARDEAU, University Paris 1 Pantheon Sorbonne, University Paris 8 Saint Denis, University Paris 12 Cr&eacute;teil, CEGID
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breezy period piece wrapped around a catchy song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this movie advertised in the theaters back in 1996, I rolled my eyes in great disdain. For one thing the advertising banner - "In every life there comes a time when that dream you dream becomes that thing you do" hit me the wrong way. After all, 95% of us never wind up doing the dream we dream...there is no WHEN in our lives for this event. Plus, I just figured it was an attempt by Tom Hanks to go highbrow via a directorial debut after those back-to-back Academy Awards. When I finally got around to seeing the film I really loved it. The first half is very upbeat as the band gets started out. They truly are the "One-ders", just like many other bands of the Beatles' transitional era. They wrote and performed one song that got them national attention, and then couldn't follow up with anything else. That's too bad, because the band does get one lucky break after another at the start. The guy in the camper that shoves a bowl of stew and a contract in front of them and tells them to "trust me" could have had them signing anything. They got lucky that he was legitimate and really did intend to get the record on the air and not steal it from them. That's what makes the disintegration of the band at the end so sad. One by one, they just walk away from their dream. To me, if the movie had any flaw, it was this - the band members just acted like the whole thing was one big amusement park ride rather than a once-in-a-lifetime life changing opportunity. Finally, I also loved all of the authentic looking stage designs. The home appliance store really brought back memories. These type of family owned appliance stores were all over the place back in the 1960's before the big box stores gradually made them extinct. Plus, the appliances being sold looked just like what was available in 1964 right down to the brand names and the styles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ingenious! One Of The Best Movies Of 1996!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie only a few years ago, and I can say that I was not disappointed in any way, shape, or form! In my point of view, this is ingenious! I remember that when I was done watching this movie for the first time, I just wanted to watch it all over again, because I just plain loved it! I mean that I loved this movie, and when I mean that I loved it, I loved it! This movie is honestly one of the best movies of the 1990's, as well as one of the best movies of 1996! This movie is totally and completely remarkable from beginning to end, from the very beginning of this movie to the very end of this movie, it is totally and completely remarkable! I honestly have nothing to say about this movie that is against it, because I was not disappointed with it at all! And once more, I thought that this movie was perfect, not only as a musical movie, but as a movie movie! This is also another movie that is a must see, because it just can't get any better than this, not kidding, it really can't get any better! While I loved the movie as a whole, I especially loved the songs and the music! In fact, I own the soundtrack to this film, as well as the film itself! This movie has got some of the best songs of any film that I have honestly ever heard, because they are extraordinary! And because I own the soundtrack and the film, I can watch this movie and listen to the songs at any time that I feel like doing it! I don't regret seeing this movie, because it blew me away! So all in all, this is another movie that scores a ten out of ten on my scale! If you haven't seen this movie yet, see it, because like I was, you are going to be blown away! I am not joking with you, this movie really is that great of a film, I mean that it is something that you are going to love from the very minute that you start watching it! Mark my words: You've got to watch this movie, it is totally and completely fabulous and extraordinary! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do that thing I do!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sukhitha Jayathilake
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Huge cast. Many popular stars today maybe at the start of their carrier. Liv Tylor and Charlice Theron. OMG they literally look like dolls. Specially Charlice. And two of my favorites, Steve Zahn and Giovanni Ribisi. It's a movie about a small town band trying to make it out in the big time. Well It's just a simple journey every band has to go through so to speak. Basically as I see it It's all just four guys playing there only hit single throughout the movie like a thousand times? Does tend to make you sick even! The reason I don't get that much of a kick out of this movie is maybe because I'm not 50. People tom Hanks' age must get to drive down the memory lane watching this one. Too bad I can't feel it. Well BTW If you think about it, This movie is pretty gay. The modern equivalent to this movie would be a movie about the Jonas brothers. Only they are still popular. But Still Liv Tyler makes it watchable. I wanted to see more Charlice Theron. She must have been an amateur then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun musical romp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have said, it's an homage to a simpler time. Love the small visual nods to "A Hard Day's Night" with the boys running through the simulation of the states. Also the hint of the same thing that happened to Lennon with the 'he's engaged' posting on the monitor. Of course, Lennon was actually engaged, if not already married! I truly don't get tired of this film. Just a feel-good movie. Also liked everything I read about how Hanks insisted that the actors learn to play their instruments well enough to look good in the film. Some of them practiced several hours a day. It's fun to see his wife pop in as a waitress where there's good jazz. Such a seemingly fun woman - but what else would you expect from Tom Hanks' wife? No, it didn't win any awards. But it's a 'keeper'. Watch it. Such fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nostalgic look back at the 1960s, when I was a beginning college student.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this movie a number of years ago but didn't remember much about it, so I saw it again today on DVD from my public library. I was a college Freshman in 1963/64, when the Beatles were first gaining popularity on this side of the pond, and this movie fairly accurately recreates that period, the way people dressed, and how teenagers reacted when seeing their pop idols live in concert. The story grabs hold of a theme I am very fond of pondering, both in real life and in fiction stories. That theme is the relative randomness of our lives, the things that happen, and then how we react to those random events. If we look at random events in our own lives, we can see how certain unexpected things shaped who we are today. In this movie a group of high school friends like to make music, one of them writes songs and is the featured singer. He has written "That Thing You Do" and they are about to perform it in a local small-potatoes contest. But the drummer, horsing around by showing the bass player how to jump over parking meters, falls and breaks his arm right before the contest. Now that is the "random event", and it leads them to ask another guy in town, who is a good drummer, to sit in for that one gig, so that they will still have a chance to win the competition. Then comes the rest of the influence of that "random event", the drummer own his own (this is important) decides to beat out a much faster tempo. It is this faster tempo that makes "That Thing You Do" a hit with the audience, attracts the attention of an agent, gets them a record, gets them a contract, puts them on tour, and has their hit rise towards the top of the charts. If their original drummer had not broken his arm, they would have just remained an ordinary band. Well as the story progresses they experience all the growing pains of sudden fame, and conflicting priorities among the members of the group. Tom Hanks directed, has a part as a record label agent, and he even wrote many of the songs. Tom Everett Scott who was in his mid-20s is very good as the replacement drummer, Guy Patterson. Liv Tyler, still a teenager was Faye Dolan who ended up traveling with the band. Her boyfriend was Johnathon Schaech as Jimmy who wrote the song and sang lead vocals. Steve Zahn was the crazy member Lenny, and Ethan Embry, also a teenager, was T. B. Player the unreliable bass player. Another teenager just starting her career was Charlize Theron as Tina in a fairly small part, as a flaky girlfriend who dumps Guy after an appointment with a handsome dentist. Plus young Giovanni Ribisi as Chad , the original drummer who breaks his arm. All in all a fairly pleasant movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You've heard of the "Jersey Boys", Well, here come the "Erie Boys!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yay! Somebody made a movie set in my home town! Historically made famous by early American battles in the infancy of our country, Erie PA is also famous for where a certain overweight US President got stuck in a bathtub, and where a comic named Bob Hope wed his lovely bride, Delores. But for Tom Hanks (here the filmmaker in addition to actor), he uses Erie as the setting for a boy's band which suddenly rises to fame and go through all of the stereotypical star-making egos where many lessons are learned. Fans of 60's rock music will love this for its accurate description of the times, through the music, fashions, beehive hairdo's and those crazy home decors usually found in the old Green Stamps catalogs. Erie residents may not recognize State Street in the few street scenes (with the exception of the still standing facade of the old Boston Store), but mentions of Mercyhurst College and radio/TV station WJET (their ABC affiliate-Channel 24 during my youth), plus constant reminders as the boys go on the road that they are Erie natives, the film becomes a hallmark card to a beautiful city that sometimes takes a ribbing but in truth is actually one of the top tourist attractions in Pennsylvania. Hanks gives an enthusiastic performance as the manager of the band who is determined to rise them to fame. If Detroit can have their Dreamgirls, then Erie is more than allowed to have their Laker Boys! While the real 1960's produced a lot of schlocky rock & roll movies (mainly through some Sam Katzman produced musicals made at Columbia studios or those silly American International Frankie/Annette "Beach Party" movies), this is a loving salute to all the glitz from the movies and television shows of this era, with a bit of "Bye Bye Birdie" and "Hairspray" thrown in. As for the energetic title song, I really was shocked to learn that it was written for the movie, not an actual hit from that era.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stands the test of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie no matters how many times you've seen it always remains an enjoyable movie to watch with some great actors. Tom Hanks definitely makes a great showing in his directorial debut. The story focuses on a local Scranton, PA band that goes from obscurity to being a fast rising band. When the original drummer of the band hurts his hand before playing a gig they bring in Guy to replace him and his participation in the band changes the trajectory of the band. Eventually they get signed to Tom Hanks character who works for a big label called Playtone Records. Things are going good for a bit touring the country doing concerts. But then they get called to Hollywood and end up doing a bunch of pointless appearances. After awhile tension builds in the band and they end up breaking up, ultimately the band ends up being nothing more then a 1 hit wonder.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The O-Needers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That Thing You Do! Is written and directed by Tom Hanks who also co-stars with Tom Everett Scott, Liv Tyler, Steve Zahn, Johnathon Schaech and Ethan Embry. Film is set in the summer of 1964 and tells of the story of American one hit wonder band, The Wonders. Who after scoring big with their catchy debut single That Thing That You Do, hope to blaze the hits trail like the British Beatles. But with success comes lifestyle changes, and inevitably cracks start to appear in the group dynamic. Utterly charming in places, and propelled by an irritatingly catchy theme tune, Tom Hanks' directing debut is enjoyable while it's on, if ultimately it's very predictable fare. It lacks bite for the dramatic threads, but the characterisations are strong, the period detail is spot on (Hanks clearly utilising his memory banks) and there's nothing to complain about in the acting. However, the trajectory of the story stays on such a safe formulaic road, with not a snippet of villainy or hardship to be found, that it's hard to genuinely root for this band to succeed. We like them, we like their song, but it's all made so easy for them, while there's also a distinct lack of humour to be found along the way. When the band starts to implode, ask yourself if you really care or not? Safe is the key word, Hanks has played it safe, it's inoffensive stuff and impossible to dislike, and there should be the odd tingle of warmth coursing through your body. But you have to be in a safe sort of mood to forgive it its lack of guts, or at the very least, adventure. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bravo, Tom Hanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie doesn't so much have a plot as a trajectory. Nevertheless, it is better to see it yourself than to know where it is going. Suffice it to say that it is about a rock band, and how its members, friends and family respond to its success. As such, it is in the slice-of-life genre. Given its nearly 2 and a half hour length on the directors cut that I saw, and recommend, it works remarkably well. After awhile, I wondered if something would happen, some disaster or twist of fate, some bad guy to thicken the plot, and noticed the movie was rather long. But I wasn't bored at all, and was enjoying seeing the story unfold. In the end, the length was just right. Also, I am not a rock fan, so I was a bit skeptical. It didn't matter. In the wrong hands, this could have turned into Partridge Family cornball. But it is solid. To all this, Tom Hanks deserves the credit as writer, director, and low- key star, who appears late in the movie. It's a first class job. Not an earth shaking masterpiece, but a well-crafted, thoroughly enjoyable movie. I am a stickler for anachronisms in movies like this. This is a period piece set in Erie, Pennsylvania, circa 1964. The Sixties was a fluid time, where the culture changed every two years; 1964 was different from 1960, 1962, 1966 and 1968. The fact that one of the band members enlists in the Marines, without any mention of Vietnam, is a good measure of the mood and innocence of 1964, versus 1966, when the war had become politicized. America was at its best around this time, and it was all downhill from there. The movie captured the spirit of this window of time. Tom Hanks was 8 at the time, so he could not rely solely on memory, and must have done some historical research to fully understand the period. Whoever was in charge of props did a fantastic job of assembling lots of appliances, radios, recording gear and lots of cars. This is a movie that got it right. I loved when Skitch handed out pocket transistor radios to everyone in the band - back then an AM radio would have cost about $10 to $15, very expensive at the time, about $50 or more in today's dollars. The only anachronism I found was when Skitch tells a customer the appliance is available in avocado. Avocado was a notoriously common kitchen appliance color in the 1970s; I see it was introduced by GE in 1966, but became a tidal wave around 1968-1970. It was one of those fashion things, a late Dating Game chic, when all of a sudden everything was avocado green (or harvest gold), color coordinated so people could have an entire kitchen of avocado, lucky you!. And then avocado, predictably, disappeared. I found a post, "The Death of Avocado" that observed it was a mistake to put a trendy color on a long-life appliance, which looked obnoxious after coordinating avocado room decor disappeared. No kidding. I was just a kid at the time, but I could see that coming. See how sensitive the cultural timeline is for the Sixties? Actually, I would say what most people think of as the Sixties began around 1963-64, with the Beatles and the period of this film, and lasted till Nixon's resignation in 1974 (although some place the beginning of change at 1959). After that, the years unfolded in a homogeneous miasma, distinguished mainly by the gradual introduction of new technology, like the VCR, the Walkman and cordless phone sizes. That an appliance color was the only missed stitch in the movie indicates just how good it was! The acting all round was excellent. There were no caricatures, even with the doorman at the LA hotel, who had some real depth to his role. And, although I read here there were pro musicians actually dubbing the music, the actors were totally convincing that they were the ones making the music. "That Thing You Do" fits most closely the mold of "Breaking Away," which also featured a cast of talented young actors, and a skeptical, practical father representing the secure, dull path. Both are about life, dreams and fallibility. They both offer a lesson for young people. And in both, in the end, they turn a corner and life goes on. This is an enjoyable, memorable and thoughtful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny seize the day and forget about the rest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr Jacques COULARDEAU
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a comedy about real young people from the Rock 'n Roll planet in the early 1960s. It's funny but also typically American. There are so many sharks going around looking for young teenage would-be rock stars that it is impossible not to be noticed by one, one day, not to become some one overnight and not to dissolved as soon as the top is reached. To stay at the top is really difficult. A band in those days, and in the USA, was the normal way for anyone who wanted to do some music on the stage to go around but bands did not last long. Everyone is not the Beatles or the Rolling Stones, you know. This is the story of the short-lived Wonders and yet the four boys and the one girl who were there at the first public appearance in the boonies, all eventually did something with their skin and their brains, if they had any, both skin and brains. Today that adventure still exists in the USA but it has also taken names like Myspace music, Youtube, Daily Motion and some others. Permanence of course is nothing in that business in 99% of the cases, but chance is also essential for those who have something in their veins. A career is often 50% talent and 50% chance, some would say opportunity. But the film is funny, though so banal that it should be a warning to anyone who wants to imitate these young teenagers. As the old Paxton would say: look after your money, women and a few other things of that type. Yesterday is a sure thing that existed but tomorrow is as brittle as an egg shell in front of a bulldozer. And the world is full of bulldozers crushing many eggshells down into the ground and powder. Dust to dust mind you. Dr Jacques COULARDEAU, University Paris 1 Pantheon Sorbonne, University Paris 8 Saint Denis, University Paris 12 Cr&eacute;teil, CEGID
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breezy period piece wrapped around a catchy song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this movie advertised in the theaters back in 1996, I rolled my eyes in great disdain. For one thing the advertising banner - "In every life there comes a time when that dream you dream becomes that thing you do" hit me the wrong way. After all, 95% of us never wind up doing the dream we dream...there is no WHEN in our lives for this event. Plus, I just figured it was an attempt by Tom Hanks to go highbrow via a directorial debut after those back-to-back Academy Awards. When I finally got around to seeing the film I really loved it. The first half is very upbeat as the band gets started out. They truly are the "One-ders", just like many other bands of the Beatles' transitional era. They wrote and performed one song that got them national attention, and then couldn't follow up with anything else. That's too bad, because the band does get one lucky break after another at the start. The guy in the camper that shoves a bowl of stew and a contract in front of them and tells them to "trust me" could have had them signing anything. They got lucky that he was legitimate and really did intend to get the record on the air and not steal it from them. That's what makes the disintegration of the band at the end so sad. One by one, they just walk away from their dream. To me, if the movie had any flaw, it was this - the band members just acted like the whole thing was one big amusement park ride rather than a once-in-a-lifetime life changing opportunity. Finally, I also loved all of the authentic looking stage designs. The home appliance store really brought back memories. These type of family owned appliance stores were all over the place back in the 1960's before the big box stores gradually made them extinct. Plus, the appliances being sold looked just like what was available in 1964 right down to the brand names and the styles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ingenious! One Of The Best Movies Of 1996!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie only a few years ago, and I can say that I was not disappointed in any way, shape, or form! In my point of view, this is ingenious! I remember that when I was done watching this movie for the first time, I just wanted to watch it all over again, because I just plain loved it! I mean that I loved this movie, and when I mean that I loved it, I loved it! This movie is honestly one of the best movies of the 1990's, as well as one of the best movies of 1996! This movie is totally and completely remarkable from beginning to end, from the very beginning of this movie to the very end of this movie, it is totally and completely remarkable! I honestly have nothing to say about this movie that is against it, because I was not disappointed with it at all! And once more, I thought that this movie was perfect, not only as a musical movie, but as a movie movie! This is also another movie that is a must see, because it just can't get any better than this, not kidding, it really can't get any better! While I loved the movie as a whole, I especially loved the songs and the music! In fact, I own the soundtrack to this film, as well as the film itself! This movie has got some of the best songs of any film that I have honestly ever heard, because they are extraordinary! And because I own the soundtrack and the film, I can watch this movie and listen to the songs at any time that I feel like doing it! I don't regret seeing this movie, because it blew me away! So all in all, this is another movie that scores a ten out of ten on my scale! If you haven't seen this movie yet, see it, because like I was, you are going to be blown away! I am not joking with you, this movie really is that great of a film, I mean that it is something that you are going to love from the very minute that you start watching it! Mark my words: You've got to watch this movie, it is totally and completely fabulous and extraordinary! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do that thing I do!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sukhitha Jayathilake
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Huge cast. Many popular stars today maybe at the start of their carrier. Liv Tylor and Charlice Theron. OMG they literally look like dolls. Specially Charlice. And two of my favorites, Steve Zahn and Giovanni Ribisi. It's a movie about a small town band trying to make it out in the big time. Well It's just a simple journey every band has to go through so to speak. Basically as I see it It's all just four guys playing there only hit single throughout the movie like a thousand times? Does tend to make you sick even! The reason I don't get that much of a kick out of this movie is maybe because I'm not 50. People tom Hanks' age must get to drive down the memory lane watching this one. Too bad I can't feel it. Well BTW If you think about it, This movie is pretty gay. The modern equivalent to this movie would be a movie about the Jonas brothers. Only they are still popular. But Still Liv Tyler makes it watchable. I wanted to see more Charlice Theron. She must have been an amateur then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fun musical romp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andreapworth
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As many people have said, it's an homage to a simpler time. Love the small visual nods to "A Hard Day's Night" with the boys running through the simulation of the states. Also the hint of the same thing that happened to Lennon with the 'he's engaged' posting on the monitor. Of course, Lennon was actually engaged, if not already married! I truly don't get tired of this film. Just a feel-good movie. Also liked everything I read about how Hanks insisted that the actors learn to play their instruments well enough to look good in the film. Some of them practiced several hours a day. It's fun to see his wife pop in as a waitress where there's good jazz. Such a seemingly fun woman - but what else would you expect from Tom Hanks' wife? No, it didn't win any awards. But it's a 'keeper'. Watch it. Such fun!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nostalgic look back at the 1960s, when I was a beginning college student.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this movie a number of years ago but didn't remember much about it, so I saw it again today on DVD from my public library. I was a college Freshman in 1963/64, when the Beatles were first gaining popularity on this side of the pond, and this movie fairly accurately recreates that period, the way people dressed, and how teenagers reacted when seeing their pop idols live in concert. The story grabs hold of a theme I am very fond of pondering, both in real life and in fiction stories. That theme is the relative randomness of our lives, the things that happen, and then how we react to those random events. If we look at random events in our own lives, we can see how certain unexpected things shaped who we are today. In this movie a group of high school friends like to make music, one of them writes songs and is the featured singer. He has written "That Thing You Do" and they are about to perform it in a local small-potatoes contest. But the drummer, horsing around by showing the bass player how to jump over parking meters, falls and breaks his arm right before the contest. Now that is the "random event", and it leads them to ask another guy in town, who is a good drummer, to sit in for that one gig, so that they will still have a chance to win the competition. Then comes the rest of the influence of that "random event", the drummer own his own (this is important) decides to beat out a much faster tempo. It is this faster tempo that makes "That Thing You Do" a hit with the audience, attracts the attention of an agent, gets them a record, gets them a contract, puts them on tour, and has their hit rise towards the top of the charts. If their original drummer had not broken his arm, they would have just remained an ordinary band. Well as the story progresses they experience all the growing pains of sudden fame, and conflicting priorities among the members of the group. Tom Hanks directed, has a part as a record label agent, and he even wrote many of the songs. Tom Everett Scott who was in his mid-20s is very good as the replacement drummer, Guy Patterson. Liv Tyler, still a teenager was Faye Dolan who ended up traveling with the band. Her boyfriend was Johnathon Schaech as Jimmy who wrote the song and sang lead vocals. Steve Zahn was the crazy member Lenny, and Ethan Embry, also a teenager, was T. B. Player the unreliable bass player. Another teenager just starting her career was Charlize Theron as Tina in a fairly small part, as a flaky girlfriend who dumps Guy after an appointment with a handsome dentist. Plus young Giovanni Ribisi as Chad , the original drummer who breaks his arm. All in all a fairly pleasant movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You've heard of the "Jersey Boys", Well, here come the "Erie Boys!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yay! Somebody made a movie set in my home town! Historically made famous by early American battles in the infancy of our country, Erie PA is also famous for where a certain overweight US President got stuck in a bathtub, and where a comic named Bob Hope wed his lovely bride, Delores. But for Tom Hanks (here the filmmaker in addition to actor), he uses Erie as the setting for a boy's band which suddenly rises to fame and go through all of the stereotypical star-making egos where many lessons are learned. Fans of 60's rock music will love this for its accurate description of the times, through the music, fashions, beehive hairdo's and those crazy home decors usually found in the old Green Stamps catalogs. Erie residents may not recognize State Street in the few street scenes (with the exception of the still standing facade of the old Boston Store), but mentions of Mercyhurst College and radio/TV station WJET (their ABC affiliate-Channel 24 during my youth), plus constant reminders as the boys go on the road that they are Erie natives, the film becomes a hallmark card to a beautiful city that sometimes takes a ribbing but in truth is actually one of the top tourist attractions in Pennsylvania. Hanks gives an enthusiastic performance as the manager of the band who is determined to rise them to fame. If Detroit can have their Dreamgirls, then Erie is more than allowed to have their Laker Boys! While the real 1960's produced a lot of schlocky rock & roll movies (mainly through some Sam Katzman produced musicals made at Columbia studios or those silly American International Frankie/Annette "Beach Party" movies), this is a loving salute to all the glitz from the movies and television shows of this era, with a bit of "Bye Bye Birdie" and "Hairspray" thrown in. As for the energetic title song, I really was shocked to learn that it was written for the movie, not an actual hit from that era.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stands the test of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie no matters how many times you've seen it always remains an enjoyable movie to watch with some great actors. Tom Hanks definitely makes a great showing in his directorial debut. The story focuses on a local Scranton, PA band that goes from obscurity to being a fast rising band. When the original drummer of the band hurts his hand before playing a gig they bring in Guy to replace him and his participation in the band changes the trajectory of the band. Eventually they get signed to Tom Hanks character who works for a big label called Playtone Records. Things are going good for a bit touring the country doing concerts. But then they get called to Hollywood and end up doing a bunch of pointless appearances. After awhile tension builds in the band and they end up breaking up, ultimately the band ends up being nothing more then a 1 hit wonder.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The O-Needers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That Thing You Do! Is written and directed by Tom Hanks who also co-stars with Tom Everett Scott, Liv Tyler, Steve Zahn, Johnathon Schaech and Ethan Embry. Film is set in the summer of 1964 and tells of the story of American one hit wonder band, The Wonders. Who after scoring big with their catchy debut single That Thing That You Do, hope to blaze the hits trail like the British Beatles. But with success comes lifestyle changes, and inevitably cracks start to appear in the group dynamic. Utterly charming in places, and propelled by an irritatingly catchy theme tune, Tom Hanks' directing debut is enjoyable while it's on, if ultimately it's very predictable fare. It lacks bite for the dramatic threads, but the characterisations are strong, the period detail is spot on (Hanks clearly utilising his memory banks) and there's nothing to complain about in the acting. However, the trajectory of the story stays on such a safe formulaic road, with not a snippet of villainy or hardship to be found, that it's hard to genuinely root for this band to succeed. We like them, we like their song, but it's all made so easy for them, while there's also a distinct lack of humour to be found along the way. When the band starts to implode, ask yourself if you really care or not? Safe is the key word, Hanks has played it safe, it's inoffensive stuff and impossible to dislike, and there should be the odd tingle of warmth coursing through your body. But you have to be in a safe sort of mood to forgive it its lack of guts, or at the very least, adventure. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bravo, Tom Hanks!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dimplet
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie doesn't so much have a plot as a trajectory. Nevertheless, it is better to see it yourself than to know where it is going. Suffice it to say that it is about a rock band, and how its members, friends and family respond to its success. As such, it is in the slice-of-life genre. Given its nearly 2 and a half hour length on the directors cut that I saw, and recommend, it works remarkably well. After awhile, I wondered if something would happen, some disaster or twist of fate, some bad guy to thicken the plot, and noticed the movie was rather long. But I wasn't bored at all, and was enjoying seeing the story unfold. In the end, the length was just right. Also, I am not a rock fan, so I was a bit skeptical. It didn't matter. In the wrong hands, this could have turned into Partridge Family cornball. But it is solid. To all this, Tom Hanks deserves the credit as writer, director, and low- key star, who appears late in the movie. It's a first class job. Not an earth shaking masterpiece, but a well-crafted, thoroughly enjoyable movie. I am a stickler for anachronisms in movies like this. This is a period piece set in Erie, Pennsylvania, circa 1964. The Sixties was a fluid time, where the culture changed every two years; 1964 was different from 1960, 1962, 1966 and 1968. The fact that one of the band members enlists in the Marines, without any mention of Vietnam, is a good measure of the mood and innocence of 1964, versus 1966, when the war had become politicized. America was at its best around this time, and it was all downhill from there. The movie captured the spirit of this window of time. Tom Hanks was 8 at the time, so he could not rely solely on memory, and must have done some historical research to fully understand the period. Whoever was in charge of props did a fantastic job of assembling lots of appliances, radios, recording gear and lots of cars. This is a movie that got it right. I loved when Skitch handed out pocket transistor radios to everyone in the band - back then an AM radio would have cost about $10 to $15, very expensive at the time, about $50 or more in today's dollars. The only anachronism I found was when Skitch tells a customer the appliance is available in avocado. Avocado was a notoriously common kitchen appliance color in the 1970s; I see it was introduced by GE in 1966, but became a tidal wave around 1968-1970. It was one of those fashion things, a late Dating Game chic, when all of a sudden everything was avocado green (or harvest gold), color coordinated so people could have an entire kitchen of avocado, lucky you!. And then avocado, predictably, disappeared. I found a post, "The Death of Avocado" that observed it was a mistake to put a trendy color on a long-life appliance, which looked obnoxious after coordinating avocado room decor disappeared. No kidding. I was just a kid at the time, but I could see that coming. See how sensitive the cultural timeline is for the Sixties? Actually, I would say what most people think of as the Sixties began around 1963-64, with the Beatles and the period of this film, and lasted till Nixon's resignation in 1974 (although some place the beginning of change at 1959). After that, the years unfolded in a homogeneous miasma, distinguished mainly by the gradual introduction of new technology, like the VCR, the Walkman and cordless phone sizes. That an appliance color was the only missed stitch in the movie indicates just how good it was! The acting all round was excellent. There were no caricatures, even with the doorman at the LA hotel, who had some real depth to his role. And, although I read here there were pro musicians actually dubbing the music, the actors were totally convincing that they were the ones making the music. "That Thing You Do" fits most closely the mold of "Breaking Away," which also featured a cast of talented young actors, and a skeptical, practical father representing the secure, dull path. Both are about life, dreams and fallibility. They both offer a lesson for young people. And in both, in the end, they turn a corner and life goes on. This is an enjoyable, memorable and thoughtful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny seize the day and forget about the rest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dr Jacques COULARDEAU
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a comedy about real young people from the Rock 'n Roll planet in the early 1960s. It's funny but also typically American. There are so many sharks going around looking for young teenage would-be rock stars that it is impossible not to be noticed by one, one day, not to become some one overnight and not to dissolved as soon as the top is reached. To stay at the top is really difficult. A band in those days, and in the USA, was the normal way for anyone who wanted to do some music on the stage to go around but bands did not last long. Everyone is not the Beatles or the Rolling Stones, you know. This is the story of the short-lived Wonders and yet the four boys and the one girl who were there at the first public appearance in the boonies, all eventually did something with their skin and their brains, if they had any, both skin and brains. Today that adventure still exists in the USA but it has also taken names like Myspace music, Youtube, Daily Motion and some others. Permanence of course is nothing in that business in 99% of the cases, but chance is also essential for those who have something in their veins. A career is often 50% talent and 50% chance, some would say opportunity. But the film is funny, though so banal that it should be a warning to anyone who wants to imitate these young teenagers. As the old Paxton would say: look after your money, women and a few other things of that type. Yesterday is a sure thing that existed but tomorrow is as brittle as an egg shell in front of a bulldozer. And the world is full of bulldozers crushing many eggshells down into the ground and powder. Dust to dust mind you. Dr Jacques COULARDEAU, University Paris 1 Pantheon Sorbonne, University Paris 8 Saint Denis, University Paris 12 Cr&eacute;teil, CEGID
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Breezy period piece wrapped around a catchy song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    calvinnme
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this movie advertised in the theaters back in 1996, I rolled my eyes in great disdain. For one thing the advertising banner - "In every life there comes a time when that dream you dream becomes that thing you do" hit me the wrong way. After all, 95% of us never wind up doing the dream we dream...there is no WHEN in our lives for this event. Plus, I just figured it was an attempt by Tom Hanks to go highbrow via a directorial debut after those back-to-back Academy Awards. When I finally got around to seeing the film I really loved it. The first half is very upbeat as the band gets started out. They truly are the "One-ders", just like many other bands of the Beatles' transitional era. They wrote and performed one song that got them national attention, and then couldn't follow up with anything else. That's too bad, because the band does get one lucky break after another at the start. The guy in the camper that shoves a bowl of stew and a contract in front of them and tells them to "trust me" could have had them signing anything. They got lucky that he was legitimate and really did intend to get the record on the air and not steal it from them. That's what makes the disintegration of the band at the end so sad. One by one, they just walk away from their dream. To me, if the movie had any flaw, it was this - the band members just acted like the whole thing was one big amusement park ride rather than a once-in-a-lifetime life changing opportunity. Finally, I also loved all of the authentic looking stage designs. The home appliance store really brought back memories. These type of family owned appliance stores were all over the place back in the 1960's before the big box stores gradually made them extinct. Plus, the appliances being sold looked just like what was available in 1964 right down to the brand names and the styles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ingenious! One Of The Best Movies Of 1996!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this movie only a few years ago, and I can say that I was not disappointed in any way, shape, or form! In my point of view, this is ingenious! I remember that when I was done watching this movie for the first time, I just wanted to watch it all over again, because I just plain loved it! I mean that I loved this movie, and when I mean that I loved it, I loved it! This movie is honestly one of the best movies of the 1990's, as well as one of the best movies of 1996! This movie is totally and completely remarkable from beginning to end, from the very beginning of this movie to the very end of this movie, it is totally and completely remarkable! I honestly have nothing to say about this movie that is against it, because I was not disappointed with it at all! And once more, I thought that this movie was perfect, not only as a musical movie, but as a movie movie! This is also another movie that is a must see, because it just can't get any better than this, not kidding, it really can't get any better! While I loved the movie as a whole, I especially loved the songs and the music! In fact, I own the soundtrack to this film, as well as the film itself! This movie has got some of the best songs of any film that I have honestly ever heard, because they are extraordinary! And because I own the soundtrack and the film, I can watch this movie and listen to the songs at any time that I feel like doing it! I don't regret seeing this movie, because it blew me away! So all in all, this is another movie that scores a ten out of ten on my scale! If you haven't seen this movie yet, see it, because like I was, you are going to be blown away! I am not joking with you, this movie really is that great of a film, I mean that it is something that you are going to love from the very minute that you start watching it! Mark my words: You've got to watch this movie, it is totally and completely fabulous and extraordinary! 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do that thing I do!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sukhitha Jayathilake
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Huge cast. Many popular stars today maybe at the start of their carrier. Liv Tylor and Charlice Theron. OMG they literally look like dolls. Specially Charlice. And two of my favorites, Steve Zahn and Giovanni Ribisi. It's a movie about a small town band trying to make it out in the big time. Well It's just a simple journey every band has to go through so to speak. Basically as I see it It's all just four guys playing there only hit single throughout the movie like a thousand times? Does tend to make you sick even! The reason I don't get that much of a kick out of this movie is maybe because I'm not 50. People tom Hanks' age must get to drive down the memory lane watching this one. Too bad I can't feel it. Well BTW If you think about it, This movie is pretty gay. The modern equivalent to this movie would be a movie about the Jonas brothers. Only they are still popular. But Still Liv Tyler makes it watchable. I wanted to see more Charlice Theron. She must have been an amateur then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
