<filme>
 <id>
  847
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116913
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Ricardo III - Um Ensaio
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Al Pacino's deeply-felt rumination on Shakespeare's significance and relevance to the modern world through interviews and an in-depth analysis of "Richard III."
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Director Al Pacino juxtaposes scene's from Richard III, scenes of rehearsals for Richard III, and sessions where parties involved discuss the play, the times that shaped the play and the events that happened at the time the play is set. Interviews with mostly British actors are also included, attempting to explain why American actors have more problems performing Shakespearean plays than they do.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Documentary
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   interview
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   rehearsal
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   reenactment
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mariachi
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Al Pacino
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   William Shakespeare
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Al Pacino
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Al Pacino
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Alec Baldwin
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kevin Spacey
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare at his best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frnc2
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so delighted that I watched this movie many times. How do you introduce many to a masterpiece of a genius? Pacino searches for him in England's history, at the streets, at the stages and rehearsals, with British actors and scholars, in a beggar that taught us about feelings, feelings in words, not only in gestures, actions, while showing the noble drama in its political subtleties. It shows the beauty not only of a language and story, but a great actor's view of a great play. Surely one of the best movies I have ever seen about a play of Shakespeare. A film that anybody who likes Shakespeare and poetry will watch many times in order to fully understand its beauty
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There is no creature loves me"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Poor King Richard III. He's killed all his rivals for the throne and there's no one left to bow and scrape. And he can't even find a horse to ride away. Al Pacino doesn't explain why he chose this play of Shakespeare's 37, but he very successfully uses this gory history drama as a prism through which to demonstrate that Shakespeare is full of sound and fury, signifying a lot -- if Americans will just take the time to be aware. Wearing shades and a baseball cap, and clutching a copy of Cliff Notes, Al Pacino travels from New York to England talking to all manner of folk about the Bard, from men-in-the-street to ivory-tower English scholars. And he dramatizes the best scenes from the play with an ensemble of crackerjack American actors. The result is a compelling argument for giving old Will another look. I read in the IMDb notes that Pacino had originally intended to film his own version of "Richard III" but decided against it when he realized he couldn't outshine Lawrence Olivier's 1955 masterpiece. It was probably a good call. Pacino comes up with something entirely unique here and it's a delight through and through. Highly recommended for anyone who'd like to know more about the writer who knew us best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Looking Differently At Documentaries
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    to_bornotb
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though I have watched this documentary many times I find that now after watching it during my enrollment in a documentary film class I am able to appreciate the film all that much more. Pacino's passion as an actor is vividly captured in this documentary and the breaks that he offers in order for the audience to "catch-up" illustrates that he understands his notions as an actor place him in a better understanding of the Shakespearean play, Richard III; but, he does not impose that notion upon the viewer. He is dedicated to helping the viewer understand the play and in doing so gives off a great sense of authority over the play and the production. I enjoyed the rehearsal readings that showed the actors were somewhat in the same boat of misunderstanding as the audience was. By walking the streets of New York and discussing Shakespeare in the most usually of places demonstrates how Pacino envisioned Shakespeare to be a more intricate part of our daily lives. As a participatory film, Pacino demonstrates the art of documenting by choosing the scenes in which he is selecting the settings for the shots to be filmed, he controls the dialogue that takes place on camera and decides which scenes of the play with be discussed more extensively on camera. This film gained a new appreciation from an old fan by noticing the different cinematic techniques that Al Pacino considers while they take place on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keep Looking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    proteus6847
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ninety minutes of mind-numbing incompetence. Pacino played Richard twice on stage (in 1973 and 1979) and both times he was blasted by the critics, for the simple and sufficient reason that he has no classical talent. Prior to making this film, his only other venture into Shakespeare was as Marc Antony in an early 80s production of Julius Caesar: here, too, the critics came to bury Al, not to praise him. But nothing can daunt a stubborn egomaniac. Well, almost nothing, for you'll note that this isn't a film version of Richard III, but rather a documentary about Pacino's "search" for the character. Interesting, that. Did Branagh make a film called "Looking for Henry V"? No, he made a film version of Henry V. Did Olivier make a film called "Looking for Othello"? No, he made a film version of Othello. So what's up here? Why is Al presenting us with a "search" for the thing instead of the thing itself? I'll give you three guesses.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling from the shoulders of giants
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timboyork
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being accompanied by some very fine actors and receiving some excellent advice, Mr Pacino turns a fine tragedy into an unintended comedy. He is clearly illiterate and ego-driven, a fatal combination when approaching the finest of all literary works. His performance mimics English actors - cadences, tonality and let's not forget iambic pentameter (could he even spell it?) - from the likes of Olivier, Gielgud, Burton ... Perhaps he was convinced that a switch of genre could work by Gielgud's triumph in Arthur and Burton's successes. Perhaps not. He seems at odds with the plot and language of the play throughout. So, why try? We are left to guess. Unfortunately, he simply makes himself ridiculous. You're very good at what you know, Al. But, you don't know this play, buddy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bringing Shakespeare to the masses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Looking for Richard" has Al Pacino, over a four-year period while he filmed various other things, delving into Shakespeare's Richard III with a cast of wonderful actors. The premise is that American actors approach Shakespeare too reverentially. Pacino gathers various actors, using places such as the Cloisters and St. John the Divine Church, to analyze, rehearse, and perform Richard III. Pacino amassed something like 80 hours, cut down to two. There are interviews with stars such as Kevin Kline, Vanessa Redgrave, F. Murray Abraham, Viveka Lindfors, Kenneth Branagh, Kevin Kline, John Gielgud, Peter Brook, and many others, including the man on the street. The final players include Kevin Conway, Kevin Spacey, Winona Ryder, Harris Yulin, Alec Baldwin, Estelle Parsons, Aiden Quinn and others. Scenes from the play are interspersed with discussion and rehearsal. Pacino's Richard emerges as raw, tough, and manipulative, whereas Olivier's was a complete slimeball. Both approaches work. This is an excellent film to show to high school students learning Shakespeare as Pacino takes some of the language apart -- the film makes the language and the human feelings and motivations behind the words very accessible. Truly excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You found him, Al!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (brice@crawfordredfern.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having lately seen Kevin Spacey's marvellous 'King Richard III' at London's Old Vic (on Broadway in a month or two) I had to see again this splendid exploration of Shakespeare, Richard and the wariness by the American public of WS and the phobic approach to his work of some actors. Yet years ago Brando joined John Gielgud and James Mason to play a thrilling Mark Antony in Mankiewicz's 'Julius Caesar', and here an American cast show themselves fine Shakespearean actors. Spacey (young and handsome!) is most enjoyable as Richard's conniving spin=doctor, Buckingham, and in his inevitably fragmented portrayal Pacino shows what a dark, deadly and witty Crookback he would be - on film or stage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As masterful director as Al is an actor (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From my education, Shakespeare isn't for common people and I praise Al to invest his stature to bring Shakespeare to us. Thus, this movie is really exciting because there are really two story lines nicely melted together: the Shakespeare's play and the passion of Al. For those like me who rates Al as their best actor, this is a must-see. The character of Richard is black as coal and Al has always been never better with those perfidious and nasty guys. On the opposite, in the real life, Al is a warm-full, sweet person and with his documentary, he opens this door for us and offers to take a peek. In addition, it's great to see Al and his pals talking about the play, looking for great exteriors and visiting the original place of Shakespeare. You see the mystery of creation in art and this special birth is always a memorable event. Actually, despite being hard of hearing (and fearing to become deaf), I just like Al's voice: it's amazing how much feelings he can show with it. That's why i'm just laughing when actors like Pitt are depicted as great because they are dwarfs compared to Al. In conclusion, beyond being "the" actor, Al reveals himself as an inspired director and he should direct more!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Traynor
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to study Richard III and Looking For Richard for school and, lucky for me I like Shakespeare so I understand it. When I was told we were studying Looking For Richard as well, I was skeptical because often the English staff choose bad movies but I really did enjoy this film immensely. Al Pacino had a brilliant idea to try and make Shakespeare more accessible to the modern public, more so the modern American public and he does a brilliant job of this. It is different though because he does not really change it too much. The cast is also very good and contains a number of famous names. Even though I have to study this film for an English class I would gladly watch this film anyway which is a testament to the film. Absolutely fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wildwoodmusic
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow! I just found this. Been out of the country for a long time and I seem to have missed a lot. I love Shakespeare and have seen many, many productions and films. I find this fascinating and could have watched more. Some say it was laughable, I don't see it. It is a learning experience and Pacino captured Richard perfectly. Better then most I have seen. There is a lovely mix of the scholarly, the actor's processes and a good bit of fun. I felt as if I was discovering new views along with the actors. Maybe it isn't to everyone's tastes but it beats out the pablum that is the usual fair in these times. I too greatly regret the whole film was never made and released in conjunction with Looking for Richard. It would have been magnificent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare at his best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frnc2
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so delighted that I watched this movie many times. How do you introduce many to a masterpiece of a genius? Pacino searches for him in England's history, at the streets, at the stages and rehearsals, with British actors and scholars, in a beggar that taught us about feelings, feelings in words, not only in gestures, actions, while showing the noble drama in its political subtleties. It shows the beauty not only of a language and story, but a great actor's view of a great play. Surely one of the best movies I have ever seen about a play of Shakespeare. A film that anybody who likes Shakespeare and poetry will watch many times in order to fully understand its beauty
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There is no creature loves me"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Poor King Richard III. He's killed all his rivals for the throne and there's no one left to bow and scrape. And he can't even find a horse to ride away. Al Pacino doesn't explain why he chose this play of Shakespeare's 37, but he very successfully uses this gory history drama as a prism through which to demonstrate that Shakespeare is full of sound and fury, signifying a lot -- if Americans will just take the time to be aware. Wearing shades and a baseball cap, and clutching a copy of Cliff Notes, Al Pacino travels from New York to England talking to all manner of folk about the Bard, from men-in-the-street to ivory-tower English scholars. And he dramatizes the best scenes from the play with an ensemble of crackerjack American actors. The result is a compelling argument for giving old Will another look. I read in the IMDb notes that Pacino had originally intended to film his own version of "Richard III" but decided against it when he realized he couldn't outshine Lawrence Olivier's 1955 masterpiece. It was probably a good call. Pacino comes up with something entirely unique here and it's a delight through and through. Highly recommended for anyone who'd like to know more about the writer who knew us best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Looking Differently At Documentaries
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    to_bornotb
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though I have watched this documentary many times I find that now after watching it during my enrollment in a documentary film class I am able to appreciate the film all that much more. Pacino's passion as an actor is vividly captured in this documentary and the breaks that he offers in order for the audience to "catch-up" illustrates that he understands his notions as an actor place him in a better understanding of the Shakespearean play, Richard III; but, he does not impose that notion upon the viewer. He is dedicated to helping the viewer understand the play and in doing so gives off a great sense of authority over the play and the production. I enjoyed the rehearsal readings that showed the actors were somewhat in the same boat of misunderstanding as the audience was. By walking the streets of New York and discussing Shakespeare in the most usually of places demonstrates how Pacino envisioned Shakespeare to be a more intricate part of our daily lives. As a participatory film, Pacino demonstrates the art of documenting by choosing the scenes in which he is selecting the settings for the shots to be filmed, he controls the dialogue that takes place on camera and decides which scenes of the play with be discussed more extensively on camera. This film gained a new appreciation from an old fan by noticing the different cinematic techniques that Al Pacino considers while they take place on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keep Looking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    proteus6847
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ninety minutes of mind-numbing incompetence. Pacino played Richard twice on stage (in 1973 and 1979) and both times he was blasted by the critics, for the simple and sufficient reason that he has no classical talent. Prior to making this film, his only other venture into Shakespeare was as Marc Antony in an early 80s production of Julius Caesar: here, too, the critics came to bury Al, not to praise him. But nothing can daunt a stubborn egomaniac. Well, almost nothing, for you'll note that this isn't a film version of Richard III, but rather a documentary about Pacino's "search" for the character. Interesting, that. Did Branagh make a film called "Looking for Henry V"? No, he made a film version of Henry V. Did Olivier make a film called "Looking for Othello"? No, he made a film version of Othello. So what's up here? Why is Al presenting us with a "search" for the thing instead of the thing itself? I'll give you three guesses.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling from the shoulders of giants
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timboyork
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being accompanied by some very fine actors and receiving some excellent advice, Mr Pacino turns a fine tragedy into an unintended comedy. He is clearly illiterate and ego-driven, a fatal combination when approaching the finest of all literary works. His performance mimics English actors - cadences, tonality and let's not forget iambic pentameter (could he even spell it?) - from the likes of Olivier, Gielgud, Burton ... Perhaps he was convinced that a switch of genre could work by Gielgud's triumph in Arthur and Burton's successes. Perhaps not. He seems at odds with the plot and language of the play throughout. So, why try? We are left to guess. Unfortunately, he simply makes himself ridiculous. You're very good at what you know, Al. But, you don't know this play, buddy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bringing Shakespeare to the masses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Looking for Richard" has Al Pacino, over a four-year period while he filmed various other things, delving into Shakespeare's Richard III with a cast of wonderful actors. The premise is that American actors approach Shakespeare too reverentially. Pacino gathers various actors, using places such as the Cloisters and St. John the Divine Church, to analyze, rehearse, and perform Richard III. Pacino amassed something like 80 hours, cut down to two. There are interviews with stars such as Kevin Kline, Vanessa Redgrave, F. Murray Abraham, Viveka Lindfors, Kenneth Branagh, Kevin Kline, John Gielgud, Peter Brook, and many others, including the man on the street. The final players include Kevin Conway, Kevin Spacey, Winona Ryder, Harris Yulin, Alec Baldwin, Estelle Parsons, Aiden Quinn and others. Scenes from the play are interspersed with discussion and rehearsal. Pacino's Richard emerges as raw, tough, and manipulative, whereas Olivier's was a complete slimeball. Both approaches work. This is an excellent film to show to high school students learning Shakespeare as Pacino takes some of the language apart -- the film makes the language and the human feelings and motivations behind the words very accessible. Truly excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You found him, Al!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (brice@crawfordredfern.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having lately seen Kevin Spacey's marvellous 'King Richard III' at London's Old Vic (on Broadway in a month or two) I had to see again this splendid exploration of Shakespeare, Richard and the wariness by the American public of WS and the phobic approach to his work of some actors. Yet years ago Brando joined John Gielgud and James Mason to play a thrilling Mark Antony in Mankiewicz's 'Julius Caesar', and here an American cast show themselves fine Shakespearean actors. Spacey (young and handsome!) is most enjoyable as Richard's conniving spin=doctor, Buckingham, and in his inevitably fragmented portrayal Pacino shows what a dark, deadly and witty Crookback he would be - on film or stage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As masterful director as Al is an actor (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From my education, Shakespeare isn't for common people and I praise Al to invest his stature to bring Shakespeare to us. Thus, this movie is really exciting because there are really two story lines nicely melted together: the Shakespeare's play and the passion of Al. For those like me who rates Al as their best actor, this is a must-see. The character of Richard is black as coal and Al has always been never better with those perfidious and nasty guys. On the opposite, in the real life, Al is a warm-full, sweet person and with his documentary, he opens this door for us and offers to take a peek. In addition, it's great to see Al and his pals talking about the play, looking for great exteriors and visiting the original place of Shakespeare. You see the mystery of creation in art and this special birth is always a memorable event. Actually, despite being hard of hearing (and fearing to become deaf), I just like Al's voice: it's amazing how much feelings he can show with it. That's why i'm just laughing when actors like Pitt are depicted as great because they are dwarfs compared to Al. In conclusion, beyond being "the" actor, Al reveals himself as an inspired director and he should direct more!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Traynor
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to study Richard III and Looking For Richard for school and, lucky for me I like Shakespeare so I understand it. When I was told we were studying Looking For Richard as well, I was skeptical because often the English staff choose bad movies but I really did enjoy this film immensely. Al Pacino had a brilliant idea to try and make Shakespeare more accessible to the modern public, more so the modern American public and he does a brilliant job of this. It is different though because he does not really change it too much. The cast is also very good and contains a number of famous names. Even though I have to study this film for an English class I would gladly watch this film anyway which is a testament to the film. Absolutely fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wildwoodmusic
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow! I just found this. Been out of the country for a long time and I seem to have missed a lot. I love Shakespeare and have seen many, many productions and films. I find this fascinating and could have watched more. Some say it was laughable, I don't see it. It is a learning experience and Pacino captured Richard perfectly. Better then most I have seen. There is a lovely mix of the scholarly, the actor's processes and a good bit of fun. I felt as if I was discovering new views along with the actors. Maybe it isn't to everyone's tastes but it beats out the pablum that is the usual fair in these times. I too greatly regret the whole film was never made and released in conjunction with Looking for Richard. It would have been magnificent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare at his best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frnc2
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so delighted that I watched this movie many times. How do you introduce many to a masterpiece of a genius? Pacino searches for him in England's history, at the streets, at the stages and rehearsals, with British actors and scholars, in a beggar that taught us about feelings, feelings in words, not only in gestures, actions, while showing the noble drama in its political subtleties. It shows the beauty not only of a language and story, but a great actor's view of a great play. Surely one of the best movies I have ever seen about a play of Shakespeare. A film that anybody who likes Shakespeare and poetry will watch many times in order to fully understand its beauty
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There is no creature loves me"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Poor King Richard III. He's killed all his rivals for the throne and there's no one left to bow and scrape. And he can't even find a horse to ride away. Al Pacino doesn't explain why he chose this play of Shakespeare's 37, but he very successfully uses this gory history drama as a prism through which to demonstrate that Shakespeare is full of sound and fury, signifying a lot -- if Americans will just take the time to be aware. Wearing shades and a baseball cap, and clutching a copy of Cliff Notes, Al Pacino travels from New York to England talking to all manner of folk about the Bard, from men-in-the-street to ivory-tower English scholars. And he dramatizes the best scenes from the play with an ensemble of crackerjack American actors. The result is a compelling argument for giving old Will another look. I read in the IMDb notes that Pacino had originally intended to film his own version of "Richard III" but decided against it when he realized he couldn't outshine Lawrence Olivier's 1955 masterpiece. It was probably a good call. Pacino comes up with something entirely unique here and it's a delight through and through. Highly recommended for anyone who'd like to know more about the writer who knew us best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Looking Differently At Documentaries
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    to_bornotb
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though I have watched this documentary many times I find that now after watching it during my enrollment in a documentary film class I am able to appreciate the film all that much more. Pacino's passion as an actor is vividly captured in this documentary and the breaks that he offers in order for the audience to "catch-up" illustrates that he understands his notions as an actor place him in a better understanding of the Shakespearean play, Richard III; but, he does not impose that notion upon the viewer. He is dedicated to helping the viewer understand the play and in doing so gives off a great sense of authority over the play and the production. I enjoyed the rehearsal readings that showed the actors were somewhat in the same boat of misunderstanding as the audience was. By walking the streets of New York and discussing Shakespeare in the most usually of places demonstrates how Pacino envisioned Shakespeare to be a more intricate part of our daily lives. As a participatory film, Pacino demonstrates the art of documenting by choosing the scenes in which he is selecting the settings for the shots to be filmed, he controls the dialogue that takes place on camera and decides which scenes of the play with be discussed more extensively on camera. This film gained a new appreciation from an old fan by noticing the different cinematic techniques that Al Pacino considers while they take place on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keep Looking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    proteus6847
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ninety minutes of mind-numbing incompetence. Pacino played Richard twice on stage (in 1973 and 1979) and both times he was blasted by the critics, for the simple and sufficient reason that he has no classical talent. Prior to making this film, his only other venture into Shakespeare was as Marc Antony in an early 80s production of Julius Caesar: here, too, the critics came to bury Al, not to praise him. But nothing can daunt a stubborn egomaniac. Well, almost nothing, for you'll note that this isn't a film version of Richard III, but rather a documentary about Pacino's "search" for the character. Interesting, that. Did Branagh make a film called "Looking for Henry V"? No, he made a film version of Henry V. Did Olivier make a film called "Looking for Othello"? No, he made a film version of Othello. So what's up here? Why is Al presenting us with a "search" for the thing instead of the thing itself? I'll give you three guesses.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling from the shoulders of giants
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timboyork
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being accompanied by some very fine actors and receiving some excellent advice, Mr Pacino turns a fine tragedy into an unintended comedy. He is clearly illiterate and ego-driven, a fatal combination when approaching the finest of all literary works. His performance mimics English actors - cadences, tonality and let's not forget iambic pentameter (could he even spell it?) - from the likes of Olivier, Gielgud, Burton ... Perhaps he was convinced that a switch of genre could work by Gielgud's triumph in Arthur and Burton's successes. Perhaps not. He seems at odds with the plot and language of the play throughout. So, why try? We are left to guess. Unfortunately, he simply makes himself ridiculous. You're very good at what you know, Al. But, you don't know this play, buddy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bringing Shakespeare to the masses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Looking for Richard" has Al Pacino, over a four-year period while he filmed various other things, delving into Shakespeare's Richard III with a cast of wonderful actors. The premise is that American actors approach Shakespeare too reverentially. Pacino gathers various actors, using places such as the Cloisters and St. John the Divine Church, to analyze, rehearse, and perform Richard III. Pacino amassed something like 80 hours, cut down to two. There are interviews with stars such as Kevin Kline, Vanessa Redgrave, F. Murray Abraham, Viveka Lindfors, Kenneth Branagh, Kevin Kline, John Gielgud, Peter Brook, and many others, including the man on the street. The final players include Kevin Conway, Kevin Spacey, Winona Ryder, Harris Yulin, Alec Baldwin, Estelle Parsons, Aiden Quinn and others. Scenes from the play are interspersed with discussion and rehearsal. Pacino's Richard emerges as raw, tough, and manipulative, whereas Olivier's was a complete slimeball. Both approaches work. This is an excellent film to show to high school students learning Shakespeare as Pacino takes some of the language apart -- the film makes the language and the human feelings and motivations behind the words very accessible. Truly excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You found him, Al!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (brice@crawfordredfern.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having lately seen Kevin Spacey's marvellous 'King Richard III' at London's Old Vic (on Broadway in a month or two) I had to see again this splendid exploration of Shakespeare, Richard and the wariness by the American public of WS and the phobic approach to his work of some actors. Yet years ago Brando joined John Gielgud and James Mason to play a thrilling Mark Antony in Mankiewicz's 'Julius Caesar', and here an American cast show themselves fine Shakespearean actors. Spacey (young and handsome!) is most enjoyable as Richard's conniving spin=doctor, Buckingham, and in his inevitably fragmented portrayal Pacino shows what a dark, deadly and witty Crookback he would be - on film or stage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As masterful director as Al is an actor (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From my education, Shakespeare isn't for common people and I praise Al to invest his stature to bring Shakespeare to us. Thus, this movie is really exciting because there are really two story lines nicely melted together: the Shakespeare's play and the passion of Al. For those like me who rates Al as their best actor, this is a must-see. The character of Richard is black as coal and Al has always been never better with those perfidious and nasty guys. On the opposite, in the real life, Al is a warm-full, sweet person and with his documentary, he opens this door for us and offers to take a peek. In addition, it's great to see Al and his pals talking about the play, looking for great exteriors and visiting the original place of Shakespeare. You see the mystery of creation in art and this special birth is always a memorable event. Actually, despite being hard of hearing (and fearing to become deaf), I just like Al's voice: it's amazing how much feelings he can show with it. That's why i'm just laughing when actors like Pitt are depicted as great because they are dwarfs compared to Al. In conclusion, beyond being "the" actor, Al reveals himself as an inspired director and he should direct more!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Traynor
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to study Richard III and Looking For Richard for school and, lucky for me I like Shakespeare so I understand it. When I was told we were studying Looking For Richard as well, I was skeptical because often the English staff choose bad movies but I really did enjoy this film immensely. Al Pacino had a brilliant idea to try and make Shakespeare more accessible to the modern public, more so the modern American public and he does a brilliant job of this. It is different though because he does not really change it too much. The cast is also very good and contains a number of famous names. Even though I have to study this film for an English class I would gladly watch this film anyway which is a testament to the film. Absolutely fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wildwoodmusic
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow! I just found this. Been out of the country for a long time and I seem to have missed a lot. I love Shakespeare and have seen many, many productions and films. I find this fascinating and could have watched more. Some say it was laughable, I don't see it. It is a learning experience and Pacino captured Richard perfectly. Better then most I have seen. There is a lovely mix of the scholarly, the actor's processes and a good bit of fun. I felt as if I was discovering new views along with the actors. Maybe it isn't to everyone's tastes but it beats out the pablum that is the usual fair in these times. I too greatly regret the whole film was never made and released in conjunction with Looking for Richard. It would have been magnificent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare at his best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frnc2
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so delighted that I watched this movie many times. How do you introduce many to a masterpiece of a genius? Pacino searches for him in England's history, at the streets, at the stages and rehearsals, with British actors and scholars, in a beggar that taught us about feelings, feelings in words, not only in gestures, actions, while showing the noble drama in its political subtleties. It shows the beauty not only of a language and story, but a great actor's view of a great play. Surely one of the best movies I have ever seen about a play of Shakespeare. A film that anybody who likes Shakespeare and poetry will watch many times in order to fully understand its beauty
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There is no creature loves me"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Poor King Richard III. He's killed all his rivals for the throne and there's no one left to bow and scrape. And he can't even find a horse to ride away. Al Pacino doesn't explain why he chose this play of Shakespeare's 37, but he very successfully uses this gory history drama as a prism through which to demonstrate that Shakespeare is full of sound and fury, signifying a lot -- if Americans will just take the time to be aware. Wearing shades and a baseball cap, and clutching a copy of Cliff Notes, Al Pacino travels from New York to England talking to all manner of folk about the Bard, from men-in-the-street to ivory-tower English scholars. And he dramatizes the best scenes from the play with an ensemble of crackerjack American actors. The result is a compelling argument for giving old Will another look. I read in the IMDb notes that Pacino had originally intended to film his own version of "Richard III" but decided against it when he realized he couldn't outshine Lawrence Olivier's 1955 masterpiece. It was probably a good call. Pacino comes up with something entirely unique here and it's a delight through and through. Highly recommended for anyone who'd like to know more about the writer who knew us best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Looking Differently At Documentaries
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    to_bornotb
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though I have watched this documentary many times I find that now after watching it during my enrollment in a documentary film class I am able to appreciate the film all that much more. Pacino's passion as an actor is vividly captured in this documentary and the breaks that he offers in order for the audience to "catch-up" illustrates that he understands his notions as an actor place him in a better understanding of the Shakespearean play, Richard III; but, he does not impose that notion upon the viewer. He is dedicated to helping the viewer understand the play and in doing so gives off a great sense of authority over the play and the production. I enjoyed the rehearsal readings that showed the actors were somewhat in the same boat of misunderstanding as the audience was. By walking the streets of New York and discussing Shakespeare in the most usually of places demonstrates how Pacino envisioned Shakespeare to be a more intricate part of our daily lives. As a participatory film, Pacino demonstrates the art of documenting by choosing the scenes in which he is selecting the settings for the shots to be filmed, he controls the dialogue that takes place on camera and decides which scenes of the play with be discussed more extensively on camera. This film gained a new appreciation from an old fan by noticing the different cinematic techniques that Al Pacino considers while they take place on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keep Looking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    proteus6847
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ninety minutes of mind-numbing incompetence. Pacino played Richard twice on stage (in 1973 and 1979) and both times he was blasted by the critics, for the simple and sufficient reason that he has no classical talent. Prior to making this film, his only other venture into Shakespeare was as Marc Antony in an early 80s production of Julius Caesar: here, too, the critics came to bury Al, not to praise him. But nothing can daunt a stubborn egomaniac. Well, almost nothing, for you'll note that this isn't a film version of Richard III, but rather a documentary about Pacino's "search" for the character. Interesting, that. Did Branagh make a film called "Looking for Henry V"? No, he made a film version of Henry V. Did Olivier make a film called "Looking for Othello"? No, he made a film version of Othello. So what's up here? Why is Al presenting us with a "search" for the thing instead of the thing itself? I'll give you three guesses.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling from the shoulders of giants
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timboyork
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being accompanied by some very fine actors and receiving some excellent advice, Mr Pacino turns a fine tragedy into an unintended comedy. He is clearly illiterate and ego-driven, a fatal combination when approaching the finest of all literary works. His performance mimics English actors - cadences, tonality and let's not forget iambic pentameter (could he even spell it?) - from the likes of Olivier, Gielgud, Burton ... Perhaps he was convinced that a switch of genre could work by Gielgud's triumph in Arthur and Burton's successes. Perhaps not. He seems at odds with the plot and language of the play throughout. So, why try? We are left to guess. Unfortunately, he simply makes himself ridiculous. You're very good at what you know, Al. But, you don't know this play, buddy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bringing Shakespeare to the masses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Looking for Richard" has Al Pacino, over a four-year period while he filmed various other things, delving into Shakespeare's Richard III with a cast of wonderful actors. The premise is that American actors approach Shakespeare too reverentially. Pacino gathers various actors, using places such as the Cloisters and St. John the Divine Church, to analyze, rehearse, and perform Richard III. Pacino amassed something like 80 hours, cut down to two. There are interviews with stars such as Kevin Kline, Vanessa Redgrave, F. Murray Abraham, Viveka Lindfors, Kenneth Branagh, Kevin Kline, John Gielgud, Peter Brook, and many others, including the man on the street. The final players include Kevin Conway, Kevin Spacey, Winona Ryder, Harris Yulin, Alec Baldwin, Estelle Parsons, Aiden Quinn and others. Scenes from the play are interspersed with discussion and rehearsal. Pacino's Richard emerges as raw, tough, and manipulative, whereas Olivier's was a complete slimeball. Both approaches work. This is an excellent film to show to high school students learning Shakespeare as Pacino takes some of the language apart -- the film makes the language and the human feelings and motivations behind the words very accessible. Truly excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You found him, Al!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (brice@crawfordredfern.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having lately seen Kevin Spacey's marvellous 'King Richard III' at London's Old Vic (on Broadway in a month or two) I had to see again this splendid exploration of Shakespeare, Richard and the wariness by the American public of WS and the phobic approach to his work of some actors. Yet years ago Brando joined John Gielgud and James Mason to play a thrilling Mark Antony in Mankiewicz's 'Julius Caesar', and here an American cast show themselves fine Shakespearean actors. Spacey (young and handsome!) is most enjoyable as Richard's conniving spin=doctor, Buckingham, and in his inevitably fragmented portrayal Pacino shows what a dark, deadly and witty Crookback he would be - on film or stage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As masterful director as Al is an actor (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From my education, Shakespeare isn't for common people and I praise Al to invest his stature to bring Shakespeare to us. Thus, this movie is really exciting because there are really two story lines nicely melted together: the Shakespeare's play and the passion of Al. For those like me who rates Al as their best actor, this is a must-see. The character of Richard is black as coal and Al has always been never better with those perfidious and nasty guys. On the opposite, in the real life, Al is a warm-full, sweet person and with his documentary, he opens this door for us and offers to take a peek. In addition, it's great to see Al and his pals talking about the play, looking for great exteriors and visiting the original place of Shakespeare. You see the mystery of creation in art and this special birth is always a memorable event. Actually, despite being hard of hearing (and fearing to become deaf), I just like Al's voice: it's amazing how much feelings he can show with it. That's why i'm just laughing when actors like Pitt are depicted as great because they are dwarfs compared to Al. In conclusion, beyond being "the" actor, Al reveals himself as an inspired director and he should direct more!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Traynor
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to study Richard III and Looking For Richard for school and, lucky for me I like Shakespeare so I understand it. When I was told we were studying Looking For Richard as well, I was skeptical because often the English staff choose bad movies but I really did enjoy this film immensely. Al Pacino had a brilliant idea to try and make Shakespeare more accessible to the modern public, more so the modern American public and he does a brilliant job of this. It is different though because he does not really change it too much. The cast is also very good and contains a number of famous names. Even though I have to study this film for an English class I would gladly watch this film anyway which is a testament to the film. Absolutely fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wildwoodmusic
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow! I just found this. Been out of the country for a long time and I seem to have missed a lot. I love Shakespeare and have seen many, many productions and films. I find this fascinating and could have watched more. Some say it was laughable, I don't see it. It is a learning experience and Pacino captured Richard perfectly. Better then most I have seen. There is a lovely mix of the scholarly, the actor's processes and a good bit of fun. I felt as if I was discovering new views along with the actors. Maybe it isn't to everyone's tastes but it beats out the pablum that is the usual fair in these times. I too greatly regret the whole film was never made and released in conjunction with Looking for Richard. It would have been magnificent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare at his best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frnc2
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so delighted that I watched this movie many times. How do you introduce many to a masterpiece of a genius? Pacino searches for him in England's history, at the streets, at the stages and rehearsals, with British actors and scholars, in a beggar that taught us about feelings, feelings in words, not only in gestures, actions, while showing the noble drama in its political subtleties. It shows the beauty not only of a language and story, but a great actor's view of a great play. Surely one of the best movies I have ever seen about a play of Shakespeare. A film that anybody who likes Shakespeare and poetry will watch many times in order to fully understand its beauty
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There is no creature loves me"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Poor King Richard III. He's killed all his rivals for the throne and there's no one left to bow and scrape. And he can't even find a horse to ride away. Al Pacino doesn't explain why he chose this play of Shakespeare's 37, but he very successfully uses this gory history drama as a prism through which to demonstrate that Shakespeare is full of sound and fury, signifying a lot -- if Americans will just take the time to be aware. Wearing shades and a baseball cap, and clutching a copy of Cliff Notes, Al Pacino travels from New York to England talking to all manner of folk about the Bard, from men-in-the-street to ivory-tower English scholars. And he dramatizes the best scenes from the play with an ensemble of crackerjack American actors. The result is a compelling argument for giving old Will another look. I read in the IMDb notes that Pacino had originally intended to film his own version of "Richard III" but decided against it when he realized he couldn't outshine Lawrence Olivier's 1955 masterpiece. It was probably a good call. Pacino comes up with something entirely unique here and it's a delight through and through. Highly recommended for anyone who'd like to know more about the writer who knew us best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Looking Differently At Documentaries
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    to_bornotb
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though I have watched this documentary many times I find that now after watching it during my enrollment in a documentary film class I am able to appreciate the film all that much more. Pacino's passion as an actor is vividly captured in this documentary and the breaks that he offers in order for the audience to "catch-up" illustrates that he understands his notions as an actor place him in a better understanding of the Shakespearean play, Richard III; but, he does not impose that notion upon the viewer. He is dedicated to helping the viewer understand the play and in doing so gives off a great sense of authority over the play and the production. I enjoyed the rehearsal readings that showed the actors were somewhat in the same boat of misunderstanding as the audience was. By walking the streets of New York and discussing Shakespeare in the most usually of places demonstrates how Pacino envisioned Shakespeare to be a more intricate part of our daily lives. As a participatory film, Pacino demonstrates the art of documenting by choosing the scenes in which he is selecting the settings for the shots to be filmed, he controls the dialogue that takes place on camera and decides which scenes of the play with be discussed more extensively on camera. This film gained a new appreciation from an old fan by noticing the different cinematic techniques that Al Pacino considers while they take place on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keep Looking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    proteus6847
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ninety minutes of mind-numbing incompetence. Pacino played Richard twice on stage (in 1973 and 1979) and both times he was blasted by the critics, for the simple and sufficient reason that he has no classical talent. Prior to making this film, his only other venture into Shakespeare was as Marc Antony in an early 80s production of Julius Caesar: here, too, the critics came to bury Al, not to praise him. But nothing can daunt a stubborn egomaniac. Well, almost nothing, for you'll note that this isn't a film version of Richard III, but rather a documentary about Pacino's "search" for the character. Interesting, that. Did Branagh make a film called "Looking for Henry V"? No, he made a film version of Henry V. Did Olivier make a film called "Looking for Othello"? No, he made a film version of Othello. So what's up here? Why is Al presenting us with a "search" for the thing instead of the thing itself? I'll give you three guesses.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling from the shoulders of giants
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timboyork
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being accompanied by some very fine actors and receiving some excellent advice, Mr Pacino turns a fine tragedy into an unintended comedy. He is clearly illiterate and ego-driven, a fatal combination when approaching the finest of all literary works. His performance mimics English actors - cadences, tonality and let's not forget iambic pentameter (could he even spell it?) - from the likes of Olivier, Gielgud, Burton ... Perhaps he was convinced that a switch of genre could work by Gielgud's triumph in Arthur and Burton's successes. Perhaps not. He seems at odds with the plot and language of the play throughout. So, why try? We are left to guess. Unfortunately, he simply makes himself ridiculous. You're very good at what you know, Al. But, you don't know this play, buddy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bringing Shakespeare to the masses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Looking for Richard" has Al Pacino, over a four-year period while he filmed various other things, delving into Shakespeare's Richard III with a cast of wonderful actors. The premise is that American actors approach Shakespeare too reverentially. Pacino gathers various actors, using places such as the Cloisters and St. John the Divine Church, to analyze, rehearse, and perform Richard III. Pacino amassed something like 80 hours, cut down to two. There are interviews with stars such as Kevin Kline, Vanessa Redgrave, F. Murray Abraham, Viveka Lindfors, Kenneth Branagh, Kevin Kline, John Gielgud, Peter Brook, and many others, including the man on the street. The final players include Kevin Conway, Kevin Spacey, Winona Ryder, Harris Yulin, Alec Baldwin, Estelle Parsons, Aiden Quinn and others. Scenes from the play are interspersed with discussion and rehearsal. Pacino's Richard emerges as raw, tough, and manipulative, whereas Olivier's was a complete slimeball. Both approaches work. This is an excellent film to show to high school students learning Shakespeare as Pacino takes some of the language apart -- the film makes the language and the human feelings and motivations behind the words very accessible. Truly excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You found him, Al!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (brice@crawfordredfern.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having lately seen Kevin Spacey's marvellous 'King Richard III' at London's Old Vic (on Broadway in a month or two) I had to see again this splendid exploration of Shakespeare, Richard and the wariness by the American public of WS and the phobic approach to his work of some actors. Yet years ago Brando joined John Gielgud and James Mason to play a thrilling Mark Antony in Mankiewicz's 'Julius Caesar', and here an American cast show themselves fine Shakespearean actors. Spacey (young and handsome!) is most enjoyable as Richard's conniving spin=doctor, Buckingham, and in his inevitably fragmented portrayal Pacino shows what a dark, deadly and witty Crookback he would be - on film or stage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As masterful director as Al is an actor (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From my education, Shakespeare isn't for common people and I praise Al to invest his stature to bring Shakespeare to us. Thus, this movie is really exciting because there are really two story lines nicely melted together: the Shakespeare's play and the passion of Al. For those like me who rates Al as their best actor, this is a must-see. The character of Richard is black as coal and Al has always been never better with those perfidious and nasty guys. On the opposite, in the real life, Al is a warm-full, sweet person and with his documentary, he opens this door for us and offers to take a peek. In addition, it's great to see Al and his pals talking about the play, looking for great exteriors and visiting the original place of Shakespeare. You see the mystery of creation in art and this special birth is always a memorable event. Actually, despite being hard of hearing (and fearing to become deaf), I just like Al's voice: it's amazing how much feelings he can show with it. That's why i'm just laughing when actors like Pitt are depicted as great because they are dwarfs compared to Al. In conclusion, beyond being "the" actor, Al reveals himself as an inspired director and he should direct more!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Traynor
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to study Richard III and Looking For Richard for school and, lucky for me I like Shakespeare so I understand it. When I was told we were studying Looking For Richard as well, I was skeptical because often the English staff choose bad movies but I really did enjoy this film immensely. Al Pacino had a brilliant idea to try and make Shakespeare more accessible to the modern public, more so the modern American public and he does a brilliant job of this. It is different though because he does not really change it too much. The cast is also very good and contains a number of famous names. Even though I have to study this film for an English class I would gladly watch this film anyway which is a testament to the film. Absolutely fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wildwoodmusic
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow! I just found this. Been out of the country for a long time and I seem to have missed a lot. I love Shakespeare and have seen many, many productions and films. I find this fascinating and could have watched more. Some say it was laughable, I don't see it. It is a learning experience and Pacino captured Richard perfectly. Better then most I have seen. There is a lovely mix of the scholarly, the actor's processes and a good bit of fun. I felt as if I was discovering new views along with the actors. Maybe it isn't to everyone's tastes but it beats out the pablum that is the usual fair in these times. I too greatly regret the whole film was never made and released in conjunction with Looking for Richard. It would have been magnificent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare at his best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frnc2
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so delighted that I watched this movie many times. How do you introduce many to a masterpiece of a genius? Pacino searches for him in England's history, at the streets, at the stages and rehearsals, with British actors and scholars, in a beggar that taught us about feelings, feelings in words, not only in gestures, actions, while showing the noble drama in its political subtleties. It shows the beauty not only of a language and story, but a great actor's view of a great play. Surely one of the best movies I have ever seen about a play of Shakespeare. A film that anybody who likes Shakespeare and poetry will watch many times in order to fully understand its beauty
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There is no creature loves me"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Poor King Richard III. He's killed all his rivals for the throne and there's no one left to bow and scrape. And he can't even find a horse to ride away. Al Pacino doesn't explain why he chose this play of Shakespeare's 37, but he very successfully uses this gory history drama as a prism through which to demonstrate that Shakespeare is full of sound and fury, signifying a lot -- if Americans will just take the time to be aware. Wearing shades and a baseball cap, and clutching a copy of Cliff Notes, Al Pacino travels from New York to England talking to all manner of folk about the Bard, from men-in-the-street to ivory-tower English scholars. And he dramatizes the best scenes from the play with an ensemble of crackerjack American actors. The result is a compelling argument for giving old Will another look. I read in the IMDb notes that Pacino had originally intended to film his own version of "Richard III" but decided against it when he realized he couldn't outshine Lawrence Olivier's 1955 masterpiece. It was probably a good call. Pacino comes up with something entirely unique here and it's a delight through and through. Highly recommended for anyone who'd like to know more about the writer who knew us best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Looking Differently At Documentaries
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    to_bornotb
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though I have watched this documentary many times I find that now after watching it during my enrollment in a documentary film class I am able to appreciate the film all that much more. Pacino's passion as an actor is vividly captured in this documentary and the breaks that he offers in order for the audience to "catch-up" illustrates that he understands his notions as an actor place him in a better understanding of the Shakespearean play, Richard III; but, he does not impose that notion upon the viewer. He is dedicated to helping the viewer understand the play and in doing so gives off a great sense of authority over the play and the production. I enjoyed the rehearsal readings that showed the actors were somewhat in the same boat of misunderstanding as the audience was. By walking the streets of New York and discussing Shakespeare in the most usually of places demonstrates how Pacino envisioned Shakespeare to be a more intricate part of our daily lives. As a participatory film, Pacino demonstrates the art of documenting by choosing the scenes in which he is selecting the settings for the shots to be filmed, he controls the dialogue that takes place on camera and decides which scenes of the play with be discussed more extensively on camera. This film gained a new appreciation from an old fan by noticing the different cinematic techniques that Al Pacino considers while they take place on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keep Looking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    proteus6847
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ninety minutes of mind-numbing incompetence. Pacino played Richard twice on stage (in 1973 and 1979) and both times he was blasted by the critics, for the simple and sufficient reason that he has no classical talent. Prior to making this film, his only other venture into Shakespeare was as Marc Antony in an early 80s production of Julius Caesar: here, too, the critics came to bury Al, not to praise him. But nothing can daunt a stubborn egomaniac. Well, almost nothing, for you'll note that this isn't a film version of Richard III, but rather a documentary about Pacino's "search" for the character. Interesting, that. Did Branagh make a film called "Looking for Henry V"? No, he made a film version of Henry V. Did Olivier make a film called "Looking for Othello"? No, he made a film version of Othello. So what's up here? Why is Al presenting us with a "search" for the thing instead of the thing itself? I'll give you three guesses.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling from the shoulders of giants
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timboyork
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being accompanied by some very fine actors and receiving some excellent advice, Mr Pacino turns a fine tragedy into an unintended comedy. He is clearly illiterate and ego-driven, a fatal combination when approaching the finest of all literary works. His performance mimics English actors - cadences, tonality and let's not forget iambic pentameter (could he even spell it?) - from the likes of Olivier, Gielgud, Burton ... Perhaps he was convinced that a switch of genre could work by Gielgud's triumph in Arthur and Burton's successes. Perhaps not. He seems at odds with the plot and language of the play throughout. So, why try? We are left to guess. Unfortunately, he simply makes himself ridiculous. You're very good at what you know, Al. But, you don't know this play, buddy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bringing Shakespeare to the masses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Looking for Richard" has Al Pacino, over a four-year period while he filmed various other things, delving into Shakespeare's Richard III with a cast of wonderful actors. The premise is that American actors approach Shakespeare too reverentially. Pacino gathers various actors, using places such as the Cloisters and St. John the Divine Church, to analyze, rehearse, and perform Richard III. Pacino amassed something like 80 hours, cut down to two. There are interviews with stars such as Kevin Kline, Vanessa Redgrave, F. Murray Abraham, Viveka Lindfors, Kenneth Branagh, Kevin Kline, John Gielgud, Peter Brook, and many others, including the man on the street. The final players include Kevin Conway, Kevin Spacey, Winona Ryder, Harris Yulin, Alec Baldwin, Estelle Parsons, Aiden Quinn and others. Scenes from the play are interspersed with discussion and rehearsal. Pacino's Richard emerges as raw, tough, and manipulative, whereas Olivier's was a complete slimeball. Both approaches work. This is an excellent film to show to high school students learning Shakespeare as Pacino takes some of the language apart -- the film makes the language and the human feelings and motivations behind the words very accessible. Truly excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You found him, Al!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (brice@crawfordredfern.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having lately seen Kevin Spacey's marvellous 'King Richard III' at London's Old Vic (on Broadway in a month or two) I had to see again this splendid exploration of Shakespeare, Richard and the wariness by the American public of WS and the phobic approach to his work of some actors. Yet years ago Brando joined John Gielgud and James Mason to play a thrilling Mark Antony in Mankiewicz's 'Julius Caesar', and here an American cast show themselves fine Shakespearean actors. Spacey (young and handsome!) is most enjoyable as Richard's conniving spin=doctor, Buckingham, and in his inevitably fragmented portrayal Pacino shows what a dark, deadly and witty Crookback he would be - on film or stage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As masterful director as Al is an actor (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From my education, Shakespeare isn't for common people and I praise Al to invest his stature to bring Shakespeare to us. Thus, this movie is really exciting because there are really two story lines nicely melted together: the Shakespeare's play and the passion of Al. For those like me who rates Al as their best actor, this is a must-see. The character of Richard is black as coal and Al has always been never better with those perfidious and nasty guys. On the opposite, in the real life, Al is a warm-full, sweet person and with his documentary, he opens this door for us and offers to take a peek. In addition, it's great to see Al and his pals talking about the play, looking for great exteriors and visiting the original place of Shakespeare. You see the mystery of creation in art and this special birth is always a memorable event. Actually, despite being hard of hearing (and fearing to become deaf), I just like Al's voice: it's amazing how much feelings he can show with it. That's why i'm just laughing when actors like Pitt are depicted as great because they are dwarfs compared to Al. In conclusion, beyond being "the" actor, Al reveals himself as an inspired director and he should direct more!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Traynor
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to study Richard III and Looking For Richard for school and, lucky for me I like Shakespeare so I understand it. When I was told we were studying Looking For Richard as well, I was skeptical because often the English staff choose bad movies but I really did enjoy this film immensely. Al Pacino had a brilliant idea to try and make Shakespeare more accessible to the modern public, more so the modern American public and he does a brilliant job of this. It is different though because he does not really change it too much. The cast is also very good and contains a number of famous names. Even though I have to study this film for an English class I would gladly watch this film anyway which is a testament to the film. Absolutely fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wildwoodmusic
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow! I just found this. Been out of the country for a long time and I seem to have missed a lot. I love Shakespeare and have seen many, many productions and films. I find this fascinating and could have watched more. Some say it was laughable, I don't see it. It is a learning experience and Pacino captured Richard perfectly. Better then most I have seen. There is a lovely mix of the scholarly, the actor's processes and a good bit of fun. I felt as if I was discovering new views along with the actors. Maybe it isn't to everyone's tastes but it beats out the pablum that is the usual fair in these times. I too greatly regret the whole film was never made and released in conjunction with Looking for Richard. It would have been magnificent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shakespeare at his best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frnc2
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was so delighted that I watched this movie many times. How do you introduce many to a masterpiece of a genius? Pacino searches for him in England's history, at the streets, at the stages and rehearsals, with British actors and scholars, in a beggar that taught us about feelings, feelings in words, not only in gestures, actions, while showing the noble drama in its political subtleties. It shows the beauty not only of a language and story, but a great actor's view of a great play. Surely one of the best movies I have ever seen about a play of Shakespeare. A film that anybody who likes Shakespeare and poetry will watch many times in order to fully understand its beauty
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There is no creature loves me"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Poor King Richard III. He's killed all his rivals for the throne and there's no one left to bow and scrape. And he can't even find a horse to ride away. Al Pacino doesn't explain why he chose this play of Shakespeare's 37, but he very successfully uses this gory history drama as a prism through which to demonstrate that Shakespeare is full of sound and fury, signifying a lot -- if Americans will just take the time to be aware. Wearing shades and a baseball cap, and clutching a copy of Cliff Notes, Al Pacino travels from New York to England talking to all manner of folk about the Bard, from men-in-the-street to ivory-tower English scholars. And he dramatizes the best scenes from the play with an ensemble of crackerjack American actors. The result is a compelling argument for giving old Will another look. I read in the IMDb notes that Pacino had originally intended to film his own version of "Richard III" but decided against it when he realized he couldn't outshine Lawrence Olivier's 1955 masterpiece. It was probably a good call. Pacino comes up with something entirely unique here and it's a delight through and through. Highly recommended for anyone who'd like to know more about the writer who knew us best.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Looking Differently At Documentaries
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    to_bornotb
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though I have watched this documentary many times I find that now after watching it during my enrollment in a documentary film class I am able to appreciate the film all that much more. Pacino's passion as an actor is vividly captured in this documentary and the breaks that he offers in order for the audience to "catch-up" illustrates that he understands his notions as an actor place him in a better understanding of the Shakespearean play, Richard III; but, he does not impose that notion upon the viewer. He is dedicated to helping the viewer understand the play and in doing so gives off a great sense of authority over the play and the production. I enjoyed the rehearsal readings that showed the actors were somewhat in the same boat of misunderstanding as the audience was. By walking the streets of New York and discussing Shakespeare in the most usually of places demonstrates how Pacino envisioned Shakespeare to be a more intricate part of our daily lives. As a participatory film, Pacino demonstrates the art of documenting by choosing the scenes in which he is selecting the settings for the shots to be filmed, he controls the dialogue that takes place on camera and decides which scenes of the play with be discussed more extensively on camera. This film gained a new appreciation from an old fan by noticing the different cinematic techniques that Al Pacino considers while they take place on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Keep Looking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    proteus6847
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ninety minutes of mind-numbing incompetence. Pacino played Richard twice on stage (in 1973 and 1979) and both times he was blasted by the critics, for the simple and sufficient reason that he has no classical talent. Prior to making this film, his only other venture into Shakespeare was as Marc Antony in an early 80s production of Julius Caesar: here, too, the critics came to bury Al, not to praise him. But nothing can daunt a stubborn egomaniac. Well, almost nothing, for you'll note that this isn't a film version of Richard III, but rather a documentary about Pacino's "search" for the character. Interesting, that. Did Branagh make a film called "Looking for Henry V"? No, he made a film version of Henry V. Did Olivier make a film called "Looking for Othello"? No, he made a film version of Othello. So what's up here? Why is Al presenting us with a "search" for the thing instead of the thing itself? I'll give you three guesses.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling from the shoulders of giants
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timboyork
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite being accompanied by some very fine actors and receiving some excellent advice, Mr Pacino turns a fine tragedy into an unintended comedy. He is clearly illiterate and ego-driven, a fatal combination when approaching the finest of all literary works. His performance mimics English actors - cadences, tonality and let's not forget iambic pentameter (could he even spell it?) - from the likes of Olivier, Gielgud, Burton ... Perhaps he was convinced that a switch of genre could work by Gielgud's triumph in Arthur and Burton's successes. Perhaps not. He seems at odds with the plot and language of the play throughout. So, why try? We are left to guess. Unfortunately, he simply makes himself ridiculous. You're very good at what you know, Al. But, you don't know this play, buddy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bringing Shakespeare to the masses
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blanche-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Looking for Richard" has Al Pacino, over a four-year period while he filmed various other things, delving into Shakespeare's Richard III with a cast of wonderful actors. The premise is that American actors approach Shakespeare too reverentially. Pacino gathers various actors, using places such as the Cloisters and St. John the Divine Church, to analyze, rehearse, and perform Richard III. Pacino amassed something like 80 hours, cut down to two. There are interviews with stars such as Kevin Kline, Vanessa Redgrave, F. Murray Abraham, Viveka Lindfors, Kenneth Branagh, Kevin Kline, John Gielgud, Peter Brook, and many others, including the man on the street. The final players include Kevin Conway, Kevin Spacey, Winona Ryder, Harris Yulin, Alec Baldwin, Estelle Parsons, Aiden Quinn and others. Scenes from the play are interspersed with discussion and rehearsal. Pacino's Richard emerges as raw, tough, and manipulative, whereas Olivier's was a complete slimeball. Both approaches work. This is an excellent film to show to high school students learning Shakespeare as Pacino takes some of the language apart -- the film makes the language and the human feelings and motivations behind the words very accessible. Truly excellent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You found him, Al!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (brice@crawfordredfern.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having lately seen Kevin Spacey's marvellous 'King Richard III' at London's Old Vic (on Broadway in a month or two) I had to see again this splendid exploration of Shakespeare, Richard and the wariness by the American public of WS and the phobic approach to his work of some actors. Yet years ago Brando joined John Gielgud and James Mason to play a thrilling Mark Antony in Mankiewicz's 'Julius Caesar', and here an American cast show themselves fine Shakespearean actors. Spacey (young and handsome!) is most enjoyable as Richard's conniving spin=doctor, Buckingham, and in his inevitably fragmented portrayal Pacino shows what a dark, deadly and witty Crookback he would be - on film or stage.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As masterful director as Al is an actor (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    From my education, Shakespeare isn't for common people and I praise Al to invest his stature to bring Shakespeare to us. Thus, this movie is really exciting because there are really two story lines nicely melted together: the Shakespeare's play and the passion of Al. For those like me who rates Al as their best actor, this is a must-see. The character of Richard is black as coal and Al has always been never better with those perfidious and nasty guys. On the opposite, in the real life, Al is a warm-full, sweet person and with his documentary, he opens this door for us and offers to take a peek. In addition, it's great to see Al and his pals talking about the play, looking for great exteriors and visiting the original place of Shakespeare. You see the mystery of creation in art and this special birth is always a memorable event. Actually, despite being hard of hearing (and fearing to become deaf), I just like Al's voice: it's amazing how much feelings he can show with it. That's why i'm just laughing when actors like Pitt are depicted as great because they are dwarfs compared to Al. In conclusion, beyond being "the" actor, Al reveals himself as an inspired director and he should direct more!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Traynor
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to study Richard III and Looking For Richard for school and, lucky for me I like Shakespeare so I understand it. When I was told we were studying Looking For Richard as well, I was skeptical because often the English staff choose bad movies but I really did enjoy this film immensely. Al Pacino had a brilliant idea to try and make Shakespeare more accessible to the modern public, more so the modern American public and he does a brilliant job of this. It is different though because he does not really change it too much. The cast is also very good and contains a number of famous names. Even though I have to study this film for an English class I would gladly watch this film anyway which is a testament to the film. Absolutely fantastic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wildwoodmusic
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow! I just found this. Been out of the country for a long time and I seem to have missed a lot. I love Shakespeare and have seen many, many productions and films. I find this fascinating and could have watched more. Some say it was laughable, I don't see it. It is a learning experience and Pacino captured Richard perfectly. Better then most I have seen. There is a lovely mix of the scholarly, the actor's processes and a good bit of fun. I felt as if I was discovering new views along with the actors. Maybe it isn't to everyone's tastes but it beats out the pablum that is the usual fair in these times. I too greatly regret the whole film was never made and released in conjunction with Looking for Richard. It would have been magnificent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
