<filme>
 <id>
  854
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092610
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1987
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Trash - N&aacute;usea Total
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The population of a small town disappears and is replaced by aliens that chase human flesh for their intergalactic fast-food chain.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Derek and his friends must investigate the missing people in a small village. Then they find out its human formed aliens that are really big headed monsters that used all the people in the small village into their snack burgers. Now, Derek must save the day and the world with his chainsaw before the meat eaters strikes the whole planet. Will Derek kill all the aliens?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   alien
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fast food
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new zealand
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   chainsaw
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   small town
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Peter Jackson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Peter Jackson
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Tony Hiles
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Terry Potter
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Pete O'Herne
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Craig Smith
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sometimes jokingly remark how Peter Jackson's career was perfect until he directed the Lord of the Rings trilogy. It's hard to imagine that this director, who now specializes in big budget Hollywood movies, started off by creating twisted and gory low budget movies  his directorial debut, Bad Taste, being the prime example of this early, strange phase. Bad Taste was by no means an easy experience for Jackson, since the filming took 4 years. However, the hard work paid off and Bad Taste can be used as a valuable lesson in "do-it-yourself: low budget film making". It's amazing how, in spite of rather limited resources, Jackson managed to make it all work and look good  he created the masks and firearm replicas for the movie himself. He even constructed his own counterweighted steady-cam. Bad Taste is a definite must see for every aspiring movie maker, if only for Peter Jackson's creativity. The movie follows 4 agents (called 'The Boys') of some sort of secret service, who investigate alien activity in a small town. Apparently, the aliens have killed the whole population and replaced it. Things become more complicated when the aliens kidnap a charity collector passing through, and it's up to The Boys to save him, by using any means necessary. As you can see, Bad Taste's plot is fairly simple, there isn't much "story" to it  the movie is mainly action and dialogue driven. Due to this fact, the movie gets boring from time to time and I find it to be the worst from Peter Jackson's early phase. I also find it to be the least funny one. While there are quite a few amusing scenes, it doesn't even come close to other early classics like Braindead and Meet the Feebles. But at least there is enough violence and gore in it to make it interesting. The movie does get pretty graphic. Did you first notice the guy missing the top of his head or the Peter Jackson cameo? The effects in the movie (influenced by the cult special effects artist Tom Savini) are surely its best quality. You'll see heads exploding, limbs being torn off and even some chainsaw action. The scene which impressed me the most was the one where a character, played by Peter Jackson, fights with another character  also played by Peter Jackson. Actually, if you're not informed prior to the watching of movie, you may not notice he plays two different characters since they don't really look alike. Who knows  maybe Jackson has an acting talent waiting to be further developed? Speaking of acting, the actors did an OK job for this kind of movie, no one is laughably bad. On a side note, I think it's important to remark that all of the dialogue was dubbed in post production; that, however, isn't much of a bother since it isn't very apparent. While I wasn't really keen on Bad Taste (like I said  I found it to be somewhat boring and I prefer other early Jackson works) I would definitely recommend it to everyone. It's a gory, funny trash/cult flick about some guys fighting off a bunch of butt shaped aliens, set to an 80s heavy metal soundtrack. Why wouldn't you watch it? Rating: 6/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Until Jackson's follow-up 'Brain Dead', this may have been the goriest film ever made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jack Hawkins (Hawkensian)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love 'Bad Taste'. I love that the film was made for about $20 and that the cast consists of Peter Jackson's mates. It's also so enjoyable because it demonstrates how talented a filmmaker Jackson is. For example, there is a scene near the beginning of the film where Derek (Peter Jackson) fights with some alien invaders on a cliff side, it is hilariously gory and feels so very dangerous; through sheer talent (and a massive amount of bravery!), the crew achieves a tangible sense of acrophobia. In 'Bad Taste', Earth is under threat from alien invaders who are endeavouring to fill a culinary gap in their intergalactic fast-food market  the demand for tasty human flesh. The malicious extra- terrestrials don't arouse suspicion as they assume human appearances. Before the Astro Investigation and Defence Service (AIDS) arrive, the malevolent visitors have already wiped out the entire town of Kaihoro, New Zealand. This elite team is comprised of Derek (Peter Jackson), a rather odd Kiwi with an insatiable bloodlust, Barry (Pete O'Hearn), a man who will use his .44 Magnum only when necessary and Frank (Mike Minett), Giles (Craig Smith) and Ozzy (Terry Potter), a trio of muscle car driving tough guys. Jackson's early films have a real talent for choreographing slapstick gore, there are heads being blown off, brains being eaten, arms being torn off, severed heads being drop kicked, seagulls being head butted, entire bodies being chain sawed and even sheep being detonated. The film is utterly drenched in an outrageous amount of viscera; however it is all of the slapstick variety with a strong Commonwealth lacing of black humour. Though the film is by no means a performance film, there is a certain charm about the cast's inexperience. Also, Peter Jackson is hilarious as the absurd, demented Derek, whose horrible shrill laugh and personal motto 'I'm a Derek, Dereks don't run!' are particularly memorable. The filming locations, such as the aforementioned cliff side, are all of outstanding natural beauty; 'Bad Taste' is as much an advertisement for the country as Jackson's later work would be. As we all know, Jackson has since gone downhill, directing the poxy 'Lord of the Rings' and 'The Hobbit' trilogies  what a shame. However, he has recently expressed interest in making another horror film; I just hope he sticks to his roots with a shoestring budget and an immeasurable amount of corn syrup and gore. www.hawkensian.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's about time Jackson was funny again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before Peter Jackson almost exclusively worked with a CGI backdrop in the land of Middle-Earth, he began his film making career in the realms of low budget comedy-horror. Utilising the 1980's trend for splatter cinema, and no doubt the influence of Sam Raimi's tongue-in-cheek zombie film, The Evil Dead (1982), Jackson's debut feature film was entrenched in a very American tradition, but beholds the humour of his native New Zealand - which incidentally is part of the British commonwealth, meaning much of the uniqueness of British comedy is transposed onto the antipodean nation, the influence of Monty Python being one particular aspect of the film that made it such a surprise success. Bad Taste was clearly a labour of love, with Jackson bringing friends and family in to contribute to the making. The nature of the films production adds something quite special to both the narrative and the humour. The home- made special effects and props (Jackson used his parents oven to bake the handmade armoury used in the film) work both as farce and as actually quite an achievement of authenticity. Set in a small, isolated town, a group of misfits, "The Boys," ordered from a shadowy government department, have been sent to investigate an invasion, where aliens have wiped out the inhabitants. What transpires is an alien fast food corporation have discovered that human flesh is the galaxy's newest taste sensation, and are accumulating cardboard boxes of flesh to market and sell to planets. At the centre of the government group is geeky scientist, Derek (Played by Jackson himself - he is also in the role of the alien Robert), who "can only relate to birds". He salivates at the sight of dismemberment and artillery. As the group discover the truth about the alien invasion, their mission is to stop them from leaving the planet. On a narrative level, Bad Taste is as simple as they come. But underneath this simplicity is a wealth of brilliantly formed characters, with their own idiosyncrasies, and a range of beautifully crafted one liners and references. There are some stand out moments created with gruesome, cheep, but effective effects. The aliens seem to be mostly influenced by the zombie cinema of George A. Romero, with their slow moving mannerisms, and like Romero and Savini, Jackson delights in slicing them up with sharp tools and exploding them with guns. One alien has the top half of his head chopped off, a scene that displays Jackson's talent for editing, as he seamlessly cuts from the actors legs stumbling, to the rubbery half-head spurting copious amounts of blood and gore. Derek provides some of the most grotesque, Grand Guignol elements after he falls from a cliff, leaving a skull flat that exposes his brain matter. After this event, he constantly battles to keep the brain inside his head, strapping it closed with a belt. These scenes merge those ideas the comedy of the absurd, with the horrific splatter of giallo or the ridiculously over- the-top gore films of Herschell Gordon Lewis. Considering the limitations of the incredibly low budget (according to IMDb, the films budget was estimated at 30,000 NZD), the film looks good. Of course the film stock, the acting and the special effects aren't up to some of the more expensive American productions of its type, but with an insanely funny script, and the excessive nature of the violence, it is a film that should be loved. I do remember first seeing this film on video around 1989/1990, no doubt initially attracted by the latex alien on the video cover flipping the bird. It was soon the talk of the playground, as school friends would delight in the gore. But more specifically, I, along with my peers, were fundamentally reacting to the outlandish and on-the-money comedy, which holds up today as much as the first two Monty Python films. Gross-out comedy on this scale, has not been so much fun as this since. It's a shame Jackson hides away in Middle-Earth so much these days, it's about time he was funny again. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, witty and playfully violent - but not to everyone's taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not too many movies with limited budget producing good outcome, especially if sci-fi is involved as one has to provide resources for camera tricks. As for Bad Taste, this movie was made for less than 30,000 USD - but it took years to complete it. The plot is peculiar and main characters is uncommon mixture of zombies and aliens. The ending is witty and distinctive - and all this is years before when Tarantino or Rodriguez began their famous mishmashes. The cast is totally amateur - Jackson's friends and acquaintances - but in a good sense, giving an interesting purity and fun. As for Jackson himself, he showed himself as talented actor, he could be used more in this function as well (later he has appeared only in cameo roles). In short, an interesting and already a cult movie, recommended to all fans of horror alien movies, but preferably no eating during watching! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most memorable treats!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avinash Shukla
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Peter Jackson for his bizarre creativity. Bad Taste, Braindead, Meet the Feebles are all bizarre in their own way. As I love splatsticks, I worship 'Bad Taste' for the position it holds in the world of splatter cinema. Peter Jackson has a strange way of using gore. His gory sequences are seldom disturbing and overuse of fake blood makes the gore look like a comedic device, which should be laughed and laughed upon for eternity! So what's the story about 'Bad Taste'? This is a typical B-film but is slicker and more tongue-in-cheek than any of the films that fall into the category of extreme cinema. Jackson's tales never let the viewer lose interest in his films. Perhaps Jackson is such an artist who can make murder look like plain humor! Considering the limitations Jackson faced both financially and technically during the filming of 'Bad Taste', the film looks as great as Taj Mahal to me. The tale is fairly simple at heart. The Astro Investigation Defense Service sends 4 men Ozzy (Terry Potter), Derek (Peter Jackson), Barry (Pete O'Herne) and Frank (Mike Minett) to a town 'Kaihoro' (Food-town in Maori?) to discover the reason behind unexplained disappearances of the townspeople. The men find blood splattered everywhere with no trace of the townsfolk. The place looks like an abattoir, as Barry tells Derek on his radio. The men soon come to know that the town is plagued with zombies, who will kill anything that comes their way. Detailed findings lead the men to the whereabouts of the zombies where they have all gathered for a meet. The meet is hosted by their chief Lord Crumb (Doug Wren). The men come to know that Lord Crumb and his zombie force are actually extraterrestrial beings in the guise of humans and have plans of harvesting human meat for their own intergalactic food franchise. So the dead townsfolk are now in the boxes, ready for the alien consumption! The men also find Giles (Craig Smith), a donation collector in a drum, soaked in spices and free him. Watching for the right time to strike, they all take positions and open fire at the dawn. Causing heavy casualties, the men force Lord Crumb to retreat in his home-faced-UFO. However, Derek has plans of his own that are more sinister than Lord Crumb could have ever imagined. The film as you can see is based on hyper-imagination. Jackson however makes this work. 'Bad Taste' has great comedy scenes and an appealing atmosphere. Thanks to Jackson's hometown Pukerua Bay and the New Zealand lush belt, where this flick was shot. These locations add good atmosphere in the film and shaky camera work at places makes the viewer dizzy. Over-the-top splatter plays a special role here and gives enough reality to the film. So if you're a kind of person who loves to puke on the nasty, give this a try. I am sure you won't be disappointed, and don't forget to watch Peter Jackson's evil twin Robert!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stay where you are then, and I'll give you an eye witness description of this, intergalactic w*nker!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I expect you're wondering what you're doing soaking in Reg's eleven secret herbs and spices. Tomorrow we're having you for lunch!" Yes, the aliens have turned the villagers into tasty burgers, and Derek (Peter Jackson) must defeat them before they spread to the whole world. This time the good guy has the chainsaw, but will he be able to defeat the evil corporate aliens who are just trying to supply their fast-food chain? And, yes, this is the same Peter Jackson of Lord of the Rings fame. Be prepared for some really bloody scenes, and humor that borders on the outrageous. Borders, heck, it is outrageously funny. Oh yes, lots of gooey, icky stuff coming out of bodies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It is what the title says, in the funniest possible way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan Ashley (DanLives1980)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the '80's and early '90's visionary director of 'Lord of the Rings', 'King Kong' and 'The Lovely Bones' Peter Jackson was making the type of films some countries don't even allow today, outside of Asia and the US. It may come as a shock for fans of his work this last decade to witness 'Meet The Feebles' or 'Braindead' and vice versa for fans of his old outings. 'Bad Taste' is an action-sci-fi-horror about a small unit of dimwitted rejects from the fictional governmental department "the Astro Investigation and Defence Service" (AIDS LOL) who are stationed in various locations around a deserted coastal town, which has been wiped out by alien invaders. Upon two of their unit being marauded by groups of the aliens disguised as humans, they regroup and head in to gather intelligence where they discover Earth has been targeted by the ruthless leader of one of the galaxy's biggest fast food corporations, hence the title, 'Bad Taste!' The film is possibly one of the tackiest and most absurd ever conceived, yet boasts of its absurdity because it is so notoriously fun to watch and has some pretty fantastic (although dated) practical special effects, and people will even watch it over and over again to remind themselves how bad it is. What people don't seem to get is that it's a balls-out parody that simply doesn't count on inter-textual references to be understood. Instead it counts on the childish humour of a bunch of male friends most likely trying to test their girlfriends' gag reflexes, almost like a fictional Jackass or Dirty Sanchez movie. It's a boys film that cuts out all the unnecessary plot and dialogue and goes straight for the knives, guns, bazookas, chainsaws, blood and guts and vomit gags, nothing more, nothing less. I may be biased in voting it a 7 out of 10 but still I tried to be fair. It's badly acted, badly produced, badly offensive and pure bad taste in every way possible but still, the performers in the movie are likable and they provide you with a lot of laughs. Peter Jackson must have made this from his garden shed back then, but if that's the case, what an effort. Love it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not gonna gloss anything over in the review....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    witster18
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tough film to review here! Bad Taste is essentially Peter Jackson learning the ropes and experimenting with practically zero cash. The result is a gory and sometimes funny mess. He polished this formula up for 'Dead Alive', and 'Dead Alive' definitely shows a progression both in Jackson's talent, and his pocketbook(although DA had a small budget too). You can see Jackson's influences. Direction similar to early Romero, and Gore that reminds me of some of the late 70's/early 80's gore-fests. The gore here is in heavy doses, and it is probably the strongest characteristic of this film - along with what he achieved overall given the restrictions with the budget and cast. He learned from the best... Other influences were surely make-up masterminds like Tom Savini and Rick Baker. You have to be in the right mindset to enjoy this movie. I've seen it three times. The first time was years ago and I didn't enjoy the film at all. Years later, after realizing that you don't have to take everything so serious, and that horror films can be as funny as they are scary - I gave it another whirl. I laughed on a few occasions and my interest was sparked but not glued. The third time I concentrated more on Jackson's technique and the little nuances that make this film more of a lesson in film-making than an enjoyable 90 minutes. My conclusion. Bad Taste is a film to be appreciated by horror/comedy fans, and fans of making film - because it's essentially someone just like you making their first backyard movie. The only difference is the effort and the near flawless shots of gore and tension that can only be achieved at the hands of someone who is A.Talented, B.Meticulous, and C.An Obvious Film-Buff. He was paying attention to how Romero achieved tension with his close-ups and sound,... and the editing here, for what it is, is amazing. The plot is a dose of Comedy, horror, and sci-fi. Bad Taste is a bitter-sweet, low-budget gore-fest with humor to boot. All that said - most people will NOT enjoy this movie. If you just love gore.. or film-making.... or the Evil Dead Series... or find yourself in love with Cult Classics like Toxic Avenger Etc... then sure, you might like it. Otherwise, skip this one because many Cult-Classics like this have extremely inflated scores here on IMDb. That's because 90% of the small number of reviewers have seen it 90 times, and that 90% is rating this a 10. It's no 10!... It's not even close!... it's exactly what I said it was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Super size me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know. Scores of Millions of dollars is OK too, but why would Peter Jackson insist on doing what he's been doing over the last decade, when he obviously found his calling in life as director of the goriest, craziest, and most outrageous splatter flicks available? And the man only made two of them, yet made a lasting, not to mention an influential impression. Before 1992's Dead Alive (still the goriest film in existence), Jackson would shoot on video, what has to be the greatest sci-fi-gore-comedy in the history of New Zealand. This is Bad Taste. It's what I've always said. There just ain't enough micro-budgeted, sci-comedy with lots and lots of gore. As sweet as the gore is, it really does take a backseat to the comic genius this film offers. Bad Taste is about an alien fast-food franchise who recently decided that human flesh would be a good choice for their menu. Cheap, convenient, not bad. After decimating the entire town of Kaihoro, in New Zealand, the Astro- Investigation and Defense Service is called in to exterminate these guys, who can take the form of humans at will. These eager beavers are ready to blow a hole in anything that moves, so if any actual humans get killed in the process, what the hell? These guys ain't too bright, and they're probably half-crazy, but they totally mean well, with trying to save the world and whatnot. Wanna know something funny? After at least 2 or 3 viewings of this film, something really peculiar occurred to me. There isn't one female to be found in Bad Taste. While it isn't a large cast to begin with, and I'm not really sure what purpose a woman would serve in a sci-fi gore-comedy, I just think it's peculiar. And no. None of this is relevant. But, anyway. What a happy day it will be when, I mean if Peter Jackson decides to return to his gory roots one more time. Since he's already done the alien thing, and not to mention the living dead masterpiece that is Dead Alive, perhaps Jackson should make a disgustingly gory Vampire flick. Or maybe he should just keep making big-budget kids movies. Yeah. That sounds about right. Something tells me Peter Jackson's days as director of films like Bad Taste and other awsomeness are long gone. Whatever. Plenty of other cult Horror filmmakers out there, doin' their thing. But there was a time, not that long ago that your beloved Lord Of The Rings guy was out there doing some amazing stuff in the underground. Once again, Dead Alive would be the best example of this theory, but Bad Taste is nothing short of amazing in its own right. That doesn't necessarily mean you should then go rush off and buy Meet The Feebles as well. That's another story for another day. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Splatterfest Flick, Jackson's Greatest Hit!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tequila101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care what anybody says about this flick but I think this is Peter Jackson's best work. After watching "Meet the Feebles" nearly seven years ago, as a kid I was always edging to watch "Bad Taste" and I was seriously expecting this to be cheap and stupid but instead I got more than what i asked for. This film for the 80's has top notch gore, funny-ass scenes, impossible situations and non stop horrific/comedic action. I always wanted to see this film as a kid and now, I'm glad that I did. The Alien look is very creative and I also love the switch between music themes, first we had creepy adventures, and very wondrous tones of what's gonna happen next and then, we had old rocking, action packed style of play. It was all very creative. Along with Meet the Feebles, (which the trailer say has no taste at all lol) to and for me this was the next level of a Peter Jackson film and it's absolutely funny and creepy at it's best. Even if I didn't find this scary on any levels and I do think that this film has an insane way of telling it's story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sometimes jokingly remark how Peter Jackson's career was perfect until he directed the Lord of the Rings trilogy. It's hard to imagine that this director, who now specializes in big budget Hollywood movies, started off by creating twisted and gory low budget movies  his directorial debut, Bad Taste, being the prime example of this early, strange phase. Bad Taste was by no means an easy experience for Jackson, since the filming took 4 years. However, the hard work paid off and Bad Taste can be used as a valuable lesson in "do-it-yourself: low budget film making". It's amazing how, in spite of rather limited resources, Jackson managed to make it all work and look good  he created the masks and firearm replicas for the movie himself. He even constructed his own counterweighted steady-cam. Bad Taste is a definite must see for every aspiring movie maker, if only for Peter Jackson's creativity. The movie follows 4 agents (called 'The Boys') of some sort of secret service, who investigate alien activity in a small town. Apparently, the aliens have killed the whole population and replaced it. Things become more complicated when the aliens kidnap a charity collector passing through, and it's up to The Boys to save him, by using any means necessary. As you can see, Bad Taste's plot is fairly simple, there isn't much "story" to it  the movie is mainly action and dialogue driven. Due to this fact, the movie gets boring from time to time and I find it to be the worst from Peter Jackson's early phase. I also find it to be the least funny one. While there are quite a few amusing scenes, it doesn't even come close to other early classics like Braindead and Meet the Feebles. But at least there is enough violence and gore in it to make it interesting. The movie does get pretty graphic. Did you first notice the guy missing the top of his head or the Peter Jackson cameo? The effects in the movie (influenced by the cult special effects artist Tom Savini) are surely its best quality. You'll see heads exploding, limbs being torn off and even some chainsaw action. The scene which impressed me the most was the one where a character, played by Peter Jackson, fights with another character  also played by Peter Jackson. Actually, if you're not informed prior to the watching of movie, you may not notice he plays two different characters since they don't really look alike. Who knows  maybe Jackson has an acting talent waiting to be further developed? Speaking of acting, the actors did an OK job for this kind of movie, no one is laughably bad. On a side note, I think it's important to remark that all of the dialogue was dubbed in post production; that, however, isn't much of a bother since it isn't very apparent. While I wasn't really keen on Bad Taste (like I said  I found it to be somewhat boring and I prefer other early Jackson works) I would definitely recommend it to everyone. It's a gory, funny trash/cult flick about some guys fighting off a bunch of butt shaped aliens, set to an 80s heavy metal soundtrack. Why wouldn't you watch it? Rating: 6/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Until Jackson's follow-up 'Brain Dead', this may have been the goriest film ever made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jack Hawkins (Hawkensian)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love 'Bad Taste'. I love that the film was made for about $20 and that the cast consists of Peter Jackson's mates. It's also so enjoyable because it demonstrates how talented a filmmaker Jackson is. For example, there is a scene near the beginning of the film where Derek (Peter Jackson) fights with some alien invaders on a cliff side, it is hilariously gory and feels so very dangerous; through sheer talent (and a massive amount of bravery!), the crew achieves a tangible sense of acrophobia. In 'Bad Taste', Earth is under threat from alien invaders who are endeavouring to fill a culinary gap in their intergalactic fast-food market  the demand for tasty human flesh. The malicious extra- terrestrials don't arouse suspicion as they assume human appearances. Before the Astro Investigation and Defence Service (AIDS) arrive, the malevolent visitors have already wiped out the entire town of Kaihoro, New Zealand. This elite team is comprised of Derek (Peter Jackson), a rather odd Kiwi with an insatiable bloodlust, Barry (Pete O'Hearn), a man who will use his .44 Magnum only when necessary and Frank (Mike Minett), Giles (Craig Smith) and Ozzy (Terry Potter), a trio of muscle car driving tough guys. Jackson's early films have a real talent for choreographing slapstick gore, there are heads being blown off, brains being eaten, arms being torn off, severed heads being drop kicked, seagulls being head butted, entire bodies being chain sawed and even sheep being detonated. The film is utterly drenched in an outrageous amount of viscera; however it is all of the slapstick variety with a strong Commonwealth lacing of black humour. Though the film is by no means a performance film, there is a certain charm about the cast's inexperience. Also, Peter Jackson is hilarious as the absurd, demented Derek, whose horrible shrill laugh and personal motto 'I'm a Derek, Dereks don't run!' are particularly memorable. The filming locations, such as the aforementioned cliff side, are all of outstanding natural beauty; 'Bad Taste' is as much an advertisement for the country as Jackson's later work would be. As we all know, Jackson has since gone downhill, directing the poxy 'Lord of the Rings' and 'The Hobbit' trilogies  what a shame. However, he has recently expressed interest in making another horror film; I just hope he sticks to his roots with a shoestring budget and an immeasurable amount of corn syrup and gore. www.hawkensian.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's about time Jackson was funny again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before Peter Jackson almost exclusively worked with a CGI backdrop in the land of Middle-Earth, he began his film making career in the realms of low budget comedy-horror. Utilising the 1980's trend for splatter cinema, and no doubt the influence of Sam Raimi's tongue-in-cheek zombie film, The Evil Dead (1982), Jackson's debut feature film was entrenched in a very American tradition, but beholds the humour of his native New Zealand - which incidentally is part of the British commonwealth, meaning much of the uniqueness of British comedy is transposed onto the antipodean nation, the influence of Monty Python being one particular aspect of the film that made it such a surprise success. Bad Taste was clearly a labour of love, with Jackson bringing friends and family in to contribute to the making. The nature of the films production adds something quite special to both the narrative and the humour. The home- made special effects and props (Jackson used his parents oven to bake the handmade armoury used in the film) work both as farce and as actually quite an achievement of authenticity. Set in a small, isolated town, a group of misfits, "The Boys," ordered from a shadowy government department, have been sent to investigate an invasion, where aliens have wiped out the inhabitants. What transpires is an alien fast food corporation have discovered that human flesh is the galaxy's newest taste sensation, and are accumulating cardboard boxes of flesh to market and sell to planets. At the centre of the government group is geeky scientist, Derek (Played by Jackson himself - he is also in the role of the alien Robert), who "can only relate to birds". He salivates at the sight of dismemberment and artillery. As the group discover the truth about the alien invasion, their mission is to stop them from leaving the planet. On a narrative level, Bad Taste is as simple as they come. But underneath this simplicity is a wealth of brilliantly formed characters, with their own idiosyncrasies, and a range of beautifully crafted one liners and references. There are some stand out moments created with gruesome, cheep, but effective effects. The aliens seem to be mostly influenced by the zombie cinema of George A. Romero, with their slow moving mannerisms, and like Romero and Savini, Jackson delights in slicing them up with sharp tools and exploding them with guns. One alien has the top half of his head chopped off, a scene that displays Jackson's talent for editing, as he seamlessly cuts from the actors legs stumbling, to the rubbery half-head spurting copious amounts of blood and gore. Derek provides some of the most grotesque, Grand Guignol elements after he falls from a cliff, leaving a skull flat that exposes his brain matter. After this event, he constantly battles to keep the brain inside his head, strapping it closed with a belt. These scenes merge those ideas the comedy of the absurd, with the horrific splatter of giallo or the ridiculously over- the-top gore films of Herschell Gordon Lewis. Considering the limitations of the incredibly low budget (according to IMDb, the films budget was estimated at 30,000 NZD), the film looks good. Of course the film stock, the acting and the special effects aren't up to some of the more expensive American productions of its type, but with an insanely funny script, and the excessive nature of the violence, it is a film that should be loved. I do remember first seeing this film on video around 1989/1990, no doubt initially attracted by the latex alien on the video cover flipping the bird. It was soon the talk of the playground, as school friends would delight in the gore. But more specifically, I, along with my peers, were fundamentally reacting to the outlandish and on-the-money comedy, which holds up today as much as the first two Monty Python films. Gross-out comedy on this scale, has not been so much fun as this since. It's a shame Jackson hides away in Middle-Earth so much these days, it's about time he was funny again. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, witty and playfully violent - but not to everyone's taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not too many movies with limited budget producing good outcome, especially if sci-fi is involved as one has to provide resources for camera tricks. As for Bad Taste, this movie was made for less than 30,000 USD - but it took years to complete it. The plot is peculiar and main characters is uncommon mixture of zombies and aliens. The ending is witty and distinctive - and all this is years before when Tarantino or Rodriguez began their famous mishmashes. The cast is totally amateur - Jackson's friends and acquaintances - but in a good sense, giving an interesting purity and fun. As for Jackson himself, he showed himself as talented actor, he could be used more in this function as well (later he has appeared only in cameo roles). In short, an interesting and already a cult movie, recommended to all fans of horror alien movies, but preferably no eating during watching! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most memorable treats!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avinash Shukla
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Peter Jackson for his bizarre creativity. Bad Taste, Braindead, Meet the Feebles are all bizarre in their own way. As I love splatsticks, I worship 'Bad Taste' for the position it holds in the world of splatter cinema. Peter Jackson has a strange way of using gore. His gory sequences are seldom disturbing and overuse of fake blood makes the gore look like a comedic device, which should be laughed and laughed upon for eternity! So what's the story about 'Bad Taste'? This is a typical B-film but is slicker and more tongue-in-cheek than any of the films that fall into the category of extreme cinema. Jackson's tales never let the viewer lose interest in his films. Perhaps Jackson is such an artist who can make murder look like plain humor! Considering the limitations Jackson faced both financially and technically during the filming of 'Bad Taste', the film looks as great as Taj Mahal to me. The tale is fairly simple at heart. The Astro Investigation Defense Service sends 4 men Ozzy (Terry Potter), Derek (Peter Jackson), Barry (Pete O'Herne) and Frank (Mike Minett) to a town 'Kaihoro' (Food-town in Maori?) to discover the reason behind unexplained disappearances of the townspeople. The men find blood splattered everywhere with no trace of the townsfolk. The place looks like an abattoir, as Barry tells Derek on his radio. The men soon come to know that the town is plagued with zombies, who will kill anything that comes their way. Detailed findings lead the men to the whereabouts of the zombies where they have all gathered for a meet. The meet is hosted by their chief Lord Crumb (Doug Wren). The men come to know that Lord Crumb and his zombie force are actually extraterrestrial beings in the guise of humans and have plans of harvesting human meat for their own intergalactic food franchise. So the dead townsfolk are now in the boxes, ready for the alien consumption! The men also find Giles (Craig Smith), a donation collector in a drum, soaked in spices and free him. Watching for the right time to strike, they all take positions and open fire at the dawn. Causing heavy casualties, the men force Lord Crumb to retreat in his home-faced-UFO. However, Derek has plans of his own that are more sinister than Lord Crumb could have ever imagined. The film as you can see is based on hyper-imagination. Jackson however makes this work. 'Bad Taste' has great comedy scenes and an appealing atmosphere. Thanks to Jackson's hometown Pukerua Bay and the New Zealand lush belt, where this flick was shot. These locations add good atmosphere in the film and shaky camera work at places makes the viewer dizzy. Over-the-top splatter plays a special role here and gives enough reality to the film. So if you're a kind of person who loves to puke on the nasty, give this a try. I am sure you won't be disappointed, and don't forget to watch Peter Jackson's evil twin Robert!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stay where you are then, and I'll give you an eye witness description of this, intergalactic w*nker!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I expect you're wondering what you're doing soaking in Reg's eleven secret herbs and spices. Tomorrow we're having you for lunch!" Yes, the aliens have turned the villagers into tasty burgers, and Derek (Peter Jackson) must defeat them before they spread to the whole world. This time the good guy has the chainsaw, but will he be able to defeat the evil corporate aliens who are just trying to supply their fast-food chain? And, yes, this is the same Peter Jackson of Lord of the Rings fame. Be prepared for some really bloody scenes, and humor that borders on the outrageous. Borders, heck, it is outrageously funny. Oh yes, lots of gooey, icky stuff coming out of bodies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It is what the title says, in the funniest possible way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan Ashley (DanLives1980)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the '80's and early '90's visionary director of 'Lord of the Rings', 'King Kong' and 'The Lovely Bones' Peter Jackson was making the type of films some countries don't even allow today, outside of Asia and the US. It may come as a shock for fans of his work this last decade to witness 'Meet The Feebles' or 'Braindead' and vice versa for fans of his old outings. 'Bad Taste' is an action-sci-fi-horror about a small unit of dimwitted rejects from the fictional governmental department "the Astro Investigation and Defence Service" (AIDS LOL) who are stationed in various locations around a deserted coastal town, which has been wiped out by alien invaders. Upon two of their unit being marauded by groups of the aliens disguised as humans, they regroup and head in to gather intelligence where they discover Earth has been targeted by the ruthless leader of one of the galaxy's biggest fast food corporations, hence the title, 'Bad Taste!' The film is possibly one of the tackiest and most absurd ever conceived, yet boasts of its absurdity because it is so notoriously fun to watch and has some pretty fantastic (although dated) practical special effects, and people will even watch it over and over again to remind themselves how bad it is. What people don't seem to get is that it's a balls-out parody that simply doesn't count on inter-textual references to be understood. Instead it counts on the childish humour of a bunch of male friends most likely trying to test their girlfriends' gag reflexes, almost like a fictional Jackass or Dirty Sanchez movie. It's a boys film that cuts out all the unnecessary plot and dialogue and goes straight for the knives, guns, bazookas, chainsaws, blood and guts and vomit gags, nothing more, nothing less. I may be biased in voting it a 7 out of 10 but still I tried to be fair. It's badly acted, badly produced, badly offensive and pure bad taste in every way possible but still, the performers in the movie are likable and they provide you with a lot of laughs. Peter Jackson must have made this from his garden shed back then, but if that's the case, what an effort. Love it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not gonna gloss anything over in the review....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    witster18
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tough film to review here! Bad Taste is essentially Peter Jackson learning the ropes and experimenting with practically zero cash. The result is a gory and sometimes funny mess. He polished this formula up for 'Dead Alive', and 'Dead Alive' definitely shows a progression both in Jackson's talent, and his pocketbook(although DA had a small budget too). You can see Jackson's influences. Direction similar to early Romero, and Gore that reminds me of some of the late 70's/early 80's gore-fests. The gore here is in heavy doses, and it is probably the strongest characteristic of this film - along with what he achieved overall given the restrictions with the budget and cast. He learned from the best... Other influences were surely make-up masterminds like Tom Savini and Rick Baker. You have to be in the right mindset to enjoy this movie. I've seen it three times. The first time was years ago and I didn't enjoy the film at all. Years later, after realizing that you don't have to take everything so serious, and that horror films can be as funny as they are scary - I gave it another whirl. I laughed on a few occasions and my interest was sparked but not glued. The third time I concentrated more on Jackson's technique and the little nuances that make this film more of a lesson in film-making than an enjoyable 90 minutes. My conclusion. Bad Taste is a film to be appreciated by horror/comedy fans, and fans of making film - because it's essentially someone just like you making their first backyard movie. The only difference is the effort and the near flawless shots of gore and tension that can only be achieved at the hands of someone who is A.Talented, B.Meticulous, and C.An Obvious Film-Buff. He was paying attention to how Romero achieved tension with his close-ups and sound,... and the editing here, for what it is, is amazing. The plot is a dose of Comedy, horror, and sci-fi. Bad Taste is a bitter-sweet, low-budget gore-fest with humor to boot. All that said - most people will NOT enjoy this movie. If you just love gore.. or film-making.... or the Evil Dead Series... or find yourself in love with Cult Classics like Toxic Avenger Etc... then sure, you might like it. Otherwise, skip this one because many Cult-Classics like this have extremely inflated scores here on IMDb. That's because 90% of the small number of reviewers have seen it 90 times, and that 90% is rating this a 10. It's no 10!... It's not even close!... it's exactly what I said it was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Super size me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know. Scores of Millions of dollars is OK too, but why would Peter Jackson insist on doing what he's been doing over the last decade, when he obviously found his calling in life as director of the goriest, craziest, and most outrageous splatter flicks available? And the man only made two of them, yet made a lasting, not to mention an influential impression. Before 1992's Dead Alive (still the goriest film in existence), Jackson would shoot on video, what has to be the greatest sci-fi-gore-comedy in the history of New Zealand. This is Bad Taste. It's what I've always said. There just ain't enough micro-budgeted, sci-comedy with lots and lots of gore. As sweet as the gore is, it really does take a backseat to the comic genius this film offers. Bad Taste is about an alien fast-food franchise who recently decided that human flesh would be a good choice for their menu. Cheap, convenient, not bad. After decimating the entire town of Kaihoro, in New Zealand, the Astro- Investigation and Defense Service is called in to exterminate these guys, who can take the form of humans at will. These eager beavers are ready to blow a hole in anything that moves, so if any actual humans get killed in the process, what the hell? These guys ain't too bright, and they're probably half-crazy, but they totally mean well, with trying to save the world and whatnot. Wanna know something funny? After at least 2 or 3 viewings of this film, something really peculiar occurred to me. There isn't one female to be found in Bad Taste. While it isn't a large cast to begin with, and I'm not really sure what purpose a woman would serve in a sci-fi gore-comedy, I just think it's peculiar. And no. None of this is relevant. But, anyway. What a happy day it will be when, I mean if Peter Jackson decides to return to his gory roots one more time. Since he's already done the alien thing, and not to mention the living dead masterpiece that is Dead Alive, perhaps Jackson should make a disgustingly gory Vampire flick. Or maybe he should just keep making big-budget kids movies. Yeah. That sounds about right. Something tells me Peter Jackson's days as director of films like Bad Taste and other awsomeness are long gone. Whatever. Plenty of other cult Horror filmmakers out there, doin' their thing. But there was a time, not that long ago that your beloved Lord Of The Rings guy was out there doing some amazing stuff in the underground. Once again, Dead Alive would be the best example of this theory, but Bad Taste is nothing short of amazing in its own right. That doesn't necessarily mean you should then go rush off and buy Meet The Feebles as well. That's another story for another day. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Splatterfest Flick, Jackson's Greatest Hit!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tequila101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care what anybody says about this flick but I think this is Peter Jackson's best work. After watching "Meet the Feebles" nearly seven years ago, as a kid I was always edging to watch "Bad Taste" and I was seriously expecting this to be cheap and stupid but instead I got more than what i asked for. This film for the 80's has top notch gore, funny-ass scenes, impossible situations and non stop horrific/comedic action. I always wanted to see this film as a kid and now, I'm glad that I did. The Alien look is very creative and I also love the switch between music themes, first we had creepy adventures, and very wondrous tones of what's gonna happen next and then, we had old rocking, action packed style of play. It was all very creative. Along with Meet the Feebles, (which the trailer say has no taste at all lol) to and for me this was the next level of a Peter Jackson film and it's absolutely funny and creepy at it's best. Even if I didn't find this scary on any levels and I do think that this film has an insane way of telling it's story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sometimes jokingly remark how Peter Jackson's career was perfect until he directed the Lord of the Rings trilogy. It's hard to imagine that this director, who now specializes in big budget Hollywood movies, started off by creating twisted and gory low budget movies  his directorial debut, Bad Taste, being the prime example of this early, strange phase. Bad Taste was by no means an easy experience for Jackson, since the filming took 4 years. However, the hard work paid off and Bad Taste can be used as a valuable lesson in "do-it-yourself: low budget film making". It's amazing how, in spite of rather limited resources, Jackson managed to make it all work and look good  he created the masks and firearm replicas for the movie himself. He even constructed his own counterweighted steady-cam. Bad Taste is a definite must see for every aspiring movie maker, if only for Peter Jackson's creativity. The movie follows 4 agents (called 'The Boys') of some sort of secret service, who investigate alien activity in a small town. Apparently, the aliens have killed the whole population and replaced it. Things become more complicated when the aliens kidnap a charity collector passing through, and it's up to The Boys to save him, by using any means necessary. As you can see, Bad Taste's plot is fairly simple, there isn't much "story" to it  the movie is mainly action and dialogue driven. Due to this fact, the movie gets boring from time to time and I find it to be the worst from Peter Jackson's early phase. I also find it to be the least funny one. While there are quite a few amusing scenes, it doesn't even come close to other early classics like Braindead and Meet the Feebles. But at least there is enough violence and gore in it to make it interesting. The movie does get pretty graphic. Did you first notice the guy missing the top of his head or the Peter Jackson cameo? The effects in the movie (influenced by the cult special effects artist Tom Savini) are surely its best quality. You'll see heads exploding, limbs being torn off and even some chainsaw action. The scene which impressed me the most was the one where a character, played by Peter Jackson, fights with another character  also played by Peter Jackson. Actually, if you're not informed prior to the watching of movie, you may not notice he plays two different characters since they don't really look alike. Who knows  maybe Jackson has an acting talent waiting to be further developed? Speaking of acting, the actors did an OK job for this kind of movie, no one is laughably bad. On a side note, I think it's important to remark that all of the dialogue was dubbed in post production; that, however, isn't much of a bother since it isn't very apparent. While I wasn't really keen on Bad Taste (like I said  I found it to be somewhat boring and I prefer other early Jackson works) I would definitely recommend it to everyone. It's a gory, funny trash/cult flick about some guys fighting off a bunch of butt shaped aliens, set to an 80s heavy metal soundtrack. Why wouldn't you watch it? Rating: 6/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Until Jackson's follow-up 'Brain Dead', this may have been the goriest film ever made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jack Hawkins (Hawkensian)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love 'Bad Taste'. I love that the film was made for about $20 and that the cast consists of Peter Jackson's mates. It's also so enjoyable because it demonstrates how talented a filmmaker Jackson is. For example, there is a scene near the beginning of the film where Derek (Peter Jackson) fights with some alien invaders on a cliff side, it is hilariously gory and feels so very dangerous; through sheer talent (and a massive amount of bravery!), the crew achieves a tangible sense of acrophobia. In 'Bad Taste', Earth is under threat from alien invaders who are endeavouring to fill a culinary gap in their intergalactic fast-food market  the demand for tasty human flesh. The malicious extra- terrestrials don't arouse suspicion as they assume human appearances. Before the Astro Investigation and Defence Service (AIDS) arrive, the malevolent visitors have already wiped out the entire town of Kaihoro, New Zealand. This elite team is comprised of Derek (Peter Jackson), a rather odd Kiwi with an insatiable bloodlust, Barry (Pete O'Hearn), a man who will use his .44 Magnum only when necessary and Frank (Mike Minett), Giles (Craig Smith) and Ozzy (Terry Potter), a trio of muscle car driving tough guys. Jackson's early films have a real talent for choreographing slapstick gore, there are heads being blown off, brains being eaten, arms being torn off, severed heads being drop kicked, seagulls being head butted, entire bodies being chain sawed and even sheep being detonated. The film is utterly drenched in an outrageous amount of viscera; however it is all of the slapstick variety with a strong Commonwealth lacing of black humour. Though the film is by no means a performance film, there is a certain charm about the cast's inexperience. Also, Peter Jackson is hilarious as the absurd, demented Derek, whose horrible shrill laugh and personal motto 'I'm a Derek, Dereks don't run!' are particularly memorable. The filming locations, such as the aforementioned cliff side, are all of outstanding natural beauty; 'Bad Taste' is as much an advertisement for the country as Jackson's later work would be. As we all know, Jackson has since gone downhill, directing the poxy 'Lord of the Rings' and 'The Hobbit' trilogies  what a shame. However, he has recently expressed interest in making another horror film; I just hope he sticks to his roots with a shoestring budget and an immeasurable amount of corn syrup and gore. www.hawkensian.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's about time Jackson was funny again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before Peter Jackson almost exclusively worked with a CGI backdrop in the land of Middle-Earth, he began his film making career in the realms of low budget comedy-horror. Utilising the 1980's trend for splatter cinema, and no doubt the influence of Sam Raimi's tongue-in-cheek zombie film, The Evil Dead (1982), Jackson's debut feature film was entrenched in a very American tradition, but beholds the humour of his native New Zealand - which incidentally is part of the British commonwealth, meaning much of the uniqueness of British comedy is transposed onto the antipodean nation, the influence of Monty Python being one particular aspect of the film that made it such a surprise success. Bad Taste was clearly a labour of love, with Jackson bringing friends and family in to contribute to the making. The nature of the films production adds something quite special to both the narrative and the humour. The home- made special effects and props (Jackson used his parents oven to bake the handmade armoury used in the film) work both as farce and as actually quite an achievement of authenticity. Set in a small, isolated town, a group of misfits, "The Boys," ordered from a shadowy government department, have been sent to investigate an invasion, where aliens have wiped out the inhabitants. What transpires is an alien fast food corporation have discovered that human flesh is the galaxy's newest taste sensation, and are accumulating cardboard boxes of flesh to market and sell to planets. At the centre of the government group is geeky scientist, Derek (Played by Jackson himself - he is also in the role of the alien Robert), who "can only relate to birds". He salivates at the sight of dismemberment and artillery. As the group discover the truth about the alien invasion, their mission is to stop them from leaving the planet. On a narrative level, Bad Taste is as simple as they come. But underneath this simplicity is a wealth of brilliantly formed characters, with their own idiosyncrasies, and a range of beautifully crafted one liners and references. There are some stand out moments created with gruesome, cheep, but effective effects. The aliens seem to be mostly influenced by the zombie cinema of George A. Romero, with their slow moving mannerisms, and like Romero and Savini, Jackson delights in slicing them up with sharp tools and exploding them with guns. One alien has the top half of his head chopped off, a scene that displays Jackson's talent for editing, as he seamlessly cuts from the actors legs stumbling, to the rubbery half-head spurting copious amounts of blood and gore. Derek provides some of the most grotesque, Grand Guignol elements after he falls from a cliff, leaving a skull flat that exposes his brain matter. After this event, he constantly battles to keep the brain inside his head, strapping it closed with a belt. These scenes merge those ideas the comedy of the absurd, with the horrific splatter of giallo or the ridiculously over- the-top gore films of Herschell Gordon Lewis. Considering the limitations of the incredibly low budget (according to IMDb, the films budget was estimated at 30,000 NZD), the film looks good. Of course the film stock, the acting and the special effects aren't up to some of the more expensive American productions of its type, but with an insanely funny script, and the excessive nature of the violence, it is a film that should be loved. I do remember first seeing this film on video around 1989/1990, no doubt initially attracted by the latex alien on the video cover flipping the bird. It was soon the talk of the playground, as school friends would delight in the gore. But more specifically, I, along with my peers, were fundamentally reacting to the outlandish and on-the-money comedy, which holds up today as much as the first two Monty Python films. Gross-out comedy on this scale, has not been so much fun as this since. It's a shame Jackson hides away in Middle-Earth so much these days, it's about time he was funny again. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, witty and playfully violent - but not to everyone's taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not too many movies with limited budget producing good outcome, especially if sci-fi is involved as one has to provide resources for camera tricks. As for Bad Taste, this movie was made for less than 30,000 USD - but it took years to complete it. The plot is peculiar and main characters is uncommon mixture of zombies and aliens. The ending is witty and distinctive - and all this is years before when Tarantino or Rodriguez began their famous mishmashes. The cast is totally amateur - Jackson's friends and acquaintances - but in a good sense, giving an interesting purity and fun. As for Jackson himself, he showed himself as talented actor, he could be used more in this function as well (later he has appeared only in cameo roles). In short, an interesting and already a cult movie, recommended to all fans of horror alien movies, but preferably no eating during watching! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most memorable treats!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avinash Shukla
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Peter Jackson for his bizarre creativity. Bad Taste, Braindead, Meet the Feebles are all bizarre in their own way. As I love splatsticks, I worship 'Bad Taste' for the position it holds in the world of splatter cinema. Peter Jackson has a strange way of using gore. His gory sequences are seldom disturbing and overuse of fake blood makes the gore look like a comedic device, which should be laughed and laughed upon for eternity! So what's the story about 'Bad Taste'? This is a typical B-film but is slicker and more tongue-in-cheek than any of the films that fall into the category of extreme cinema. Jackson's tales never let the viewer lose interest in his films. Perhaps Jackson is such an artist who can make murder look like plain humor! Considering the limitations Jackson faced both financially and technically during the filming of 'Bad Taste', the film looks as great as Taj Mahal to me. The tale is fairly simple at heart. The Astro Investigation Defense Service sends 4 men Ozzy (Terry Potter), Derek (Peter Jackson), Barry (Pete O'Herne) and Frank (Mike Minett) to a town 'Kaihoro' (Food-town in Maori?) to discover the reason behind unexplained disappearances of the townspeople. The men find blood splattered everywhere with no trace of the townsfolk. The place looks like an abattoir, as Barry tells Derek on his radio. The men soon come to know that the town is plagued with zombies, who will kill anything that comes their way. Detailed findings lead the men to the whereabouts of the zombies where they have all gathered for a meet. The meet is hosted by their chief Lord Crumb (Doug Wren). The men come to know that Lord Crumb and his zombie force are actually extraterrestrial beings in the guise of humans and have plans of harvesting human meat for their own intergalactic food franchise. So the dead townsfolk are now in the boxes, ready for the alien consumption! The men also find Giles (Craig Smith), a donation collector in a drum, soaked in spices and free him. Watching for the right time to strike, they all take positions and open fire at the dawn. Causing heavy casualties, the men force Lord Crumb to retreat in his home-faced-UFO. However, Derek has plans of his own that are more sinister than Lord Crumb could have ever imagined. The film as you can see is based on hyper-imagination. Jackson however makes this work. 'Bad Taste' has great comedy scenes and an appealing atmosphere. Thanks to Jackson's hometown Pukerua Bay and the New Zealand lush belt, where this flick was shot. These locations add good atmosphere in the film and shaky camera work at places makes the viewer dizzy. Over-the-top splatter plays a special role here and gives enough reality to the film. So if you're a kind of person who loves to puke on the nasty, give this a try. I am sure you won't be disappointed, and don't forget to watch Peter Jackson's evil twin Robert!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stay where you are then, and I'll give you an eye witness description of this, intergalactic w*nker!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I expect you're wondering what you're doing soaking in Reg's eleven secret herbs and spices. Tomorrow we're having you for lunch!" Yes, the aliens have turned the villagers into tasty burgers, and Derek (Peter Jackson) must defeat them before they spread to the whole world. This time the good guy has the chainsaw, but will he be able to defeat the evil corporate aliens who are just trying to supply their fast-food chain? And, yes, this is the same Peter Jackson of Lord of the Rings fame. Be prepared for some really bloody scenes, and humor that borders on the outrageous. Borders, heck, it is outrageously funny. Oh yes, lots of gooey, icky stuff coming out of bodies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It is what the title says, in the funniest possible way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan Ashley (DanLives1980)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the '80's and early '90's visionary director of 'Lord of the Rings', 'King Kong' and 'The Lovely Bones' Peter Jackson was making the type of films some countries don't even allow today, outside of Asia and the US. It may come as a shock for fans of his work this last decade to witness 'Meet The Feebles' or 'Braindead' and vice versa for fans of his old outings. 'Bad Taste' is an action-sci-fi-horror about a small unit of dimwitted rejects from the fictional governmental department "the Astro Investigation and Defence Service" (AIDS LOL) who are stationed in various locations around a deserted coastal town, which has been wiped out by alien invaders. Upon two of their unit being marauded by groups of the aliens disguised as humans, they regroup and head in to gather intelligence where they discover Earth has been targeted by the ruthless leader of one of the galaxy's biggest fast food corporations, hence the title, 'Bad Taste!' The film is possibly one of the tackiest and most absurd ever conceived, yet boasts of its absurdity because it is so notoriously fun to watch and has some pretty fantastic (although dated) practical special effects, and people will even watch it over and over again to remind themselves how bad it is. What people don't seem to get is that it's a balls-out parody that simply doesn't count on inter-textual references to be understood. Instead it counts on the childish humour of a bunch of male friends most likely trying to test their girlfriends' gag reflexes, almost like a fictional Jackass or Dirty Sanchez movie. It's a boys film that cuts out all the unnecessary plot and dialogue and goes straight for the knives, guns, bazookas, chainsaws, blood and guts and vomit gags, nothing more, nothing less. I may be biased in voting it a 7 out of 10 but still I tried to be fair. It's badly acted, badly produced, badly offensive and pure bad taste in every way possible but still, the performers in the movie are likable and they provide you with a lot of laughs. Peter Jackson must have made this from his garden shed back then, but if that's the case, what an effort. Love it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not gonna gloss anything over in the review....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    witster18
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tough film to review here! Bad Taste is essentially Peter Jackson learning the ropes and experimenting with practically zero cash. The result is a gory and sometimes funny mess. He polished this formula up for 'Dead Alive', and 'Dead Alive' definitely shows a progression both in Jackson's talent, and his pocketbook(although DA had a small budget too). You can see Jackson's influences. Direction similar to early Romero, and Gore that reminds me of some of the late 70's/early 80's gore-fests. The gore here is in heavy doses, and it is probably the strongest characteristic of this film - along with what he achieved overall given the restrictions with the budget and cast. He learned from the best... Other influences were surely make-up masterminds like Tom Savini and Rick Baker. You have to be in the right mindset to enjoy this movie. I've seen it three times. The first time was years ago and I didn't enjoy the film at all. Years later, after realizing that you don't have to take everything so serious, and that horror films can be as funny as they are scary - I gave it another whirl. I laughed on a few occasions and my interest was sparked but not glued. The third time I concentrated more on Jackson's technique and the little nuances that make this film more of a lesson in film-making than an enjoyable 90 minutes. My conclusion. Bad Taste is a film to be appreciated by horror/comedy fans, and fans of making film - because it's essentially someone just like you making their first backyard movie. The only difference is the effort and the near flawless shots of gore and tension that can only be achieved at the hands of someone who is A.Talented, B.Meticulous, and C.An Obvious Film-Buff. He was paying attention to how Romero achieved tension with his close-ups and sound,... and the editing here, for what it is, is amazing. The plot is a dose of Comedy, horror, and sci-fi. Bad Taste is a bitter-sweet, low-budget gore-fest with humor to boot. All that said - most people will NOT enjoy this movie. If you just love gore.. or film-making.... or the Evil Dead Series... or find yourself in love with Cult Classics like Toxic Avenger Etc... then sure, you might like it. Otherwise, skip this one because many Cult-Classics like this have extremely inflated scores here on IMDb. That's because 90% of the small number of reviewers have seen it 90 times, and that 90% is rating this a 10. It's no 10!... It's not even close!... it's exactly what I said it was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Super size me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know. Scores of Millions of dollars is OK too, but why would Peter Jackson insist on doing what he's been doing over the last decade, when he obviously found his calling in life as director of the goriest, craziest, and most outrageous splatter flicks available? And the man only made two of them, yet made a lasting, not to mention an influential impression. Before 1992's Dead Alive (still the goriest film in existence), Jackson would shoot on video, what has to be the greatest sci-fi-gore-comedy in the history of New Zealand. This is Bad Taste. It's what I've always said. There just ain't enough micro-budgeted, sci-comedy with lots and lots of gore. As sweet as the gore is, it really does take a backseat to the comic genius this film offers. Bad Taste is about an alien fast-food franchise who recently decided that human flesh would be a good choice for their menu. Cheap, convenient, not bad. After decimating the entire town of Kaihoro, in New Zealand, the Astro- Investigation and Defense Service is called in to exterminate these guys, who can take the form of humans at will. These eager beavers are ready to blow a hole in anything that moves, so if any actual humans get killed in the process, what the hell? These guys ain't too bright, and they're probably half-crazy, but they totally mean well, with trying to save the world and whatnot. Wanna know something funny? After at least 2 or 3 viewings of this film, something really peculiar occurred to me. There isn't one female to be found in Bad Taste. While it isn't a large cast to begin with, and I'm not really sure what purpose a woman would serve in a sci-fi gore-comedy, I just think it's peculiar. And no. None of this is relevant. But, anyway. What a happy day it will be when, I mean if Peter Jackson decides to return to his gory roots one more time. Since he's already done the alien thing, and not to mention the living dead masterpiece that is Dead Alive, perhaps Jackson should make a disgustingly gory Vampire flick. Or maybe he should just keep making big-budget kids movies. Yeah. That sounds about right. Something tells me Peter Jackson's days as director of films like Bad Taste and other awsomeness are long gone. Whatever. Plenty of other cult Horror filmmakers out there, doin' their thing. But there was a time, not that long ago that your beloved Lord Of The Rings guy was out there doing some amazing stuff in the underground. Once again, Dead Alive would be the best example of this theory, but Bad Taste is nothing short of amazing in its own right. That doesn't necessarily mean you should then go rush off and buy Meet The Feebles as well. That's another story for another day. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Splatterfest Flick, Jackson's Greatest Hit!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tequila101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care what anybody says about this flick but I think this is Peter Jackson's best work. After watching "Meet the Feebles" nearly seven years ago, as a kid I was always edging to watch "Bad Taste" and I was seriously expecting this to be cheap and stupid but instead I got more than what i asked for. This film for the 80's has top notch gore, funny-ass scenes, impossible situations and non stop horrific/comedic action. I always wanted to see this film as a kid and now, I'm glad that I did. The Alien look is very creative and I also love the switch between music themes, first we had creepy adventures, and very wondrous tones of what's gonna happen next and then, we had old rocking, action packed style of play. It was all very creative. Along with Meet the Feebles, (which the trailer say has no taste at all lol) to and for me this was the next level of a Peter Jackson film and it's absolutely funny and creepy at it's best. Even if I didn't find this scary on any levels and I do think that this film has an insane way of telling it's story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sometimes jokingly remark how Peter Jackson's career was perfect until he directed the Lord of the Rings trilogy. It's hard to imagine that this director, who now specializes in big budget Hollywood movies, started off by creating twisted and gory low budget movies  his directorial debut, Bad Taste, being the prime example of this early, strange phase. Bad Taste was by no means an easy experience for Jackson, since the filming took 4 years. However, the hard work paid off and Bad Taste can be used as a valuable lesson in "do-it-yourself: low budget film making". It's amazing how, in spite of rather limited resources, Jackson managed to make it all work and look good  he created the masks and firearm replicas for the movie himself. He even constructed his own counterweighted steady-cam. Bad Taste is a definite must see for every aspiring movie maker, if only for Peter Jackson's creativity. The movie follows 4 agents (called 'The Boys') of some sort of secret service, who investigate alien activity in a small town. Apparently, the aliens have killed the whole population and replaced it. Things become more complicated when the aliens kidnap a charity collector passing through, and it's up to The Boys to save him, by using any means necessary. As you can see, Bad Taste's plot is fairly simple, there isn't much "story" to it  the movie is mainly action and dialogue driven. Due to this fact, the movie gets boring from time to time and I find it to be the worst from Peter Jackson's early phase. I also find it to be the least funny one. While there are quite a few amusing scenes, it doesn't even come close to other early classics like Braindead and Meet the Feebles. But at least there is enough violence and gore in it to make it interesting. The movie does get pretty graphic. Did you first notice the guy missing the top of his head or the Peter Jackson cameo? The effects in the movie (influenced by the cult special effects artist Tom Savini) are surely its best quality. You'll see heads exploding, limbs being torn off and even some chainsaw action. The scene which impressed me the most was the one where a character, played by Peter Jackson, fights with another character  also played by Peter Jackson. Actually, if you're not informed prior to the watching of movie, you may not notice he plays two different characters since they don't really look alike. Who knows  maybe Jackson has an acting talent waiting to be further developed? Speaking of acting, the actors did an OK job for this kind of movie, no one is laughably bad. On a side note, I think it's important to remark that all of the dialogue was dubbed in post production; that, however, isn't much of a bother since it isn't very apparent. While I wasn't really keen on Bad Taste (like I said  I found it to be somewhat boring and I prefer other early Jackson works) I would definitely recommend it to everyone. It's a gory, funny trash/cult flick about some guys fighting off a bunch of butt shaped aliens, set to an 80s heavy metal soundtrack. Why wouldn't you watch it? Rating: 6/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Until Jackson's follow-up 'Brain Dead', this may have been the goriest film ever made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jack Hawkins (Hawkensian)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love 'Bad Taste'. I love that the film was made for about $20 and that the cast consists of Peter Jackson's mates. It's also so enjoyable because it demonstrates how talented a filmmaker Jackson is. For example, there is a scene near the beginning of the film where Derek (Peter Jackson) fights with some alien invaders on a cliff side, it is hilariously gory and feels so very dangerous; through sheer talent (and a massive amount of bravery!), the crew achieves a tangible sense of acrophobia. In 'Bad Taste', Earth is under threat from alien invaders who are endeavouring to fill a culinary gap in their intergalactic fast-food market  the demand for tasty human flesh. The malicious extra- terrestrials don't arouse suspicion as they assume human appearances. Before the Astro Investigation and Defence Service (AIDS) arrive, the malevolent visitors have already wiped out the entire town of Kaihoro, New Zealand. This elite team is comprised of Derek (Peter Jackson), a rather odd Kiwi with an insatiable bloodlust, Barry (Pete O'Hearn), a man who will use his .44 Magnum only when necessary and Frank (Mike Minett), Giles (Craig Smith) and Ozzy (Terry Potter), a trio of muscle car driving tough guys. Jackson's early films have a real talent for choreographing slapstick gore, there are heads being blown off, brains being eaten, arms being torn off, severed heads being drop kicked, seagulls being head butted, entire bodies being chain sawed and even sheep being detonated. The film is utterly drenched in an outrageous amount of viscera; however it is all of the slapstick variety with a strong Commonwealth lacing of black humour. Though the film is by no means a performance film, there is a certain charm about the cast's inexperience. Also, Peter Jackson is hilarious as the absurd, demented Derek, whose horrible shrill laugh and personal motto 'I'm a Derek, Dereks don't run!' are particularly memorable. The filming locations, such as the aforementioned cliff side, are all of outstanding natural beauty; 'Bad Taste' is as much an advertisement for the country as Jackson's later work would be. As we all know, Jackson has since gone downhill, directing the poxy 'Lord of the Rings' and 'The Hobbit' trilogies  what a shame. However, he has recently expressed interest in making another horror film; I just hope he sticks to his roots with a shoestring budget and an immeasurable amount of corn syrup and gore. www.hawkensian.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's about time Jackson was funny again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before Peter Jackson almost exclusively worked with a CGI backdrop in the land of Middle-Earth, he began his film making career in the realms of low budget comedy-horror. Utilising the 1980's trend for splatter cinema, and no doubt the influence of Sam Raimi's tongue-in-cheek zombie film, The Evil Dead (1982), Jackson's debut feature film was entrenched in a very American tradition, but beholds the humour of his native New Zealand - which incidentally is part of the British commonwealth, meaning much of the uniqueness of British comedy is transposed onto the antipodean nation, the influence of Monty Python being one particular aspect of the film that made it such a surprise success. Bad Taste was clearly a labour of love, with Jackson bringing friends and family in to contribute to the making. The nature of the films production adds something quite special to both the narrative and the humour. The home- made special effects and props (Jackson used his parents oven to bake the handmade armoury used in the film) work both as farce and as actually quite an achievement of authenticity. Set in a small, isolated town, a group of misfits, "The Boys," ordered from a shadowy government department, have been sent to investigate an invasion, where aliens have wiped out the inhabitants. What transpires is an alien fast food corporation have discovered that human flesh is the galaxy's newest taste sensation, and are accumulating cardboard boxes of flesh to market and sell to planets. At the centre of the government group is geeky scientist, Derek (Played by Jackson himself - he is also in the role of the alien Robert), who "can only relate to birds". He salivates at the sight of dismemberment and artillery. As the group discover the truth about the alien invasion, their mission is to stop them from leaving the planet. On a narrative level, Bad Taste is as simple as they come. But underneath this simplicity is a wealth of brilliantly formed characters, with their own idiosyncrasies, and a range of beautifully crafted one liners and references. There are some stand out moments created with gruesome, cheep, but effective effects. The aliens seem to be mostly influenced by the zombie cinema of George A. Romero, with their slow moving mannerisms, and like Romero and Savini, Jackson delights in slicing them up with sharp tools and exploding them with guns. One alien has the top half of his head chopped off, a scene that displays Jackson's talent for editing, as he seamlessly cuts from the actors legs stumbling, to the rubbery half-head spurting copious amounts of blood and gore. Derek provides some of the most grotesque, Grand Guignol elements after he falls from a cliff, leaving a skull flat that exposes his brain matter. After this event, he constantly battles to keep the brain inside his head, strapping it closed with a belt. These scenes merge those ideas the comedy of the absurd, with the horrific splatter of giallo or the ridiculously over- the-top gore films of Herschell Gordon Lewis. Considering the limitations of the incredibly low budget (according to IMDb, the films budget was estimated at 30,000 NZD), the film looks good. Of course the film stock, the acting and the special effects aren't up to some of the more expensive American productions of its type, but with an insanely funny script, and the excessive nature of the violence, it is a film that should be loved. I do remember first seeing this film on video around 1989/1990, no doubt initially attracted by the latex alien on the video cover flipping the bird. It was soon the talk of the playground, as school friends would delight in the gore. But more specifically, I, along with my peers, were fundamentally reacting to the outlandish and on-the-money comedy, which holds up today as much as the first two Monty Python films. Gross-out comedy on this scale, has not been so much fun as this since. It's a shame Jackson hides away in Middle-Earth so much these days, it's about time he was funny again. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, witty and playfully violent - but not to everyone's taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not too many movies with limited budget producing good outcome, especially if sci-fi is involved as one has to provide resources for camera tricks. As for Bad Taste, this movie was made for less than 30,000 USD - but it took years to complete it. The plot is peculiar and main characters is uncommon mixture of zombies and aliens. The ending is witty and distinctive - and all this is years before when Tarantino or Rodriguez began their famous mishmashes. The cast is totally amateur - Jackson's friends and acquaintances - but in a good sense, giving an interesting purity and fun. As for Jackson himself, he showed himself as talented actor, he could be used more in this function as well (later he has appeared only in cameo roles). In short, an interesting and already a cult movie, recommended to all fans of horror alien movies, but preferably no eating during watching! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most memorable treats!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avinash Shukla
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Peter Jackson for his bizarre creativity. Bad Taste, Braindead, Meet the Feebles are all bizarre in their own way. As I love splatsticks, I worship 'Bad Taste' for the position it holds in the world of splatter cinema. Peter Jackson has a strange way of using gore. His gory sequences are seldom disturbing and overuse of fake blood makes the gore look like a comedic device, which should be laughed and laughed upon for eternity! So what's the story about 'Bad Taste'? This is a typical B-film but is slicker and more tongue-in-cheek than any of the films that fall into the category of extreme cinema. Jackson's tales never let the viewer lose interest in his films. Perhaps Jackson is such an artist who can make murder look like plain humor! Considering the limitations Jackson faced both financially and technically during the filming of 'Bad Taste', the film looks as great as Taj Mahal to me. The tale is fairly simple at heart. The Astro Investigation Defense Service sends 4 men Ozzy (Terry Potter), Derek (Peter Jackson), Barry (Pete O'Herne) and Frank (Mike Minett) to a town 'Kaihoro' (Food-town in Maori?) to discover the reason behind unexplained disappearances of the townspeople. The men find blood splattered everywhere with no trace of the townsfolk. The place looks like an abattoir, as Barry tells Derek on his radio. The men soon come to know that the town is plagued with zombies, who will kill anything that comes their way. Detailed findings lead the men to the whereabouts of the zombies where they have all gathered for a meet. The meet is hosted by their chief Lord Crumb (Doug Wren). The men come to know that Lord Crumb and his zombie force are actually extraterrestrial beings in the guise of humans and have plans of harvesting human meat for their own intergalactic food franchise. So the dead townsfolk are now in the boxes, ready for the alien consumption! The men also find Giles (Craig Smith), a donation collector in a drum, soaked in spices and free him. Watching for the right time to strike, they all take positions and open fire at the dawn. Causing heavy casualties, the men force Lord Crumb to retreat in his home-faced-UFO. However, Derek has plans of his own that are more sinister than Lord Crumb could have ever imagined. The film as you can see is based on hyper-imagination. Jackson however makes this work. 'Bad Taste' has great comedy scenes and an appealing atmosphere. Thanks to Jackson's hometown Pukerua Bay and the New Zealand lush belt, where this flick was shot. These locations add good atmosphere in the film and shaky camera work at places makes the viewer dizzy. Over-the-top splatter plays a special role here and gives enough reality to the film. So if you're a kind of person who loves to puke on the nasty, give this a try. I am sure you won't be disappointed, and don't forget to watch Peter Jackson's evil twin Robert!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stay where you are then, and I'll give you an eye witness description of this, intergalactic w*nker!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I expect you're wondering what you're doing soaking in Reg's eleven secret herbs and spices. Tomorrow we're having you for lunch!" Yes, the aliens have turned the villagers into tasty burgers, and Derek (Peter Jackson) must defeat them before they spread to the whole world. This time the good guy has the chainsaw, but will he be able to defeat the evil corporate aliens who are just trying to supply their fast-food chain? And, yes, this is the same Peter Jackson of Lord of the Rings fame. Be prepared for some really bloody scenes, and humor that borders on the outrageous. Borders, heck, it is outrageously funny. Oh yes, lots of gooey, icky stuff coming out of bodies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It is what the title says, in the funniest possible way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan Ashley (DanLives1980)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the '80's and early '90's visionary director of 'Lord of the Rings', 'King Kong' and 'The Lovely Bones' Peter Jackson was making the type of films some countries don't even allow today, outside of Asia and the US. It may come as a shock for fans of his work this last decade to witness 'Meet The Feebles' or 'Braindead' and vice versa for fans of his old outings. 'Bad Taste' is an action-sci-fi-horror about a small unit of dimwitted rejects from the fictional governmental department "the Astro Investigation and Defence Service" (AIDS LOL) who are stationed in various locations around a deserted coastal town, which has been wiped out by alien invaders. Upon two of their unit being marauded by groups of the aliens disguised as humans, they regroup and head in to gather intelligence where they discover Earth has been targeted by the ruthless leader of one of the galaxy's biggest fast food corporations, hence the title, 'Bad Taste!' The film is possibly one of the tackiest and most absurd ever conceived, yet boasts of its absurdity because it is so notoriously fun to watch and has some pretty fantastic (although dated) practical special effects, and people will even watch it over and over again to remind themselves how bad it is. What people don't seem to get is that it's a balls-out parody that simply doesn't count on inter-textual references to be understood. Instead it counts on the childish humour of a bunch of male friends most likely trying to test their girlfriends' gag reflexes, almost like a fictional Jackass or Dirty Sanchez movie. It's a boys film that cuts out all the unnecessary plot and dialogue and goes straight for the knives, guns, bazookas, chainsaws, blood and guts and vomit gags, nothing more, nothing less. I may be biased in voting it a 7 out of 10 but still I tried to be fair. It's badly acted, badly produced, badly offensive and pure bad taste in every way possible but still, the performers in the movie are likable and they provide you with a lot of laughs. Peter Jackson must have made this from his garden shed back then, but if that's the case, what an effort. Love it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not gonna gloss anything over in the review....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    witster18
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tough film to review here! Bad Taste is essentially Peter Jackson learning the ropes and experimenting with practically zero cash. The result is a gory and sometimes funny mess. He polished this formula up for 'Dead Alive', and 'Dead Alive' definitely shows a progression both in Jackson's talent, and his pocketbook(although DA had a small budget too). You can see Jackson's influences. Direction similar to early Romero, and Gore that reminds me of some of the late 70's/early 80's gore-fests. The gore here is in heavy doses, and it is probably the strongest characteristic of this film - along with what he achieved overall given the restrictions with the budget and cast. He learned from the best... Other influences were surely make-up masterminds like Tom Savini and Rick Baker. You have to be in the right mindset to enjoy this movie. I've seen it three times. The first time was years ago and I didn't enjoy the film at all. Years later, after realizing that you don't have to take everything so serious, and that horror films can be as funny as they are scary - I gave it another whirl. I laughed on a few occasions and my interest was sparked but not glued. The third time I concentrated more on Jackson's technique and the little nuances that make this film more of a lesson in film-making than an enjoyable 90 minutes. My conclusion. Bad Taste is a film to be appreciated by horror/comedy fans, and fans of making film - because it's essentially someone just like you making their first backyard movie. The only difference is the effort and the near flawless shots of gore and tension that can only be achieved at the hands of someone who is A.Talented, B.Meticulous, and C.An Obvious Film-Buff. He was paying attention to how Romero achieved tension with his close-ups and sound,... and the editing here, for what it is, is amazing. The plot is a dose of Comedy, horror, and sci-fi. Bad Taste is a bitter-sweet, low-budget gore-fest with humor to boot. All that said - most people will NOT enjoy this movie. If you just love gore.. or film-making.... or the Evil Dead Series... or find yourself in love with Cult Classics like Toxic Avenger Etc... then sure, you might like it. Otherwise, skip this one because many Cult-Classics like this have extremely inflated scores here on IMDb. That's because 90% of the small number of reviewers have seen it 90 times, and that 90% is rating this a 10. It's no 10!... It's not even close!... it's exactly what I said it was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Super size me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know. Scores of Millions of dollars is OK too, but why would Peter Jackson insist on doing what he's been doing over the last decade, when he obviously found his calling in life as director of the goriest, craziest, and most outrageous splatter flicks available? And the man only made two of them, yet made a lasting, not to mention an influential impression. Before 1992's Dead Alive (still the goriest film in existence), Jackson would shoot on video, what has to be the greatest sci-fi-gore-comedy in the history of New Zealand. This is Bad Taste. It's what I've always said. There just ain't enough micro-budgeted, sci-comedy with lots and lots of gore. As sweet as the gore is, it really does take a backseat to the comic genius this film offers. Bad Taste is about an alien fast-food franchise who recently decided that human flesh would be a good choice for their menu. Cheap, convenient, not bad. After decimating the entire town of Kaihoro, in New Zealand, the Astro- Investigation and Defense Service is called in to exterminate these guys, who can take the form of humans at will. These eager beavers are ready to blow a hole in anything that moves, so if any actual humans get killed in the process, what the hell? These guys ain't too bright, and they're probably half-crazy, but they totally mean well, with trying to save the world and whatnot. Wanna know something funny? After at least 2 or 3 viewings of this film, something really peculiar occurred to me. There isn't one female to be found in Bad Taste. While it isn't a large cast to begin with, and I'm not really sure what purpose a woman would serve in a sci-fi gore-comedy, I just think it's peculiar. And no. None of this is relevant. But, anyway. What a happy day it will be when, I mean if Peter Jackson decides to return to his gory roots one more time. Since he's already done the alien thing, and not to mention the living dead masterpiece that is Dead Alive, perhaps Jackson should make a disgustingly gory Vampire flick. Or maybe he should just keep making big-budget kids movies. Yeah. That sounds about right. Something tells me Peter Jackson's days as director of films like Bad Taste and other awsomeness are long gone. Whatever. Plenty of other cult Horror filmmakers out there, doin' their thing. But there was a time, not that long ago that your beloved Lord Of The Rings guy was out there doing some amazing stuff in the underground. Once again, Dead Alive would be the best example of this theory, but Bad Taste is nothing short of amazing in its own right. That doesn't necessarily mean you should then go rush off and buy Meet The Feebles as well. That's another story for another day. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Splatterfest Flick, Jackson's Greatest Hit!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tequila101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care what anybody says about this flick but I think this is Peter Jackson's best work. After watching "Meet the Feebles" nearly seven years ago, as a kid I was always edging to watch "Bad Taste" and I was seriously expecting this to be cheap and stupid but instead I got more than what i asked for. This film for the 80's has top notch gore, funny-ass scenes, impossible situations and non stop horrific/comedic action. I always wanted to see this film as a kid and now, I'm glad that I did. The Alien look is very creative and I also love the switch between music themes, first we had creepy adventures, and very wondrous tones of what's gonna happen next and then, we had old rocking, action packed style of play. It was all very creative. Along with Meet the Feebles, (which the trailer say has no taste at all lol) to and for me this was the next level of a Peter Jackson film and it's absolutely funny and creepy at it's best. Even if I didn't find this scary on any levels and I do think that this film has an insane way of telling it's story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sometimes jokingly remark how Peter Jackson's career was perfect until he directed the Lord of the Rings trilogy. It's hard to imagine that this director, who now specializes in big budget Hollywood movies, started off by creating twisted and gory low budget movies  his directorial debut, Bad Taste, being the prime example of this early, strange phase. Bad Taste was by no means an easy experience for Jackson, since the filming took 4 years. However, the hard work paid off and Bad Taste can be used as a valuable lesson in "do-it-yourself: low budget film making". It's amazing how, in spite of rather limited resources, Jackson managed to make it all work and look good  he created the masks and firearm replicas for the movie himself. He even constructed his own counterweighted steady-cam. Bad Taste is a definite must see for every aspiring movie maker, if only for Peter Jackson's creativity. The movie follows 4 agents (called 'The Boys') of some sort of secret service, who investigate alien activity in a small town. Apparently, the aliens have killed the whole population and replaced it. Things become more complicated when the aliens kidnap a charity collector passing through, and it's up to The Boys to save him, by using any means necessary. As you can see, Bad Taste's plot is fairly simple, there isn't much "story" to it  the movie is mainly action and dialogue driven. Due to this fact, the movie gets boring from time to time and I find it to be the worst from Peter Jackson's early phase. I also find it to be the least funny one. While there are quite a few amusing scenes, it doesn't even come close to other early classics like Braindead and Meet the Feebles. But at least there is enough violence and gore in it to make it interesting. The movie does get pretty graphic. Did you first notice the guy missing the top of his head or the Peter Jackson cameo? The effects in the movie (influenced by the cult special effects artist Tom Savini) are surely its best quality. You'll see heads exploding, limbs being torn off and even some chainsaw action. The scene which impressed me the most was the one where a character, played by Peter Jackson, fights with another character  also played by Peter Jackson. Actually, if you're not informed prior to the watching of movie, you may not notice he plays two different characters since they don't really look alike. Who knows  maybe Jackson has an acting talent waiting to be further developed? Speaking of acting, the actors did an OK job for this kind of movie, no one is laughably bad. On a side note, I think it's important to remark that all of the dialogue was dubbed in post production; that, however, isn't much of a bother since it isn't very apparent. While I wasn't really keen on Bad Taste (like I said  I found it to be somewhat boring and I prefer other early Jackson works) I would definitely recommend it to everyone. It's a gory, funny trash/cult flick about some guys fighting off a bunch of butt shaped aliens, set to an 80s heavy metal soundtrack. Why wouldn't you watch it? Rating: 6/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Until Jackson's follow-up 'Brain Dead', this may have been the goriest film ever made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jack Hawkins (Hawkensian)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love 'Bad Taste'. I love that the film was made for about $20 and that the cast consists of Peter Jackson's mates. It's also so enjoyable because it demonstrates how talented a filmmaker Jackson is. For example, there is a scene near the beginning of the film where Derek (Peter Jackson) fights with some alien invaders on a cliff side, it is hilariously gory and feels so very dangerous; through sheer talent (and a massive amount of bravery!), the crew achieves a tangible sense of acrophobia. In 'Bad Taste', Earth is under threat from alien invaders who are endeavouring to fill a culinary gap in their intergalactic fast-food market  the demand for tasty human flesh. The malicious extra- terrestrials don't arouse suspicion as they assume human appearances. Before the Astro Investigation and Defence Service (AIDS) arrive, the malevolent visitors have already wiped out the entire town of Kaihoro, New Zealand. This elite team is comprised of Derek (Peter Jackson), a rather odd Kiwi with an insatiable bloodlust, Barry (Pete O'Hearn), a man who will use his .44 Magnum only when necessary and Frank (Mike Minett), Giles (Craig Smith) and Ozzy (Terry Potter), a trio of muscle car driving tough guys. Jackson's early films have a real talent for choreographing slapstick gore, there are heads being blown off, brains being eaten, arms being torn off, severed heads being drop kicked, seagulls being head butted, entire bodies being chain sawed and even sheep being detonated. The film is utterly drenched in an outrageous amount of viscera; however it is all of the slapstick variety with a strong Commonwealth lacing of black humour. Though the film is by no means a performance film, there is a certain charm about the cast's inexperience. Also, Peter Jackson is hilarious as the absurd, demented Derek, whose horrible shrill laugh and personal motto 'I'm a Derek, Dereks don't run!' are particularly memorable. The filming locations, such as the aforementioned cliff side, are all of outstanding natural beauty; 'Bad Taste' is as much an advertisement for the country as Jackson's later work would be. As we all know, Jackson has since gone downhill, directing the poxy 'Lord of the Rings' and 'The Hobbit' trilogies  what a shame. However, he has recently expressed interest in making another horror film; I just hope he sticks to his roots with a shoestring budget and an immeasurable amount of corn syrup and gore. www.hawkensian.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's about time Jackson was funny again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before Peter Jackson almost exclusively worked with a CGI backdrop in the land of Middle-Earth, he began his film making career in the realms of low budget comedy-horror. Utilising the 1980's trend for splatter cinema, and no doubt the influence of Sam Raimi's tongue-in-cheek zombie film, The Evil Dead (1982), Jackson's debut feature film was entrenched in a very American tradition, but beholds the humour of his native New Zealand - which incidentally is part of the British commonwealth, meaning much of the uniqueness of British comedy is transposed onto the antipodean nation, the influence of Monty Python being one particular aspect of the film that made it such a surprise success. Bad Taste was clearly a labour of love, with Jackson bringing friends and family in to contribute to the making. The nature of the films production adds something quite special to both the narrative and the humour. The home- made special effects and props (Jackson used his parents oven to bake the handmade armoury used in the film) work both as farce and as actually quite an achievement of authenticity. Set in a small, isolated town, a group of misfits, "The Boys," ordered from a shadowy government department, have been sent to investigate an invasion, where aliens have wiped out the inhabitants. What transpires is an alien fast food corporation have discovered that human flesh is the galaxy's newest taste sensation, and are accumulating cardboard boxes of flesh to market and sell to planets. At the centre of the government group is geeky scientist, Derek (Played by Jackson himself - he is also in the role of the alien Robert), who "can only relate to birds". He salivates at the sight of dismemberment and artillery. As the group discover the truth about the alien invasion, their mission is to stop them from leaving the planet. On a narrative level, Bad Taste is as simple as they come. But underneath this simplicity is a wealth of brilliantly formed characters, with their own idiosyncrasies, and a range of beautifully crafted one liners and references. There are some stand out moments created with gruesome, cheep, but effective effects. The aliens seem to be mostly influenced by the zombie cinema of George A. Romero, with their slow moving mannerisms, and like Romero and Savini, Jackson delights in slicing them up with sharp tools and exploding them with guns. One alien has the top half of his head chopped off, a scene that displays Jackson's talent for editing, as he seamlessly cuts from the actors legs stumbling, to the rubbery half-head spurting copious amounts of blood and gore. Derek provides some of the most grotesque, Grand Guignol elements after he falls from a cliff, leaving a skull flat that exposes his brain matter. After this event, he constantly battles to keep the brain inside his head, strapping it closed with a belt. These scenes merge those ideas the comedy of the absurd, with the horrific splatter of giallo or the ridiculously over- the-top gore films of Herschell Gordon Lewis. Considering the limitations of the incredibly low budget (according to IMDb, the films budget was estimated at 30,000 NZD), the film looks good. Of course the film stock, the acting and the special effects aren't up to some of the more expensive American productions of its type, but with an insanely funny script, and the excessive nature of the violence, it is a film that should be loved. I do remember first seeing this film on video around 1989/1990, no doubt initially attracted by the latex alien on the video cover flipping the bird. It was soon the talk of the playground, as school friends would delight in the gore. But more specifically, I, along with my peers, were fundamentally reacting to the outlandish and on-the-money comedy, which holds up today as much as the first two Monty Python films. Gross-out comedy on this scale, has not been so much fun as this since. It's a shame Jackson hides away in Middle-Earth so much these days, it's about time he was funny again. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, witty and playfully violent - but not to everyone's taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not too many movies with limited budget producing good outcome, especially if sci-fi is involved as one has to provide resources for camera tricks. As for Bad Taste, this movie was made for less than 30,000 USD - but it took years to complete it. The plot is peculiar and main characters is uncommon mixture of zombies and aliens. The ending is witty and distinctive - and all this is years before when Tarantino or Rodriguez began their famous mishmashes. The cast is totally amateur - Jackson's friends and acquaintances - but in a good sense, giving an interesting purity and fun. As for Jackson himself, he showed himself as talented actor, he could be used more in this function as well (later he has appeared only in cameo roles). In short, an interesting and already a cult movie, recommended to all fans of horror alien movies, but preferably no eating during watching! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most memorable treats!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avinash Shukla
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Peter Jackson for his bizarre creativity. Bad Taste, Braindead, Meet the Feebles are all bizarre in their own way. As I love splatsticks, I worship 'Bad Taste' for the position it holds in the world of splatter cinema. Peter Jackson has a strange way of using gore. His gory sequences are seldom disturbing and overuse of fake blood makes the gore look like a comedic device, which should be laughed and laughed upon for eternity! So what's the story about 'Bad Taste'? This is a typical B-film but is slicker and more tongue-in-cheek than any of the films that fall into the category of extreme cinema. Jackson's tales never let the viewer lose interest in his films. Perhaps Jackson is such an artist who can make murder look like plain humor! Considering the limitations Jackson faced both financially and technically during the filming of 'Bad Taste', the film looks as great as Taj Mahal to me. The tale is fairly simple at heart. The Astro Investigation Defense Service sends 4 men Ozzy (Terry Potter), Derek (Peter Jackson), Barry (Pete O'Herne) and Frank (Mike Minett) to a town 'Kaihoro' (Food-town in Maori?) to discover the reason behind unexplained disappearances of the townspeople. The men find blood splattered everywhere with no trace of the townsfolk. The place looks like an abattoir, as Barry tells Derek on his radio. The men soon come to know that the town is plagued with zombies, who will kill anything that comes their way. Detailed findings lead the men to the whereabouts of the zombies where they have all gathered for a meet. The meet is hosted by their chief Lord Crumb (Doug Wren). The men come to know that Lord Crumb and his zombie force are actually extraterrestrial beings in the guise of humans and have plans of harvesting human meat for their own intergalactic food franchise. So the dead townsfolk are now in the boxes, ready for the alien consumption! The men also find Giles (Craig Smith), a donation collector in a drum, soaked in spices and free him. Watching for the right time to strike, they all take positions and open fire at the dawn. Causing heavy casualties, the men force Lord Crumb to retreat in his home-faced-UFO. However, Derek has plans of his own that are more sinister than Lord Crumb could have ever imagined. The film as you can see is based on hyper-imagination. Jackson however makes this work. 'Bad Taste' has great comedy scenes and an appealing atmosphere. Thanks to Jackson's hometown Pukerua Bay and the New Zealand lush belt, where this flick was shot. These locations add good atmosphere in the film and shaky camera work at places makes the viewer dizzy. Over-the-top splatter plays a special role here and gives enough reality to the film. So if you're a kind of person who loves to puke on the nasty, give this a try. I am sure you won't be disappointed, and don't forget to watch Peter Jackson's evil twin Robert!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stay where you are then, and I'll give you an eye witness description of this, intergalactic w*nker!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I expect you're wondering what you're doing soaking in Reg's eleven secret herbs and spices. Tomorrow we're having you for lunch!" Yes, the aliens have turned the villagers into tasty burgers, and Derek (Peter Jackson) must defeat them before they spread to the whole world. This time the good guy has the chainsaw, but will he be able to defeat the evil corporate aliens who are just trying to supply their fast-food chain? And, yes, this is the same Peter Jackson of Lord of the Rings fame. Be prepared for some really bloody scenes, and humor that borders on the outrageous. Borders, heck, it is outrageously funny. Oh yes, lots of gooey, icky stuff coming out of bodies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It is what the title says, in the funniest possible way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan Ashley (DanLives1980)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the '80's and early '90's visionary director of 'Lord of the Rings', 'King Kong' and 'The Lovely Bones' Peter Jackson was making the type of films some countries don't even allow today, outside of Asia and the US. It may come as a shock for fans of his work this last decade to witness 'Meet The Feebles' or 'Braindead' and vice versa for fans of his old outings. 'Bad Taste' is an action-sci-fi-horror about a small unit of dimwitted rejects from the fictional governmental department "the Astro Investigation and Defence Service" (AIDS LOL) who are stationed in various locations around a deserted coastal town, which has been wiped out by alien invaders. Upon two of their unit being marauded by groups of the aliens disguised as humans, they regroup and head in to gather intelligence where they discover Earth has been targeted by the ruthless leader of one of the galaxy's biggest fast food corporations, hence the title, 'Bad Taste!' The film is possibly one of the tackiest and most absurd ever conceived, yet boasts of its absurdity because it is so notoriously fun to watch and has some pretty fantastic (although dated) practical special effects, and people will even watch it over and over again to remind themselves how bad it is. What people don't seem to get is that it's a balls-out parody that simply doesn't count on inter-textual references to be understood. Instead it counts on the childish humour of a bunch of male friends most likely trying to test their girlfriends' gag reflexes, almost like a fictional Jackass or Dirty Sanchez movie. It's a boys film that cuts out all the unnecessary plot and dialogue and goes straight for the knives, guns, bazookas, chainsaws, blood and guts and vomit gags, nothing more, nothing less. I may be biased in voting it a 7 out of 10 but still I tried to be fair. It's badly acted, badly produced, badly offensive and pure bad taste in every way possible but still, the performers in the movie are likable and they provide you with a lot of laughs. Peter Jackson must have made this from his garden shed back then, but if that's the case, what an effort. Love it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not gonna gloss anything over in the review....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    witster18
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tough film to review here! Bad Taste is essentially Peter Jackson learning the ropes and experimenting with practically zero cash. The result is a gory and sometimes funny mess. He polished this formula up for 'Dead Alive', and 'Dead Alive' definitely shows a progression both in Jackson's talent, and his pocketbook(although DA had a small budget too). You can see Jackson's influences. Direction similar to early Romero, and Gore that reminds me of some of the late 70's/early 80's gore-fests. The gore here is in heavy doses, and it is probably the strongest characteristic of this film - along with what he achieved overall given the restrictions with the budget and cast. He learned from the best... Other influences were surely make-up masterminds like Tom Savini and Rick Baker. You have to be in the right mindset to enjoy this movie. I've seen it three times. The first time was years ago and I didn't enjoy the film at all. Years later, after realizing that you don't have to take everything so serious, and that horror films can be as funny as they are scary - I gave it another whirl. I laughed on a few occasions and my interest was sparked but not glued. The third time I concentrated more on Jackson's technique and the little nuances that make this film more of a lesson in film-making than an enjoyable 90 minutes. My conclusion. Bad Taste is a film to be appreciated by horror/comedy fans, and fans of making film - because it's essentially someone just like you making their first backyard movie. The only difference is the effort and the near flawless shots of gore and tension that can only be achieved at the hands of someone who is A.Talented, B.Meticulous, and C.An Obvious Film-Buff. He was paying attention to how Romero achieved tension with his close-ups and sound,... and the editing here, for what it is, is amazing. The plot is a dose of Comedy, horror, and sci-fi. Bad Taste is a bitter-sweet, low-budget gore-fest with humor to boot. All that said - most people will NOT enjoy this movie. If you just love gore.. or film-making.... or the Evil Dead Series... or find yourself in love with Cult Classics like Toxic Avenger Etc... then sure, you might like it. Otherwise, skip this one because many Cult-Classics like this have extremely inflated scores here on IMDb. That's because 90% of the small number of reviewers have seen it 90 times, and that 90% is rating this a 10. It's no 10!... It's not even close!... it's exactly what I said it was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Super size me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know. Scores of Millions of dollars is OK too, but why would Peter Jackson insist on doing what he's been doing over the last decade, when he obviously found his calling in life as director of the goriest, craziest, and most outrageous splatter flicks available? And the man only made two of them, yet made a lasting, not to mention an influential impression. Before 1992's Dead Alive (still the goriest film in existence), Jackson would shoot on video, what has to be the greatest sci-fi-gore-comedy in the history of New Zealand. This is Bad Taste. It's what I've always said. There just ain't enough micro-budgeted, sci-comedy with lots and lots of gore. As sweet as the gore is, it really does take a backseat to the comic genius this film offers. Bad Taste is about an alien fast-food franchise who recently decided that human flesh would be a good choice for their menu. Cheap, convenient, not bad. After decimating the entire town of Kaihoro, in New Zealand, the Astro- Investigation and Defense Service is called in to exterminate these guys, who can take the form of humans at will. These eager beavers are ready to blow a hole in anything that moves, so if any actual humans get killed in the process, what the hell? These guys ain't too bright, and they're probably half-crazy, but they totally mean well, with trying to save the world and whatnot. Wanna know something funny? After at least 2 or 3 viewings of this film, something really peculiar occurred to me. There isn't one female to be found in Bad Taste. While it isn't a large cast to begin with, and I'm not really sure what purpose a woman would serve in a sci-fi gore-comedy, I just think it's peculiar. And no. None of this is relevant. But, anyway. What a happy day it will be when, I mean if Peter Jackson decides to return to his gory roots one more time. Since he's already done the alien thing, and not to mention the living dead masterpiece that is Dead Alive, perhaps Jackson should make a disgustingly gory Vampire flick. Or maybe he should just keep making big-budget kids movies. Yeah. That sounds about right. Something tells me Peter Jackson's days as director of films like Bad Taste and other awsomeness are long gone. Whatever. Plenty of other cult Horror filmmakers out there, doin' their thing. But there was a time, not that long ago that your beloved Lord Of The Rings guy was out there doing some amazing stuff in the underground. Once again, Dead Alive would be the best example of this theory, but Bad Taste is nothing short of amazing in its own right. That doesn't necessarily mean you should then go rush off and buy Meet The Feebles as well. That's another story for another day. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Splatterfest Flick, Jackson's Greatest Hit!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tequila101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care what anybody says about this flick but I think this is Peter Jackson's best work. After watching "Meet the Feebles" nearly seven years ago, as a kid I was always edging to watch "Bad Taste" and I was seriously expecting this to be cheap and stupid but instead I got more than what i asked for. This film for the 80's has top notch gore, funny-ass scenes, impossible situations and non stop horrific/comedic action. I always wanted to see this film as a kid and now, I'm glad that I did. The Alien look is very creative and I also love the switch between music themes, first we had creepy adventures, and very wondrous tones of what's gonna happen next and then, we had old rocking, action packed style of play. It was all very creative. Along with Meet the Feebles, (which the trailer say has no taste at all lol) to and for me this was the next level of a Peter Jackson film and it's absolutely funny and creepy at it's best. Even if I didn't find this scary on any levels and I do think that this film has an insane way of telling it's story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sometimes jokingly remark how Peter Jackson's career was perfect until he directed the Lord of the Rings trilogy. It's hard to imagine that this director, who now specializes in big budget Hollywood movies, started off by creating twisted and gory low budget movies  his directorial debut, Bad Taste, being the prime example of this early, strange phase. Bad Taste was by no means an easy experience for Jackson, since the filming took 4 years. However, the hard work paid off and Bad Taste can be used as a valuable lesson in "do-it-yourself: low budget film making". It's amazing how, in spite of rather limited resources, Jackson managed to make it all work and look good  he created the masks and firearm replicas for the movie himself. He even constructed his own counterweighted steady-cam. Bad Taste is a definite must see for every aspiring movie maker, if only for Peter Jackson's creativity. The movie follows 4 agents (called 'The Boys') of some sort of secret service, who investigate alien activity in a small town. Apparently, the aliens have killed the whole population and replaced it. Things become more complicated when the aliens kidnap a charity collector passing through, and it's up to The Boys to save him, by using any means necessary. As you can see, Bad Taste's plot is fairly simple, there isn't much "story" to it  the movie is mainly action and dialogue driven. Due to this fact, the movie gets boring from time to time and I find it to be the worst from Peter Jackson's early phase. I also find it to be the least funny one. While there are quite a few amusing scenes, it doesn't even come close to other early classics like Braindead and Meet the Feebles. But at least there is enough violence and gore in it to make it interesting. The movie does get pretty graphic. Did you first notice the guy missing the top of his head or the Peter Jackson cameo? The effects in the movie (influenced by the cult special effects artist Tom Savini) are surely its best quality. You'll see heads exploding, limbs being torn off and even some chainsaw action. The scene which impressed me the most was the one where a character, played by Peter Jackson, fights with another character  also played by Peter Jackson. Actually, if you're not informed prior to the watching of movie, you may not notice he plays two different characters since they don't really look alike. Who knows  maybe Jackson has an acting talent waiting to be further developed? Speaking of acting, the actors did an OK job for this kind of movie, no one is laughably bad. On a side note, I think it's important to remark that all of the dialogue was dubbed in post production; that, however, isn't much of a bother since it isn't very apparent. While I wasn't really keen on Bad Taste (like I said  I found it to be somewhat boring and I prefer other early Jackson works) I would definitely recommend it to everyone. It's a gory, funny trash/cult flick about some guys fighting off a bunch of butt shaped aliens, set to an 80s heavy metal soundtrack. Why wouldn't you watch it? Rating: 6/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Until Jackson's follow-up 'Brain Dead', this may have been the goriest film ever made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jack Hawkins (Hawkensian)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love 'Bad Taste'. I love that the film was made for about $20 and that the cast consists of Peter Jackson's mates. It's also so enjoyable because it demonstrates how talented a filmmaker Jackson is. For example, there is a scene near the beginning of the film where Derek (Peter Jackson) fights with some alien invaders on a cliff side, it is hilariously gory and feels so very dangerous; through sheer talent (and a massive amount of bravery!), the crew achieves a tangible sense of acrophobia. In 'Bad Taste', Earth is under threat from alien invaders who are endeavouring to fill a culinary gap in their intergalactic fast-food market  the demand for tasty human flesh. The malicious extra- terrestrials don't arouse suspicion as they assume human appearances. Before the Astro Investigation and Defence Service (AIDS) arrive, the malevolent visitors have already wiped out the entire town of Kaihoro, New Zealand. This elite team is comprised of Derek (Peter Jackson), a rather odd Kiwi with an insatiable bloodlust, Barry (Pete O'Hearn), a man who will use his .44 Magnum only when necessary and Frank (Mike Minett), Giles (Craig Smith) and Ozzy (Terry Potter), a trio of muscle car driving tough guys. Jackson's early films have a real talent for choreographing slapstick gore, there are heads being blown off, brains being eaten, arms being torn off, severed heads being drop kicked, seagulls being head butted, entire bodies being chain sawed and even sheep being detonated. The film is utterly drenched in an outrageous amount of viscera; however it is all of the slapstick variety with a strong Commonwealth lacing of black humour. Though the film is by no means a performance film, there is a certain charm about the cast's inexperience. Also, Peter Jackson is hilarious as the absurd, demented Derek, whose horrible shrill laugh and personal motto 'I'm a Derek, Dereks don't run!' are particularly memorable. The filming locations, such as the aforementioned cliff side, are all of outstanding natural beauty; 'Bad Taste' is as much an advertisement for the country as Jackson's later work would be. As we all know, Jackson has since gone downhill, directing the poxy 'Lord of the Rings' and 'The Hobbit' trilogies  what a shame. However, he has recently expressed interest in making another horror film; I just hope he sticks to his roots with a shoestring budget and an immeasurable amount of corn syrup and gore. www.hawkensian.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's about time Jackson was funny again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before Peter Jackson almost exclusively worked with a CGI backdrop in the land of Middle-Earth, he began his film making career in the realms of low budget comedy-horror. Utilising the 1980's trend for splatter cinema, and no doubt the influence of Sam Raimi's tongue-in-cheek zombie film, The Evil Dead (1982), Jackson's debut feature film was entrenched in a very American tradition, but beholds the humour of his native New Zealand - which incidentally is part of the British commonwealth, meaning much of the uniqueness of British comedy is transposed onto the antipodean nation, the influence of Monty Python being one particular aspect of the film that made it such a surprise success. Bad Taste was clearly a labour of love, with Jackson bringing friends and family in to contribute to the making. The nature of the films production adds something quite special to both the narrative and the humour. The home- made special effects and props (Jackson used his parents oven to bake the handmade armoury used in the film) work both as farce and as actually quite an achievement of authenticity. Set in a small, isolated town, a group of misfits, "The Boys," ordered from a shadowy government department, have been sent to investigate an invasion, where aliens have wiped out the inhabitants. What transpires is an alien fast food corporation have discovered that human flesh is the galaxy's newest taste sensation, and are accumulating cardboard boxes of flesh to market and sell to planets. At the centre of the government group is geeky scientist, Derek (Played by Jackson himself - he is also in the role of the alien Robert), who "can only relate to birds". He salivates at the sight of dismemberment and artillery. As the group discover the truth about the alien invasion, their mission is to stop them from leaving the planet. On a narrative level, Bad Taste is as simple as they come. But underneath this simplicity is a wealth of brilliantly formed characters, with their own idiosyncrasies, and a range of beautifully crafted one liners and references. There are some stand out moments created with gruesome, cheep, but effective effects. The aliens seem to be mostly influenced by the zombie cinema of George A. Romero, with their slow moving mannerisms, and like Romero and Savini, Jackson delights in slicing them up with sharp tools and exploding them with guns. One alien has the top half of his head chopped off, a scene that displays Jackson's talent for editing, as he seamlessly cuts from the actors legs stumbling, to the rubbery half-head spurting copious amounts of blood and gore. Derek provides some of the most grotesque, Grand Guignol elements after he falls from a cliff, leaving a skull flat that exposes his brain matter. After this event, he constantly battles to keep the brain inside his head, strapping it closed with a belt. These scenes merge those ideas the comedy of the absurd, with the horrific splatter of giallo or the ridiculously over- the-top gore films of Herschell Gordon Lewis. Considering the limitations of the incredibly low budget (according to IMDb, the films budget was estimated at 30,000 NZD), the film looks good. Of course the film stock, the acting and the special effects aren't up to some of the more expensive American productions of its type, but with an insanely funny script, and the excessive nature of the violence, it is a film that should be loved. I do remember first seeing this film on video around 1989/1990, no doubt initially attracted by the latex alien on the video cover flipping the bird. It was soon the talk of the playground, as school friends would delight in the gore. But more specifically, I, along with my peers, were fundamentally reacting to the outlandish and on-the-money comedy, which holds up today as much as the first two Monty Python films. Gross-out comedy on this scale, has not been so much fun as this since. It's a shame Jackson hides away in Middle-Earth so much these days, it's about time he was funny again. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, witty and playfully violent - but not to everyone's taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not too many movies with limited budget producing good outcome, especially if sci-fi is involved as one has to provide resources for camera tricks. As for Bad Taste, this movie was made for less than 30,000 USD - but it took years to complete it. The plot is peculiar and main characters is uncommon mixture of zombies and aliens. The ending is witty and distinctive - and all this is years before when Tarantino or Rodriguez began their famous mishmashes. The cast is totally amateur - Jackson's friends and acquaintances - but in a good sense, giving an interesting purity and fun. As for Jackson himself, he showed himself as talented actor, he could be used more in this function as well (later he has appeared only in cameo roles). In short, an interesting and already a cult movie, recommended to all fans of horror alien movies, but preferably no eating during watching! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most memorable treats!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avinash Shukla
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Peter Jackson for his bizarre creativity. Bad Taste, Braindead, Meet the Feebles are all bizarre in their own way. As I love splatsticks, I worship 'Bad Taste' for the position it holds in the world of splatter cinema. Peter Jackson has a strange way of using gore. His gory sequences are seldom disturbing and overuse of fake blood makes the gore look like a comedic device, which should be laughed and laughed upon for eternity! So what's the story about 'Bad Taste'? This is a typical B-film but is slicker and more tongue-in-cheek than any of the films that fall into the category of extreme cinema. Jackson's tales never let the viewer lose interest in his films. Perhaps Jackson is such an artist who can make murder look like plain humor! Considering the limitations Jackson faced both financially and technically during the filming of 'Bad Taste', the film looks as great as Taj Mahal to me. The tale is fairly simple at heart. The Astro Investigation Defense Service sends 4 men Ozzy (Terry Potter), Derek (Peter Jackson), Barry (Pete O'Herne) and Frank (Mike Minett) to a town 'Kaihoro' (Food-town in Maori?) to discover the reason behind unexplained disappearances of the townspeople. The men find blood splattered everywhere with no trace of the townsfolk. The place looks like an abattoir, as Barry tells Derek on his radio. The men soon come to know that the town is plagued with zombies, who will kill anything that comes their way. Detailed findings lead the men to the whereabouts of the zombies where they have all gathered for a meet. The meet is hosted by their chief Lord Crumb (Doug Wren). The men come to know that Lord Crumb and his zombie force are actually extraterrestrial beings in the guise of humans and have plans of harvesting human meat for their own intergalactic food franchise. So the dead townsfolk are now in the boxes, ready for the alien consumption! The men also find Giles (Craig Smith), a donation collector in a drum, soaked in spices and free him. Watching for the right time to strike, they all take positions and open fire at the dawn. Causing heavy casualties, the men force Lord Crumb to retreat in his home-faced-UFO. However, Derek has plans of his own that are more sinister than Lord Crumb could have ever imagined. The film as you can see is based on hyper-imagination. Jackson however makes this work. 'Bad Taste' has great comedy scenes and an appealing atmosphere. Thanks to Jackson's hometown Pukerua Bay and the New Zealand lush belt, where this flick was shot. These locations add good atmosphere in the film and shaky camera work at places makes the viewer dizzy. Over-the-top splatter plays a special role here and gives enough reality to the film. So if you're a kind of person who loves to puke on the nasty, give this a try. I am sure you won't be disappointed, and don't forget to watch Peter Jackson's evil twin Robert!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stay where you are then, and I'll give you an eye witness description of this, intergalactic w*nker!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I expect you're wondering what you're doing soaking in Reg's eleven secret herbs and spices. Tomorrow we're having you for lunch!" Yes, the aliens have turned the villagers into tasty burgers, and Derek (Peter Jackson) must defeat them before they spread to the whole world. This time the good guy has the chainsaw, but will he be able to defeat the evil corporate aliens who are just trying to supply their fast-food chain? And, yes, this is the same Peter Jackson of Lord of the Rings fame. Be prepared for some really bloody scenes, and humor that borders on the outrageous. Borders, heck, it is outrageously funny. Oh yes, lots of gooey, icky stuff coming out of bodies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It is what the title says, in the funniest possible way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan Ashley (DanLives1980)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the '80's and early '90's visionary director of 'Lord of the Rings', 'King Kong' and 'The Lovely Bones' Peter Jackson was making the type of films some countries don't even allow today, outside of Asia and the US. It may come as a shock for fans of his work this last decade to witness 'Meet The Feebles' or 'Braindead' and vice versa for fans of his old outings. 'Bad Taste' is an action-sci-fi-horror about a small unit of dimwitted rejects from the fictional governmental department "the Astro Investigation and Defence Service" (AIDS LOL) who are stationed in various locations around a deserted coastal town, which has been wiped out by alien invaders. Upon two of their unit being marauded by groups of the aliens disguised as humans, they regroup and head in to gather intelligence where they discover Earth has been targeted by the ruthless leader of one of the galaxy's biggest fast food corporations, hence the title, 'Bad Taste!' The film is possibly one of the tackiest and most absurd ever conceived, yet boasts of its absurdity because it is so notoriously fun to watch and has some pretty fantastic (although dated) practical special effects, and people will even watch it over and over again to remind themselves how bad it is. What people don't seem to get is that it's a balls-out parody that simply doesn't count on inter-textual references to be understood. Instead it counts on the childish humour of a bunch of male friends most likely trying to test their girlfriends' gag reflexes, almost like a fictional Jackass or Dirty Sanchez movie. It's a boys film that cuts out all the unnecessary plot and dialogue and goes straight for the knives, guns, bazookas, chainsaws, blood and guts and vomit gags, nothing more, nothing less. I may be biased in voting it a 7 out of 10 but still I tried to be fair. It's badly acted, badly produced, badly offensive and pure bad taste in every way possible but still, the performers in the movie are likable and they provide you with a lot of laughs. Peter Jackson must have made this from his garden shed back then, but if that's the case, what an effort. Love it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not gonna gloss anything over in the review....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    witster18
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tough film to review here! Bad Taste is essentially Peter Jackson learning the ropes and experimenting with practically zero cash. The result is a gory and sometimes funny mess. He polished this formula up for 'Dead Alive', and 'Dead Alive' definitely shows a progression both in Jackson's talent, and his pocketbook(although DA had a small budget too). You can see Jackson's influences. Direction similar to early Romero, and Gore that reminds me of some of the late 70's/early 80's gore-fests. The gore here is in heavy doses, and it is probably the strongest characteristic of this film - along with what he achieved overall given the restrictions with the budget and cast. He learned from the best... Other influences were surely make-up masterminds like Tom Savini and Rick Baker. You have to be in the right mindset to enjoy this movie. I've seen it three times. The first time was years ago and I didn't enjoy the film at all. Years later, after realizing that you don't have to take everything so serious, and that horror films can be as funny as they are scary - I gave it another whirl. I laughed on a few occasions and my interest was sparked but not glued. The third time I concentrated more on Jackson's technique and the little nuances that make this film more of a lesson in film-making than an enjoyable 90 minutes. My conclusion. Bad Taste is a film to be appreciated by horror/comedy fans, and fans of making film - because it's essentially someone just like you making their first backyard movie. The only difference is the effort and the near flawless shots of gore and tension that can only be achieved at the hands of someone who is A.Talented, B.Meticulous, and C.An Obvious Film-Buff. He was paying attention to how Romero achieved tension with his close-ups and sound,... and the editing here, for what it is, is amazing. The plot is a dose of Comedy, horror, and sci-fi. Bad Taste is a bitter-sweet, low-budget gore-fest with humor to boot. All that said - most people will NOT enjoy this movie. If you just love gore.. or film-making.... or the Evil Dead Series... or find yourself in love with Cult Classics like Toxic Avenger Etc... then sure, you might like it. Otherwise, skip this one because many Cult-Classics like this have extremely inflated scores here on IMDb. That's because 90% of the small number of reviewers have seen it 90 times, and that 90% is rating this a 10. It's no 10!... It's not even close!... it's exactly what I said it was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Super size me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know. Scores of Millions of dollars is OK too, but why would Peter Jackson insist on doing what he's been doing over the last decade, when he obviously found his calling in life as director of the goriest, craziest, and most outrageous splatter flicks available? And the man only made two of them, yet made a lasting, not to mention an influential impression. Before 1992's Dead Alive (still the goriest film in existence), Jackson would shoot on video, what has to be the greatest sci-fi-gore-comedy in the history of New Zealand. This is Bad Taste. It's what I've always said. There just ain't enough micro-budgeted, sci-comedy with lots and lots of gore. As sweet as the gore is, it really does take a backseat to the comic genius this film offers. Bad Taste is about an alien fast-food franchise who recently decided that human flesh would be a good choice for their menu. Cheap, convenient, not bad. After decimating the entire town of Kaihoro, in New Zealand, the Astro- Investigation and Defense Service is called in to exterminate these guys, who can take the form of humans at will. These eager beavers are ready to blow a hole in anything that moves, so if any actual humans get killed in the process, what the hell? These guys ain't too bright, and they're probably half-crazy, but they totally mean well, with trying to save the world and whatnot. Wanna know something funny? After at least 2 or 3 viewings of this film, something really peculiar occurred to me. There isn't one female to be found in Bad Taste. While it isn't a large cast to begin with, and I'm not really sure what purpose a woman would serve in a sci-fi gore-comedy, I just think it's peculiar. And no. None of this is relevant. But, anyway. What a happy day it will be when, I mean if Peter Jackson decides to return to his gory roots one more time. Since he's already done the alien thing, and not to mention the living dead masterpiece that is Dead Alive, perhaps Jackson should make a disgustingly gory Vampire flick. Or maybe he should just keep making big-budget kids movies. Yeah. That sounds about right. Something tells me Peter Jackson's days as director of films like Bad Taste and other awsomeness are long gone. Whatever. Plenty of other cult Horror filmmakers out there, doin' their thing. But there was a time, not that long ago that your beloved Lord Of The Rings guy was out there doing some amazing stuff in the underground. Once again, Dead Alive would be the best example of this theory, but Bad Taste is nothing short of amazing in its own right. That doesn't necessarily mean you should then go rush off and buy Meet The Feebles as well. That's another story for another day. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Splatterfest Flick, Jackson's Greatest Hit!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tequila101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care what anybody says about this flick but I think this is Peter Jackson's best work. After watching "Meet the Feebles" nearly seven years ago, as a kid I was always edging to watch "Bad Taste" and I was seriously expecting this to be cheap and stupid but instead I got more than what i asked for. This film for the 80's has top notch gore, funny-ass scenes, impossible situations and non stop horrific/comedic action. I always wanted to see this film as a kid and now, I'm glad that I did. The Alien look is very creative and I also love the switch between music themes, first we had creepy adventures, and very wondrous tones of what's gonna happen next and then, we had old rocking, action packed style of play. It was all very creative. Along with Meet the Feebles, (which the trailer say has no taste at all lol) to and for me this was the next level of a Peter Jackson film and it's absolutely funny and creepy at it's best. Even if I didn't find this scary on any levels and I do think that this film has an insane way of telling it's story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sometimes jokingly remark how Peter Jackson's career was perfect until he directed the Lord of the Rings trilogy. It's hard to imagine that this director, who now specializes in big budget Hollywood movies, started off by creating twisted and gory low budget movies  his directorial debut, Bad Taste, being the prime example of this early, strange phase. Bad Taste was by no means an easy experience for Jackson, since the filming took 4 years. However, the hard work paid off and Bad Taste can be used as a valuable lesson in "do-it-yourself: low budget film making". It's amazing how, in spite of rather limited resources, Jackson managed to make it all work and look good  he created the masks and firearm replicas for the movie himself. He even constructed his own counterweighted steady-cam. Bad Taste is a definite must see for every aspiring movie maker, if only for Peter Jackson's creativity. The movie follows 4 agents (called 'The Boys') of some sort of secret service, who investigate alien activity in a small town. Apparently, the aliens have killed the whole population and replaced it. Things become more complicated when the aliens kidnap a charity collector passing through, and it's up to The Boys to save him, by using any means necessary. As you can see, Bad Taste's plot is fairly simple, there isn't much "story" to it  the movie is mainly action and dialogue driven. Due to this fact, the movie gets boring from time to time and I find it to be the worst from Peter Jackson's early phase. I also find it to be the least funny one. While there are quite a few amusing scenes, it doesn't even come close to other early classics like Braindead and Meet the Feebles. But at least there is enough violence and gore in it to make it interesting. The movie does get pretty graphic. Did you first notice the guy missing the top of his head or the Peter Jackson cameo? The effects in the movie (influenced by the cult special effects artist Tom Savini) are surely its best quality. You'll see heads exploding, limbs being torn off and even some chainsaw action. The scene which impressed me the most was the one where a character, played by Peter Jackson, fights with another character  also played by Peter Jackson. Actually, if you're not informed prior to the watching of movie, you may not notice he plays two different characters since they don't really look alike. Who knows  maybe Jackson has an acting talent waiting to be further developed? Speaking of acting, the actors did an OK job for this kind of movie, no one is laughably bad. On a side note, I think it's important to remark that all of the dialogue was dubbed in post production; that, however, isn't much of a bother since it isn't very apparent. While I wasn't really keen on Bad Taste (like I said  I found it to be somewhat boring and I prefer other early Jackson works) I would definitely recommend it to everyone. It's a gory, funny trash/cult flick about some guys fighting off a bunch of butt shaped aliens, set to an 80s heavy metal soundtrack. Why wouldn't you watch it? Rating: 6/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Until Jackson's follow-up 'Brain Dead', this may have been the goriest film ever made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jack Hawkins (Hawkensian)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love 'Bad Taste'. I love that the film was made for about $20 and that the cast consists of Peter Jackson's mates. It's also so enjoyable because it demonstrates how talented a filmmaker Jackson is. For example, there is a scene near the beginning of the film where Derek (Peter Jackson) fights with some alien invaders on a cliff side, it is hilariously gory and feels so very dangerous; through sheer talent (and a massive amount of bravery!), the crew achieves a tangible sense of acrophobia. In 'Bad Taste', Earth is under threat from alien invaders who are endeavouring to fill a culinary gap in their intergalactic fast-food market  the demand for tasty human flesh. The malicious extra- terrestrials don't arouse suspicion as they assume human appearances. Before the Astro Investigation and Defence Service (AIDS) arrive, the malevolent visitors have already wiped out the entire town of Kaihoro, New Zealand. This elite team is comprised of Derek (Peter Jackson), a rather odd Kiwi with an insatiable bloodlust, Barry (Pete O'Hearn), a man who will use his .44 Magnum only when necessary and Frank (Mike Minett), Giles (Craig Smith) and Ozzy (Terry Potter), a trio of muscle car driving tough guys. Jackson's early films have a real talent for choreographing slapstick gore, there are heads being blown off, brains being eaten, arms being torn off, severed heads being drop kicked, seagulls being head butted, entire bodies being chain sawed and even sheep being detonated. The film is utterly drenched in an outrageous amount of viscera; however it is all of the slapstick variety with a strong Commonwealth lacing of black humour. Though the film is by no means a performance film, there is a certain charm about the cast's inexperience. Also, Peter Jackson is hilarious as the absurd, demented Derek, whose horrible shrill laugh and personal motto 'I'm a Derek, Dereks don't run!' are particularly memorable. The filming locations, such as the aforementioned cliff side, are all of outstanding natural beauty; 'Bad Taste' is as much an advertisement for the country as Jackson's later work would be. As we all know, Jackson has since gone downhill, directing the poxy 'Lord of the Rings' and 'The Hobbit' trilogies  what a shame. However, he has recently expressed interest in making another horror film; I just hope he sticks to his roots with a shoestring budget and an immeasurable amount of corn syrup and gore. www.hawkensian.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's about time Jackson was funny again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before Peter Jackson almost exclusively worked with a CGI backdrop in the land of Middle-Earth, he began his film making career in the realms of low budget comedy-horror. Utilising the 1980's trend for splatter cinema, and no doubt the influence of Sam Raimi's tongue-in-cheek zombie film, The Evil Dead (1982), Jackson's debut feature film was entrenched in a very American tradition, but beholds the humour of his native New Zealand - which incidentally is part of the British commonwealth, meaning much of the uniqueness of British comedy is transposed onto the antipodean nation, the influence of Monty Python being one particular aspect of the film that made it such a surprise success. Bad Taste was clearly a labour of love, with Jackson bringing friends and family in to contribute to the making. The nature of the films production adds something quite special to both the narrative and the humour. The home- made special effects and props (Jackson used his parents oven to bake the handmade armoury used in the film) work both as farce and as actually quite an achievement of authenticity. Set in a small, isolated town, a group of misfits, "The Boys," ordered from a shadowy government department, have been sent to investigate an invasion, where aliens have wiped out the inhabitants. What transpires is an alien fast food corporation have discovered that human flesh is the galaxy's newest taste sensation, and are accumulating cardboard boxes of flesh to market and sell to planets. At the centre of the government group is geeky scientist, Derek (Played by Jackson himself - he is also in the role of the alien Robert), who "can only relate to birds". He salivates at the sight of dismemberment and artillery. As the group discover the truth about the alien invasion, their mission is to stop them from leaving the planet. On a narrative level, Bad Taste is as simple as they come. But underneath this simplicity is a wealth of brilliantly formed characters, with their own idiosyncrasies, and a range of beautifully crafted one liners and references. There are some stand out moments created with gruesome, cheep, but effective effects. The aliens seem to be mostly influenced by the zombie cinema of George A. Romero, with their slow moving mannerisms, and like Romero and Savini, Jackson delights in slicing them up with sharp tools and exploding them with guns. One alien has the top half of his head chopped off, a scene that displays Jackson's talent for editing, as he seamlessly cuts from the actors legs stumbling, to the rubbery half-head spurting copious amounts of blood and gore. Derek provides some of the most grotesque, Grand Guignol elements after he falls from a cliff, leaving a skull flat that exposes his brain matter. After this event, he constantly battles to keep the brain inside his head, strapping it closed with a belt. These scenes merge those ideas the comedy of the absurd, with the horrific splatter of giallo or the ridiculously over- the-top gore films of Herschell Gordon Lewis. Considering the limitations of the incredibly low budget (according to IMDb, the films budget was estimated at 30,000 NZD), the film looks good. Of course the film stock, the acting and the special effects aren't up to some of the more expensive American productions of its type, but with an insanely funny script, and the excessive nature of the violence, it is a film that should be loved. I do remember first seeing this film on video around 1989/1990, no doubt initially attracted by the latex alien on the video cover flipping the bird. It was soon the talk of the playground, as school friends would delight in the gore. But more specifically, I, along with my peers, were fundamentally reacting to the outlandish and on-the-money comedy, which holds up today as much as the first two Monty Python films. Gross-out comedy on this scale, has not been so much fun as this since. It's a shame Jackson hides away in Middle-Earth so much these days, it's about time he was funny again. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, witty and playfully violent - but not to everyone's taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not too many movies with limited budget producing good outcome, especially if sci-fi is involved as one has to provide resources for camera tricks. As for Bad Taste, this movie was made for less than 30,000 USD - but it took years to complete it. The plot is peculiar and main characters is uncommon mixture of zombies and aliens. The ending is witty and distinctive - and all this is years before when Tarantino or Rodriguez began their famous mishmashes. The cast is totally amateur - Jackson's friends and acquaintances - but in a good sense, giving an interesting purity and fun. As for Jackson himself, he showed himself as talented actor, he could be used more in this function as well (later he has appeared only in cameo roles). In short, an interesting and already a cult movie, recommended to all fans of horror alien movies, but preferably no eating during watching! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most memorable treats!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avinash Shukla
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Peter Jackson for his bizarre creativity. Bad Taste, Braindead, Meet the Feebles are all bizarre in their own way. As I love splatsticks, I worship 'Bad Taste' for the position it holds in the world of splatter cinema. Peter Jackson has a strange way of using gore. His gory sequences are seldom disturbing and overuse of fake blood makes the gore look like a comedic device, which should be laughed and laughed upon for eternity! So what's the story about 'Bad Taste'? This is a typical B-film but is slicker and more tongue-in-cheek than any of the films that fall into the category of extreme cinema. Jackson's tales never let the viewer lose interest in his films. Perhaps Jackson is such an artist who can make murder look like plain humor! Considering the limitations Jackson faced both financially and technically during the filming of 'Bad Taste', the film looks as great as Taj Mahal to me. The tale is fairly simple at heart. The Astro Investigation Defense Service sends 4 men Ozzy (Terry Potter), Derek (Peter Jackson), Barry (Pete O'Herne) and Frank (Mike Minett) to a town 'Kaihoro' (Food-town in Maori?) to discover the reason behind unexplained disappearances of the townspeople. The men find blood splattered everywhere with no trace of the townsfolk. The place looks like an abattoir, as Barry tells Derek on his radio. The men soon come to know that the town is plagued with zombies, who will kill anything that comes their way. Detailed findings lead the men to the whereabouts of the zombies where they have all gathered for a meet. The meet is hosted by their chief Lord Crumb (Doug Wren). The men come to know that Lord Crumb and his zombie force are actually extraterrestrial beings in the guise of humans and have plans of harvesting human meat for their own intergalactic food franchise. So the dead townsfolk are now in the boxes, ready for the alien consumption! The men also find Giles (Craig Smith), a donation collector in a drum, soaked in spices and free him. Watching for the right time to strike, they all take positions and open fire at the dawn. Causing heavy casualties, the men force Lord Crumb to retreat in his home-faced-UFO. However, Derek has plans of his own that are more sinister than Lord Crumb could have ever imagined. The film as you can see is based on hyper-imagination. Jackson however makes this work. 'Bad Taste' has great comedy scenes and an appealing atmosphere. Thanks to Jackson's hometown Pukerua Bay and the New Zealand lush belt, where this flick was shot. These locations add good atmosphere in the film and shaky camera work at places makes the viewer dizzy. Over-the-top splatter plays a special role here and gives enough reality to the film. So if you're a kind of person who loves to puke on the nasty, give this a try. I am sure you won't be disappointed, and don't forget to watch Peter Jackson's evil twin Robert!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stay where you are then, and I'll give you an eye witness description of this, intergalactic w*nker!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I expect you're wondering what you're doing soaking in Reg's eleven secret herbs and spices. Tomorrow we're having you for lunch!" Yes, the aliens have turned the villagers into tasty burgers, and Derek (Peter Jackson) must defeat them before they spread to the whole world. This time the good guy has the chainsaw, but will he be able to defeat the evil corporate aliens who are just trying to supply their fast-food chain? And, yes, this is the same Peter Jackson of Lord of the Rings fame. Be prepared for some really bloody scenes, and humor that borders on the outrageous. Borders, heck, it is outrageously funny. Oh yes, lots of gooey, icky stuff coming out of bodies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It is what the title says, in the funniest possible way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan Ashley (DanLives1980)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the '80's and early '90's visionary director of 'Lord of the Rings', 'King Kong' and 'The Lovely Bones' Peter Jackson was making the type of films some countries don't even allow today, outside of Asia and the US. It may come as a shock for fans of his work this last decade to witness 'Meet The Feebles' or 'Braindead' and vice versa for fans of his old outings. 'Bad Taste' is an action-sci-fi-horror about a small unit of dimwitted rejects from the fictional governmental department "the Astro Investigation and Defence Service" (AIDS LOL) who are stationed in various locations around a deserted coastal town, which has been wiped out by alien invaders. Upon two of their unit being marauded by groups of the aliens disguised as humans, they regroup and head in to gather intelligence where they discover Earth has been targeted by the ruthless leader of one of the galaxy's biggest fast food corporations, hence the title, 'Bad Taste!' The film is possibly one of the tackiest and most absurd ever conceived, yet boasts of its absurdity because it is so notoriously fun to watch and has some pretty fantastic (although dated) practical special effects, and people will even watch it over and over again to remind themselves how bad it is. What people don't seem to get is that it's a balls-out parody that simply doesn't count on inter-textual references to be understood. Instead it counts on the childish humour of a bunch of male friends most likely trying to test their girlfriends' gag reflexes, almost like a fictional Jackass or Dirty Sanchez movie. It's a boys film that cuts out all the unnecessary plot and dialogue and goes straight for the knives, guns, bazookas, chainsaws, blood and guts and vomit gags, nothing more, nothing less. I may be biased in voting it a 7 out of 10 but still I tried to be fair. It's badly acted, badly produced, badly offensive and pure bad taste in every way possible but still, the performers in the movie are likable and they provide you with a lot of laughs. Peter Jackson must have made this from his garden shed back then, but if that's the case, what an effort. Love it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not gonna gloss anything over in the review....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    witster18
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tough film to review here! Bad Taste is essentially Peter Jackson learning the ropes and experimenting with practically zero cash. The result is a gory and sometimes funny mess. He polished this formula up for 'Dead Alive', and 'Dead Alive' definitely shows a progression both in Jackson's talent, and his pocketbook(although DA had a small budget too). You can see Jackson's influences. Direction similar to early Romero, and Gore that reminds me of some of the late 70's/early 80's gore-fests. The gore here is in heavy doses, and it is probably the strongest characteristic of this film - along with what he achieved overall given the restrictions with the budget and cast. He learned from the best... Other influences were surely make-up masterminds like Tom Savini and Rick Baker. You have to be in the right mindset to enjoy this movie. I've seen it three times. The first time was years ago and I didn't enjoy the film at all. Years later, after realizing that you don't have to take everything so serious, and that horror films can be as funny as they are scary - I gave it another whirl. I laughed on a few occasions and my interest was sparked but not glued. The third time I concentrated more on Jackson's technique and the little nuances that make this film more of a lesson in film-making than an enjoyable 90 minutes. My conclusion. Bad Taste is a film to be appreciated by horror/comedy fans, and fans of making film - because it's essentially someone just like you making their first backyard movie. The only difference is the effort and the near flawless shots of gore and tension that can only be achieved at the hands of someone who is A.Talented, B.Meticulous, and C.An Obvious Film-Buff. He was paying attention to how Romero achieved tension with his close-ups and sound,... and the editing here, for what it is, is amazing. The plot is a dose of Comedy, horror, and sci-fi. Bad Taste is a bitter-sweet, low-budget gore-fest with humor to boot. All that said - most people will NOT enjoy this movie. If you just love gore.. or film-making.... or the Evil Dead Series... or find yourself in love with Cult Classics like Toxic Avenger Etc... then sure, you might like it. Otherwise, skip this one because many Cult-Classics like this have extremely inflated scores here on IMDb. That's because 90% of the small number of reviewers have seen it 90 times, and that 90% is rating this a 10. It's no 10!... It's not even close!... it's exactly what I said it was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Super size me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know. Scores of Millions of dollars is OK too, but why would Peter Jackson insist on doing what he's been doing over the last decade, when he obviously found his calling in life as director of the goriest, craziest, and most outrageous splatter flicks available? And the man only made two of them, yet made a lasting, not to mention an influential impression. Before 1992's Dead Alive (still the goriest film in existence), Jackson would shoot on video, what has to be the greatest sci-fi-gore-comedy in the history of New Zealand. This is Bad Taste. It's what I've always said. There just ain't enough micro-budgeted, sci-comedy with lots and lots of gore. As sweet as the gore is, it really does take a backseat to the comic genius this film offers. Bad Taste is about an alien fast-food franchise who recently decided that human flesh would be a good choice for their menu. Cheap, convenient, not bad. After decimating the entire town of Kaihoro, in New Zealand, the Astro- Investigation and Defense Service is called in to exterminate these guys, who can take the form of humans at will. These eager beavers are ready to blow a hole in anything that moves, so if any actual humans get killed in the process, what the hell? These guys ain't too bright, and they're probably half-crazy, but they totally mean well, with trying to save the world and whatnot. Wanna know something funny? After at least 2 or 3 viewings of this film, something really peculiar occurred to me. There isn't one female to be found in Bad Taste. While it isn't a large cast to begin with, and I'm not really sure what purpose a woman would serve in a sci-fi gore-comedy, I just think it's peculiar. And no. None of this is relevant. But, anyway. What a happy day it will be when, I mean if Peter Jackson decides to return to his gory roots one more time. Since he's already done the alien thing, and not to mention the living dead masterpiece that is Dead Alive, perhaps Jackson should make a disgustingly gory Vampire flick. Or maybe he should just keep making big-budget kids movies. Yeah. That sounds about right. Something tells me Peter Jackson's days as director of films like Bad Taste and other awsomeness are long gone. Whatever. Plenty of other cult Horror filmmakers out there, doin' their thing. But there was a time, not that long ago that your beloved Lord Of The Rings guy was out there doing some amazing stuff in the underground. Once again, Dead Alive would be the best example of this theory, but Bad Taste is nothing short of amazing in its own right. That doesn't necessarily mean you should then go rush off and buy Meet The Feebles as well. That's another story for another day. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Splatterfest Flick, Jackson's Greatest Hit!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tequila101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care what anybody says about this flick but I think this is Peter Jackson's best work. After watching "Meet the Feebles" nearly seven years ago, as a kid I was always edging to watch "Bad Taste" and I was seriously expecting this to be cheap and stupid but instead I got more than what i asked for. This film for the 80's has top notch gore, funny-ass scenes, impossible situations and non stop horrific/comedic action. I always wanted to see this film as a kid and now, I'm glad that I did. The Alien look is very creative and I also love the switch between music themes, first we had creepy adventures, and very wondrous tones of what's gonna happen next and then, we had old rocking, action packed style of play. It was all very creative. Along with Meet the Feebles, (which the trailer say has no taste at all lol) to and for me this was the next level of a Peter Jackson film and it's absolutely funny and creepy at it's best. Even if I didn't find this scary on any levels and I do think that this film has an insane way of telling it's story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sometimes jokingly remark how Peter Jackson's career was perfect until he directed the Lord of the Rings trilogy. It's hard to imagine that this director, who now specializes in big budget Hollywood movies, started off by creating twisted and gory low budget movies  his directorial debut, Bad Taste, being the prime example of this early, strange phase. Bad Taste was by no means an easy experience for Jackson, since the filming took 4 years. However, the hard work paid off and Bad Taste can be used as a valuable lesson in "do-it-yourself: low budget film making". It's amazing how, in spite of rather limited resources, Jackson managed to make it all work and look good  he created the masks and firearm replicas for the movie himself. He even constructed his own counterweighted steady-cam. Bad Taste is a definite must see for every aspiring movie maker, if only for Peter Jackson's creativity. The movie follows 4 agents (called 'The Boys') of some sort of secret service, who investigate alien activity in a small town. Apparently, the aliens have killed the whole population and replaced it. Things become more complicated when the aliens kidnap a charity collector passing through, and it's up to The Boys to save him, by using any means necessary. As you can see, Bad Taste's plot is fairly simple, there isn't much "story" to it  the movie is mainly action and dialogue driven. Due to this fact, the movie gets boring from time to time and I find it to be the worst from Peter Jackson's early phase. I also find it to be the least funny one. While there are quite a few amusing scenes, it doesn't even come close to other early classics like Braindead and Meet the Feebles. But at least there is enough violence and gore in it to make it interesting. The movie does get pretty graphic. Did you first notice the guy missing the top of his head or the Peter Jackson cameo? The effects in the movie (influenced by the cult special effects artist Tom Savini) are surely its best quality. You'll see heads exploding, limbs being torn off and even some chainsaw action. The scene which impressed me the most was the one where a character, played by Peter Jackson, fights with another character  also played by Peter Jackson. Actually, if you're not informed prior to the watching of movie, you may not notice he plays two different characters since they don't really look alike. Who knows  maybe Jackson has an acting talent waiting to be further developed? Speaking of acting, the actors did an OK job for this kind of movie, no one is laughably bad. On a side note, I think it's important to remark that all of the dialogue was dubbed in post production; that, however, isn't much of a bother since it isn't very apparent. While I wasn't really keen on Bad Taste (like I said  I found it to be somewhat boring and I prefer other early Jackson works) I would definitely recommend it to everyone. It's a gory, funny trash/cult flick about some guys fighting off a bunch of butt shaped aliens, set to an 80s heavy metal soundtrack. Why wouldn't you watch it? Rating: 6/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Until Jackson's follow-up 'Brain Dead', this may have been the goriest film ever made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jack Hawkins (Hawkensian)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love 'Bad Taste'. I love that the film was made for about $20 and that the cast consists of Peter Jackson's mates. It's also so enjoyable because it demonstrates how talented a filmmaker Jackson is. For example, there is a scene near the beginning of the film where Derek (Peter Jackson) fights with some alien invaders on a cliff side, it is hilariously gory and feels so very dangerous; through sheer talent (and a massive amount of bravery!), the crew achieves a tangible sense of acrophobia. In 'Bad Taste', Earth is under threat from alien invaders who are endeavouring to fill a culinary gap in their intergalactic fast-food market  the demand for tasty human flesh. The malicious extra- terrestrials don't arouse suspicion as they assume human appearances. Before the Astro Investigation and Defence Service (AIDS) arrive, the malevolent visitors have already wiped out the entire town of Kaihoro, New Zealand. This elite team is comprised of Derek (Peter Jackson), a rather odd Kiwi with an insatiable bloodlust, Barry (Pete O'Hearn), a man who will use his .44 Magnum only when necessary and Frank (Mike Minett), Giles (Craig Smith) and Ozzy (Terry Potter), a trio of muscle car driving tough guys. Jackson's early films have a real talent for choreographing slapstick gore, there are heads being blown off, brains being eaten, arms being torn off, severed heads being drop kicked, seagulls being head butted, entire bodies being chain sawed and even sheep being detonated. The film is utterly drenched in an outrageous amount of viscera; however it is all of the slapstick variety with a strong Commonwealth lacing of black humour. Though the film is by no means a performance film, there is a certain charm about the cast's inexperience. Also, Peter Jackson is hilarious as the absurd, demented Derek, whose horrible shrill laugh and personal motto 'I'm a Derek, Dereks don't run!' are particularly memorable. The filming locations, such as the aforementioned cliff side, are all of outstanding natural beauty; 'Bad Taste' is as much an advertisement for the country as Jackson's later work would be. As we all know, Jackson has since gone downhill, directing the poxy 'Lord of the Rings' and 'The Hobbit' trilogies  what a shame. However, he has recently expressed interest in making another horror film; I just hope he sticks to his roots with a shoestring budget and an immeasurable amount of corn syrup and gore. www.hawkensian.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's about time Jackson was funny again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before Peter Jackson almost exclusively worked with a CGI backdrop in the land of Middle-Earth, he began his film making career in the realms of low budget comedy-horror. Utilising the 1980's trend for splatter cinema, and no doubt the influence of Sam Raimi's tongue-in-cheek zombie film, The Evil Dead (1982), Jackson's debut feature film was entrenched in a very American tradition, but beholds the humour of his native New Zealand - which incidentally is part of the British commonwealth, meaning much of the uniqueness of British comedy is transposed onto the antipodean nation, the influence of Monty Python being one particular aspect of the film that made it such a surprise success. Bad Taste was clearly a labour of love, with Jackson bringing friends and family in to contribute to the making. The nature of the films production adds something quite special to both the narrative and the humour. The home- made special effects and props (Jackson used his parents oven to bake the handmade armoury used in the film) work both as farce and as actually quite an achievement of authenticity. Set in a small, isolated town, a group of misfits, "The Boys," ordered from a shadowy government department, have been sent to investigate an invasion, where aliens have wiped out the inhabitants. What transpires is an alien fast food corporation have discovered that human flesh is the galaxy's newest taste sensation, and are accumulating cardboard boxes of flesh to market and sell to planets. At the centre of the government group is geeky scientist, Derek (Played by Jackson himself - he is also in the role of the alien Robert), who "can only relate to birds". He salivates at the sight of dismemberment and artillery. As the group discover the truth about the alien invasion, their mission is to stop them from leaving the planet. On a narrative level, Bad Taste is as simple as they come. But underneath this simplicity is a wealth of brilliantly formed characters, with their own idiosyncrasies, and a range of beautifully crafted one liners and references. There are some stand out moments created with gruesome, cheep, but effective effects. The aliens seem to be mostly influenced by the zombie cinema of George A. Romero, with their slow moving mannerisms, and like Romero and Savini, Jackson delights in slicing them up with sharp tools and exploding them with guns. One alien has the top half of his head chopped off, a scene that displays Jackson's talent for editing, as he seamlessly cuts from the actors legs stumbling, to the rubbery half-head spurting copious amounts of blood and gore. Derek provides some of the most grotesque, Grand Guignol elements after he falls from a cliff, leaving a skull flat that exposes his brain matter. After this event, he constantly battles to keep the brain inside his head, strapping it closed with a belt. These scenes merge those ideas the comedy of the absurd, with the horrific splatter of giallo or the ridiculously over- the-top gore films of Herschell Gordon Lewis. Considering the limitations of the incredibly low budget (according to IMDb, the films budget was estimated at 30,000 NZD), the film looks good. Of course the film stock, the acting and the special effects aren't up to some of the more expensive American productions of its type, but with an insanely funny script, and the excessive nature of the violence, it is a film that should be loved. I do remember first seeing this film on video around 1989/1990, no doubt initially attracted by the latex alien on the video cover flipping the bird. It was soon the talk of the playground, as school friends would delight in the gore. But more specifically, I, along with my peers, were fundamentally reacting to the outlandish and on-the-money comedy, which holds up today as much as the first two Monty Python films. Gross-out comedy on this scale, has not been so much fun as this since. It's a shame Jackson hides away in Middle-Earth so much these days, it's about time he was funny again. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, witty and playfully violent - but not to everyone's taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not too many movies with limited budget producing good outcome, especially if sci-fi is involved as one has to provide resources for camera tricks. As for Bad Taste, this movie was made for less than 30,000 USD - but it took years to complete it. The plot is peculiar and main characters is uncommon mixture of zombies and aliens. The ending is witty and distinctive - and all this is years before when Tarantino or Rodriguez began their famous mishmashes. The cast is totally amateur - Jackson's friends and acquaintances - but in a good sense, giving an interesting purity and fun. As for Jackson himself, he showed himself as talented actor, he could be used more in this function as well (later he has appeared only in cameo roles). In short, an interesting and already a cult movie, recommended to all fans of horror alien movies, but preferably no eating during watching! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most memorable treats!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avinash Shukla
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Peter Jackson for his bizarre creativity. Bad Taste, Braindead, Meet the Feebles are all bizarre in their own way. As I love splatsticks, I worship 'Bad Taste' for the position it holds in the world of splatter cinema. Peter Jackson has a strange way of using gore. His gory sequences are seldom disturbing and overuse of fake blood makes the gore look like a comedic device, which should be laughed and laughed upon for eternity! So what's the story about 'Bad Taste'? This is a typical B-film but is slicker and more tongue-in-cheek than any of the films that fall into the category of extreme cinema. Jackson's tales never let the viewer lose interest in his films. Perhaps Jackson is such an artist who can make murder look like plain humor! Considering the limitations Jackson faced both financially and technically during the filming of 'Bad Taste', the film looks as great as Taj Mahal to me. The tale is fairly simple at heart. The Astro Investigation Defense Service sends 4 men Ozzy (Terry Potter), Derek (Peter Jackson), Barry (Pete O'Herne) and Frank (Mike Minett) to a town 'Kaihoro' (Food-town in Maori?) to discover the reason behind unexplained disappearances of the townspeople. The men find blood splattered everywhere with no trace of the townsfolk. The place looks like an abattoir, as Barry tells Derek on his radio. The men soon come to know that the town is plagued with zombies, who will kill anything that comes their way. Detailed findings lead the men to the whereabouts of the zombies where they have all gathered for a meet. The meet is hosted by their chief Lord Crumb (Doug Wren). The men come to know that Lord Crumb and his zombie force are actually extraterrestrial beings in the guise of humans and have plans of harvesting human meat for their own intergalactic food franchise. So the dead townsfolk are now in the boxes, ready for the alien consumption! The men also find Giles (Craig Smith), a donation collector in a drum, soaked in spices and free him. Watching for the right time to strike, they all take positions and open fire at the dawn. Causing heavy casualties, the men force Lord Crumb to retreat in his home-faced-UFO. However, Derek has plans of his own that are more sinister than Lord Crumb could have ever imagined. The film as you can see is based on hyper-imagination. Jackson however makes this work. 'Bad Taste' has great comedy scenes and an appealing atmosphere. Thanks to Jackson's hometown Pukerua Bay and the New Zealand lush belt, where this flick was shot. These locations add good atmosphere in the film and shaky camera work at places makes the viewer dizzy. Over-the-top splatter plays a special role here and gives enough reality to the film. So if you're a kind of person who loves to puke on the nasty, give this a try. I am sure you won't be disappointed, and don't forget to watch Peter Jackson's evil twin Robert!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stay where you are then, and I'll give you an eye witness description of this, intergalactic w*nker!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I expect you're wondering what you're doing soaking in Reg's eleven secret herbs and spices. Tomorrow we're having you for lunch!" Yes, the aliens have turned the villagers into tasty burgers, and Derek (Peter Jackson) must defeat them before they spread to the whole world. This time the good guy has the chainsaw, but will he be able to defeat the evil corporate aliens who are just trying to supply their fast-food chain? And, yes, this is the same Peter Jackson of Lord of the Rings fame. Be prepared for some really bloody scenes, and humor that borders on the outrageous. Borders, heck, it is outrageously funny. Oh yes, lots of gooey, icky stuff coming out of bodies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It is what the title says, in the funniest possible way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan Ashley (DanLives1980)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the '80's and early '90's visionary director of 'Lord of the Rings', 'King Kong' and 'The Lovely Bones' Peter Jackson was making the type of films some countries don't even allow today, outside of Asia and the US. It may come as a shock for fans of his work this last decade to witness 'Meet The Feebles' or 'Braindead' and vice versa for fans of his old outings. 'Bad Taste' is an action-sci-fi-horror about a small unit of dimwitted rejects from the fictional governmental department "the Astro Investigation and Defence Service" (AIDS LOL) who are stationed in various locations around a deserted coastal town, which has been wiped out by alien invaders. Upon two of their unit being marauded by groups of the aliens disguised as humans, they regroup and head in to gather intelligence where they discover Earth has been targeted by the ruthless leader of one of the galaxy's biggest fast food corporations, hence the title, 'Bad Taste!' The film is possibly one of the tackiest and most absurd ever conceived, yet boasts of its absurdity because it is so notoriously fun to watch and has some pretty fantastic (although dated) practical special effects, and people will even watch it over and over again to remind themselves how bad it is. What people don't seem to get is that it's a balls-out parody that simply doesn't count on inter-textual references to be understood. Instead it counts on the childish humour of a bunch of male friends most likely trying to test their girlfriends' gag reflexes, almost like a fictional Jackass or Dirty Sanchez movie. It's a boys film that cuts out all the unnecessary plot and dialogue and goes straight for the knives, guns, bazookas, chainsaws, blood and guts and vomit gags, nothing more, nothing less. I may be biased in voting it a 7 out of 10 but still I tried to be fair. It's badly acted, badly produced, badly offensive and pure bad taste in every way possible but still, the performers in the movie are likable and they provide you with a lot of laughs. Peter Jackson must have made this from his garden shed back then, but if that's the case, what an effort. Love it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not gonna gloss anything over in the review....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    witster18
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tough film to review here! Bad Taste is essentially Peter Jackson learning the ropes and experimenting with practically zero cash. The result is a gory and sometimes funny mess. He polished this formula up for 'Dead Alive', and 'Dead Alive' definitely shows a progression both in Jackson's talent, and his pocketbook(although DA had a small budget too). You can see Jackson's influences. Direction similar to early Romero, and Gore that reminds me of some of the late 70's/early 80's gore-fests. The gore here is in heavy doses, and it is probably the strongest characteristic of this film - along with what he achieved overall given the restrictions with the budget and cast. He learned from the best... Other influences were surely make-up masterminds like Tom Savini and Rick Baker. You have to be in the right mindset to enjoy this movie. I've seen it three times. The first time was years ago and I didn't enjoy the film at all. Years later, after realizing that you don't have to take everything so serious, and that horror films can be as funny as they are scary - I gave it another whirl. I laughed on a few occasions and my interest was sparked but not glued. The third time I concentrated more on Jackson's technique and the little nuances that make this film more of a lesson in film-making than an enjoyable 90 minutes. My conclusion. Bad Taste is a film to be appreciated by horror/comedy fans, and fans of making film - because it's essentially someone just like you making their first backyard movie. The only difference is the effort and the near flawless shots of gore and tension that can only be achieved at the hands of someone who is A.Talented, B.Meticulous, and C.An Obvious Film-Buff. He was paying attention to how Romero achieved tension with his close-ups and sound,... and the editing here, for what it is, is amazing. The plot is a dose of Comedy, horror, and sci-fi. Bad Taste is a bitter-sweet, low-budget gore-fest with humor to boot. All that said - most people will NOT enjoy this movie. If you just love gore.. or film-making.... or the Evil Dead Series... or find yourself in love with Cult Classics like Toxic Avenger Etc... then sure, you might like it. Otherwise, skip this one because many Cult-Classics like this have extremely inflated scores here on IMDb. That's because 90% of the small number of reviewers have seen it 90 times, and that 90% is rating this a 10. It's no 10!... It's not even close!... it's exactly what I said it was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Super size me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know. Scores of Millions of dollars is OK too, but why would Peter Jackson insist on doing what he's been doing over the last decade, when he obviously found his calling in life as director of the goriest, craziest, and most outrageous splatter flicks available? And the man only made two of them, yet made a lasting, not to mention an influential impression. Before 1992's Dead Alive (still the goriest film in existence), Jackson would shoot on video, what has to be the greatest sci-fi-gore-comedy in the history of New Zealand. This is Bad Taste. It's what I've always said. There just ain't enough micro-budgeted, sci-comedy with lots and lots of gore. As sweet as the gore is, it really does take a backseat to the comic genius this film offers. Bad Taste is about an alien fast-food franchise who recently decided that human flesh would be a good choice for their menu. Cheap, convenient, not bad. After decimating the entire town of Kaihoro, in New Zealand, the Astro- Investigation and Defense Service is called in to exterminate these guys, who can take the form of humans at will. These eager beavers are ready to blow a hole in anything that moves, so if any actual humans get killed in the process, what the hell? These guys ain't too bright, and they're probably half-crazy, but they totally mean well, with trying to save the world and whatnot. Wanna know something funny? After at least 2 or 3 viewings of this film, something really peculiar occurred to me. There isn't one female to be found in Bad Taste. While it isn't a large cast to begin with, and I'm not really sure what purpose a woman would serve in a sci-fi gore-comedy, I just think it's peculiar. And no. None of this is relevant. But, anyway. What a happy day it will be when, I mean if Peter Jackson decides to return to his gory roots one more time. Since he's already done the alien thing, and not to mention the living dead masterpiece that is Dead Alive, perhaps Jackson should make a disgustingly gory Vampire flick. Or maybe he should just keep making big-budget kids movies. Yeah. That sounds about right. Something tells me Peter Jackson's days as director of films like Bad Taste and other awsomeness are long gone. Whatever. Plenty of other cult Horror filmmakers out there, doin' their thing. But there was a time, not that long ago that your beloved Lord Of The Rings guy was out there doing some amazing stuff in the underground. Once again, Dead Alive would be the best example of this theory, but Bad Taste is nothing short of amazing in its own right. That doesn't necessarily mean you should then go rush off and buy Meet The Feebles as well. That's another story for another day. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Splatterfest Flick, Jackson's Greatest Hit!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tequila101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care what anybody says about this flick but I think this is Peter Jackson's best work. After watching "Meet the Feebles" nearly seven years ago, as a kid I was always edging to watch "Bad Taste" and I was seriously expecting this to be cheap and stupid but instead I got more than what i asked for. This film for the 80's has top notch gore, funny-ass scenes, impossible situations and non stop horrific/comedic action. I always wanted to see this film as a kid and now, I'm glad that I did. The Alien look is very creative and I also love the switch between music themes, first we had creepy adventures, and very wondrous tones of what's gonna happen next and then, we had old rocking, action packed style of play. It was all very creative. Along with Meet the Feebles, (which the trailer say has no taste at all lol) to and for me this was the next level of a Peter Jackson film and it's absolutely funny and creepy at it's best. Even if I didn't find this scary on any levels and I do think that this film has an insane way of telling it's story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sometimes jokingly remark how Peter Jackson's career was perfect until he directed the Lord of the Rings trilogy. It's hard to imagine that this director, who now specializes in big budget Hollywood movies, started off by creating twisted and gory low budget movies  his directorial debut, Bad Taste, being the prime example of this early, strange phase. Bad Taste was by no means an easy experience for Jackson, since the filming took 4 years. However, the hard work paid off and Bad Taste can be used as a valuable lesson in "do-it-yourself: low budget film making". It's amazing how, in spite of rather limited resources, Jackson managed to make it all work and look good  he created the masks and firearm replicas for the movie himself. He even constructed his own counterweighted steady-cam. Bad Taste is a definite must see for every aspiring movie maker, if only for Peter Jackson's creativity. The movie follows 4 agents (called 'The Boys') of some sort of secret service, who investigate alien activity in a small town. Apparently, the aliens have killed the whole population and replaced it. Things become more complicated when the aliens kidnap a charity collector passing through, and it's up to The Boys to save him, by using any means necessary. As you can see, Bad Taste's plot is fairly simple, there isn't much "story" to it  the movie is mainly action and dialogue driven. Due to this fact, the movie gets boring from time to time and I find it to be the worst from Peter Jackson's early phase. I also find it to be the least funny one. While there are quite a few amusing scenes, it doesn't even come close to other early classics like Braindead and Meet the Feebles. But at least there is enough violence and gore in it to make it interesting. The movie does get pretty graphic. Did you first notice the guy missing the top of his head or the Peter Jackson cameo? The effects in the movie (influenced by the cult special effects artist Tom Savini) are surely its best quality. You'll see heads exploding, limbs being torn off and even some chainsaw action. The scene which impressed me the most was the one where a character, played by Peter Jackson, fights with another character  also played by Peter Jackson. Actually, if you're not informed prior to the watching of movie, you may not notice he plays two different characters since they don't really look alike. Who knows  maybe Jackson has an acting talent waiting to be further developed? Speaking of acting, the actors did an OK job for this kind of movie, no one is laughably bad. On a side note, I think it's important to remark that all of the dialogue was dubbed in post production; that, however, isn't much of a bother since it isn't very apparent. While I wasn't really keen on Bad Taste (like I said  I found it to be somewhat boring and I prefer other early Jackson works) I would definitely recommend it to everyone. It's a gory, funny trash/cult flick about some guys fighting off a bunch of butt shaped aliens, set to an 80s heavy metal soundtrack. Why wouldn't you watch it? Rating: 6/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Until Jackson's follow-up 'Brain Dead', this may have been the goriest film ever made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jack Hawkins (Hawkensian)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love 'Bad Taste'. I love that the film was made for about $20 and that the cast consists of Peter Jackson's mates. It's also so enjoyable because it demonstrates how talented a filmmaker Jackson is. For example, there is a scene near the beginning of the film where Derek (Peter Jackson) fights with some alien invaders on a cliff side, it is hilariously gory and feels so very dangerous; through sheer talent (and a massive amount of bravery!), the crew achieves a tangible sense of acrophobia. In 'Bad Taste', Earth is under threat from alien invaders who are endeavouring to fill a culinary gap in their intergalactic fast-food market  the demand for tasty human flesh. The malicious extra- terrestrials don't arouse suspicion as they assume human appearances. Before the Astro Investigation and Defence Service (AIDS) arrive, the malevolent visitors have already wiped out the entire town of Kaihoro, New Zealand. This elite team is comprised of Derek (Peter Jackson), a rather odd Kiwi with an insatiable bloodlust, Barry (Pete O'Hearn), a man who will use his .44 Magnum only when necessary and Frank (Mike Minett), Giles (Craig Smith) and Ozzy (Terry Potter), a trio of muscle car driving tough guys. Jackson's early films have a real talent for choreographing slapstick gore, there are heads being blown off, brains being eaten, arms being torn off, severed heads being drop kicked, seagulls being head butted, entire bodies being chain sawed and even sheep being detonated. The film is utterly drenched in an outrageous amount of viscera; however it is all of the slapstick variety with a strong Commonwealth lacing of black humour. Though the film is by no means a performance film, there is a certain charm about the cast's inexperience. Also, Peter Jackson is hilarious as the absurd, demented Derek, whose horrible shrill laugh and personal motto 'I'm a Derek, Dereks don't run!' are particularly memorable. The filming locations, such as the aforementioned cliff side, are all of outstanding natural beauty; 'Bad Taste' is as much an advertisement for the country as Jackson's later work would be. As we all know, Jackson has since gone downhill, directing the poxy 'Lord of the Rings' and 'The Hobbit' trilogies  what a shame. However, he has recently expressed interest in making another horror film; I just hope he sticks to his roots with a shoestring budget and an immeasurable amount of corn syrup and gore. www.hawkensian.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's about time Jackson was funny again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before Peter Jackson almost exclusively worked with a CGI backdrop in the land of Middle-Earth, he began his film making career in the realms of low budget comedy-horror. Utilising the 1980's trend for splatter cinema, and no doubt the influence of Sam Raimi's tongue-in-cheek zombie film, The Evil Dead (1982), Jackson's debut feature film was entrenched in a very American tradition, but beholds the humour of his native New Zealand - which incidentally is part of the British commonwealth, meaning much of the uniqueness of British comedy is transposed onto the antipodean nation, the influence of Monty Python being one particular aspect of the film that made it such a surprise success. Bad Taste was clearly a labour of love, with Jackson bringing friends and family in to contribute to the making. The nature of the films production adds something quite special to both the narrative and the humour. The home- made special effects and props (Jackson used his parents oven to bake the handmade armoury used in the film) work both as farce and as actually quite an achievement of authenticity. Set in a small, isolated town, a group of misfits, "The Boys," ordered from a shadowy government department, have been sent to investigate an invasion, where aliens have wiped out the inhabitants. What transpires is an alien fast food corporation have discovered that human flesh is the galaxy's newest taste sensation, and are accumulating cardboard boxes of flesh to market and sell to planets. At the centre of the government group is geeky scientist, Derek (Played by Jackson himself - he is also in the role of the alien Robert), who "can only relate to birds". He salivates at the sight of dismemberment and artillery. As the group discover the truth about the alien invasion, their mission is to stop them from leaving the planet. On a narrative level, Bad Taste is as simple as they come. But underneath this simplicity is a wealth of brilliantly formed characters, with their own idiosyncrasies, and a range of beautifully crafted one liners and references. There are some stand out moments created with gruesome, cheep, but effective effects. The aliens seem to be mostly influenced by the zombie cinema of George A. Romero, with their slow moving mannerisms, and like Romero and Savini, Jackson delights in slicing them up with sharp tools and exploding them with guns. One alien has the top half of his head chopped off, a scene that displays Jackson's talent for editing, as he seamlessly cuts from the actors legs stumbling, to the rubbery half-head spurting copious amounts of blood and gore. Derek provides some of the most grotesque, Grand Guignol elements after he falls from a cliff, leaving a skull flat that exposes his brain matter. After this event, he constantly battles to keep the brain inside his head, strapping it closed with a belt. These scenes merge those ideas the comedy of the absurd, with the horrific splatter of giallo or the ridiculously over- the-top gore films of Herschell Gordon Lewis. Considering the limitations of the incredibly low budget (according to IMDb, the films budget was estimated at 30,000 NZD), the film looks good. Of course the film stock, the acting and the special effects aren't up to some of the more expensive American productions of its type, but with an insanely funny script, and the excessive nature of the violence, it is a film that should be loved. I do remember first seeing this film on video around 1989/1990, no doubt initially attracted by the latex alien on the video cover flipping the bird. It was soon the talk of the playground, as school friends would delight in the gore. But more specifically, I, along with my peers, were fundamentally reacting to the outlandish and on-the-money comedy, which holds up today as much as the first two Monty Python films. Gross-out comedy on this scale, has not been so much fun as this since. It's a shame Jackson hides away in Middle-Earth so much these days, it's about time he was funny again. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, witty and playfully violent - but not to everyone's taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not too many movies with limited budget producing good outcome, especially if sci-fi is involved as one has to provide resources for camera tricks. As for Bad Taste, this movie was made for less than 30,000 USD - but it took years to complete it. The plot is peculiar and main characters is uncommon mixture of zombies and aliens. The ending is witty and distinctive - and all this is years before when Tarantino or Rodriguez began their famous mishmashes. The cast is totally amateur - Jackson's friends and acquaintances - but in a good sense, giving an interesting purity and fun. As for Jackson himself, he showed himself as talented actor, he could be used more in this function as well (later he has appeared only in cameo roles). In short, an interesting and already a cult movie, recommended to all fans of horror alien movies, but preferably no eating during watching! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most memorable treats!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avinash Shukla
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Peter Jackson for his bizarre creativity. Bad Taste, Braindead, Meet the Feebles are all bizarre in their own way. As I love splatsticks, I worship 'Bad Taste' for the position it holds in the world of splatter cinema. Peter Jackson has a strange way of using gore. His gory sequences are seldom disturbing and overuse of fake blood makes the gore look like a comedic device, which should be laughed and laughed upon for eternity! So what's the story about 'Bad Taste'? This is a typical B-film but is slicker and more tongue-in-cheek than any of the films that fall into the category of extreme cinema. Jackson's tales never let the viewer lose interest in his films. Perhaps Jackson is such an artist who can make murder look like plain humor! Considering the limitations Jackson faced both financially and technically during the filming of 'Bad Taste', the film looks as great as Taj Mahal to me. The tale is fairly simple at heart. The Astro Investigation Defense Service sends 4 men Ozzy (Terry Potter), Derek (Peter Jackson), Barry (Pete O'Herne) and Frank (Mike Minett) to a town 'Kaihoro' (Food-town in Maori?) to discover the reason behind unexplained disappearances of the townspeople. The men find blood splattered everywhere with no trace of the townsfolk. The place looks like an abattoir, as Barry tells Derek on his radio. The men soon come to know that the town is plagued with zombies, who will kill anything that comes their way. Detailed findings lead the men to the whereabouts of the zombies where they have all gathered for a meet. The meet is hosted by their chief Lord Crumb (Doug Wren). The men come to know that Lord Crumb and his zombie force are actually extraterrestrial beings in the guise of humans and have plans of harvesting human meat for their own intergalactic food franchise. So the dead townsfolk are now in the boxes, ready for the alien consumption! The men also find Giles (Craig Smith), a donation collector in a drum, soaked in spices and free him. Watching for the right time to strike, they all take positions and open fire at the dawn. Causing heavy casualties, the men force Lord Crumb to retreat in his home-faced-UFO. However, Derek has plans of his own that are more sinister than Lord Crumb could have ever imagined. The film as you can see is based on hyper-imagination. Jackson however makes this work. 'Bad Taste' has great comedy scenes and an appealing atmosphere. Thanks to Jackson's hometown Pukerua Bay and the New Zealand lush belt, where this flick was shot. These locations add good atmosphere in the film and shaky camera work at places makes the viewer dizzy. Over-the-top splatter plays a special role here and gives enough reality to the film. So if you're a kind of person who loves to puke on the nasty, give this a try. I am sure you won't be disappointed, and don't forget to watch Peter Jackson's evil twin Robert!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stay where you are then, and I'll give you an eye witness description of this, intergalactic w*nker!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I expect you're wondering what you're doing soaking in Reg's eleven secret herbs and spices. Tomorrow we're having you for lunch!" Yes, the aliens have turned the villagers into tasty burgers, and Derek (Peter Jackson) must defeat them before they spread to the whole world. This time the good guy has the chainsaw, but will he be able to defeat the evil corporate aliens who are just trying to supply their fast-food chain? And, yes, this is the same Peter Jackson of Lord of the Rings fame. Be prepared for some really bloody scenes, and humor that borders on the outrageous. Borders, heck, it is outrageously funny. Oh yes, lots of gooey, icky stuff coming out of bodies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It is what the title says, in the funniest possible way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan Ashley (DanLives1980)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the '80's and early '90's visionary director of 'Lord of the Rings', 'King Kong' and 'The Lovely Bones' Peter Jackson was making the type of films some countries don't even allow today, outside of Asia and the US. It may come as a shock for fans of his work this last decade to witness 'Meet The Feebles' or 'Braindead' and vice versa for fans of his old outings. 'Bad Taste' is an action-sci-fi-horror about a small unit of dimwitted rejects from the fictional governmental department "the Astro Investigation and Defence Service" (AIDS LOL) who are stationed in various locations around a deserted coastal town, which has been wiped out by alien invaders. Upon two of their unit being marauded by groups of the aliens disguised as humans, they regroup and head in to gather intelligence where they discover Earth has been targeted by the ruthless leader of one of the galaxy's biggest fast food corporations, hence the title, 'Bad Taste!' The film is possibly one of the tackiest and most absurd ever conceived, yet boasts of its absurdity because it is so notoriously fun to watch and has some pretty fantastic (although dated) practical special effects, and people will even watch it over and over again to remind themselves how bad it is. What people don't seem to get is that it's a balls-out parody that simply doesn't count on inter-textual references to be understood. Instead it counts on the childish humour of a bunch of male friends most likely trying to test their girlfriends' gag reflexes, almost like a fictional Jackass or Dirty Sanchez movie. It's a boys film that cuts out all the unnecessary plot and dialogue and goes straight for the knives, guns, bazookas, chainsaws, blood and guts and vomit gags, nothing more, nothing less. I may be biased in voting it a 7 out of 10 but still I tried to be fair. It's badly acted, badly produced, badly offensive and pure bad taste in every way possible but still, the performers in the movie are likable and they provide you with a lot of laughs. Peter Jackson must have made this from his garden shed back then, but if that's the case, what an effort. Love it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not gonna gloss anything over in the review....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    witster18
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tough film to review here! Bad Taste is essentially Peter Jackson learning the ropes and experimenting with practically zero cash. The result is a gory and sometimes funny mess. He polished this formula up for 'Dead Alive', and 'Dead Alive' definitely shows a progression both in Jackson's talent, and his pocketbook(although DA had a small budget too). You can see Jackson's influences. Direction similar to early Romero, and Gore that reminds me of some of the late 70's/early 80's gore-fests. The gore here is in heavy doses, and it is probably the strongest characteristic of this film - along with what he achieved overall given the restrictions with the budget and cast. He learned from the best... Other influences were surely make-up masterminds like Tom Savini and Rick Baker. You have to be in the right mindset to enjoy this movie. I've seen it three times. The first time was years ago and I didn't enjoy the film at all. Years later, after realizing that you don't have to take everything so serious, and that horror films can be as funny as they are scary - I gave it another whirl. I laughed on a few occasions and my interest was sparked but not glued. The third time I concentrated more on Jackson's technique and the little nuances that make this film more of a lesson in film-making than an enjoyable 90 minutes. My conclusion. Bad Taste is a film to be appreciated by horror/comedy fans, and fans of making film - because it's essentially someone just like you making their first backyard movie. The only difference is the effort and the near flawless shots of gore and tension that can only be achieved at the hands of someone who is A.Talented, B.Meticulous, and C.An Obvious Film-Buff. He was paying attention to how Romero achieved tension with his close-ups and sound,... and the editing here, for what it is, is amazing. The plot is a dose of Comedy, horror, and sci-fi. Bad Taste is a bitter-sweet, low-budget gore-fest with humor to boot. All that said - most people will NOT enjoy this movie. If you just love gore.. or film-making.... or the Evil Dead Series... or find yourself in love with Cult Classics like Toxic Avenger Etc... then sure, you might like it. Otherwise, skip this one because many Cult-Classics like this have extremely inflated scores here on IMDb. That's because 90% of the small number of reviewers have seen it 90 times, and that 90% is rating this a 10. It's no 10!... It's not even close!... it's exactly what I said it was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Super size me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know. Scores of Millions of dollars is OK too, but why would Peter Jackson insist on doing what he's been doing over the last decade, when he obviously found his calling in life as director of the goriest, craziest, and most outrageous splatter flicks available? And the man only made two of them, yet made a lasting, not to mention an influential impression. Before 1992's Dead Alive (still the goriest film in existence), Jackson would shoot on video, what has to be the greatest sci-fi-gore-comedy in the history of New Zealand. This is Bad Taste. It's what I've always said. There just ain't enough micro-budgeted, sci-comedy with lots and lots of gore. As sweet as the gore is, it really does take a backseat to the comic genius this film offers. Bad Taste is about an alien fast-food franchise who recently decided that human flesh would be a good choice for their menu. Cheap, convenient, not bad. After decimating the entire town of Kaihoro, in New Zealand, the Astro- Investigation and Defense Service is called in to exterminate these guys, who can take the form of humans at will. These eager beavers are ready to blow a hole in anything that moves, so if any actual humans get killed in the process, what the hell? These guys ain't too bright, and they're probably half-crazy, but they totally mean well, with trying to save the world and whatnot. Wanna know something funny? After at least 2 or 3 viewings of this film, something really peculiar occurred to me. There isn't one female to be found in Bad Taste. While it isn't a large cast to begin with, and I'm not really sure what purpose a woman would serve in a sci-fi gore-comedy, I just think it's peculiar. And no. None of this is relevant. But, anyway. What a happy day it will be when, I mean if Peter Jackson decides to return to his gory roots one more time. Since he's already done the alien thing, and not to mention the living dead masterpiece that is Dead Alive, perhaps Jackson should make a disgustingly gory Vampire flick. Or maybe he should just keep making big-budget kids movies. Yeah. That sounds about right. Something tells me Peter Jackson's days as director of films like Bad Taste and other awsomeness are long gone. Whatever. Plenty of other cult Horror filmmakers out there, doin' their thing. But there was a time, not that long ago that your beloved Lord Of The Rings guy was out there doing some amazing stuff in the underground. Once again, Dead Alive would be the best example of this theory, but Bad Taste is nothing short of amazing in its own right. That doesn't necessarily mean you should then go rush off and buy Meet The Feebles as well. That's another story for another day. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Splatterfest Flick, Jackson's Greatest Hit!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tequila101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care what anybody says about this flick but I think this is Peter Jackson's best work. After watching "Meet the Feebles" nearly seven years ago, as a kid I was always edging to watch "Bad Taste" and I was seriously expecting this to be cheap and stupid but instead I got more than what i asked for. This film for the 80's has top notch gore, funny-ass scenes, impossible situations and non stop horrific/comedic action. I always wanted to see this film as a kid and now, I'm glad that I did. The Alien look is very creative and I also love the switch between music themes, first we had creepy adventures, and very wondrous tones of what's gonna happen next and then, we had old rocking, action packed style of play. It was all very creative. Along with Meet the Feebles, (which the trailer say has no taste at all lol) to and for me this was the next level of a Peter Jackson film and it's absolutely funny and creepy at it's best. Even if I didn't find this scary on any levels and I do think that this film has an insane way of telling it's story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pass the Popcorn review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PassPopcorn
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I sometimes jokingly remark how Peter Jackson's career was perfect until he directed the Lord of the Rings trilogy. It's hard to imagine that this director, who now specializes in big budget Hollywood movies, started off by creating twisted and gory low budget movies  his directorial debut, Bad Taste, being the prime example of this early, strange phase. Bad Taste was by no means an easy experience for Jackson, since the filming took 4 years. However, the hard work paid off and Bad Taste can be used as a valuable lesson in "do-it-yourself: low budget film making". It's amazing how, in spite of rather limited resources, Jackson managed to make it all work and look good  he created the masks and firearm replicas for the movie himself. He even constructed his own counterweighted steady-cam. Bad Taste is a definite must see for every aspiring movie maker, if only for Peter Jackson's creativity. The movie follows 4 agents (called 'The Boys') of some sort of secret service, who investigate alien activity in a small town. Apparently, the aliens have killed the whole population and replaced it. Things become more complicated when the aliens kidnap a charity collector passing through, and it's up to The Boys to save him, by using any means necessary. As you can see, Bad Taste's plot is fairly simple, there isn't much "story" to it  the movie is mainly action and dialogue driven. Due to this fact, the movie gets boring from time to time and I find it to be the worst from Peter Jackson's early phase. I also find it to be the least funny one. While there are quite a few amusing scenes, it doesn't even come close to other early classics like Braindead and Meet the Feebles. But at least there is enough violence and gore in it to make it interesting. The movie does get pretty graphic. Did you first notice the guy missing the top of his head or the Peter Jackson cameo? The effects in the movie (influenced by the cult special effects artist Tom Savini) are surely its best quality. You'll see heads exploding, limbs being torn off and even some chainsaw action. The scene which impressed me the most was the one where a character, played by Peter Jackson, fights with another character  also played by Peter Jackson. Actually, if you're not informed prior to the watching of movie, you may not notice he plays two different characters since they don't really look alike. Who knows  maybe Jackson has an acting talent waiting to be further developed? Speaking of acting, the actors did an OK job for this kind of movie, no one is laughably bad. On a side note, I think it's important to remark that all of the dialogue was dubbed in post production; that, however, isn't much of a bother since it isn't very apparent. While I wasn't really keen on Bad Taste (like I said  I found it to be somewhat boring and I prefer other early Jackson works) I would definitely recommend it to everyone. It's a gory, funny trash/cult flick about some guys fighting off a bunch of butt shaped aliens, set to an 80s heavy metal soundtrack. Why wouldn't you watch it? Rating: 6/10 Read more at http://passpopcorn.wordpress.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Until Jackson's follow-up 'Brain Dead', this may have been the goriest film ever made.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jack Hawkins (Hawkensian)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love 'Bad Taste'. I love that the film was made for about $20 and that the cast consists of Peter Jackson's mates. It's also so enjoyable because it demonstrates how talented a filmmaker Jackson is. For example, there is a scene near the beginning of the film where Derek (Peter Jackson) fights with some alien invaders on a cliff side, it is hilariously gory and feels so very dangerous; through sheer talent (and a massive amount of bravery!), the crew achieves a tangible sense of acrophobia. In 'Bad Taste', Earth is under threat from alien invaders who are endeavouring to fill a culinary gap in their intergalactic fast-food market  the demand for tasty human flesh. The malicious extra- terrestrials don't arouse suspicion as they assume human appearances. Before the Astro Investigation and Defence Service (AIDS) arrive, the malevolent visitors have already wiped out the entire town of Kaihoro, New Zealand. This elite team is comprised of Derek (Peter Jackson), a rather odd Kiwi with an insatiable bloodlust, Barry (Pete O'Hearn), a man who will use his .44 Magnum only when necessary and Frank (Mike Minett), Giles (Craig Smith) and Ozzy (Terry Potter), a trio of muscle car driving tough guys. Jackson's early films have a real talent for choreographing slapstick gore, there are heads being blown off, brains being eaten, arms being torn off, severed heads being drop kicked, seagulls being head butted, entire bodies being chain sawed and even sheep being detonated. The film is utterly drenched in an outrageous amount of viscera; however it is all of the slapstick variety with a strong Commonwealth lacing of black humour. Though the film is by no means a performance film, there is a certain charm about the cast's inexperience. Also, Peter Jackson is hilarious as the absurd, demented Derek, whose horrible shrill laugh and personal motto 'I'm a Derek, Dereks don't run!' are particularly memorable. The filming locations, such as the aforementioned cliff side, are all of outstanding natural beauty; 'Bad Taste' is as much an advertisement for the country as Jackson's later work would be. As we all know, Jackson has since gone downhill, directing the poxy 'Lord of the Rings' and 'The Hobbit' trilogies  what a shame. However, he has recently expressed interest in making another horror film; I just hope he sticks to his roots with a shoestring budget and an immeasurable amount of corn syrup and gore. www.hawkensian.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's about time Jackson was funny again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tomgillespie2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Before Peter Jackson almost exclusively worked with a CGI backdrop in the land of Middle-Earth, he began his film making career in the realms of low budget comedy-horror. Utilising the 1980's trend for splatter cinema, and no doubt the influence of Sam Raimi's tongue-in-cheek zombie film, The Evil Dead (1982), Jackson's debut feature film was entrenched in a very American tradition, but beholds the humour of his native New Zealand - which incidentally is part of the British commonwealth, meaning much of the uniqueness of British comedy is transposed onto the antipodean nation, the influence of Monty Python being one particular aspect of the film that made it such a surprise success. Bad Taste was clearly a labour of love, with Jackson bringing friends and family in to contribute to the making. The nature of the films production adds something quite special to both the narrative and the humour. The home- made special effects and props (Jackson used his parents oven to bake the handmade armoury used in the film) work both as farce and as actually quite an achievement of authenticity. Set in a small, isolated town, a group of misfits, "The Boys," ordered from a shadowy government department, have been sent to investigate an invasion, where aliens have wiped out the inhabitants. What transpires is an alien fast food corporation have discovered that human flesh is the galaxy's newest taste sensation, and are accumulating cardboard boxes of flesh to market and sell to planets. At the centre of the government group is geeky scientist, Derek (Played by Jackson himself - he is also in the role of the alien Robert), who "can only relate to birds". He salivates at the sight of dismemberment and artillery. As the group discover the truth about the alien invasion, their mission is to stop them from leaving the planet. On a narrative level, Bad Taste is as simple as they come. But underneath this simplicity is a wealth of brilliantly formed characters, with their own idiosyncrasies, and a range of beautifully crafted one liners and references. There are some stand out moments created with gruesome, cheep, but effective effects. The aliens seem to be mostly influenced by the zombie cinema of George A. Romero, with their slow moving mannerisms, and like Romero and Savini, Jackson delights in slicing them up with sharp tools and exploding them with guns. One alien has the top half of his head chopped off, a scene that displays Jackson's talent for editing, as he seamlessly cuts from the actors legs stumbling, to the rubbery half-head spurting copious amounts of blood and gore. Derek provides some of the most grotesque, Grand Guignol elements after he falls from a cliff, leaving a skull flat that exposes his brain matter. After this event, he constantly battles to keep the brain inside his head, strapping it closed with a belt. These scenes merge those ideas the comedy of the absurd, with the horrific splatter of giallo or the ridiculously over- the-top gore films of Herschell Gordon Lewis. Considering the limitations of the incredibly low budget (according to IMDb, the films budget was estimated at 30,000 NZD), the film looks good. Of course the film stock, the acting and the special effects aren't up to some of the more expensive American productions of its type, but with an insanely funny script, and the excessive nature of the violence, it is a film that should be loved. I do remember first seeing this film on video around 1989/1990, no doubt initially attracted by the latex alien on the video cover flipping the bird. It was soon the talk of the playground, as school friends would delight in the gore. But more specifically, I, along with my peers, were fundamentally reacting to the outlandish and on-the-money comedy, which holds up today as much as the first two Monty Python films. Gross-out comedy on this scale, has not been so much fun as this since. It's a shame Jackson hides away in Middle-Earth so much these days, it's about time he was funny again. www.the-wrath-of-blog.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, witty and playfully violent - but not to everyone's taste
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are not too many movies with limited budget producing good outcome, especially if sci-fi is involved as one has to provide resources for camera tricks. As for Bad Taste, this movie was made for less than 30,000 USD - but it took years to complete it. The plot is peculiar and main characters is uncommon mixture of zombies and aliens. The ending is witty and distinctive - and all this is years before when Tarantino or Rodriguez began their famous mishmashes. The cast is totally amateur - Jackson's friends and acquaintances - but in a good sense, giving an interesting purity and fun. As for Jackson himself, he showed himself as talented actor, he could be used more in this function as well (later he has appeared only in cameo roles). In short, an interesting and already a cult movie, recommended to all fans of horror alien movies, but preferably no eating during watching! :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most memorable treats!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avinash Shukla
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Peter Jackson for his bizarre creativity. Bad Taste, Braindead, Meet the Feebles are all bizarre in their own way. As I love splatsticks, I worship 'Bad Taste' for the position it holds in the world of splatter cinema. Peter Jackson has a strange way of using gore. His gory sequences are seldom disturbing and overuse of fake blood makes the gore look like a comedic device, which should be laughed and laughed upon for eternity! So what's the story about 'Bad Taste'? This is a typical B-film but is slicker and more tongue-in-cheek than any of the films that fall into the category of extreme cinema. Jackson's tales never let the viewer lose interest in his films. Perhaps Jackson is such an artist who can make murder look like plain humor! Considering the limitations Jackson faced both financially and technically during the filming of 'Bad Taste', the film looks as great as Taj Mahal to me. The tale is fairly simple at heart. The Astro Investigation Defense Service sends 4 men Ozzy (Terry Potter), Derek (Peter Jackson), Barry (Pete O'Herne) and Frank (Mike Minett) to a town 'Kaihoro' (Food-town in Maori?) to discover the reason behind unexplained disappearances of the townspeople. The men find blood splattered everywhere with no trace of the townsfolk. The place looks like an abattoir, as Barry tells Derek on his radio. The men soon come to know that the town is plagued with zombies, who will kill anything that comes their way. Detailed findings lead the men to the whereabouts of the zombies where they have all gathered for a meet. The meet is hosted by their chief Lord Crumb (Doug Wren). The men come to know that Lord Crumb and his zombie force are actually extraterrestrial beings in the guise of humans and have plans of harvesting human meat for their own intergalactic food franchise. So the dead townsfolk are now in the boxes, ready for the alien consumption! The men also find Giles (Craig Smith), a donation collector in a drum, soaked in spices and free him. Watching for the right time to strike, they all take positions and open fire at the dawn. Causing heavy casualties, the men force Lord Crumb to retreat in his home-faced-UFO. However, Derek has plans of his own that are more sinister than Lord Crumb could have ever imagined. The film as you can see is based on hyper-imagination. Jackson however makes this work. 'Bad Taste' has great comedy scenes and an appealing atmosphere. Thanks to Jackson's hometown Pukerua Bay and the New Zealand lush belt, where this flick was shot. These locations add good atmosphere in the film and shaky camera work at places makes the viewer dizzy. Over-the-top splatter plays a special role here and gives enough reality to the film. So if you're a kind of person who loves to puke on the nasty, give this a try. I am sure you won't be disappointed, and don't forget to watch Peter Jackson's evil twin Robert!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stay where you are then, and I'll give you an eye witness description of this, intergalactic w*nker!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I expect you're wondering what you're doing soaking in Reg's eleven secret herbs and spices. Tomorrow we're having you for lunch!" Yes, the aliens have turned the villagers into tasty burgers, and Derek (Peter Jackson) must defeat them before they spread to the whole world. This time the good guy has the chainsaw, but will he be able to defeat the evil corporate aliens who are just trying to supply their fast-food chain? And, yes, this is the same Peter Jackson of Lord of the Rings fame. Be prepared for some really bloody scenes, and humor that borders on the outrageous. Borders, heck, it is outrageously funny. Oh yes, lots of gooey, icky stuff coming out of bodies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It is what the title says, in the funniest possible way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan Ashley (DanLives1980)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the '80's and early '90's visionary director of 'Lord of the Rings', 'King Kong' and 'The Lovely Bones' Peter Jackson was making the type of films some countries don't even allow today, outside of Asia and the US. It may come as a shock for fans of his work this last decade to witness 'Meet The Feebles' or 'Braindead' and vice versa for fans of his old outings. 'Bad Taste' is an action-sci-fi-horror about a small unit of dimwitted rejects from the fictional governmental department "the Astro Investigation and Defence Service" (AIDS LOL) who are stationed in various locations around a deserted coastal town, which has been wiped out by alien invaders. Upon two of their unit being marauded by groups of the aliens disguised as humans, they regroup and head in to gather intelligence where they discover Earth has been targeted by the ruthless leader of one of the galaxy's biggest fast food corporations, hence the title, 'Bad Taste!' The film is possibly one of the tackiest and most absurd ever conceived, yet boasts of its absurdity because it is so notoriously fun to watch and has some pretty fantastic (although dated) practical special effects, and people will even watch it over and over again to remind themselves how bad it is. What people don't seem to get is that it's a balls-out parody that simply doesn't count on inter-textual references to be understood. Instead it counts on the childish humour of a bunch of male friends most likely trying to test their girlfriends' gag reflexes, almost like a fictional Jackass or Dirty Sanchez movie. It's a boys film that cuts out all the unnecessary plot and dialogue and goes straight for the knives, guns, bazookas, chainsaws, blood and guts and vomit gags, nothing more, nothing less. I may be biased in voting it a 7 out of 10 but still I tried to be fair. It's badly acted, badly produced, badly offensive and pure bad taste in every way possible but still, the performers in the movie are likable and they provide you with a lot of laughs. Peter Jackson must have made this from his garden shed back then, but if that's the case, what an effort. Love it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not gonna gloss anything over in the review....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    witster18
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tough film to review here! Bad Taste is essentially Peter Jackson learning the ropes and experimenting with practically zero cash. The result is a gory and sometimes funny mess. He polished this formula up for 'Dead Alive', and 'Dead Alive' definitely shows a progression both in Jackson's talent, and his pocketbook(although DA had a small budget too). You can see Jackson's influences. Direction similar to early Romero, and Gore that reminds me of some of the late 70's/early 80's gore-fests. The gore here is in heavy doses, and it is probably the strongest characteristic of this film - along with what he achieved overall given the restrictions with the budget and cast. He learned from the best... Other influences were surely make-up masterminds like Tom Savini and Rick Baker. You have to be in the right mindset to enjoy this movie. I've seen it three times. The first time was years ago and I didn't enjoy the film at all. Years later, after realizing that you don't have to take everything so serious, and that horror films can be as funny as they are scary - I gave it another whirl. I laughed on a few occasions and my interest was sparked but not glued. The third time I concentrated more on Jackson's technique and the little nuances that make this film more of a lesson in film-making than an enjoyable 90 minutes. My conclusion. Bad Taste is a film to be appreciated by horror/comedy fans, and fans of making film - because it's essentially someone just like you making their first backyard movie. The only difference is the effort and the near flawless shots of gore and tension that can only be achieved at the hands of someone who is A.Talented, B.Meticulous, and C.An Obvious Film-Buff. He was paying attention to how Romero achieved tension with his close-ups and sound,... and the editing here, for what it is, is amazing. The plot is a dose of Comedy, horror, and sci-fi. Bad Taste is a bitter-sweet, low-budget gore-fest with humor to boot. All that said - most people will NOT enjoy this movie. If you just love gore.. or film-making.... or the Evil Dead Series... or find yourself in love with Cult Classics like Toxic Avenger Etc... then sure, you might like it. Otherwise, skip this one because many Cult-Classics like this have extremely inflated scores here on IMDb. That's because 90% of the small number of reviewers have seen it 90 times, and that 90% is rating this a 10. It's no 10!... It's not even close!... it's exactly what I said it was.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Super size me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tromafreak
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know. Scores of Millions of dollars is OK too, but why would Peter Jackson insist on doing what he's been doing over the last decade, when he obviously found his calling in life as director of the goriest, craziest, and most outrageous splatter flicks available? And the man only made two of them, yet made a lasting, not to mention an influential impression. Before 1992's Dead Alive (still the goriest film in existence), Jackson would shoot on video, what has to be the greatest sci-fi-gore-comedy in the history of New Zealand. This is Bad Taste. It's what I've always said. There just ain't enough micro-budgeted, sci-comedy with lots and lots of gore. As sweet as the gore is, it really does take a backseat to the comic genius this film offers. Bad Taste is about an alien fast-food franchise who recently decided that human flesh would be a good choice for their menu. Cheap, convenient, not bad. After decimating the entire town of Kaihoro, in New Zealand, the Astro- Investigation and Defense Service is called in to exterminate these guys, who can take the form of humans at will. These eager beavers are ready to blow a hole in anything that moves, so if any actual humans get killed in the process, what the hell? These guys ain't too bright, and they're probably half-crazy, but they totally mean well, with trying to save the world and whatnot. Wanna know something funny? After at least 2 or 3 viewings of this film, something really peculiar occurred to me. There isn't one female to be found in Bad Taste. While it isn't a large cast to begin with, and I'm not really sure what purpose a woman would serve in a sci-fi gore-comedy, I just think it's peculiar. And no. None of this is relevant. But, anyway. What a happy day it will be when, I mean if Peter Jackson decides to return to his gory roots one more time. Since he's already done the alien thing, and not to mention the living dead masterpiece that is Dead Alive, perhaps Jackson should make a disgustingly gory Vampire flick. Or maybe he should just keep making big-budget kids movies. Yeah. That sounds about right. Something tells me Peter Jackson's days as director of films like Bad Taste and other awsomeness are long gone. Whatever. Plenty of other cult Horror filmmakers out there, doin' their thing. But there was a time, not that long ago that your beloved Lord Of The Rings guy was out there doing some amazing stuff in the underground. Once again, Dead Alive would be the best example of this theory, but Bad Taste is nothing short of amazing in its own right. That doesn't necessarily mean you should then go rush off and buy Meet The Feebles as well. That's another story for another day. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Splatterfest Flick, Jackson's Greatest Hit!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tequila101
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't care what anybody says about this flick but I think this is Peter Jackson's best work. After watching "Meet the Feebles" nearly seven years ago, as a kid I was always edging to watch "Bad Taste" and I was seriously expecting this to be cheap and stupid but instead I got more than what i asked for. This film for the 80's has top notch gore, funny-ass scenes, impossible situations and non stop horrific/comedic action. I always wanted to see this film as a kid and now, I'm glad that I did. The Alien look is very creative and I also love the switch between music themes, first we had creepy adventures, and very wondrous tones of what's gonna happen next and then, we had old rocking, action packed style of play. It was all very creative. Along with Meet the Feebles, (which the trailer say has no taste at all lol) to and for me this was the next level of a Peter Jackson film and it's absolutely funny and creepy at it's best. Even if I didn't find this scary on any levels and I do think that this film has an insane way of telling it's story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
