<filme>
 <id>
  86
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0107943
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Vest&iacute;gios do Dia
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A butler who sacrificed body and soul to service in the years post World War II realizes too late how misguided his loyalty has been.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A rule bound head butler's world of manners and decorum in the household he maintains is tested by the arrival of a housekeeper who falls in love with him in post-WWI Britain. The possibility of romance and his master's cultivation of ties with the Nazi cause challenge his carefully maintained veneer of servitude.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   butler
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nazi
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   loyalty
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   service
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   britain
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   James Ivory
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Kazuo Ishiguro
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Ruth Prawer Jhabvala
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Anthony Hopkins
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Emma Thompson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   John Haycraft
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A subtle insight into flawed characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Srinivas G Phani
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are a few films that stand out due to their simplicity. Amour was one of those this year. The Remains of the Day falls into the same category. Helmed by James Ivory, known for his moving period pieces, the film stands a few notches above all his previous achievements. I am an ardent Merchant-Ivory fan and Howards End is one of the most exquisitely pictured films and deeply moving within its seemingly shallow screenplay and characters. Remains of the Day is no less an achievement in its exploration of a bunch of flawed characters whose acts are easy to criticize but understanding their inhibitions and regrets, very difficult. Much of the story takes place within a huge country-mansion called Darlington Hall, owned by the pro-Nazi gentleman, Lord Darlington. Mr Stevens is the head butler for the mansion and takes great pride in his excellence and capabilities. And then comes Miss Kenton, only to criticize him first, and then fall in love with him. Not as simple, Mr Stevens gives duties preference and what turns out is a tale of regret of choices and complications in the definition of duty. To sum up a long story short, The Remains of the Day is a fantastic film and is more pertinent to modern-day audience. With World War  II and rise of Nazism in backdrop, it beautifully explores the lives of people who are more indirectly affected by the changing political scenario. Deep within, it is essentially a story of unrequited love with not a single scene of romance! The film has so much to tell, so much happening that one cannot assimilate the film entirely at once. While the romantic angle takes preference in the final reels, the under-currents of success in career and regret over decisions is loud and clear. Agreed most artists associated with the film have limited range  James Ivory, Pierce-Roberts, Prawer Jhabvala, Emma Thompson and to an extent Anthony Hopkins. But what wonderfully they utilize their range, churning out gold within their repertoire. James Ivory's direction is outstanding at places and stays above 'very good' throughout. He builds up the tension so well during the conference is just an example of how good the direction is. Rightly noted in Wikipedia, the film touches a lot of themes and each of them translate smoothly onto the screen all thanks to Ivory and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins rise above the story and direction and give truly heart-felt performances. Their interactions are the best scenes of the film. Especially the one where she is crying within and he blabbers about their routine the next day and the one where she sobs on the floor. I will not reveal what he does in the latter scene for it would be a spoiler but Hopkins is so much in his character that his actions in that scene are easy to empathize although evil in the traditional sense. The scenes of their brief rendezvous after twenty years are truly unwatchable. The film is very depressing and ends without showing any hope of a better future for the characters. Tony Peirce-Roberts' cinematography is strictly functional and nothing compared to his work in Howards End. Every actor gives his very best in the film. Performances, direction and screenplay are of the highest order. The Remains of the Day captures the very essence of its title, thoroughly justifying it, etches out really flawed characters and brings them alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fine film personifies excellence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clehoullier
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We often refer to this film as a reference point when pondering the extreme disappointment with so many of today's movies (it is July 2013). So many movies are released with huge budgets, loads of buzz, and (apparently), stacked ratings on websites. Perhaps it is just a change in taste due to generational shifts..... Wonderful soundtrack, perfect casting, engaging plot, transcendent performances, and complexity - all are here. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins are so good that it is as if it is all real, not an act. There is so much emotion bubbling under the surface. The ending will leave you shaken for many days. We are thankful for films such as Remains of the Day, Out of Africa, Howard's End, Babbette's Feast - films that dig inside of us, films that make us part of their very fabric. All of the sifting through the trash that is mostly what is released today can be washed clean by going back to a beloved film such as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Acting Masterclass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrost71w
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By some happy coincidence, everybody in this film gives one of their best performances, especially the two leads. Anthony Hopkins is breathtaking; he plays a repressed butler who never overtly shows emotion. How on earth do you play such a character and not appear wooden? You have to be Anthony Hopkins, that's how. Somehow, with just a raise of the eyebrow or the down-turn of the mouth he manages to convey hate, love, humour, distaste, horror, regret and every other emotion under the sun in scene after scene. I have never seen anything like it. I knew exactly how he was feeling from just a tiny crinkling of the eyes. He had a thousand slightly different smiles each of which conveyed a different emotion that he was supposed to be feeling. Watch in awe all you wannabe actors for surely THIS is how it is done. And if anyone wants proof that the Oscars are meaningless, the fact that Remains of The Day won no Oscars is a bigger farce that LA Confidential being kept off the win sheet by bloody Titanic
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dense, literary and eloquent..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    American screenwriter, producer and director James Ivory's nineteenth feature film which was written by German author and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, is an adaptation of a novel from 1989 by Japanese author Kazuo Ishiguro. It was shot on locations in England and is a UK-USA co-production which was produced by Indian screenwriter, producer and director Ismail Merchant, American screenwriter, producer and director Mike Nichols and American producer John Calley. It tells the story about a butler named James Stevens who whilst executing his profession with the utmost dignity at a large mansion called Darlington Hall for the Lord of Darlington, hires a housekeeper named Sarah Kenton. Subtly and precisely directed by British filmmaker James Ivory, this quietly paced fictional tale which is narrated from the two main characters viewpoints, draws a heartrending portrayal of a middle-aged man who is courted by a compassionate woman whom he keeps at distance by remaining utterly professional whenever they interact. While notable for it's naturalistic, atmospheric and mostly interior milieu depictions, sterling production design by production designer Luciana Arrighi, cinematography by English cinematographer Tony-Pierce Roberts, costume design by costume designers Jenny Beaven and John Bright and make-up by make-up artist Christine Beveridge, this dialog-driven and narrative-driven story depicts a refined study of character and contains a good score by American composer Richard Robins. This somewhat political, oppressively romantic and conversational period drama which is set on a country estate in post-war England during the 1930s and 1940s where a woman tries to reach into the feelings of a man whom is completely dedicated to his work and where human emotions are disguised by manners, is impelled and reinforced by it's fragmented narrative structure, subtle character development and continuity and understated and memorable acting performances by Welsh actor Anthony Hopkins and English actress Emma Thompson. A dense, literary and eloquent love-story from the early 1990s which gained, among numerous other awards, the award for Best Actor Anthony Hopkins at the 65th NBR Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man shall never regret what he did, only what he didn't do ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Remains of the Day" is the kind of film where you first hope for something to happen then that nothing ever break the serene harmony inhabiting the story. Yet, to say that the film is plot-less would be as unfair as untrue: another successful product of the director and producer's duo: James Ivory and Ismail Merchant, the film offers another riveting slice of the British aristocratic life, this time during the inter-war, this time for a story even more enthralling because it is told from the servants' perspective, from the diary of William Stevens, the butler. As Stevens, Anthony Hopkins delivers such a solid performance, in all nuance and subtlety, that we can't doubt the man has been or could have been anything but a butler, obviously belonging to a tradition as old as the hills and whose William Stevens Sr. (Peter Vaughan) is another living remain. Stevens Jr. has been impregnated his whole life by this impeccable perfectionism, total dedication to the master, and the dilution of his own ego into work; and to a certain extent, the butler's tasks, no matter how prestigious and dignified they seem in the beginning, turn our to be ingrate as the story progresses. This unfortunate hardship is crucial though as an empathy-builder, we see Stevens with eyes of sorrow for he's incapable to demonstrate any hint of freethinking or independent personality. And the power of Hopkins is to portray a man trapped in the one-note performance requested for his job, in a poignantly three-dimensional way. In fact, the main thrills of "The Remains of the Day" consist of spotting the little hints betraying Mr Stevens' capability for feelings. One clue: they mostly happen during the scenes involving directly or indirectly Emma Thompson, the second lead of the film. As Mrs Kenton, Emma Thompson, the smart and pretty housekeeper is educated and trained enough to see in Mr Stevens, a worthy of admiration colleague, and she's equal to him enough, in the household hierarchy, to allow herself some familiarities. Obviously fascinated by this mountain of coldness, she brings some flowers to his private room and then, something interesting happens. While he almost dismisses the flowers as 'distractions', he politely asks Mrs Kenton to display more respect toward his father, by not calling him by his Christian name. The scene can mislead by foreshadowing several clashes between the two servants, when they are only benign misunderstandings. But it does show that that there is a heart beating behind this impeccable costume and demeanor. And when this heart is about to collapse while the father is dying, Stevens continues to serve the Master's guest: no matter what happens, work must go on. This is Stevens' inner conflict, whose paradox is to create a gap between him and Mrs Kenton but in the same time, allows their mutual respect and tacit attraction, to grow patiently and discreetly with the passing of time. But we know that the romance is doomed from the very beginning, the story doesn't leave much for optimism. We know, when the movie opens that Stevens still work in the same manor, that his Master Lord Darlington died, and an American Congressman, played by Christopher Reeve, bought the house. Mrs Kenton left Darlington before the outbreak of the war and got married. The flow of the film conveys an insightful parallel between the romance and the relationship with the Master. James Fox plays Lord Darlington, not a Nazi sympathizer, but an ambiguous well-mannered gentleman who 'understands' the Germans. During a memorable toast, the American Congressman, and future house owner, would call all the assembled European politicians 'amateurs', an allegation that only shocks his audience, but doesn't fool us, not even Darlington's godson (Hugh Grant). The 'amateur' speech, with the same resonance than Churchill's 'dishonour and war' line, foresees the last days of an agonizing order that exploited the guilt of WWI victory, to roll the red carpets to the Nazis. And the tragic choices of Darlington would spill over Stevens' life. Incapable of adopting one defying attitude against his own master, Stevens condemned himself to a standard of life sadly prone to unhappiness and frustration. And it's precisely the kind of life that Mrs Kenton rejected by leaving the house. And her personal tragedy is that she left the only man she truly loved. "The Remains of the Day" chronicles two separate stories, challenging the solemn and unflappably professionalism of Mr Stevens, and interlocking each other until leading Stevens to a dead-end. And twenty years later, Stevens maintains the same level of mystery. People ask him where he stood for regarding his Master's opinion. Invoking the call of duty, he served his Master the best he could. He deplored some uninspired choices, the most significant being the revocation of two Jewish maids. But still, Stevens embraced his master's choices without being an accomplice. A few years later, the seal of infamy marks the name of Darlington, but not Stevens', yet there's no doubt his heart carries some regrets, and maybe, his unfulfilled relationship with Mrs Kenton is a way to make up for his own guilt. To have followed Darlington or not following Mrs Kenton? Looking back on his life, Stevens would understand the value of regrets, whether it's for done or undone choices, maybe by persuading a divorced Mrs Kenton to go back to Darlington? As a character study, the film is a wonderful examination of lives made of unmade choices and 'what if' questions, as a romance, it happens to be admirably poignant and brilliant, because feelings are so intimate and real that they can hardly be expressed, let alone from a man of such a few words like Mr Stevens. And this is why the ending plays as the perfect emotional pay-off for a film so full of frustrating inhibitions, a light of hope after an eternity spent in the Master's shadow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hopkins' finest role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Remains Of The Day" is a script that clearly stood or fell with the casting of the Mr.Stevens character, and thank God they hit that one out of the park. Anthony Hopkins is perfect in this complex role, the writing isn't always that solid but Hopkins can just make any scene work here. Playing a character that's supposed to hide all his emotions is a challenge, but Hopkins still manages to give Stevens amazing depth. It's all in the little things I guess: occasionally Stevens will smile, but you never know if he's really happy or if he just does everything he does because it's expected from the butler. You can't look in the character's mind because he's so brilliantly underplayed. The best scene of "Remains Of The Day" comes near the end, when Stevens enters the room of a sobbing Emma Thompson. The climax to that scene (or lack thereof) is so fitting and so amazing. This is not my favorite movie ever because as I said, it isn't even that well-scripted or directed, but it's very compelling nonetheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Remains of the Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unrequited love finds multiple reasons to remain unrequited in The Remains of the Day, a film as beautifully written, acted, and shot (interiors and exteriors), as it is frustrating in its unrepressed examination of repression. Anthony Hopkins plays James Stevens, head butler of Darlington Hall, the residence of Lord Darlington (James Fox), an English aristocrat who hosts interwar dinners and conferences for world politicians, including the prime minister and foreign ambassadors. Darlington wishes to appease Nazi Germany, whom he feels was too harshly treated by the Treaty of Versailles. Christopher Reeve plays Jack Lewis, the American delegate, who invades the proceedings to call the attendees "amateurs." Hugh Grant, in one of his better roles, plays Darlington's godson, Reginald Cardinal, a "news hound" who eventually agrees with Lewis and detects the abuse of Darlington's "good, noble intentions" by the Germans, the intentions of whose leader are not fully comprehended by Darlington, who will later recognize his own gullibility. It is within this context of large-scale moral and political conflict and international affairs that super-butler Stevens toils to keep a good house. Not only does he try, with every fiber of his being, to remain detached from the world-shaking decisions being made around him (he seems more concerned with the return of a chair to its proper place), but he also maintains an ostensible detachment from his feelings (he shows more emotion over the breaking of a wine bottle than over the death of his father). Stevens extends this detachment to his feelings for the housekeeper, Miss Kenton (Emma Thompson), who, compared with Mr. Stevens, wears her emotions on her sleeve. Stevens justifies his detachment by the unwavering "dignity" required of a great butler, especially one in the service of a house carrying the importance of Darlington Hall. Emma Thompson's Oscar-nominated performance is earnest and superb. Her character, who is considered old by the underservants and young by Mr. Stevens, passes through a range of emotions and tactics: she offers matronly advice to a younger maidservant rushing into marriage, plays provocative detective in bringing to light the errors committed by Stevens' father, tenderly comforts Stevens when his father falls ill, chastises Stevens for his moral inertness in the face of his master's racist turn, criticizes herself for placing her needs above her convictions, and, in one of the most brilliant scenes of the film, encroaches upon Stevens' "private time" to pry into the subject matter of his reading material, while walking a fine line between playful mockery and seductive cajoling. The supporting cast, which includes Peter Vaughan in a wonderful performance as Stevens' father, William, is also superb. Richard Robbins' whimsical, enchanting, hypnotic music is like a good wine: somberly intoxicating. The centerpiece of the film is Anthony Hopkins' Oscar-nominated performance as Stevens, a role which requires tremendous inner energy, as we must always see that he is, in fact, affected by events, while the emotional hollowness of his verbal interactions with the other characters belies his concern. The continual bombardment of his stoicism by personal challenges seems almost humorously intentional on the part of the filmmakers, like tourists trying to make a member of the Royal Guard laugh. Stevens, who cracks a nervous smile now and again, never has a real laugh, and never pursues his love for Miss Kenton, until it is too late. Honor, duty, and dignity are the reasons given for his failure to launch, but it seems as though Stevens comes from a long line of married people, including his father, who also worked as a butler and still managed to have a family of his own. There is a fair share of upstairs-downstairs going on in the world of the film, most pronounced in an uncomfortable scene in which Stevens' ignorance of world affairs is used to prove a point against democracy, but it doesn't seem completely antagonistic; when Mr. Stevens, Sr. trips and falls, dropping a full tray of items, the "men of stature" he is waiting on come to his aid quickly and treat him humanely. The cause of Stevens' reluctance to accept love when it presents itself appears to be more personal than societal. Stevens, deserving of the benefit of the doubt, is more a workaholic than a sociopath, although there is a faint, remote comparison drawn between Stevens' blind obedience and that of the Nazi soldiers whom Stevens' master is accused of throwing in with. Whatever the reasona reason that seems to escape Stevens himselfthe unrequited love between Ms. Kenton and Mr. Stevens is a source of heartbreaking regret and sadness for this long-time admirer of the filma feeling that lingers after the final, symbolic scene in which Mr. Stevens, after having assisted Mr. Lewis in releasing a temporarily trapped bird, closes forever the window of opportunity on a chance at love, at unchaining his heart, at escaping Darlington Hall to pursue a life of his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this again recently on cable after many years and it is even better than I remembered. Like many Merchant Ivory movies there are many details that can't all be absorbed one viewing. It helps to know the premise of the plot in advance so the going back and forth in time is not confusing. The story is powerful and the story of appeasement in pre WWII Britain is both chilling and fascinating to watch. Makes one look at the butler's job in a different light - more like running a hotel. The Butler's role felt crucial to support the critical but misguided peace talks. The subplot with his father is touching. The screenplay captures both the grand sweep of the larger events and the intimate personal story. The filming, interiors, scenery and cinematography are all beautiful. It is Emma Thompson's best role. Every emotion is so transparent and clear on her face. Her frustration and sadness are moving and memorable. Anthony Hopkins is so convincing in the character that it's hard to imagine you are not watching a real butler. Hope he is remembered more for this role than "Silence of the Lambs". The scenes between them are loaded with emotion and unspoken feelings. Excellent supporting cast including the regal James Fox and a well cast Christopher Reeve. If not for the stiff competition that year including Schindler's List, Philadelphia, Age of Innocence, I think in any other year this would have swept the table. A truly wonderful result of the combination of a Japanese author, a German screenwriter, an American director and the top British actors. One of the best movies in the last 50 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Ismail Merchant was Indian by birth and James Ivory American, and although many of their film-scripts, including this one, were written by the German-born Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, the Merchant-Ivory partnership came to be seen as quintessentially British film-makers. They were responsible for some of the best-known British films of the eighties and nineties, mostly costume dramas based upon literary sources and dealing with the lives of the well-to-do classes. They did not invent the film genre which has become known as "heritage cinema"- that dates back at least to the late sixties- but are perhaps its best-known practitioners. "The Remains of the Day"- the significance of the title is rather obscure- is in many ways a typical example of their work, although the action takes place in the 1930s and 1950s rather than the late Victorian/Edwardian era with which they are normally associated. The main character is Mr. Stevens, the butler of Darlington Hall, an English stately home, during the 1930s. (Stevens' Christian name is James, but he is rarely referred to as such. By convention, senior servants in a household were referred to by their surnames alone). There are two strands to the plot, one political and the other personal. The political strand involves Stevens' employer Lord Darlington, an influential politician who frequently hosts gatherings of important international figures at this home. The personal strand involves Stevens' relations with Lord Darlington's housekeeper Miss Kenton, who falls in love with him although he fails to reciprocate her sentiments. (Or possibly he does, but fails to show it). The central political theme of the film is the politics of appeasement. Darlington initially appears to be in many ways an admirable character, kindly, honourable and idealistic. Although he served in the First World War he, unlike many veterans of that conflict, bears no hatred or animosity towards the Germans- indeed, he believes that Germany was harshly treated in 1919 by the vindictive Allies. His main fault is that he cannot understand those who are not honourable and idealistic, and this blinds him to the evils of Nazism; in the misguided belief that Hitler is a trustworthy man of honour he becomes an outspoken advocate of appeasement. As the film progresses, however, his own character deteriorates; he openly welcomes outright Nazi sympathisers as guests in his home, and even dismisses two Jewish chambermaids for fear of upsetting such persons. Stevens prides himself on being a model butler. He is calm, courteous and efficient, punctilious in the performance of his duties, unfailingly loyal to his employer. He regards any display of emotion as a weakness, and preserves an iron self-control at all times. Miss Kenton- we learn late on in the film that her name is Sarah, although she prefers to be called Sally- is equally efficient professionally, but is warmer and more openly emotional. The question the film raises is whether one should allow oneself to be defined entirely through one's work and through one's relationship with one's superiors. It is the same question as the great Austrian dramatist Franz Grillparzer was raising in his play "Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn". Like Grillparzer's hero Bancbanus, Stevens is a "faithful servant of his master"- the literal meaning of the German title- but one whose faithful service comes at a cost. In Stevens' case that cost is both personal, in that he sacrifices his chances of finding love, and moral, in that his loyalty leads him to close his eyes to his master's behaviour. When the two Jewish maids are dismissed, Miss Kenton is outraged, but Stevens refuses to utter a word of criticism of his employer, even in private. We are left wondering whether he is simply being diplomatic, or whether he actually does believe that the rich and powerful can do not wrong. When I recently reviewed "84, Charing Cross Road", I stated that while Anthony Hopkins is sometimes regarded in specialising in forceful, flamboyant or monstrous characters such as Hannibal Lecter or Captain Bligh in "The Bounty", he can be equally good as quieter, more restrained individuals, such as Dr Treves in "The Elephant Man", C S Lewis in "Shadowlands" or Frank Doel in "84, Charing Cross Road" itself. "The Remains of the Day" is perhaps Hopkins' finest performance in his vein. It is a superb piece of acting, quiet and unobtrusive, but all the more effective for being so. Emma Thompson is also good as Miss Kenton, as is James Fox as Lord Darlington. There are also good performances in smaller parts from the likes of Peter Vaughan as Stevens' elderly father, although I was less impressed by Christopher Reeve as American Congressman Jack Lewis. (Lewis' part appears to have been expanded beyond that he plays in the novel by Kazuo Ishiguro, doubtless in order to provide a role for a big Hollywood name). The film displays the typical Merchant-Ivory characteristics of high production values and a loving recreation of period detail. It is, to my mind, perhaps too leisurely and slow-moving, which is why I would not rate it as highly as some other Merchant-Ivory productions, such as "A Room with a View" or "Howards End", made the year before and also starring Hopkins and Thompson. It is, however, a well-acted and well-photographed movie, and often a thought-provoking one in its analysis of interwar history and its theme that loyalty often comes with a hidden cost. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching story and another great acting from Anthony Hopkins.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nail Yener
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't I watch this movie before? This is the question that I asked myself after I finished watching The Remains of the Day. I have seen most movies of Anthony Hopkins but I didn't even know this movie existed until yesterday when I was doing some research about 90s movies. It was always a great pleasure for me to see Anthony Hopkins in a movie no matter what his role was. And his performance in this movie once more gives me a reason to watch him again and again and again. But I didn't like this movie just because of him. I liked it because of many things such as its story, the performance of Emma Thompson and other actors/actresses and the atmosphere of the film as a whole. The story of The Remains of the Day focuses on nobility and suppressed feelings. I really felt like as if I was witnessing a real section from that time while watching the movie. At the end, when I go over the whole story in my head once more, although I wished that Mr. Stevens and Miss Kenton would reveal their true feelings to each other, I think I didn't feel sorry for them. Because this is the way Mr. Stevens is and this is the message of this movie in my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A subtle insight into flawed characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Srinivas G Phani
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are a few films that stand out due to their simplicity. Amour was one of those this year. The Remains of the Day falls into the same category. Helmed by James Ivory, known for his moving period pieces, the film stands a few notches above all his previous achievements. I am an ardent Merchant-Ivory fan and Howards End is one of the most exquisitely pictured films and deeply moving within its seemingly shallow screenplay and characters. Remains of the Day is no less an achievement in its exploration of a bunch of flawed characters whose acts are easy to criticize but understanding their inhibitions and regrets, very difficult. Much of the story takes place within a huge country-mansion called Darlington Hall, owned by the pro-Nazi gentleman, Lord Darlington. Mr Stevens is the head butler for the mansion and takes great pride in his excellence and capabilities. And then comes Miss Kenton, only to criticize him first, and then fall in love with him. Not as simple, Mr Stevens gives duties preference and what turns out is a tale of regret of choices and complications in the definition of duty. To sum up a long story short, The Remains of the Day is a fantastic film and is more pertinent to modern-day audience. With World War  II and rise of Nazism in backdrop, it beautifully explores the lives of people who are more indirectly affected by the changing political scenario. Deep within, it is essentially a story of unrequited love with not a single scene of romance! The film has so much to tell, so much happening that one cannot assimilate the film entirely at once. While the romantic angle takes preference in the final reels, the under-currents of success in career and regret over decisions is loud and clear. Agreed most artists associated with the film have limited range  James Ivory, Pierce-Roberts, Prawer Jhabvala, Emma Thompson and to an extent Anthony Hopkins. But what wonderfully they utilize their range, churning out gold within their repertoire. James Ivory's direction is outstanding at places and stays above 'very good' throughout. He builds up the tension so well during the conference is just an example of how good the direction is. Rightly noted in Wikipedia, the film touches a lot of themes and each of them translate smoothly onto the screen all thanks to Ivory and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins rise above the story and direction and give truly heart-felt performances. Their interactions are the best scenes of the film. Especially the one where she is crying within and he blabbers about their routine the next day and the one where she sobs on the floor. I will not reveal what he does in the latter scene for it would be a spoiler but Hopkins is so much in his character that his actions in that scene are easy to empathize although evil in the traditional sense. The scenes of their brief rendezvous after twenty years are truly unwatchable. The film is very depressing and ends without showing any hope of a better future for the characters. Tony Peirce-Roberts' cinematography is strictly functional and nothing compared to his work in Howards End. Every actor gives his very best in the film. Performances, direction and screenplay are of the highest order. The Remains of the Day captures the very essence of its title, thoroughly justifying it, etches out really flawed characters and brings them alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fine film personifies excellence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clehoullier
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We often refer to this film as a reference point when pondering the extreme disappointment with so many of today's movies (it is July 2013). So many movies are released with huge budgets, loads of buzz, and (apparently), stacked ratings on websites. Perhaps it is just a change in taste due to generational shifts..... Wonderful soundtrack, perfect casting, engaging plot, transcendent performances, and complexity - all are here. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins are so good that it is as if it is all real, not an act. There is so much emotion bubbling under the surface. The ending will leave you shaken for many days. We are thankful for films such as Remains of the Day, Out of Africa, Howard's End, Babbette's Feast - films that dig inside of us, films that make us part of their very fabric. All of the sifting through the trash that is mostly what is released today can be washed clean by going back to a beloved film such as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Acting Masterclass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrost71w
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By some happy coincidence, everybody in this film gives one of their best performances, especially the two leads. Anthony Hopkins is breathtaking; he plays a repressed butler who never overtly shows emotion. How on earth do you play such a character and not appear wooden? You have to be Anthony Hopkins, that's how. Somehow, with just a raise of the eyebrow or the down-turn of the mouth he manages to convey hate, love, humour, distaste, horror, regret and every other emotion under the sun in scene after scene. I have never seen anything like it. I knew exactly how he was feeling from just a tiny crinkling of the eyes. He had a thousand slightly different smiles each of which conveyed a different emotion that he was supposed to be feeling. Watch in awe all you wannabe actors for surely THIS is how it is done. And if anyone wants proof that the Oscars are meaningless, the fact that Remains of The Day won no Oscars is a bigger farce that LA Confidential being kept off the win sheet by bloody Titanic
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dense, literary and eloquent..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    American screenwriter, producer and director James Ivory's nineteenth feature film which was written by German author and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, is an adaptation of a novel from 1989 by Japanese author Kazuo Ishiguro. It was shot on locations in England and is a UK-USA co-production which was produced by Indian screenwriter, producer and director Ismail Merchant, American screenwriter, producer and director Mike Nichols and American producer John Calley. It tells the story about a butler named James Stevens who whilst executing his profession with the utmost dignity at a large mansion called Darlington Hall for the Lord of Darlington, hires a housekeeper named Sarah Kenton. Subtly and precisely directed by British filmmaker James Ivory, this quietly paced fictional tale which is narrated from the two main characters viewpoints, draws a heartrending portrayal of a middle-aged man who is courted by a compassionate woman whom he keeps at distance by remaining utterly professional whenever they interact. While notable for it's naturalistic, atmospheric and mostly interior milieu depictions, sterling production design by production designer Luciana Arrighi, cinematography by English cinematographer Tony-Pierce Roberts, costume design by costume designers Jenny Beaven and John Bright and make-up by make-up artist Christine Beveridge, this dialog-driven and narrative-driven story depicts a refined study of character and contains a good score by American composer Richard Robins. This somewhat political, oppressively romantic and conversational period drama which is set on a country estate in post-war England during the 1930s and 1940s where a woman tries to reach into the feelings of a man whom is completely dedicated to his work and where human emotions are disguised by manners, is impelled and reinforced by it's fragmented narrative structure, subtle character development and continuity and understated and memorable acting performances by Welsh actor Anthony Hopkins and English actress Emma Thompson. A dense, literary and eloquent love-story from the early 1990s which gained, among numerous other awards, the award for Best Actor Anthony Hopkins at the 65th NBR Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man shall never regret what he did, only what he didn't do ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Remains of the Day" is the kind of film where you first hope for something to happen then that nothing ever break the serene harmony inhabiting the story. Yet, to say that the film is plot-less would be as unfair as untrue: another successful product of the director and producer's duo: James Ivory and Ismail Merchant, the film offers another riveting slice of the British aristocratic life, this time during the inter-war, this time for a story even more enthralling because it is told from the servants' perspective, from the diary of William Stevens, the butler. As Stevens, Anthony Hopkins delivers such a solid performance, in all nuance and subtlety, that we can't doubt the man has been or could have been anything but a butler, obviously belonging to a tradition as old as the hills and whose William Stevens Sr. (Peter Vaughan) is another living remain. Stevens Jr. has been impregnated his whole life by this impeccable perfectionism, total dedication to the master, and the dilution of his own ego into work; and to a certain extent, the butler's tasks, no matter how prestigious and dignified they seem in the beginning, turn our to be ingrate as the story progresses. This unfortunate hardship is crucial though as an empathy-builder, we see Stevens with eyes of sorrow for he's incapable to demonstrate any hint of freethinking or independent personality. And the power of Hopkins is to portray a man trapped in the one-note performance requested for his job, in a poignantly three-dimensional way. In fact, the main thrills of "The Remains of the Day" consist of spotting the little hints betraying Mr Stevens' capability for feelings. One clue: they mostly happen during the scenes involving directly or indirectly Emma Thompson, the second lead of the film. As Mrs Kenton, Emma Thompson, the smart and pretty housekeeper is educated and trained enough to see in Mr Stevens, a worthy of admiration colleague, and she's equal to him enough, in the household hierarchy, to allow herself some familiarities. Obviously fascinated by this mountain of coldness, she brings some flowers to his private room and then, something interesting happens. While he almost dismisses the flowers as 'distractions', he politely asks Mrs Kenton to display more respect toward his father, by not calling him by his Christian name. The scene can mislead by foreshadowing several clashes between the two servants, when they are only benign misunderstandings. But it does show that that there is a heart beating behind this impeccable costume and demeanor. And when this heart is about to collapse while the father is dying, Stevens continues to serve the Master's guest: no matter what happens, work must go on. This is Stevens' inner conflict, whose paradox is to create a gap between him and Mrs Kenton but in the same time, allows their mutual respect and tacit attraction, to grow patiently and discreetly with the passing of time. But we know that the romance is doomed from the very beginning, the story doesn't leave much for optimism. We know, when the movie opens that Stevens still work in the same manor, that his Master Lord Darlington died, and an American Congressman, played by Christopher Reeve, bought the house. Mrs Kenton left Darlington before the outbreak of the war and got married. The flow of the film conveys an insightful parallel between the romance and the relationship with the Master. James Fox plays Lord Darlington, not a Nazi sympathizer, but an ambiguous well-mannered gentleman who 'understands' the Germans. During a memorable toast, the American Congressman, and future house owner, would call all the assembled European politicians 'amateurs', an allegation that only shocks his audience, but doesn't fool us, not even Darlington's godson (Hugh Grant). The 'amateur' speech, with the same resonance than Churchill's 'dishonour and war' line, foresees the last days of an agonizing order that exploited the guilt of WWI victory, to roll the red carpets to the Nazis. And the tragic choices of Darlington would spill over Stevens' life. Incapable of adopting one defying attitude against his own master, Stevens condemned himself to a standard of life sadly prone to unhappiness and frustration. And it's precisely the kind of life that Mrs Kenton rejected by leaving the house. And her personal tragedy is that she left the only man she truly loved. "The Remains of the Day" chronicles two separate stories, challenging the solemn and unflappably professionalism of Mr Stevens, and interlocking each other until leading Stevens to a dead-end. And twenty years later, Stevens maintains the same level of mystery. People ask him where he stood for regarding his Master's opinion. Invoking the call of duty, he served his Master the best he could. He deplored some uninspired choices, the most significant being the revocation of two Jewish maids. But still, Stevens embraced his master's choices without being an accomplice. A few years later, the seal of infamy marks the name of Darlington, but not Stevens', yet there's no doubt his heart carries some regrets, and maybe, his unfulfilled relationship with Mrs Kenton is a way to make up for his own guilt. To have followed Darlington or not following Mrs Kenton? Looking back on his life, Stevens would understand the value of regrets, whether it's for done or undone choices, maybe by persuading a divorced Mrs Kenton to go back to Darlington? As a character study, the film is a wonderful examination of lives made of unmade choices and 'what if' questions, as a romance, it happens to be admirably poignant and brilliant, because feelings are so intimate and real that they can hardly be expressed, let alone from a man of such a few words like Mr Stevens. And this is why the ending plays as the perfect emotional pay-off for a film so full of frustrating inhibitions, a light of hope after an eternity spent in the Master's shadow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hopkins' finest role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Remains Of The Day" is a script that clearly stood or fell with the casting of the Mr.Stevens character, and thank God they hit that one out of the park. Anthony Hopkins is perfect in this complex role, the writing isn't always that solid but Hopkins can just make any scene work here. Playing a character that's supposed to hide all his emotions is a challenge, but Hopkins still manages to give Stevens amazing depth. It's all in the little things I guess: occasionally Stevens will smile, but you never know if he's really happy or if he just does everything he does because it's expected from the butler. You can't look in the character's mind because he's so brilliantly underplayed. The best scene of "Remains Of The Day" comes near the end, when Stevens enters the room of a sobbing Emma Thompson. The climax to that scene (or lack thereof) is so fitting and so amazing. This is not my favorite movie ever because as I said, it isn't even that well-scripted or directed, but it's very compelling nonetheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Remains of the Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unrequited love finds multiple reasons to remain unrequited in The Remains of the Day, a film as beautifully written, acted, and shot (interiors and exteriors), as it is frustrating in its unrepressed examination of repression. Anthony Hopkins plays James Stevens, head butler of Darlington Hall, the residence of Lord Darlington (James Fox), an English aristocrat who hosts interwar dinners and conferences for world politicians, including the prime minister and foreign ambassadors. Darlington wishes to appease Nazi Germany, whom he feels was too harshly treated by the Treaty of Versailles. Christopher Reeve plays Jack Lewis, the American delegate, who invades the proceedings to call the attendees "amateurs." Hugh Grant, in one of his better roles, plays Darlington's godson, Reginald Cardinal, a "news hound" who eventually agrees with Lewis and detects the abuse of Darlington's "good, noble intentions" by the Germans, the intentions of whose leader are not fully comprehended by Darlington, who will later recognize his own gullibility. It is within this context of large-scale moral and political conflict and international affairs that super-butler Stevens toils to keep a good house. Not only does he try, with every fiber of his being, to remain detached from the world-shaking decisions being made around him (he seems more concerned with the return of a chair to its proper place), but he also maintains an ostensible detachment from his feelings (he shows more emotion over the breaking of a wine bottle than over the death of his father). Stevens extends this detachment to his feelings for the housekeeper, Miss Kenton (Emma Thompson), who, compared with Mr. Stevens, wears her emotions on her sleeve. Stevens justifies his detachment by the unwavering "dignity" required of a great butler, especially one in the service of a house carrying the importance of Darlington Hall. Emma Thompson's Oscar-nominated performance is earnest and superb. Her character, who is considered old by the underservants and young by Mr. Stevens, passes through a range of emotions and tactics: she offers matronly advice to a younger maidservant rushing into marriage, plays provocative detective in bringing to light the errors committed by Stevens' father, tenderly comforts Stevens when his father falls ill, chastises Stevens for his moral inertness in the face of his master's racist turn, criticizes herself for placing her needs above her convictions, and, in one of the most brilliant scenes of the film, encroaches upon Stevens' "private time" to pry into the subject matter of his reading material, while walking a fine line between playful mockery and seductive cajoling. The supporting cast, which includes Peter Vaughan in a wonderful performance as Stevens' father, William, is also superb. Richard Robbins' whimsical, enchanting, hypnotic music is like a good wine: somberly intoxicating. The centerpiece of the film is Anthony Hopkins' Oscar-nominated performance as Stevens, a role which requires tremendous inner energy, as we must always see that he is, in fact, affected by events, while the emotional hollowness of his verbal interactions with the other characters belies his concern. The continual bombardment of his stoicism by personal challenges seems almost humorously intentional on the part of the filmmakers, like tourists trying to make a member of the Royal Guard laugh. Stevens, who cracks a nervous smile now and again, never has a real laugh, and never pursues his love for Miss Kenton, until it is too late. Honor, duty, and dignity are the reasons given for his failure to launch, but it seems as though Stevens comes from a long line of married people, including his father, who also worked as a butler and still managed to have a family of his own. There is a fair share of upstairs-downstairs going on in the world of the film, most pronounced in an uncomfortable scene in which Stevens' ignorance of world affairs is used to prove a point against democracy, but it doesn't seem completely antagonistic; when Mr. Stevens, Sr. trips and falls, dropping a full tray of items, the "men of stature" he is waiting on come to his aid quickly and treat him humanely. The cause of Stevens' reluctance to accept love when it presents itself appears to be more personal than societal. Stevens, deserving of the benefit of the doubt, is more a workaholic than a sociopath, although there is a faint, remote comparison drawn between Stevens' blind obedience and that of the Nazi soldiers whom Stevens' master is accused of throwing in with. Whatever the reasona reason that seems to escape Stevens himselfthe unrequited love between Ms. Kenton and Mr. Stevens is a source of heartbreaking regret and sadness for this long-time admirer of the filma feeling that lingers after the final, symbolic scene in which Mr. Stevens, after having assisted Mr. Lewis in releasing a temporarily trapped bird, closes forever the window of opportunity on a chance at love, at unchaining his heart, at escaping Darlington Hall to pursue a life of his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this again recently on cable after many years and it is even better than I remembered. Like many Merchant Ivory movies there are many details that can't all be absorbed one viewing. It helps to know the premise of the plot in advance so the going back and forth in time is not confusing. The story is powerful and the story of appeasement in pre WWII Britain is both chilling and fascinating to watch. Makes one look at the butler's job in a different light - more like running a hotel. The Butler's role felt crucial to support the critical but misguided peace talks. The subplot with his father is touching. The screenplay captures both the grand sweep of the larger events and the intimate personal story. The filming, interiors, scenery and cinematography are all beautiful. It is Emma Thompson's best role. Every emotion is so transparent and clear on her face. Her frustration and sadness are moving and memorable. Anthony Hopkins is so convincing in the character that it's hard to imagine you are not watching a real butler. Hope he is remembered more for this role than "Silence of the Lambs". The scenes between them are loaded with emotion and unspoken feelings. Excellent supporting cast including the regal James Fox and a well cast Christopher Reeve. If not for the stiff competition that year including Schindler's List, Philadelphia, Age of Innocence, I think in any other year this would have swept the table. A truly wonderful result of the combination of a Japanese author, a German screenwriter, an American director and the top British actors. One of the best movies in the last 50 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Ismail Merchant was Indian by birth and James Ivory American, and although many of their film-scripts, including this one, were written by the German-born Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, the Merchant-Ivory partnership came to be seen as quintessentially British film-makers. They were responsible for some of the best-known British films of the eighties and nineties, mostly costume dramas based upon literary sources and dealing with the lives of the well-to-do classes. They did not invent the film genre which has become known as "heritage cinema"- that dates back at least to the late sixties- but are perhaps its best-known practitioners. "The Remains of the Day"- the significance of the title is rather obscure- is in many ways a typical example of their work, although the action takes place in the 1930s and 1950s rather than the late Victorian/Edwardian era with which they are normally associated. The main character is Mr. Stevens, the butler of Darlington Hall, an English stately home, during the 1930s. (Stevens' Christian name is James, but he is rarely referred to as such. By convention, senior servants in a household were referred to by their surnames alone). There are two strands to the plot, one political and the other personal. The political strand involves Stevens' employer Lord Darlington, an influential politician who frequently hosts gatherings of important international figures at this home. The personal strand involves Stevens' relations with Lord Darlington's housekeeper Miss Kenton, who falls in love with him although he fails to reciprocate her sentiments. (Or possibly he does, but fails to show it). The central political theme of the film is the politics of appeasement. Darlington initially appears to be in many ways an admirable character, kindly, honourable and idealistic. Although he served in the First World War he, unlike many veterans of that conflict, bears no hatred or animosity towards the Germans- indeed, he believes that Germany was harshly treated in 1919 by the vindictive Allies. His main fault is that he cannot understand those who are not honourable and idealistic, and this blinds him to the evils of Nazism; in the misguided belief that Hitler is a trustworthy man of honour he becomes an outspoken advocate of appeasement. As the film progresses, however, his own character deteriorates; he openly welcomes outright Nazi sympathisers as guests in his home, and even dismisses two Jewish chambermaids for fear of upsetting such persons. Stevens prides himself on being a model butler. He is calm, courteous and efficient, punctilious in the performance of his duties, unfailingly loyal to his employer. He regards any display of emotion as a weakness, and preserves an iron self-control at all times. Miss Kenton- we learn late on in the film that her name is Sarah, although she prefers to be called Sally- is equally efficient professionally, but is warmer and more openly emotional. The question the film raises is whether one should allow oneself to be defined entirely through one's work and through one's relationship with one's superiors. It is the same question as the great Austrian dramatist Franz Grillparzer was raising in his play "Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn". Like Grillparzer's hero Bancbanus, Stevens is a "faithful servant of his master"- the literal meaning of the German title- but one whose faithful service comes at a cost. In Stevens' case that cost is both personal, in that he sacrifices his chances of finding love, and moral, in that his loyalty leads him to close his eyes to his master's behaviour. When the two Jewish maids are dismissed, Miss Kenton is outraged, but Stevens refuses to utter a word of criticism of his employer, even in private. We are left wondering whether he is simply being diplomatic, or whether he actually does believe that the rich and powerful can do not wrong. When I recently reviewed "84, Charing Cross Road", I stated that while Anthony Hopkins is sometimes regarded in specialising in forceful, flamboyant or monstrous characters such as Hannibal Lecter or Captain Bligh in "The Bounty", he can be equally good as quieter, more restrained individuals, such as Dr Treves in "The Elephant Man", C S Lewis in "Shadowlands" or Frank Doel in "84, Charing Cross Road" itself. "The Remains of the Day" is perhaps Hopkins' finest performance in his vein. It is a superb piece of acting, quiet and unobtrusive, but all the more effective for being so. Emma Thompson is also good as Miss Kenton, as is James Fox as Lord Darlington. There are also good performances in smaller parts from the likes of Peter Vaughan as Stevens' elderly father, although I was less impressed by Christopher Reeve as American Congressman Jack Lewis. (Lewis' part appears to have been expanded beyond that he plays in the novel by Kazuo Ishiguro, doubtless in order to provide a role for a big Hollywood name). The film displays the typical Merchant-Ivory characteristics of high production values and a loving recreation of period detail. It is, to my mind, perhaps too leisurely and slow-moving, which is why I would not rate it as highly as some other Merchant-Ivory productions, such as "A Room with a View" or "Howards End", made the year before and also starring Hopkins and Thompson. It is, however, a well-acted and well-photographed movie, and often a thought-provoking one in its analysis of interwar history and its theme that loyalty often comes with a hidden cost. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching story and another great acting from Anthony Hopkins.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nail Yener
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't I watch this movie before? This is the question that I asked myself after I finished watching The Remains of the Day. I have seen most movies of Anthony Hopkins but I didn't even know this movie existed until yesterday when I was doing some research about 90s movies. It was always a great pleasure for me to see Anthony Hopkins in a movie no matter what his role was. And his performance in this movie once more gives me a reason to watch him again and again and again. But I didn't like this movie just because of him. I liked it because of many things such as its story, the performance of Emma Thompson and other actors/actresses and the atmosphere of the film as a whole. The story of The Remains of the Day focuses on nobility and suppressed feelings. I really felt like as if I was witnessing a real section from that time while watching the movie. At the end, when I go over the whole story in my head once more, although I wished that Mr. Stevens and Miss Kenton would reveal their true feelings to each other, I think I didn't feel sorry for them. Because this is the way Mr. Stevens is and this is the message of this movie in my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A subtle insight into flawed characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Srinivas G Phani
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are a few films that stand out due to their simplicity. Amour was one of those this year. The Remains of the Day falls into the same category. Helmed by James Ivory, known for his moving period pieces, the film stands a few notches above all his previous achievements. I am an ardent Merchant-Ivory fan and Howards End is one of the most exquisitely pictured films and deeply moving within its seemingly shallow screenplay and characters. Remains of the Day is no less an achievement in its exploration of a bunch of flawed characters whose acts are easy to criticize but understanding their inhibitions and regrets, very difficult. Much of the story takes place within a huge country-mansion called Darlington Hall, owned by the pro-Nazi gentleman, Lord Darlington. Mr Stevens is the head butler for the mansion and takes great pride in his excellence and capabilities. And then comes Miss Kenton, only to criticize him first, and then fall in love with him. Not as simple, Mr Stevens gives duties preference and what turns out is a tale of regret of choices and complications in the definition of duty. To sum up a long story short, The Remains of the Day is a fantastic film and is more pertinent to modern-day audience. With World War  II and rise of Nazism in backdrop, it beautifully explores the lives of people who are more indirectly affected by the changing political scenario. Deep within, it is essentially a story of unrequited love with not a single scene of romance! The film has so much to tell, so much happening that one cannot assimilate the film entirely at once. While the romantic angle takes preference in the final reels, the under-currents of success in career and regret over decisions is loud and clear. Agreed most artists associated with the film have limited range  James Ivory, Pierce-Roberts, Prawer Jhabvala, Emma Thompson and to an extent Anthony Hopkins. But what wonderfully they utilize their range, churning out gold within their repertoire. James Ivory's direction is outstanding at places and stays above 'very good' throughout. He builds up the tension so well during the conference is just an example of how good the direction is. Rightly noted in Wikipedia, the film touches a lot of themes and each of them translate smoothly onto the screen all thanks to Ivory and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins rise above the story and direction and give truly heart-felt performances. Their interactions are the best scenes of the film. Especially the one where she is crying within and he blabbers about their routine the next day and the one where she sobs on the floor. I will not reveal what he does in the latter scene for it would be a spoiler but Hopkins is so much in his character that his actions in that scene are easy to empathize although evil in the traditional sense. The scenes of their brief rendezvous after twenty years are truly unwatchable. The film is very depressing and ends without showing any hope of a better future for the characters. Tony Peirce-Roberts' cinematography is strictly functional and nothing compared to his work in Howards End. Every actor gives his very best in the film. Performances, direction and screenplay are of the highest order. The Remains of the Day captures the very essence of its title, thoroughly justifying it, etches out really flawed characters and brings them alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fine film personifies excellence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clehoullier
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We often refer to this film as a reference point when pondering the extreme disappointment with so many of today's movies (it is July 2013). So many movies are released with huge budgets, loads of buzz, and (apparently), stacked ratings on websites. Perhaps it is just a change in taste due to generational shifts..... Wonderful soundtrack, perfect casting, engaging plot, transcendent performances, and complexity - all are here. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins are so good that it is as if it is all real, not an act. There is so much emotion bubbling under the surface. The ending will leave you shaken for many days. We are thankful for films such as Remains of the Day, Out of Africa, Howard's End, Babbette's Feast - films that dig inside of us, films that make us part of their very fabric. All of the sifting through the trash that is mostly what is released today can be washed clean by going back to a beloved film such as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Acting Masterclass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrost71w
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By some happy coincidence, everybody in this film gives one of their best performances, especially the two leads. Anthony Hopkins is breathtaking; he plays a repressed butler who never overtly shows emotion. How on earth do you play such a character and not appear wooden? You have to be Anthony Hopkins, that's how. Somehow, with just a raise of the eyebrow or the down-turn of the mouth he manages to convey hate, love, humour, distaste, horror, regret and every other emotion under the sun in scene after scene. I have never seen anything like it. I knew exactly how he was feeling from just a tiny crinkling of the eyes. He had a thousand slightly different smiles each of which conveyed a different emotion that he was supposed to be feeling. Watch in awe all you wannabe actors for surely THIS is how it is done. And if anyone wants proof that the Oscars are meaningless, the fact that Remains of The Day won no Oscars is a bigger farce that LA Confidential being kept off the win sheet by bloody Titanic
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dense, literary and eloquent..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    American screenwriter, producer and director James Ivory's nineteenth feature film which was written by German author and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, is an adaptation of a novel from 1989 by Japanese author Kazuo Ishiguro. It was shot on locations in England and is a UK-USA co-production which was produced by Indian screenwriter, producer and director Ismail Merchant, American screenwriter, producer and director Mike Nichols and American producer John Calley. It tells the story about a butler named James Stevens who whilst executing his profession with the utmost dignity at a large mansion called Darlington Hall for the Lord of Darlington, hires a housekeeper named Sarah Kenton. Subtly and precisely directed by British filmmaker James Ivory, this quietly paced fictional tale which is narrated from the two main characters viewpoints, draws a heartrending portrayal of a middle-aged man who is courted by a compassionate woman whom he keeps at distance by remaining utterly professional whenever they interact. While notable for it's naturalistic, atmospheric and mostly interior milieu depictions, sterling production design by production designer Luciana Arrighi, cinematography by English cinematographer Tony-Pierce Roberts, costume design by costume designers Jenny Beaven and John Bright and make-up by make-up artist Christine Beveridge, this dialog-driven and narrative-driven story depicts a refined study of character and contains a good score by American composer Richard Robins. This somewhat political, oppressively romantic and conversational period drama which is set on a country estate in post-war England during the 1930s and 1940s where a woman tries to reach into the feelings of a man whom is completely dedicated to his work and where human emotions are disguised by manners, is impelled and reinforced by it's fragmented narrative structure, subtle character development and continuity and understated and memorable acting performances by Welsh actor Anthony Hopkins and English actress Emma Thompson. A dense, literary and eloquent love-story from the early 1990s which gained, among numerous other awards, the award for Best Actor Anthony Hopkins at the 65th NBR Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man shall never regret what he did, only what he didn't do ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Remains of the Day" is the kind of film where you first hope for something to happen then that nothing ever break the serene harmony inhabiting the story. Yet, to say that the film is plot-less would be as unfair as untrue: another successful product of the director and producer's duo: James Ivory and Ismail Merchant, the film offers another riveting slice of the British aristocratic life, this time during the inter-war, this time for a story even more enthralling because it is told from the servants' perspective, from the diary of William Stevens, the butler. As Stevens, Anthony Hopkins delivers such a solid performance, in all nuance and subtlety, that we can't doubt the man has been or could have been anything but a butler, obviously belonging to a tradition as old as the hills and whose William Stevens Sr. (Peter Vaughan) is another living remain. Stevens Jr. has been impregnated his whole life by this impeccable perfectionism, total dedication to the master, and the dilution of his own ego into work; and to a certain extent, the butler's tasks, no matter how prestigious and dignified they seem in the beginning, turn our to be ingrate as the story progresses. This unfortunate hardship is crucial though as an empathy-builder, we see Stevens with eyes of sorrow for he's incapable to demonstrate any hint of freethinking or independent personality. And the power of Hopkins is to portray a man trapped in the one-note performance requested for his job, in a poignantly three-dimensional way. In fact, the main thrills of "The Remains of the Day" consist of spotting the little hints betraying Mr Stevens' capability for feelings. One clue: they mostly happen during the scenes involving directly or indirectly Emma Thompson, the second lead of the film. As Mrs Kenton, Emma Thompson, the smart and pretty housekeeper is educated and trained enough to see in Mr Stevens, a worthy of admiration colleague, and she's equal to him enough, in the household hierarchy, to allow herself some familiarities. Obviously fascinated by this mountain of coldness, she brings some flowers to his private room and then, something interesting happens. While he almost dismisses the flowers as 'distractions', he politely asks Mrs Kenton to display more respect toward his father, by not calling him by his Christian name. The scene can mislead by foreshadowing several clashes between the two servants, when they are only benign misunderstandings. But it does show that that there is a heart beating behind this impeccable costume and demeanor. And when this heart is about to collapse while the father is dying, Stevens continues to serve the Master's guest: no matter what happens, work must go on. This is Stevens' inner conflict, whose paradox is to create a gap between him and Mrs Kenton but in the same time, allows their mutual respect and tacit attraction, to grow patiently and discreetly with the passing of time. But we know that the romance is doomed from the very beginning, the story doesn't leave much for optimism. We know, when the movie opens that Stevens still work in the same manor, that his Master Lord Darlington died, and an American Congressman, played by Christopher Reeve, bought the house. Mrs Kenton left Darlington before the outbreak of the war and got married. The flow of the film conveys an insightful parallel between the romance and the relationship with the Master. James Fox plays Lord Darlington, not a Nazi sympathizer, but an ambiguous well-mannered gentleman who 'understands' the Germans. During a memorable toast, the American Congressman, and future house owner, would call all the assembled European politicians 'amateurs', an allegation that only shocks his audience, but doesn't fool us, not even Darlington's godson (Hugh Grant). The 'amateur' speech, with the same resonance than Churchill's 'dishonour and war' line, foresees the last days of an agonizing order that exploited the guilt of WWI victory, to roll the red carpets to the Nazis. And the tragic choices of Darlington would spill over Stevens' life. Incapable of adopting one defying attitude against his own master, Stevens condemned himself to a standard of life sadly prone to unhappiness and frustration. And it's precisely the kind of life that Mrs Kenton rejected by leaving the house. And her personal tragedy is that she left the only man she truly loved. "The Remains of the Day" chronicles two separate stories, challenging the solemn and unflappably professionalism of Mr Stevens, and interlocking each other until leading Stevens to a dead-end. And twenty years later, Stevens maintains the same level of mystery. People ask him where he stood for regarding his Master's opinion. Invoking the call of duty, he served his Master the best he could. He deplored some uninspired choices, the most significant being the revocation of two Jewish maids. But still, Stevens embraced his master's choices without being an accomplice. A few years later, the seal of infamy marks the name of Darlington, but not Stevens', yet there's no doubt his heart carries some regrets, and maybe, his unfulfilled relationship with Mrs Kenton is a way to make up for his own guilt. To have followed Darlington or not following Mrs Kenton? Looking back on his life, Stevens would understand the value of regrets, whether it's for done or undone choices, maybe by persuading a divorced Mrs Kenton to go back to Darlington? As a character study, the film is a wonderful examination of lives made of unmade choices and 'what if' questions, as a romance, it happens to be admirably poignant and brilliant, because feelings are so intimate and real that they can hardly be expressed, let alone from a man of such a few words like Mr Stevens. And this is why the ending plays as the perfect emotional pay-off for a film so full of frustrating inhibitions, a light of hope after an eternity spent in the Master's shadow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hopkins' finest role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Remains Of The Day" is a script that clearly stood or fell with the casting of the Mr.Stevens character, and thank God they hit that one out of the park. Anthony Hopkins is perfect in this complex role, the writing isn't always that solid but Hopkins can just make any scene work here. Playing a character that's supposed to hide all his emotions is a challenge, but Hopkins still manages to give Stevens amazing depth. It's all in the little things I guess: occasionally Stevens will smile, but you never know if he's really happy or if he just does everything he does because it's expected from the butler. You can't look in the character's mind because he's so brilliantly underplayed. The best scene of "Remains Of The Day" comes near the end, when Stevens enters the room of a sobbing Emma Thompson. The climax to that scene (or lack thereof) is so fitting and so amazing. This is not my favorite movie ever because as I said, it isn't even that well-scripted or directed, but it's very compelling nonetheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Remains of the Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unrequited love finds multiple reasons to remain unrequited in The Remains of the Day, a film as beautifully written, acted, and shot (interiors and exteriors), as it is frustrating in its unrepressed examination of repression. Anthony Hopkins plays James Stevens, head butler of Darlington Hall, the residence of Lord Darlington (James Fox), an English aristocrat who hosts interwar dinners and conferences for world politicians, including the prime minister and foreign ambassadors. Darlington wishes to appease Nazi Germany, whom he feels was too harshly treated by the Treaty of Versailles. Christopher Reeve plays Jack Lewis, the American delegate, who invades the proceedings to call the attendees "amateurs." Hugh Grant, in one of his better roles, plays Darlington's godson, Reginald Cardinal, a "news hound" who eventually agrees with Lewis and detects the abuse of Darlington's "good, noble intentions" by the Germans, the intentions of whose leader are not fully comprehended by Darlington, who will later recognize his own gullibility. It is within this context of large-scale moral and political conflict and international affairs that super-butler Stevens toils to keep a good house. Not only does he try, with every fiber of his being, to remain detached from the world-shaking decisions being made around him (he seems more concerned with the return of a chair to its proper place), but he also maintains an ostensible detachment from his feelings (he shows more emotion over the breaking of a wine bottle than over the death of his father). Stevens extends this detachment to his feelings for the housekeeper, Miss Kenton (Emma Thompson), who, compared with Mr. Stevens, wears her emotions on her sleeve. Stevens justifies his detachment by the unwavering "dignity" required of a great butler, especially one in the service of a house carrying the importance of Darlington Hall. Emma Thompson's Oscar-nominated performance is earnest and superb. Her character, who is considered old by the underservants and young by Mr. Stevens, passes through a range of emotions and tactics: she offers matronly advice to a younger maidservant rushing into marriage, plays provocative detective in bringing to light the errors committed by Stevens' father, tenderly comforts Stevens when his father falls ill, chastises Stevens for his moral inertness in the face of his master's racist turn, criticizes herself for placing her needs above her convictions, and, in one of the most brilliant scenes of the film, encroaches upon Stevens' "private time" to pry into the subject matter of his reading material, while walking a fine line between playful mockery and seductive cajoling. The supporting cast, which includes Peter Vaughan in a wonderful performance as Stevens' father, William, is also superb. Richard Robbins' whimsical, enchanting, hypnotic music is like a good wine: somberly intoxicating. The centerpiece of the film is Anthony Hopkins' Oscar-nominated performance as Stevens, a role which requires tremendous inner energy, as we must always see that he is, in fact, affected by events, while the emotional hollowness of his verbal interactions with the other characters belies his concern. The continual bombardment of his stoicism by personal challenges seems almost humorously intentional on the part of the filmmakers, like tourists trying to make a member of the Royal Guard laugh. Stevens, who cracks a nervous smile now and again, never has a real laugh, and never pursues his love for Miss Kenton, until it is too late. Honor, duty, and dignity are the reasons given for his failure to launch, but it seems as though Stevens comes from a long line of married people, including his father, who also worked as a butler and still managed to have a family of his own. There is a fair share of upstairs-downstairs going on in the world of the film, most pronounced in an uncomfortable scene in which Stevens' ignorance of world affairs is used to prove a point against democracy, but it doesn't seem completely antagonistic; when Mr. Stevens, Sr. trips and falls, dropping a full tray of items, the "men of stature" he is waiting on come to his aid quickly and treat him humanely. The cause of Stevens' reluctance to accept love when it presents itself appears to be more personal than societal. Stevens, deserving of the benefit of the doubt, is more a workaholic than a sociopath, although there is a faint, remote comparison drawn between Stevens' blind obedience and that of the Nazi soldiers whom Stevens' master is accused of throwing in with. Whatever the reasona reason that seems to escape Stevens himselfthe unrequited love between Ms. Kenton and Mr. Stevens is a source of heartbreaking regret and sadness for this long-time admirer of the filma feeling that lingers after the final, symbolic scene in which Mr. Stevens, after having assisted Mr. Lewis in releasing a temporarily trapped bird, closes forever the window of opportunity on a chance at love, at unchaining his heart, at escaping Darlington Hall to pursue a life of his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this again recently on cable after many years and it is even better than I remembered. Like many Merchant Ivory movies there are many details that can't all be absorbed one viewing. It helps to know the premise of the plot in advance so the going back and forth in time is not confusing. The story is powerful and the story of appeasement in pre WWII Britain is both chilling and fascinating to watch. Makes one look at the butler's job in a different light - more like running a hotel. The Butler's role felt crucial to support the critical but misguided peace talks. The subplot with his father is touching. The screenplay captures both the grand sweep of the larger events and the intimate personal story. The filming, interiors, scenery and cinematography are all beautiful. It is Emma Thompson's best role. Every emotion is so transparent and clear on her face. Her frustration and sadness are moving and memorable. Anthony Hopkins is so convincing in the character that it's hard to imagine you are not watching a real butler. Hope he is remembered more for this role than "Silence of the Lambs". The scenes between them are loaded with emotion and unspoken feelings. Excellent supporting cast including the regal James Fox and a well cast Christopher Reeve. If not for the stiff competition that year including Schindler's List, Philadelphia, Age of Innocence, I think in any other year this would have swept the table. A truly wonderful result of the combination of a Japanese author, a German screenwriter, an American director and the top British actors. One of the best movies in the last 50 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Ismail Merchant was Indian by birth and James Ivory American, and although many of their film-scripts, including this one, were written by the German-born Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, the Merchant-Ivory partnership came to be seen as quintessentially British film-makers. They were responsible for some of the best-known British films of the eighties and nineties, mostly costume dramas based upon literary sources and dealing with the lives of the well-to-do classes. They did not invent the film genre which has become known as "heritage cinema"- that dates back at least to the late sixties- but are perhaps its best-known practitioners. "The Remains of the Day"- the significance of the title is rather obscure- is in many ways a typical example of their work, although the action takes place in the 1930s and 1950s rather than the late Victorian/Edwardian era with which they are normally associated. The main character is Mr. Stevens, the butler of Darlington Hall, an English stately home, during the 1930s. (Stevens' Christian name is James, but he is rarely referred to as such. By convention, senior servants in a household were referred to by their surnames alone). There are two strands to the plot, one political and the other personal. The political strand involves Stevens' employer Lord Darlington, an influential politician who frequently hosts gatherings of important international figures at this home. The personal strand involves Stevens' relations with Lord Darlington's housekeeper Miss Kenton, who falls in love with him although he fails to reciprocate her sentiments. (Or possibly he does, but fails to show it). The central political theme of the film is the politics of appeasement. Darlington initially appears to be in many ways an admirable character, kindly, honourable and idealistic. Although he served in the First World War he, unlike many veterans of that conflict, bears no hatred or animosity towards the Germans- indeed, he believes that Germany was harshly treated in 1919 by the vindictive Allies. His main fault is that he cannot understand those who are not honourable and idealistic, and this blinds him to the evils of Nazism; in the misguided belief that Hitler is a trustworthy man of honour he becomes an outspoken advocate of appeasement. As the film progresses, however, his own character deteriorates; he openly welcomes outright Nazi sympathisers as guests in his home, and even dismisses two Jewish chambermaids for fear of upsetting such persons. Stevens prides himself on being a model butler. He is calm, courteous and efficient, punctilious in the performance of his duties, unfailingly loyal to his employer. He regards any display of emotion as a weakness, and preserves an iron self-control at all times. Miss Kenton- we learn late on in the film that her name is Sarah, although she prefers to be called Sally- is equally efficient professionally, but is warmer and more openly emotional. The question the film raises is whether one should allow oneself to be defined entirely through one's work and through one's relationship with one's superiors. It is the same question as the great Austrian dramatist Franz Grillparzer was raising in his play "Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn". Like Grillparzer's hero Bancbanus, Stevens is a "faithful servant of his master"- the literal meaning of the German title- but one whose faithful service comes at a cost. In Stevens' case that cost is both personal, in that he sacrifices his chances of finding love, and moral, in that his loyalty leads him to close his eyes to his master's behaviour. When the two Jewish maids are dismissed, Miss Kenton is outraged, but Stevens refuses to utter a word of criticism of his employer, even in private. We are left wondering whether he is simply being diplomatic, or whether he actually does believe that the rich and powerful can do not wrong. When I recently reviewed "84, Charing Cross Road", I stated that while Anthony Hopkins is sometimes regarded in specialising in forceful, flamboyant or monstrous characters such as Hannibal Lecter or Captain Bligh in "The Bounty", he can be equally good as quieter, more restrained individuals, such as Dr Treves in "The Elephant Man", C S Lewis in "Shadowlands" or Frank Doel in "84, Charing Cross Road" itself. "The Remains of the Day" is perhaps Hopkins' finest performance in his vein. It is a superb piece of acting, quiet and unobtrusive, but all the more effective for being so. Emma Thompson is also good as Miss Kenton, as is James Fox as Lord Darlington. There are also good performances in smaller parts from the likes of Peter Vaughan as Stevens' elderly father, although I was less impressed by Christopher Reeve as American Congressman Jack Lewis. (Lewis' part appears to have been expanded beyond that he plays in the novel by Kazuo Ishiguro, doubtless in order to provide a role for a big Hollywood name). The film displays the typical Merchant-Ivory characteristics of high production values and a loving recreation of period detail. It is, to my mind, perhaps too leisurely and slow-moving, which is why I would not rate it as highly as some other Merchant-Ivory productions, such as "A Room with a View" or "Howards End", made the year before and also starring Hopkins and Thompson. It is, however, a well-acted and well-photographed movie, and often a thought-provoking one in its analysis of interwar history and its theme that loyalty often comes with a hidden cost. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching story and another great acting from Anthony Hopkins.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nail Yener
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't I watch this movie before? This is the question that I asked myself after I finished watching The Remains of the Day. I have seen most movies of Anthony Hopkins but I didn't even know this movie existed until yesterday when I was doing some research about 90s movies. It was always a great pleasure for me to see Anthony Hopkins in a movie no matter what his role was. And his performance in this movie once more gives me a reason to watch him again and again and again. But I didn't like this movie just because of him. I liked it because of many things such as its story, the performance of Emma Thompson and other actors/actresses and the atmosphere of the film as a whole. The story of The Remains of the Day focuses on nobility and suppressed feelings. I really felt like as if I was witnessing a real section from that time while watching the movie. At the end, when I go over the whole story in my head once more, although I wished that Mr. Stevens and Miss Kenton would reveal their true feelings to each other, I think I didn't feel sorry for them. Because this is the way Mr. Stevens is and this is the message of this movie in my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A subtle insight into flawed characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Srinivas G Phani
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are a few films that stand out due to their simplicity. Amour was one of those this year. The Remains of the Day falls into the same category. Helmed by James Ivory, known for his moving period pieces, the film stands a few notches above all his previous achievements. I am an ardent Merchant-Ivory fan and Howards End is one of the most exquisitely pictured films and deeply moving within its seemingly shallow screenplay and characters. Remains of the Day is no less an achievement in its exploration of a bunch of flawed characters whose acts are easy to criticize but understanding their inhibitions and regrets, very difficult. Much of the story takes place within a huge country-mansion called Darlington Hall, owned by the pro-Nazi gentleman, Lord Darlington. Mr Stevens is the head butler for the mansion and takes great pride in his excellence and capabilities. And then comes Miss Kenton, only to criticize him first, and then fall in love with him. Not as simple, Mr Stevens gives duties preference and what turns out is a tale of regret of choices and complications in the definition of duty. To sum up a long story short, The Remains of the Day is a fantastic film and is more pertinent to modern-day audience. With World War  II and rise of Nazism in backdrop, it beautifully explores the lives of people who are more indirectly affected by the changing political scenario. Deep within, it is essentially a story of unrequited love with not a single scene of romance! The film has so much to tell, so much happening that one cannot assimilate the film entirely at once. While the romantic angle takes preference in the final reels, the under-currents of success in career and regret over decisions is loud and clear. Agreed most artists associated with the film have limited range  James Ivory, Pierce-Roberts, Prawer Jhabvala, Emma Thompson and to an extent Anthony Hopkins. But what wonderfully they utilize their range, churning out gold within their repertoire. James Ivory's direction is outstanding at places and stays above 'very good' throughout. He builds up the tension so well during the conference is just an example of how good the direction is. Rightly noted in Wikipedia, the film touches a lot of themes and each of them translate smoothly onto the screen all thanks to Ivory and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins rise above the story and direction and give truly heart-felt performances. Their interactions are the best scenes of the film. Especially the one where she is crying within and he blabbers about their routine the next day and the one where she sobs on the floor. I will not reveal what he does in the latter scene for it would be a spoiler but Hopkins is so much in his character that his actions in that scene are easy to empathize although evil in the traditional sense. The scenes of their brief rendezvous after twenty years are truly unwatchable. The film is very depressing and ends without showing any hope of a better future for the characters. Tony Peirce-Roberts' cinematography is strictly functional and nothing compared to his work in Howards End. Every actor gives his very best in the film. Performances, direction and screenplay are of the highest order. The Remains of the Day captures the very essence of its title, thoroughly justifying it, etches out really flawed characters and brings them alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fine film personifies excellence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clehoullier
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We often refer to this film as a reference point when pondering the extreme disappointment with so many of today's movies (it is July 2013). So many movies are released with huge budgets, loads of buzz, and (apparently), stacked ratings on websites. Perhaps it is just a change in taste due to generational shifts..... Wonderful soundtrack, perfect casting, engaging plot, transcendent performances, and complexity - all are here. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins are so good that it is as if it is all real, not an act. There is so much emotion bubbling under the surface. The ending will leave you shaken for many days. We are thankful for films such as Remains of the Day, Out of Africa, Howard's End, Babbette's Feast - films that dig inside of us, films that make us part of their very fabric. All of the sifting through the trash that is mostly what is released today can be washed clean by going back to a beloved film such as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Acting Masterclass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrost71w
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By some happy coincidence, everybody in this film gives one of their best performances, especially the two leads. Anthony Hopkins is breathtaking; he plays a repressed butler who never overtly shows emotion. How on earth do you play such a character and not appear wooden? You have to be Anthony Hopkins, that's how. Somehow, with just a raise of the eyebrow or the down-turn of the mouth he manages to convey hate, love, humour, distaste, horror, regret and every other emotion under the sun in scene after scene. I have never seen anything like it. I knew exactly how he was feeling from just a tiny crinkling of the eyes. He had a thousand slightly different smiles each of which conveyed a different emotion that he was supposed to be feeling. Watch in awe all you wannabe actors for surely THIS is how it is done. And if anyone wants proof that the Oscars are meaningless, the fact that Remains of The Day won no Oscars is a bigger farce that LA Confidential being kept off the win sheet by bloody Titanic
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dense, literary and eloquent..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    American screenwriter, producer and director James Ivory's nineteenth feature film which was written by German author and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, is an adaptation of a novel from 1989 by Japanese author Kazuo Ishiguro. It was shot on locations in England and is a UK-USA co-production which was produced by Indian screenwriter, producer and director Ismail Merchant, American screenwriter, producer and director Mike Nichols and American producer John Calley. It tells the story about a butler named James Stevens who whilst executing his profession with the utmost dignity at a large mansion called Darlington Hall for the Lord of Darlington, hires a housekeeper named Sarah Kenton. Subtly and precisely directed by British filmmaker James Ivory, this quietly paced fictional tale which is narrated from the two main characters viewpoints, draws a heartrending portrayal of a middle-aged man who is courted by a compassionate woman whom he keeps at distance by remaining utterly professional whenever they interact. While notable for it's naturalistic, atmospheric and mostly interior milieu depictions, sterling production design by production designer Luciana Arrighi, cinematography by English cinematographer Tony-Pierce Roberts, costume design by costume designers Jenny Beaven and John Bright and make-up by make-up artist Christine Beveridge, this dialog-driven and narrative-driven story depicts a refined study of character and contains a good score by American composer Richard Robins. This somewhat political, oppressively romantic and conversational period drama which is set on a country estate in post-war England during the 1930s and 1940s where a woman tries to reach into the feelings of a man whom is completely dedicated to his work and where human emotions are disguised by manners, is impelled and reinforced by it's fragmented narrative structure, subtle character development and continuity and understated and memorable acting performances by Welsh actor Anthony Hopkins and English actress Emma Thompson. A dense, literary and eloquent love-story from the early 1990s which gained, among numerous other awards, the award for Best Actor Anthony Hopkins at the 65th NBR Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man shall never regret what he did, only what he didn't do ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Remains of the Day" is the kind of film where you first hope for something to happen then that nothing ever break the serene harmony inhabiting the story. Yet, to say that the film is plot-less would be as unfair as untrue: another successful product of the director and producer's duo: James Ivory and Ismail Merchant, the film offers another riveting slice of the British aristocratic life, this time during the inter-war, this time for a story even more enthralling because it is told from the servants' perspective, from the diary of William Stevens, the butler. As Stevens, Anthony Hopkins delivers such a solid performance, in all nuance and subtlety, that we can't doubt the man has been or could have been anything but a butler, obviously belonging to a tradition as old as the hills and whose William Stevens Sr. (Peter Vaughan) is another living remain. Stevens Jr. has been impregnated his whole life by this impeccable perfectionism, total dedication to the master, and the dilution of his own ego into work; and to a certain extent, the butler's tasks, no matter how prestigious and dignified they seem in the beginning, turn our to be ingrate as the story progresses. This unfortunate hardship is crucial though as an empathy-builder, we see Stevens with eyes of sorrow for he's incapable to demonstrate any hint of freethinking or independent personality. And the power of Hopkins is to portray a man trapped in the one-note performance requested for his job, in a poignantly three-dimensional way. In fact, the main thrills of "The Remains of the Day" consist of spotting the little hints betraying Mr Stevens' capability for feelings. One clue: they mostly happen during the scenes involving directly or indirectly Emma Thompson, the second lead of the film. As Mrs Kenton, Emma Thompson, the smart and pretty housekeeper is educated and trained enough to see in Mr Stevens, a worthy of admiration colleague, and she's equal to him enough, in the household hierarchy, to allow herself some familiarities. Obviously fascinated by this mountain of coldness, she brings some flowers to his private room and then, something interesting happens. While he almost dismisses the flowers as 'distractions', he politely asks Mrs Kenton to display more respect toward his father, by not calling him by his Christian name. The scene can mislead by foreshadowing several clashes between the two servants, when they are only benign misunderstandings. But it does show that that there is a heart beating behind this impeccable costume and demeanor. And when this heart is about to collapse while the father is dying, Stevens continues to serve the Master's guest: no matter what happens, work must go on. This is Stevens' inner conflict, whose paradox is to create a gap between him and Mrs Kenton but in the same time, allows their mutual respect and tacit attraction, to grow patiently and discreetly with the passing of time. But we know that the romance is doomed from the very beginning, the story doesn't leave much for optimism. We know, when the movie opens that Stevens still work in the same manor, that his Master Lord Darlington died, and an American Congressman, played by Christopher Reeve, bought the house. Mrs Kenton left Darlington before the outbreak of the war and got married. The flow of the film conveys an insightful parallel between the romance and the relationship with the Master. James Fox plays Lord Darlington, not a Nazi sympathizer, but an ambiguous well-mannered gentleman who 'understands' the Germans. During a memorable toast, the American Congressman, and future house owner, would call all the assembled European politicians 'amateurs', an allegation that only shocks his audience, but doesn't fool us, not even Darlington's godson (Hugh Grant). The 'amateur' speech, with the same resonance than Churchill's 'dishonour and war' line, foresees the last days of an agonizing order that exploited the guilt of WWI victory, to roll the red carpets to the Nazis. And the tragic choices of Darlington would spill over Stevens' life. Incapable of adopting one defying attitude against his own master, Stevens condemned himself to a standard of life sadly prone to unhappiness and frustration. And it's precisely the kind of life that Mrs Kenton rejected by leaving the house. And her personal tragedy is that she left the only man she truly loved. "The Remains of the Day" chronicles two separate stories, challenging the solemn and unflappably professionalism of Mr Stevens, and interlocking each other until leading Stevens to a dead-end. And twenty years later, Stevens maintains the same level of mystery. People ask him where he stood for regarding his Master's opinion. Invoking the call of duty, he served his Master the best he could. He deplored some uninspired choices, the most significant being the revocation of two Jewish maids. But still, Stevens embraced his master's choices without being an accomplice. A few years later, the seal of infamy marks the name of Darlington, but not Stevens', yet there's no doubt his heart carries some regrets, and maybe, his unfulfilled relationship with Mrs Kenton is a way to make up for his own guilt. To have followed Darlington or not following Mrs Kenton? Looking back on his life, Stevens would understand the value of regrets, whether it's for done or undone choices, maybe by persuading a divorced Mrs Kenton to go back to Darlington? As a character study, the film is a wonderful examination of lives made of unmade choices and 'what if' questions, as a romance, it happens to be admirably poignant and brilliant, because feelings are so intimate and real that they can hardly be expressed, let alone from a man of such a few words like Mr Stevens. And this is why the ending plays as the perfect emotional pay-off for a film so full of frustrating inhibitions, a light of hope after an eternity spent in the Master's shadow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hopkins' finest role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Remains Of The Day" is a script that clearly stood or fell with the casting of the Mr.Stevens character, and thank God they hit that one out of the park. Anthony Hopkins is perfect in this complex role, the writing isn't always that solid but Hopkins can just make any scene work here. Playing a character that's supposed to hide all his emotions is a challenge, but Hopkins still manages to give Stevens amazing depth. It's all in the little things I guess: occasionally Stevens will smile, but you never know if he's really happy or if he just does everything he does because it's expected from the butler. You can't look in the character's mind because he's so brilliantly underplayed. The best scene of "Remains Of The Day" comes near the end, when Stevens enters the room of a sobbing Emma Thompson. The climax to that scene (or lack thereof) is so fitting and so amazing. This is not my favorite movie ever because as I said, it isn't even that well-scripted or directed, but it's very compelling nonetheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Remains of the Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unrequited love finds multiple reasons to remain unrequited in The Remains of the Day, a film as beautifully written, acted, and shot (interiors and exteriors), as it is frustrating in its unrepressed examination of repression. Anthony Hopkins plays James Stevens, head butler of Darlington Hall, the residence of Lord Darlington (James Fox), an English aristocrat who hosts interwar dinners and conferences for world politicians, including the prime minister and foreign ambassadors. Darlington wishes to appease Nazi Germany, whom he feels was too harshly treated by the Treaty of Versailles. Christopher Reeve plays Jack Lewis, the American delegate, who invades the proceedings to call the attendees "amateurs." Hugh Grant, in one of his better roles, plays Darlington's godson, Reginald Cardinal, a "news hound" who eventually agrees with Lewis and detects the abuse of Darlington's "good, noble intentions" by the Germans, the intentions of whose leader are not fully comprehended by Darlington, who will later recognize his own gullibility. It is within this context of large-scale moral and political conflict and international affairs that super-butler Stevens toils to keep a good house. Not only does he try, with every fiber of his being, to remain detached from the world-shaking decisions being made around him (he seems more concerned with the return of a chair to its proper place), but he also maintains an ostensible detachment from his feelings (he shows more emotion over the breaking of a wine bottle than over the death of his father). Stevens extends this detachment to his feelings for the housekeeper, Miss Kenton (Emma Thompson), who, compared with Mr. Stevens, wears her emotions on her sleeve. Stevens justifies his detachment by the unwavering "dignity" required of a great butler, especially one in the service of a house carrying the importance of Darlington Hall. Emma Thompson's Oscar-nominated performance is earnest and superb. Her character, who is considered old by the underservants and young by Mr. Stevens, passes through a range of emotions and tactics: she offers matronly advice to a younger maidservant rushing into marriage, plays provocative detective in bringing to light the errors committed by Stevens' father, tenderly comforts Stevens when his father falls ill, chastises Stevens for his moral inertness in the face of his master's racist turn, criticizes herself for placing her needs above her convictions, and, in one of the most brilliant scenes of the film, encroaches upon Stevens' "private time" to pry into the subject matter of his reading material, while walking a fine line between playful mockery and seductive cajoling. The supporting cast, which includes Peter Vaughan in a wonderful performance as Stevens' father, William, is also superb. Richard Robbins' whimsical, enchanting, hypnotic music is like a good wine: somberly intoxicating. The centerpiece of the film is Anthony Hopkins' Oscar-nominated performance as Stevens, a role which requires tremendous inner energy, as we must always see that he is, in fact, affected by events, while the emotional hollowness of his verbal interactions with the other characters belies his concern. The continual bombardment of his stoicism by personal challenges seems almost humorously intentional on the part of the filmmakers, like tourists trying to make a member of the Royal Guard laugh. Stevens, who cracks a nervous smile now and again, never has a real laugh, and never pursues his love for Miss Kenton, until it is too late. Honor, duty, and dignity are the reasons given for his failure to launch, but it seems as though Stevens comes from a long line of married people, including his father, who also worked as a butler and still managed to have a family of his own. There is a fair share of upstairs-downstairs going on in the world of the film, most pronounced in an uncomfortable scene in which Stevens' ignorance of world affairs is used to prove a point against democracy, but it doesn't seem completely antagonistic; when Mr. Stevens, Sr. trips and falls, dropping a full tray of items, the "men of stature" he is waiting on come to his aid quickly and treat him humanely. The cause of Stevens' reluctance to accept love when it presents itself appears to be more personal than societal. Stevens, deserving of the benefit of the doubt, is more a workaholic than a sociopath, although there is a faint, remote comparison drawn between Stevens' blind obedience and that of the Nazi soldiers whom Stevens' master is accused of throwing in with. Whatever the reasona reason that seems to escape Stevens himselfthe unrequited love between Ms. Kenton and Mr. Stevens is a source of heartbreaking regret and sadness for this long-time admirer of the filma feeling that lingers after the final, symbolic scene in which Mr. Stevens, after having assisted Mr. Lewis in releasing a temporarily trapped bird, closes forever the window of opportunity on a chance at love, at unchaining his heart, at escaping Darlington Hall to pursue a life of his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this again recently on cable after many years and it is even better than I remembered. Like many Merchant Ivory movies there are many details that can't all be absorbed one viewing. It helps to know the premise of the plot in advance so the going back and forth in time is not confusing. The story is powerful and the story of appeasement in pre WWII Britain is both chilling and fascinating to watch. Makes one look at the butler's job in a different light - more like running a hotel. The Butler's role felt crucial to support the critical but misguided peace talks. The subplot with his father is touching. The screenplay captures both the grand sweep of the larger events and the intimate personal story. The filming, interiors, scenery and cinematography are all beautiful. It is Emma Thompson's best role. Every emotion is so transparent and clear on her face. Her frustration and sadness are moving and memorable. Anthony Hopkins is so convincing in the character that it's hard to imagine you are not watching a real butler. Hope he is remembered more for this role than "Silence of the Lambs". The scenes between them are loaded with emotion and unspoken feelings. Excellent supporting cast including the regal James Fox and a well cast Christopher Reeve. If not for the stiff competition that year including Schindler's List, Philadelphia, Age of Innocence, I think in any other year this would have swept the table. A truly wonderful result of the combination of a Japanese author, a German screenwriter, an American director and the top British actors. One of the best movies in the last 50 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Ismail Merchant was Indian by birth and James Ivory American, and although many of their film-scripts, including this one, were written by the German-born Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, the Merchant-Ivory partnership came to be seen as quintessentially British film-makers. They were responsible for some of the best-known British films of the eighties and nineties, mostly costume dramas based upon literary sources and dealing with the lives of the well-to-do classes. They did not invent the film genre which has become known as "heritage cinema"- that dates back at least to the late sixties- but are perhaps its best-known practitioners. "The Remains of the Day"- the significance of the title is rather obscure- is in many ways a typical example of their work, although the action takes place in the 1930s and 1950s rather than the late Victorian/Edwardian era with which they are normally associated. The main character is Mr. Stevens, the butler of Darlington Hall, an English stately home, during the 1930s. (Stevens' Christian name is James, but he is rarely referred to as such. By convention, senior servants in a household were referred to by their surnames alone). There are two strands to the plot, one political and the other personal. The political strand involves Stevens' employer Lord Darlington, an influential politician who frequently hosts gatherings of important international figures at this home. The personal strand involves Stevens' relations with Lord Darlington's housekeeper Miss Kenton, who falls in love with him although he fails to reciprocate her sentiments. (Or possibly he does, but fails to show it). The central political theme of the film is the politics of appeasement. Darlington initially appears to be in many ways an admirable character, kindly, honourable and idealistic. Although he served in the First World War he, unlike many veterans of that conflict, bears no hatred or animosity towards the Germans- indeed, he believes that Germany was harshly treated in 1919 by the vindictive Allies. His main fault is that he cannot understand those who are not honourable and idealistic, and this blinds him to the evils of Nazism; in the misguided belief that Hitler is a trustworthy man of honour he becomes an outspoken advocate of appeasement. As the film progresses, however, his own character deteriorates; he openly welcomes outright Nazi sympathisers as guests in his home, and even dismisses two Jewish chambermaids for fear of upsetting such persons. Stevens prides himself on being a model butler. He is calm, courteous and efficient, punctilious in the performance of his duties, unfailingly loyal to his employer. He regards any display of emotion as a weakness, and preserves an iron self-control at all times. Miss Kenton- we learn late on in the film that her name is Sarah, although she prefers to be called Sally- is equally efficient professionally, but is warmer and more openly emotional. The question the film raises is whether one should allow oneself to be defined entirely through one's work and through one's relationship with one's superiors. It is the same question as the great Austrian dramatist Franz Grillparzer was raising in his play "Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn". Like Grillparzer's hero Bancbanus, Stevens is a "faithful servant of his master"- the literal meaning of the German title- but one whose faithful service comes at a cost. In Stevens' case that cost is both personal, in that he sacrifices his chances of finding love, and moral, in that his loyalty leads him to close his eyes to his master's behaviour. When the two Jewish maids are dismissed, Miss Kenton is outraged, but Stevens refuses to utter a word of criticism of his employer, even in private. We are left wondering whether he is simply being diplomatic, or whether he actually does believe that the rich and powerful can do not wrong. When I recently reviewed "84, Charing Cross Road", I stated that while Anthony Hopkins is sometimes regarded in specialising in forceful, flamboyant or monstrous characters such as Hannibal Lecter or Captain Bligh in "The Bounty", he can be equally good as quieter, more restrained individuals, such as Dr Treves in "The Elephant Man", C S Lewis in "Shadowlands" or Frank Doel in "84, Charing Cross Road" itself. "The Remains of the Day" is perhaps Hopkins' finest performance in his vein. It is a superb piece of acting, quiet and unobtrusive, but all the more effective for being so. Emma Thompson is also good as Miss Kenton, as is James Fox as Lord Darlington. There are also good performances in smaller parts from the likes of Peter Vaughan as Stevens' elderly father, although I was less impressed by Christopher Reeve as American Congressman Jack Lewis. (Lewis' part appears to have been expanded beyond that he plays in the novel by Kazuo Ishiguro, doubtless in order to provide a role for a big Hollywood name). The film displays the typical Merchant-Ivory characteristics of high production values and a loving recreation of period detail. It is, to my mind, perhaps too leisurely and slow-moving, which is why I would not rate it as highly as some other Merchant-Ivory productions, such as "A Room with a View" or "Howards End", made the year before and also starring Hopkins and Thompson. It is, however, a well-acted and well-photographed movie, and often a thought-provoking one in its analysis of interwar history and its theme that loyalty often comes with a hidden cost. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching story and another great acting from Anthony Hopkins.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nail Yener
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't I watch this movie before? This is the question that I asked myself after I finished watching The Remains of the Day. I have seen most movies of Anthony Hopkins but I didn't even know this movie existed until yesterday when I was doing some research about 90s movies. It was always a great pleasure for me to see Anthony Hopkins in a movie no matter what his role was. And his performance in this movie once more gives me a reason to watch him again and again and again. But I didn't like this movie just because of him. I liked it because of many things such as its story, the performance of Emma Thompson and other actors/actresses and the atmosphere of the film as a whole. The story of The Remains of the Day focuses on nobility and suppressed feelings. I really felt like as if I was witnessing a real section from that time while watching the movie. At the end, when I go over the whole story in my head once more, although I wished that Mr. Stevens and Miss Kenton would reveal their true feelings to each other, I think I didn't feel sorry for them. Because this is the way Mr. Stevens is and this is the message of this movie in my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A subtle insight into flawed characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Srinivas G Phani
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are a few films that stand out due to their simplicity. Amour was one of those this year. The Remains of the Day falls into the same category. Helmed by James Ivory, known for his moving period pieces, the film stands a few notches above all his previous achievements. I am an ardent Merchant-Ivory fan and Howards End is one of the most exquisitely pictured films and deeply moving within its seemingly shallow screenplay and characters. Remains of the Day is no less an achievement in its exploration of a bunch of flawed characters whose acts are easy to criticize but understanding their inhibitions and regrets, very difficult. Much of the story takes place within a huge country-mansion called Darlington Hall, owned by the pro-Nazi gentleman, Lord Darlington. Mr Stevens is the head butler for the mansion and takes great pride in his excellence and capabilities. And then comes Miss Kenton, only to criticize him first, and then fall in love with him. Not as simple, Mr Stevens gives duties preference and what turns out is a tale of regret of choices and complications in the definition of duty. To sum up a long story short, The Remains of the Day is a fantastic film and is more pertinent to modern-day audience. With World War  II and rise of Nazism in backdrop, it beautifully explores the lives of people who are more indirectly affected by the changing political scenario. Deep within, it is essentially a story of unrequited love with not a single scene of romance! The film has so much to tell, so much happening that one cannot assimilate the film entirely at once. While the romantic angle takes preference in the final reels, the under-currents of success in career and regret over decisions is loud and clear. Agreed most artists associated with the film have limited range  James Ivory, Pierce-Roberts, Prawer Jhabvala, Emma Thompson and to an extent Anthony Hopkins. But what wonderfully they utilize their range, churning out gold within their repertoire. James Ivory's direction is outstanding at places and stays above 'very good' throughout. He builds up the tension so well during the conference is just an example of how good the direction is. Rightly noted in Wikipedia, the film touches a lot of themes and each of them translate smoothly onto the screen all thanks to Ivory and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins rise above the story and direction and give truly heart-felt performances. Their interactions are the best scenes of the film. Especially the one where she is crying within and he blabbers about their routine the next day and the one where she sobs on the floor. I will not reveal what he does in the latter scene for it would be a spoiler but Hopkins is so much in his character that his actions in that scene are easy to empathize although evil in the traditional sense. The scenes of their brief rendezvous after twenty years are truly unwatchable. The film is very depressing and ends without showing any hope of a better future for the characters. Tony Peirce-Roberts' cinematography is strictly functional and nothing compared to his work in Howards End. Every actor gives his very best in the film. Performances, direction and screenplay are of the highest order. The Remains of the Day captures the very essence of its title, thoroughly justifying it, etches out really flawed characters and brings them alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fine film personifies excellence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clehoullier
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We often refer to this film as a reference point when pondering the extreme disappointment with so many of today's movies (it is July 2013). So many movies are released with huge budgets, loads of buzz, and (apparently), stacked ratings on websites. Perhaps it is just a change in taste due to generational shifts..... Wonderful soundtrack, perfect casting, engaging plot, transcendent performances, and complexity - all are here. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins are so good that it is as if it is all real, not an act. There is so much emotion bubbling under the surface. The ending will leave you shaken for many days. We are thankful for films such as Remains of the Day, Out of Africa, Howard's End, Babbette's Feast - films that dig inside of us, films that make us part of their very fabric. All of the sifting through the trash that is mostly what is released today can be washed clean by going back to a beloved film such as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Acting Masterclass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrost71w
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By some happy coincidence, everybody in this film gives one of their best performances, especially the two leads. Anthony Hopkins is breathtaking; he plays a repressed butler who never overtly shows emotion. How on earth do you play such a character and not appear wooden? You have to be Anthony Hopkins, that's how. Somehow, with just a raise of the eyebrow or the down-turn of the mouth he manages to convey hate, love, humour, distaste, horror, regret and every other emotion under the sun in scene after scene. I have never seen anything like it. I knew exactly how he was feeling from just a tiny crinkling of the eyes. He had a thousand slightly different smiles each of which conveyed a different emotion that he was supposed to be feeling. Watch in awe all you wannabe actors for surely THIS is how it is done. And if anyone wants proof that the Oscars are meaningless, the fact that Remains of The Day won no Oscars is a bigger farce that LA Confidential being kept off the win sheet by bloody Titanic
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dense, literary and eloquent..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    American screenwriter, producer and director James Ivory's nineteenth feature film which was written by German author and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, is an adaptation of a novel from 1989 by Japanese author Kazuo Ishiguro. It was shot on locations in England and is a UK-USA co-production which was produced by Indian screenwriter, producer and director Ismail Merchant, American screenwriter, producer and director Mike Nichols and American producer John Calley. It tells the story about a butler named James Stevens who whilst executing his profession with the utmost dignity at a large mansion called Darlington Hall for the Lord of Darlington, hires a housekeeper named Sarah Kenton. Subtly and precisely directed by British filmmaker James Ivory, this quietly paced fictional tale which is narrated from the two main characters viewpoints, draws a heartrending portrayal of a middle-aged man who is courted by a compassionate woman whom he keeps at distance by remaining utterly professional whenever they interact. While notable for it's naturalistic, atmospheric and mostly interior milieu depictions, sterling production design by production designer Luciana Arrighi, cinematography by English cinematographer Tony-Pierce Roberts, costume design by costume designers Jenny Beaven and John Bright and make-up by make-up artist Christine Beveridge, this dialog-driven and narrative-driven story depicts a refined study of character and contains a good score by American composer Richard Robins. This somewhat political, oppressively romantic and conversational period drama which is set on a country estate in post-war England during the 1930s and 1940s where a woman tries to reach into the feelings of a man whom is completely dedicated to his work and where human emotions are disguised by manners, is impelled and reinforced by it's fragmented narrative structure, subtle character development and continuity and understated and memorable acting performances by Welsh actor Anthony Hopkins and English actress Emma Thompson. A dense, literary and eloquent love-story from the early 1990s which gained, among numerous other awards, the award for Best Actor Anthony Hopkins at the 65th NBR Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man shall never regret what he did, only what he didn't do ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Remains of the Day" is the kind of film where you first hope for something to happen then that nothing ever break the serene harmony inhabiting the story. Yet, to say that the film is plot-less would be as unfair as untrue: another successful product of the director and producer's duo: James Ivory and Ismail Merchant, the film offers another riveting slice of the British aristocratic life, this time during the inter-war, this time for a story even more enthralling because it is told from the servants' perspective, from the diary of William Stevens, the butler. As Stevens, Anthony Hopkins delivers such a solid performance, in all nuance and subtlety, that we can't doubt the man has been or could have been anything but a butler, obviously belonging to a tradition as old as the hills and whose William Stevens Sr. (Peter Vaughan) is another living remain. Stevens Jr. has been impregnated his whole life by this impeccable perfectionism, total dedication to the master, and the dilution of his own ego into work; and to a certain extent, the butler's tasks, no matter how prestigious and dignified they seem in the beginning, turn our to be ingrate as the story progresses. This unfortunate hardship is crucial though as an empathy-builder, we see Stevens with eyes of sorrow for he's incapable to demonstrate any hint of freethinking or independent personality. And the power of Hopkins is to portray a man trapped in the one-note performance requested for his job, in a poignantly three-dimensional way. In fact, the main thrills of "The Remains of the Day" consist of spotting the little hints betraying Mr Stevens' capability for feelings. One clue: they mostly happen during the scenes involving directly or indirectly Emma Thompson, the second lead of the film. As Mrs Kenton, Emma Thompson, the smart and pretty housekeeper is educated and trained enough to see in Mr Stevens, a worthy of admiration colleague, and she's equal to him enough, in the household hierarchy, to allow herself some familiarities. Obviously fascinated by this mountain of coldness, she brings some flowers to his private room and then, something interesting happens. While he almost dismisses the flowers as 'distractions', he politely asks Mrs Kenton to display more respect toward his father, by not calling him by his Christian name. The scene can mislead by foreshadowing several clashes between the two servants, when they are only benign misunderstandings. But it does show that that there is a heart beating behind this impeccable costume and demeanor. And when this heart is about to collapse while the father is dying, Stevens continues to serve the Master's guest: no matter what happens, work must go on. This is Stevens' inner conflict, whose paradox is to create a gap between him and Mrs Kenton but in the same time, allows their mutual respect and tacit attraction, to grow patiently and discreetly with the passing of time. But we know that the romance is doomed from the very beginning, the story doesn't leave much for optimism. We know, when the movie opens that Stevens still work in the same manor, that his Master Lord Darlington died, and an American Congressman, played by Christopher Reeve, bought the house. Mrs Kenton left Darlington before the outbreak of the war and got married. The flow of the film conveys an insightful parallel between the romance and the relationship with the Master. James Fox plays Lord Darlington, not a Nazi sympathizer, but an ambiguous well-mannered gentleman who 'understands' the Germans. During a memorable toast, the American Congressman, and future house owner, would call all the assembled European politicians 'amateurs', an allegation that only shocks his audience, but doesn't fool us, not even Darlington's godson (Hugh Grant). The 'amateur' speech, with the same resonance than Churchill's 'dishonour and war' line, foresees the last days of an agonizing order that exploited the guilt of WWI victory, to roll the red carpets to the Nazis. And the tragic choices of Darlington would spill over Stevens' life. Incapable of adopting one defying attitude against his own master, Stevens condemned himself to a standard of life sadly prone to unhappiness and frustration. And it's precisely the kind of life that Mrs Kenton rejected by leaving the house. And her personal tragedy is that she left the only man she truly loved. "The Remains of the Day" chronicles two separate stories, challenging the solemn and unflappably professionalism of Mr Stevens, and interlocking each other until leading Stevens to a dead-end. And twenty years later, Stevens maintains the same level of mystery. People ask him where he stood for regarding his Master's opinion. Invoking the call of duty, he served his Master the best he could. He deplored some uninspired choices, the most significant being the revocation of two Jewish maids. But still, Stevens embraced his master's choices without being an accomplice. A few years later, the seal of infamy marks the name of Darlington, but not Stevens', yet there's no doubt his heart carries some regrets, and maybe, his unfulfilled relationship with Mrs Kenton is a way to make up for his own guilt. To have followed Darlington or not following Mrs Kenton? Looking back on his life, Stevens would understand the value of regrets, whether it's for done or undone choices, maybe by persuading a divorced Mrs Kenton to go back to Darlington? As a character study, the film is a wonderful examination of lives made of unmade choices and 'what if' questions, as a romance, it happens to be admirably poignant and brilliant, because feelings are so intimate and real that they can hardly be expressed, let alone from a man of such a few words like Mr Stevens. And this is why the ending plays as the perfect emotional pay-off for a film so full of frustrating inhibitions, a light of hope after an eternity spent in the Master's shadow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hopkins' finest role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Remains Of The Day" is a script that clearly stood or fell with the casting of the Mr.Stevens character, and thank God they hit that one out of the park. Anthony Hopkins is perfect in this complex role, the writing isn't always that solid but Hopkins can just make any scene work here. Playing a character that's supposed to hide all his emotions is a challenge, but Hopkins still manages to give Stevens amazing depth. It's all in the little things I guess: occasionally Stevens will smile, but you never know if he's really happy or if he just does everything he does because it's expected from the butler. You can't look in the character's mind because he's so brilliantly underplayed. The best scene of "Remains Of The Day" comes near the end, when Stevens enters the room of a sobbing Emma Thompson. The climax to that scene (or lack thereof) is so fitting and so amazing. This is not my favorite movie ever because as I said, it isn't even that well-scripted or directed, but it's very compelling nonetheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Remains of the Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unrequited love finds multiple reasons to remain unrequited in The Remains of the Day, a film as beautifully written, acted, and shot (interiors and exteriors), as it is frustrating in its unrepressed examination of repression. Anthony Hopkins plays James Stevens, head butler of Darlington Hall, the residence of Lord Darlington (James Fox), an English aristocrat who hosts interwar dinners and conferences for world politicians, including the prime minister and foreign ambassadors. Darlington wishes to appease Nazi Germany, whom he feels was too harshly treated by the Treaty of Versailles. Christopher Reeve plays Jack Lewis, the American delegate, who invades the proceedings to call the attendees "amateurs." Hugh Grant, in one of his better roles, plays Darlington's godson, Reginald Cardinal, a "news hound" who eventually agrees with Lewis and detects the abuse of Darlington's "good, noble intentions" by the Germans, the intentions of whose leader are not fully comprehended by Darlington, who will later recognize his own gullibility. It is within this context of large-scale moral and political conflict and international affairs that super-butler Stevens toils to keep a good house. Not only does he try, with every fiber of his being, to remain detached from the world-shaking decisions being made around him (he seems more concerned with the return of a chair to its proper place), but he also maintains an ostensible detachment from his feelings (he shows more emotion over the breaking of a wine bottle than over the death of his father). Stevens extends this detachment to his feelings for the housekeeper, Miss Kenton (Emma Thompson), who, compared with Mr. Stevens, wears her emotions on her sleeve. Stevens justifies his detachment by the unwavering "dignity" required of a great butler, especially one in the service of a house carrying the importance of Darlington Hall. Emma Thompson's Oscar-nominated performance is earnest and superb. Her character, who is considered old by the underservants and young by Mr. Stevens, passes through a range of emotions and tactics: she offers matronly advice to a younger maidservant rushing into marriage, plays provocative detective in bringing to light the errors committed by Stevens' father, tenderly comforts Stevens when his father falls ill, chastises Stevens for his moral inertness in the face of his master's racist turn, criticizes herself for placing her needs above her convictions, and, in one of the most brilliant scenes of the film, encroaches upon Stevens' "private time" to pry into the subject matter of his reading material, while walking a fine line between playful mockery and seductive cajoling. The supporting cast, which includes Peter Vaughan in a wonderful performance as Stevens' father, William, is also superb. Richard Robbins' whimsical, enchanting, hypnotic music is like a good wine: somberly intoxicating. The centerpiece of the film is Anthony Hopkins' Oscar-nominated performance as Stevens, a role which requires tremendous inner energy, as we must always see that he is, in fact, affected by events, while the emotional hollowness of his verbal interactions with the other characters belies his concern. The continual bombardment of his stoicism by personal challenges seems almost humorously intentional on the part of the filmmakers, like tourists trying to make a member of the Royal Guard laugh. Stevens, who cracks a nervous smile now and again, never has a real laugh, and never pursues his love for Miss Kenton, until it is too late. Honor, duty, and dignity are the reasons given for his failure to launch, but it seems as though Stevens comes from a long line of married people, including his father, who also worked as a butler and still managed to have a family of his own. There is a fair share of upstairs-downstairs going on in the world of the film, most pronounced in an uncomfortable scene in which Stevens' ignorance of world affairs is used to prove a point against democracy, but it doesn't seem completely antagonistic; when Mr. Stevens, Sr. trips and falls, dropping a full tray of items, the "men of stature" he is waiting on come to his aid quickly and treat him humanely. The cause of Stevens' reluctance to accept love when it presents itself appears to be more personal than societal. Stevens, deserving of the benefit of the doubt, is more a workaholic than a sociopath, although there is a faint, remote comparison drawn between Stevens' blind obedience and that of the Nazi soldiers whom Stevens' master is accused of throwing in with. Whatever the reasona reason that seems to escape Stevens himselfthe unrequited love between Ms. Kenton and Mr. Stevens is a source of heartbreaking regret and sadness for this long-time admirer of the filma feeling that lingers after the final, symbolic scene in which Mr. Stevens, after having assisted Mr. Lewis in releasing a temporarily trapped bird, closes forever the window of opportunity on a chance at love, at unchaining his heart, at escaping Darlington Hall to pursue a life of his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this again recently on cable after many years and it is even better than I remembered. Like many Merchant Ivory movies there are many details that can't all be absorbed one viewing. It helps to know the premise of the plot in advance so the going back and forth in time is not confusing. The story is powerful and the story of appeasement in pre WWII Britain is both chilling and fascinating to watch. Makes one look at the butler's job in a different light - more like running a hotel. The Butler's role felt crucial to support the critical but misguided peace talks. The subplot with his father is touching. The screenplay captures both the grand sweep of the larger events and the intimate personal story. The filming, interiors, scenery and cinematography are all beautiful. It is Emma Thompson's best role. Every emotion is so transparent and clear on her face. Her frustration and sadness are moving and memorable. Anthony Hopkins is so convincing in the character that it's hard to imagine you are not watching a real butler. Hope he is remembered more for this role than "Silence of the Lambs". The scenes between them are loaded with emotion and unspoken feelings. Excellent supporting cast including the regal James Fox and a well cast Christopher Reeve. If not for the stiff competition that year including Schindler's List, Philadelphia, Age of Innocence, I think in any other year this would have swept the table. A truly wonderful result of the combination of a Japanese author, a German screenwriter, an American director and the top British actors. One of the best movies in the last 50 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Ismail Merchant was Indian by birth and James Ivory American, and although many of their film-scripts, including this one, were written by the German-born Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, the Merchant-Ivory partnership came to be seen as quintessentially British film-makers. They were responsible for some of the best-known British films of the eighties and nineties, mostly costume dramas based upon literary sources and dealing with the lives of the well-to-do classes. They did not invent the film genre which has become known as "heritage cinema"- that dates back at least to the late sixties- but are perhaps its best-known practitioners. "The Remains of the Day"- the significance of the title is rather obscure- is in many ways a typical example of their work, although the action takes place in the 1930s and 1950s rather than the late Victorian/Edwardian era with which they are normally associated. The main character is Mr. Stevens, the butler of Darlington Hall, an English stately home, during the 1930s. (Stevens' Christian name is James, but he is rarely referred to as such. By convention, senior servants in a household were referred to by their surnames alone). There are two strands to the plot, one political and the other personal. The political strand involves Stevens' employer Lord Darlington, an influential politician who frequently hosts gatherings of important international figures at this home. The personal strand involves Stevens' relations with Lord Darlington's housekeeper Miss Kenton, who falls in love with him although he fails to reciprocate her sentiments. (Or possibly he does, but fails to show it). The central political theme of the film is the politics of appeasement. Darlington initially appears to be in many ways an admirable character, kindly, honourable and idealistic. Although he served in the First World War he, unlike many veterans of that conflict, bears no hatred or animosity towards the Germans- indeed, he believes that Germany was harshly treated in 1919 by the vindictive Allies. His main fault is that he cannot understand those who are not honourable and idealistic, and this blinds him to the evils of Nazism; in the misguided belief that Hitler is a trustworthy man of honour he becomes an outspoken advocate of appeasement. As the film progresses, however, his own character deteriorates; he openly welcomes outright Nazi sympathisers as guests in his home, and even dismisses two Jewish chambermaids for fear of upsetting such persons. Stevens prides himself on being a model butler. He is calm, courteous and efficient, punctilious in the performance of his duties, unfailingly loyal to his employer. He regards any display of emotion as a weakness, and preserves an iron self-control at all times. Miss Kenton- we learn late on in the film that her name is Sarah, although she prefers to be called Sally- is equally efficient professionally, but is warmer and more openly emotional. The question the film raises is whether one should allow oneself to be defined entirely through one's work and through one's relationship with one's superiors. It is the same question as the great Austrian dramatist Franz Grillparzer was raising in his play "Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn". Like Grillparzer's hero Bancbanus, Stevens is a "faithful servant of his master"- the literal meaning of the German title- but one whose faithful service comes at a cost. In Stevens' case that cost is both personal, in that he sacrifices his chances of finding love, and moral, in that his loyalty leads him to close his eyes to his master's behaviour. When the two Jewish maids are dismissed, Miss Kenton is outraged, but Stevens refuses to utter a word of criticism of his employer, even in private. We are left wondering whether he is simply being diplomatic, or whether he actually does believe that the rich and powerful can do not wrong. When I recently reviewed "84, Charing Cross Road", I stated that while Anthony Hopkins is sometimes regarded in specialising in forceful, flamboyant or monstrous characters such as Hannibal Lecter or Captain Bligh in "The Bounty", he can be equally good as quieter, more restrained individuals, such as Dr Treves in "The Elephant Man", C S Lewis in "Shadowlands" or Frank Doel in "84, Charing Cross Road" itself. "The Remains of the Day" is perhaps Hopkins' finest performance in his vein. It is a superb piece of acting, quiet and unobtrusive, but all the more effective for being so. Emma Thompson is also good as Miss Kenton, as is James Fox as Lord Darlington. There are also good performances in smaller parts from the likes of Peter Vaughan as Stevens' elderly father, although I was less impressed by Christopher Reeve as American Congressman Jack Lewis. (Lewis' part appears to have been expanded beyond that he plays in the novel by Kazuo Ishiguro, doubtless in order to provide a role for a big Hollywood name). The film displays the typical Merchant-Ivory characteristics of high production values and a loving recreation of period detail. It is, to my mind, perhaps too leisurely and slow-moving, which is why I would not rate it as highly as some other Merchant-Ivory productions, such as "A Room with a View" or "Howards End", made the year before and also starring Hopkins and Thompson. It is, however, a well-acted and well-photographed movie, and often a thought-provoking one in its analysis of interwar history and its theme that loyalty often comes with a hidden cost. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching story and another great acting from Anthony Hopkins.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nail Yener
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't I watch this movie before? This is the question that I asked myself after I finished watching The Remains of the Day. I have seen most movies of Anthony Hopkins but I didn't even know this movie existed until yesterday when I was doing some research about 90s movies. It was always a great pleasure for me to see Anthony Hopkins in a movie no matter what his role was. And his performance in this movie once more gives me a reason to watch him again and again and again. But I didn't like this movie just because of him. I liked it because of many things such as its story, the performance of Emma Thompson and other actors/actresses and the atmosphere of the film as a whole. The story of The Remains of the Day focuses on nobility and suppressed feelings. I really felt like as if I was witnessing a real section from that time while watching the movie. At the end, when I go over the whole story in my head once more, although I wished that Mr. Stevens and Miss Kenton would reveal their true feelings to each other, I think I didn't feel sorry for them. Because this is the way Mr. Stevens is and this is the message of this movie in my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A subtle insight into flawed characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Srinivas G Phani
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are a few films that stand out due to their simplicity. Amour was one of those this year. The Remains of the Day falls into the same category. Helmed by James Ivory, known for his moving period pieces, the film stands a few notches above all his previous achievements. I am an ardent Merchant-Ivory fan and Howards End is one of the most exquisitely pictured films and deeply moving within its seemingly shallow screenplay and characters. Remains of the Day is no less an achievement in its exploration of a bunch of flawed characters whose acts are easy to criticize but understanding their inhibitions and regrets, very difficult. Much of the story takes place within a huge country-mansion called Darlington Hall, owned by the pro-Nazi gentleman, Lord Darlington. Mr Stevens is the head butler for the mansion and takes great pride in his excellence and capabilities. And then comes Miss Kenton, only to criticize him first, and then fall in love with him. Not as simple, Mr Stevens gives duties preference and what turns out is a tale of regret of choices and complications in the definition of duty. To sum up a long story short, The Remains of the Day is a fantastic film and is more pertinent to modern-day audience. With World War  II and rise of Nazism in backdrop, it beautifully explores the lives of people who are more indirectly affected by the changing political scenario. Deep within, it is essentially a story of unrequited love with not a single scene of romance! The film has so much to tell, so much happening that one cannot assimilate the film entirely at once. While the romantic angle takes preference in the final reels, the under-currents of success in career and regret over decisions is loud and clear. Agreed most artists associated with the film have limited range  James Ivory, Pierce-Roberts, Prawer Jhabvala, Emma Thompson and to an extent Anthony Hopkins. But what wonderfully they utilize their range, churning out gold within their repertoire. James Ivory's direction is outstanding at places and stays above 'very good' throughout. He builds up the tension so well during the conference is just an example of how good the direction is. Rightly noted in Wikipedia, the film touches a lot of themes and each of them translate smoothly onto the screen all thanks to Ivory and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins rise above the story and direction and give truly heart-felt performances. Their interactions are the best scenes of the film. Especially the one where she is crying within and he blabbers about their routine the next day and the one where she sobs on the floor. I will not reveal what he does in the latter scene for it would be a spoiler but Hopkins is so much in his character that his actions in that scene are easy to empathize although evil in the traditional sense. The scenes of their brief rendezvous after twenty years are truly unwatchable. The film is very depressing and ends without showing any hope of a better future for the characters. Tony Peirce-Roberts' cinematography is strictly functional and nothing compared to his work in Howards End. Every actor gives his very best in the film. Performances, direction and screenplay are of the highest order. The Remains of the Day captures the very essence of its title, thoroughly justifying it, etches out really flawed characters and brings them alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fine film personifies excellence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clehoullier
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We often refer to this film as a reference point when pondering the extreme disappointment with so many of today's movies (it is July 2013). So many movies are released with huge budgets, loads of buzz, and (apparently), stacked ratings on websites. Perhaps it is just a change in taste due to generational shifts..... Wonderful soundtrack, perfect casting, engaging plot, transcendent performances, and complexity - all are here. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins are so good that it is as if it is all real, not an act. There is so much emotion bubbling under the surface. The ending will leave you shaken for many days. We are thankful for films such as Remains of the Day, Out of Africa, Howard's End, Babbette's Feast - films that dig inside of us, films that make us part of their very fabric. All of the sifting through the trash that is mostly what is released today can be washed clean by going back to a beloved film such as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Acting Masterclass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrost71w
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By some happy coincidence, everybody in this film gives one of their best performances, especially the two leads. Anthony Hopkins is breathtaking; he plays a repressed butler who never overtly shows emotion. How on earth do you play such a character and not appear wooden? You have to be Anthony Hopkins, that's how. Somehow, with just a raise of the eyebrow or the down-turn of the mouth he manages to convey hate, love, humour, distaste, horror, regret and every other emotion under the sun in scene after scene. I have never seen anything like it. I knew exactly how he was feeling from just a tiny crinkling of the eyes. He had a thousand slightly different smiles each of which conveyed a different emotion that he was supposed to be feeling. Watch in awe all you wannabe actors for surely THIS is how it is done. And if anyone wants proof that the Oscars are meaningless, the fact that Remains of The Day won no Oscars is a bigger farce that LA Confidential being kept off the win sheet by bloody Titanic
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dense, literary and eloquent..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    American screenwriter, producer and director James Ivory's nineteenth feature film which was written by German author and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, is an adaptation of a novel from 1989 by Japanese author Kazuo Ishiguro. It was shot on locations in England and is a UK-USA co-production which was produced by Indian screenwriter, producer and director Ismail Merchant, American screenwriter, producer and director Mike Nichols and American producer John Calley. It tells the story about a butler named James Stevens who whilst executing his profession with the utmost dignity at a large mansion called Darlington Hall for the Lord of Darlington, hires a housekeeper named Sarah Kenton. Subtly and precisely directed by British filmmaker James Ivory, this quietly paced fictional tale which is narrated from the two main characters viewpoints, draws a heartrending portrayal of a middle-aged man who is courted by a compassionate woman whom he keeps at distance by remaining utterly professional whenever they interact. While notable for it's naturalistic, atmospheric and mostly interior milieu depictions, sterling production design by production designer Luciana Arrighi, cinematography by English cinematographer Tony-Pierce Roberts, costume design by costume designers Jenny Beaven and John Bright and make-up by make-up artist Christine Beveridge, this dialog-driven and narrative-driven story depicts a refined study of character and contains a good score by American composer Richard Robins. This somewhat political, oppressively romantic and conversational period drama which is set on a country estate in post-war England during the 1930s and 1940s where a woman tries to reach into the feelings of a man whom is completely dedicated to his work and where human emotions are disguised by manners, is impelled and reinforced by it's fragmented narrative structure, subtle character development and continuity and understated and memorable acting performances by Welsh actor Anthony Hopkins and English actress Emma Thompson. A dense, literary and eloquent love-story from the early 1990s which gained, among numerous other awards, the award for Best Actor Anthony Hopkins at the 65th NBR Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man shall never regret what he did, only what he didn't do ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Remains of the Day" is the kind of film where you first hope for something to happen then that nothing ever break the serene harmony inhabiting the story. Yet, to say that the film is plot-less would be as unfair as untrue: another successful product of the director and producer's duo: James Ivory and Ismail Merchant, the film offers another riveting slice of the British aristocratic life, this time during the inter-war, this time for a story even more enthralling because it is told from the servants' perspective, from the diary of William Stevens, the butler. As Stevens, Anthony Hopkins delivers such a solid performance, in all nuance and subtlety, that we can't doubt the man has been or could have been anything but a butler, obviously belonging to a tradition as old as the hills and whose William Stevens Sr. (Peter Vaughan) is another living remain. Stevens Jr. has been impregnated his whole life by this impeccable perfectionism, total dedication to the master, and the dilution of his own ego into work; and to a certain extent, the butler's tasks, no matter how prestigious and dignified they seem in the beginning, turn our to be ingrate as the story progresses. This unfortunate hardship is crucial though as an empathy-builder, we see Stevens with eyes of sorrow for he's incapable to demonstrate any hint of freethinking or independent personality. And the power of Hopkins is to portray a man trapped in the one-note performance requested for his job, in a poignantly three-dimensional way. In fact, the main thrills of "The Remains of the Day" consist of spotting the little hints betraying Mr Stevens' capability for feelings. One clue: they mostly happen during the scenes involving directly or indirectly Emma Thompson, the second lead of the film. As Mrs Kenton, Emma Thompson, the smart and pretty housekeeper is educated and trained enough to see in Mr Stevens, a worthy of admiration colleague, and she's equal to him enough, in the household hierarchy, to allow herself some familiarities. Obviously fascinated by this mountain of coldness, she brings some flowers to his private room and then, something interesting happens. While he almost dismisses the flowers as 'distractions', he politely asks Mrs Kenton to display more respect toward his father, by not calling him by his Christian name. The scene can mislead by foreshadowing several clashes between the two servants, when they are only benign misunderstandings. But it does show that that there is a heart beating behind this impeccable costume and demeanor. And when this heart is about to collapse while the father is dying, Stevens continues to serve the Master's guest: no matter what happens, work must go on. This is Stevens' inner conflict, whose paradox is to create a gap between him and Mrs Kenton but in the same time, allows their mutual respect and tacit attraction, to grow patiently and discreetly with the passing of time. But we know that the romance is doomed from the very beginning, the story doesn't leave much for optimism. We know, when the movie opens that Stevens still work in the same manor, that his Master Lord Darlington died, and an American Congressman, played by Christopher Reeve, bought the house. Mrs Kenton left Darlington before the outbreak of the war and got married. The flow of the film conveys an insightful parallel between the romance and the relationship with the Master. James Fox plays Lord Darlington, not a Nazi sympathizer, but an ambiguous well-mannered gentleman who 'understands' the Germans. During a memorable toast, the American Congressman, and future house owner, would call all the assembled European politicians 'amateurs', an allegation that only shocks his audience, but doesn't fool us, not even Darlington's godson (Hugh Grant). The 'amateur' speech, with the same resonance than Churchill's 'dishonour and war' line, foresees the last days of an agonizing order that exploited the guilt of WWI victory, to roll the red carpets to the Nazis. And the tragic choices of Darlington would spill over Stevens' life. Incapable of adopting one defying attitude against his own master, Stevens condemned himself to a standard of life sadly prone to unhappiness and frustration. And it's precisely the kind of life that Mrs Kenton rejected by leaving the house. And her personal tragedy is that she left the only man she truly loved. "The Remains of the Day" chronicles two separate stories, challenging the solemn and unflappably professionalism of Mr Stevens, and interlocking each other until leading Stevens to a dead-end. And twenty years later, Stevens maintains the same level of mystery. People ask him where he stood for regarding his Master's opinion. Invoking the call of duty, he served his Master the best he could. He deplored some uninspired choices, the most significant being the revocation of two Jewish maids. But still, Stevens embraced his master's choices without being an accomplice. A few years later, the seal of infamy marks the name of Darlington, but not Stevens', yet there's no doubt his heart carries some regrets, and maybe, his unfulfilled relationship with Mrs Kenton is a way to make up for his own guilt. To have followed Darlington or not following Mrs Kenton? Looking back on his life, Stevens would understand the value of regrets, whether it's for done or undone choices, maybe by persuading a divorced Mrs Kenton to go back to Darlington? As a character study, the film is a wonderful examination of lives made of unmade choices and 'what if' questions, as a romance, it happens to be admirably poignant and brilliant, because feelings are so intimate and real that they can hardly be expressed, let alone from a man of such a few words like Mr Stevens. And this is why the ending plays as the perfect emotional pay-off for a film so full of frustrating inhibitions, a light of hope after an eternity spent in the Master's shadow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hopkins' finest role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Remains Of The Day" is a script that clearly stood or fell with the casting of the Mr.Stevens character, and thank God they hit that one out of the park. Anthony Hopkins is perfect in this complex role, the writing isn't always that solid but Hopkins can just make any scene work here. Playing a character that's supposed to hide all his emotions is a challenge, but Hopkins still manages to give Stevens amazing depth. It's all in the little things I guess: occasionally Stevens will smile, but you never know if he's really happy or if he just does everything he does because it's expected from the butler. You can't look in the character's mind because he's so brilliantly underplayed. The best scene of "Remains Of The Day" comes near the end, when Stevens enters the room of a sobbing Emma Thompson. The climax to that scene (or lack thereof) is so fitting and so amazing. This is not my favorite movie ever because as I said, it isn't even that well-scripted or directed, but it's very compelling nonetheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Remains of the Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unrequited love finds multiple reasons to remain unrequited in The Remains of the Day, a film as beautifully written, acted, and shot (interiors and exteriors), as it is frustrating in its unrepressed examination of repression. Anthony Hopkins plays James Stevens, head butler of Darlington Hall, the residence of Lord Darlington (James Fox), an English aristocrat who hosts interwar dinners and conferences for world politicians, including the prime minister and foreign ambassadors. Darlington wishes to appease Nazi Germany, whom he feels was too harshly treated by the Treaty of Versailles. Christopher Reeve plays Jack Lewis, the American delegate, who invades the proceedings to call the attendees "amateurs." Hugh Grant, in one of his better roles, plays Darlington's godson, Reginald Cardinal, a "news hound" who eventually agrees with Lewis and detects the abuse of Darlington's "good, noble intentions" by the Germans, the intentions of whose leader are not fully comprehended by Darlington, who will later recognize his own gullibility. It is within this context of large-scale moral and political conflict and international affairs that super-butler Stevens toils to keep a good house. Not only does he try, with every fiber of his being, to remain detached from the world-shaking decisions being made around him (he seems more concerned with the return of a chair to its proper place), but he also maintains an ostensible detachment from his feelings (he shows more emotion over the breaking of a wine bottle than over the death of his father). Stevens extends this detachment to his feelings for the housekeeper, Miss Kenton (Emma Thompson), who, compared with Mr. Stevens, wears her emotions on her sleeve. Stevens justifies his detachment by the unwavering "dignity" required of a great butler, especially one in the service of a house carrying the importance of Darlington Hall. Emma Thompson's Oscar-nominated performance is earnest and superb. Her character, who is considered old by the underservants and young by Mr. Stevens, passes through a range of emotions and tactics: she offers matronly advice to a younger maidservant rushing into marriage, plays provocative detective in bringing to light the errors committed by Stevens' father, tenderly comforts Stevens when his father falls ill, chastises Stevens for his moral inertness in the face of his master's racist turn, criticizes herself for placing her needs above her convictions, and, in one of the most brilliant scenes of the film, encroaches upon Stevens' "private time" to pry into the subject matter of his reading material, while walking a fine line between playful mockery and seductive cajoling. The supporting cast, which includes Peter Vaughan in a wonderful performance as Stevens' father, William, is also superb. Richard Robbins' whimsical, enchanting, hypnotic music is like a good wine: somberly intoxicating. The centerpiece of the film is Anthony Hopkins' Oscar-nominated performance as Stevens, a role which requires tremendous inner energy, as we must always see that he is, in fact, affected by events, while the emotional hollowness of his verbal interactions with the other characters belies his concern. The continual bombardment of his stoicism by personal challenges seems almost humorously intentional on the part of the filmmakers, like tourists trying to make a member of the Royal Guard laugh. Stevens, who cracks a nervous smile now and again, never has a real laugh, and never pursues his love for Miss Kenton, until it is too late. Honor, duty, and dignity are the reasons given for his failure to launch, but it seems as though Stevens comes from a long line of married people, including his father, who also worked as a butler and still managed to have a family of his own. There is a fair share of upstairs-downstairs going on in the world of the film, most pronounced in an uncomfortable scene in which Stevens' ignorance of world affairs is used to prove a point against democracy, but it doesn't seem completely antagonistic; when Mr. Stevens, Sr. trips and falls, dropping a full tray of items, the "men of stature" he is waiting on come to his aid quickly and treat him humanely. The cause of Stevens' reluctance to accept love when it presents itself appears to be more personal than societal. Stevens, deserving of the benefit of the doubt, is more a workaholic than a sociopath, although there is a faint, remote comparison drawn between Stevens' blind obedience and that of the Nazi soldiers whom Stevens' master is accused of throwing in with. Whatever the reasona reason that seems to escape Stevens himselfthe unrequited love between Ms. Kenton and Mr. Stevens is a source of heartbreaking regret and sadness for this long-time admirer of the filma feeling that lingers after the final, symbolic scene in which Mr. Stevens, after having assisted Mr. Lewis in releasing a temporarily trapped bird, closes forever the window of opportunity on a chance at love, at unchaining his heart, at escaping Darlington Hall to pursue a life of his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this again recently on cable after many years and it is even better than I remembered. Like many Merchant Ivory movies there are many details that can't all be absorbed one viewing. It helps to know the premise of the plot in advance so the going back and forth in time is not confusing. The story is powerful and the story of appeasement in pre WWII Britain is both chilling and fascinating to watch. Makes one look at the butler's job in a different light - more like running a hotel. The Butler's role felt crucial to support the critical but misguided peace talks. The subplot with his father is touching. The screenplay captures both the grand sweep of the larger events and the intimate personal story. The filming, interiors, scenery and cinematography are all beautiful. It is Emma Thompson's best role. Every emotion is so transparent and clear on her face. Her frustration and sadness are moving and memorable. Anthony Hopkins is so convincing in the character that it's hard to imagine you are not watching a real butler. Hope he is remembered more for this role than "Silence of the Lambs". The scenes between them are loaded with emotion and unspoken feelings. Excellent supporting cast including the regal James Fox and a well cast Christopher Reeve. If not for the stiff competition that year including Schindler's List, Philadelphia, Age of Innocence, I think in any other year this would have swept the table. A truly wonderful result of the combination of a Japanese author, a German screenwriter, an American director and the top British actors. One of the best movies in the last 50 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Ismail Merchant was Indian by birth and James Ivory American, and although many of their film-scripts, including this one, were written by the German-born Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, the Merchant-Ivory partnership came to be seen as quintessentially British film-makers. They were responsible for some of the best-known British films of the eighties and nineties, mostly costume dramas based upon literary sources and dealing with the lives of the well-to-do classes. They did not invent the film genre which has become known as "heritage cinema"- that dates back at least to the late sixties- but are perhaps its best-known practitioners. "The Remains of the Day"- the significance of the title is rather obscure- is in many ways a typical example of their work, although the action takes place in the 1930s and 1950s rather than the late Victorian/Edwardian era with which they are normally associated. The main character is Mr. Stevens, the butler of Darlington Hall, an English stately home, during the 1930s. (Stevens' Christian name is James, but he is rarely referred to as such. By convention, senior servants in a household were referred to by their surnames alone). There are two strands to the plot, one political and the other personal. The political strand involves Stevens' employer Lord Darlington, an influential politician who frequently hosts gatherings of important international figures at this home. The personal strand involves Stevens' relations with Lord Darlington's housekeeper Miss Kenton, who falls in love with him although he fails to reciprocate her sentiments. (Or possibly he does, but fails to show it). The central political theme of the film is the politics of appeasement. Darlington initially appears to be in many ways an admirable character, kindly, honourable and idealistic. Although he served in the First World War he, unlike many veterans of that conflict, bears no hatred or animosity towards the Germans- indeed, he believes that Germany was harshly treated in 1919 by the vindictive Allies. His main fault is that he cannot understand those who are not honourable and idealistic, and this blinds him to the evils of Nazism; in the misguided belief that Hitler is a trustworthy man of honour he becomes an outspoken advocate of appeasement. As the film progresses, however, his own character deteriorates; he openly welcomes outright Nazi sympathisers as guests in his home, and even dismisses two Jewish chambermaids for fear of upsetting such persons. Stevens prides himself on being a model butler. He is calm, courteous and efficient, punctilious in the performance of his duties, unfailingly loyal to his employer. He regards any display of emotion as a weakness, and preserves an iron self-control at all times. Miss Kenton- we learn late on in the film that her name is Sarah, although she prefers to be called Sally- is equally efficient professionally, but is warmer and more openly emotional. The question the film raises is whether one should allow oneself to be defined entirely through one's work and through one's relationship with one's superiors. It is the same question as the great Austrian dramatist Franz Grillparzer was raising in his play "Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn". Like Grillparzer's hero Bancbanus, Stevens is a "faithful servant of his master"- the literal meaning of the German title- but one whose faithful service comes at a cost. In Stevens' case that cost is both personal, in that he sacrifices his chances of finding love, and moral, in that his loyalty leads him to close his eyes to his master's behaviour. When the two Jewish maids are dismissed, Miss Kenton is outraged, but Stevens refuses to utter a word of criticism of his employer, even in private. We are left wondering whether he is simply being diplomatic, or whether he actually does believe that the rich and powerful can do not wrong. When I recently reviewed "84, Charing Cross Road", I stated that while Anthony Hopkins is sometimes regarded in specialising in forceful, flamboyant or monstrous characters such as Hannibal Lecter or Captain Bligh in "The Bounty", he can be equally good as quieter, more restrained individuals, such as Dr Treves in "The Elephant Man", C S Lewis in "Shadowlands" or Frank Doel in "84, Charing Cross Road" itself. "The Remains of the Day" is perhaps Hopkins' finest performance in his vein. It is a superb piece of acting, quiet and unobtrusive, but all the more effective for being so. Emma Thompson is also good as Miss Kenton, as is James Fox as Lord Darlington. There are also good performances in smaller parts from the likes of Peter Vaughan as Stevens' elderly father, although I was less impressed by Christopher Reeve as American Congressman Jack Lewis. (Lewis' part appears to have been expanded beyond that he plays in the novel by Kazuo Ishiguro, doubtless in order to provide a role for a big Hollywood name). The film displays the typical Merchant-Ivory characteristics of high production values and a loving recreation of period detail. It is, to my mind, perhaps too leisurely and slow-moving, which is why I would not rate it as highly as some other Merchant-Ivory productions, such as "A Room with a View" or "Howards End", made the year before and also starring Hopkins and Thompson. It is, however, a well-acted and well-photographed movie, and often a thought-provoking one in its analysis of interwar history and its theme that loyalty often comes with a hidden cost. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching story and another great acting from Anthony Hopkins.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nail Yener
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't I watch this movie before? This is the question that I asked myself after I finished watching The Remains of the Day. I have seen most movies of Anthony Hopkins but I didn't even know this movie existed until yesterday when I was doing some research about 90s movies. It was always a great pleasure for me to see Anthony Hopkins in a movie no matter what his role was. And his performance in this movie once more gives me a reason to watch him again and again and again. But I didn't like this movie just because of him. I liked it because of many things such as its story, the performance of Emma Thompson and other actors/actresses and the atmosphere of the film as a whole. The story of The Remains of the Day focuses on nobility and suppressed feelings. I really felt like as if I was witnessing a real section from that time while watching the movie. At the end, when I go over the whole story in my head once more, although I wished that Mr. Stevens and Miss Kenton would reveal their true feelings to each other, I think I didn't feel sorry for them. Because this is the way Mr. Stevens is and this is the message of this movie in my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A subtle insight into flawed characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Srinivas G Phani
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are a few films that stand out due to their simplicity. Amour was one of those this year. The Remains of the Day falls into the same category. Helmed by James Ivory, known for his moving period pieces, the film stands a few notches above all his previous achievements. I am an ardent Merchant-Ivory fan and Howards End is one of the most exquisitely pictured films and deeply moving within its seemingly shallow screenplay and characters. Remains of the Day is no less an achievement in its exploration of a bunch of flawed characters whose acts are easy to criticize but understanding their inhibitions and regrets, very difficult. Much of the story takes place within a huge country-mansion called Darlington Hall, owned by the pro-Nazi gentleman, Lord Darlington. Mr Stevens is the head butler for the mansion and takes great pride in his excellence and capabilities. And then comes Miss Kenton, only to criticize him first, and then fall in love with him. Not as simple, Mr Stevens gives duties preference and what turns out is a tale of regret of choices and complications in the definition of duty. To sum up a long story short, The Remains of the Day is a fantastic film and is more pertinent to modern-day audience. With World War  II and rise of Nazism in backdrop, it beautifully explores the lives of people who are more indirectly affected by the changing political scenario. Deep within, it is essentially a story of unrequited love with not a single scene of romance! The film has so much to tell, so much happening that one cannot assimilate the film entirely at once. While the romantic angle takes preference in the final reels, the under-currents of success in career and regret over decisions is loud and clear. Agreed most artists associated with the film have limited range  James Ivory, Pierce-Roberts, Prawer Jhabvala, Emma Thompson and to an extent Anthony Hopkins. But what wonderfully they utilize their range, churning out gold within their repertoire. James Ivory's direction is outstanding at places and stays above 'very good' throughout. He builds up the tension so well during the conference is just an example of how good the direction is. Rightly noted in Wikipedia, the film touches a lot of themes and each of them translate smoothly onto the screen all thanks to Ivory and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins rise above the story and direction and give truly heart-felt performances. Their interactions are the best scenes of the film. Especially the one where she is crying within and he blabbers about their routine the next day and the one where she sobs on the floor. I will not reveal what he does in the latter scene for it would be a spoiler but Hopkins is so much in his character that his actions in that scene are easy to empathize although evil in the traditional sense. The scenes of their brief rendezvous after twenty years are truly unwatchable. The film is very depressing and ends without showing any hope of a better future for the characters. Tony Peirce-Roberts' cinematography is strictly functional and nothing compared to his work in Howards End. Every actor gives his very best in the film. Performances, direction and screenplay are of the highest order. The Remains of the Day captures the very essence of its title, thoroughly justifying it, etches out really flawed characters and brings them alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fine film personifies excellence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clehoullier
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We often refer to this film as a reference point when pondering the extreme disappointment with so many of today's movies (it is July 2013). So many movies are released with huge budgets, loads of buzz, and (apparently), stacked ratings on websites. Perhaps it is just a change in taste due to generational shifts..... Wonderful soundtrack, perfect casting, engaging plot, transcendent performances, and complexity - all are here. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins are so good that it is as if it is all real, not an act. There is so much emotion bubbling under the surface. The ending will leave you shaken for many days. We are thankful for films such as Remains of the Day, Out of Africa, Howard's End, Babbette's Feast - films that dig inside of us, films that make us part of their very fabric. All of the sifting through the trash that is mostly what is released today can be washed clean by going back to a beloved film such as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Acting Masterclass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrost71w
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By some happy coincidence, everybody in this film gives one of their best performances, especially the two leads. Anthony Hopkins is breathtaking; he plays a repressed butler who never overtly shows emotion. How on earth do you play such a character and not appear wooden? You have to be Anthony Hopkins, that's how. Somehow, with just a raise of the eyebrow or the down-turn of the mouth he manages to convey hate, love, humour, distaste, horror, regret and every other emotion under the sun in scene after scene. I have never seen anything like it. I knew exactly how he was feeling from just a tiny crinkling of the eyes. He had a thousand slightly different smiles each of which conveyed a different emotion that he was supposed to be feeling. Watch in awe all you wannabe actors for surely THIS is how it is done. And if anyone wants proof that the Oscars are meaningless, the fact that Remains of The Day won no Oscars is a bigger farce that LA Confidential being kept off the win sheet by bloody Titanic
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dense, literary and eloquent..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    American screenwriter, producer and director James Ivory's nineteenth feature film which was written by German author and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, is an adaptation of a novel from 1989 by Japanese author Kazuo Ishiguro. It was shot on locations in England and is a UK-USA co-production which was produced by Indian screenwriter, producer and director Ismail Merchant, American screenwriter, producer and director Mike Nichols and American producer John Calley. It tells the story about a butler named James Stevens who whilst executing his profession with the utmost dignity at a large mansion called Darlington Hall for the Lord of Darlington, hires a housekeeper named Sarah Kenton. Subtly and precisely directed by British filmmaker James Ivory, this quietly paced fictional tale which is narrated from the two main characters viewpoints, draws a heartrending portrayal of a middle-aged man who is courted by a compassionate woman whom he keeps at distance by remaining utterly professional whenever they interact. While notable for it's naturalistic, atmospheric and mostly interior milieu depictions, sterling production design by production designer Luciana Arrighi, cinematography by English cinematographer Tony-Pierce Roberts, costume design by costume designers Jenny Beaven and John Bright and make-up by make-up artist Christine Beveridge, this dialog-driven and narrative-driven story depicts a refined study of character and contains a good score by American composer Richard Robins. This somewhat political, oppressively romantic and conversational period drama which is set on a country estate in post-war England during the 1930s and 1940s where a woman tries to reach into the feelings of a man whom is completely dedicated to his work and where human emotions are disguised by manners, is impelled and reinforced by it's fragmented narrative structure, subtle character development and continuity and understated and memorable acting performances by Welsh actor Anthony Hopkins and English actress Emma Thompson. A dense, literary and eloquent love-story from the early 1990s which gained, among numerous other awards, the award for Best Actor Anthony Hopkins at the 65th NBR Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man shall never regret what he did, only what he didn't do ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Remains of the Day" is the kind of film where you first hope for something to happen then that nothing ever break the serene harmony inhabiting the story. Yet, to say that the film is plot-less would be as unfair as untrue: another successful product of the director and producer's duo: James Ivory and Ismail Merchant, the film offers another riveting slice of the British aristocratic life, this time during the inter-war, this time for a story even more enthralling because it is told from the servants' perspective, from the diary of William Stevens, the butler. As Stevens, Anthony Hopkins delivers such a solid performance, in all nuance and subtlety, that we can't doubt the man has been or could have been anything but a butler, obviously belonging to a tradition as old as the hills and whose William Stevens Sr. (Peter Vaughan) is another living remain. Stevens Jr. has been impregnated his whole life by this impeccable perfectionism, total dedication to the master, and the dilution of his own ego into work; and to a certain extent, the butler's tasks, no matter how prestigious and dignified they seem in the beginning, turn our to be ingrate as the story progresses. This unfortunate hardship is crucial though as an empathy-builder, we see Stevens with eyes of sorrow for he's incapable to demonstrate any hint of freethinking or independent personality. And the power of Hopkins is to portray a man trapped in the one-note performance requested for his job, in a poignantly three-dimensional way. In fact, the main thrills of "The Remains of the Day" consist of spotting the little hints betraying Mr Stevens' capability for feelings. One clue: they mostly happen during the scenes involving directly or indirectly Emma Thompson, the second lead of the film. As Mrs Kenton, Emma Thompson, the smart and pretty housekeeper is educated and trained enough to see in Mr Stevens, a worthy of admiration colleague, and she's equal to him enough, in the household hierarchy, to allow herself some familiarities. Obviously fascinated by this mountain of coldness, she brings some flowers to his private room and then, something interesting happens. While he almost dismisses the flowers as 'distractions', he politely asks Mrs Kenton to display more respect toward his father, by not calling him by his Christian name. The scene can mislead by foreshadowing several clashes between the two servants, when they are only benign misunderstandings. But it does show that that there is a heart beating behind this impeccable costume and demeanor. And when this heart is about to collapse while the father is dying, Stevens continues to serve the Master's guest: no matter what happens, work must go on. This is Stevens' inner conflict, whose paradox is to create a gap between him and Mrs Kenton but in the same time, allows their mutual respect and tacit attraction, to grow patiently and discreetly with the passing of time. But we know that the romance is doomed from the very beginning, the story doesn't leave much for optimism. We know, when the movie opens that Stevens still work in the same manor, that his Master Lord Darlington died, and an American Congressman, played by Christopher Reeve, bought the house. Mrs Kenton left Darlington before the outbreak of the war and got married. The flow of the film conveys an insightful parallel between the romance and the relationship with the Master. James Fox plays Lord Darlington, not a Nazi sympathizer, but an ambiguous well-mannered gentleman who 'understands' the Germans. During a memorable toast, the American Congressman, and future house owner, would call all the assembled European politicians 'amateurs', an allegation that only shocks his audience, but doesn't fool us, not even Darlington's godson (Hugh Grant). The 'amateur' speech, with the same resonance than Churchill's 'dishonour and war' line, foresees the last days of an agonizing order that exploited the guilt of WWI victory, to roll the red carpets to the Nazis. And the tragic choices of Darlington would spill over Stevens' life. Incapable of adopting one defying attitude against his own master, Stevens condemned himself to a standard of life sadly prone to unhappiness and frustration. And it's precisely the kind of life that Mrs Kenton rejected by leaving the house. And her personal tragedy is that she left the only man she truly loved. "The Remains of the Day" chronicles two separate stories, challenging the solemn and unflappably professionalism of Mr Stevens, and interlocking each other until leading Stevens to a dead-end. And twenty years later, Stevens maintains the same level of mystery. People ask him where he stood for regarding his Master's opinion. Invoking the call of duty, he served his Master the best he could. He deplored some uninspired choices, the most significant being the revocation of two Jewish maids. But still, Stevens embraced his master's choices without being an accomplice. A few years later, the seal of infamy marks the name of Darlington, but not Stevens', yet there's no doubt his heart carries some regrets, and maybe, his unfulfilled relationship with Mrs Kenton is a way to make up for his own guilt. To have followed Darlington or not following Mrs Kenton? Looking back on his life, Stevens would understand the value of regrets, whether it's for done or undone choices, maybe by persuading a divorced Mrs Kenton to go back to Darlington? As a character study, the film is a wonderful examination of lives made of unmade choices and 'what if' questions, as a romance, it happens to be admirably poignant and brilliant, because feelings are so intimate and real that they can hardly be expressed, let alone from a man of such a few words like Mr Stevens. And this is why the ending plays as the perfect emotional pay-off for a film so full of frustrating inhibitions, a light of hope after an eternity spent in the Master's shadow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hopkins' finest role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Remains Of The Day" is a script that clearly stood or fell with the casting of the Mr.Stevens character, and thank God they hit that one out of the park. Anthony Hopkins is perfect in this complex role, the writing isn't always that solid but Hopkins can just make any scene work here. Playing a character that's supposed to hide all his emotions is a challenge, but Hopkins still manages to give Stevens amazing depth. It's all in the little things I guess: occasionally Stevens will smile, but you never know if he's really happy or if he just does everything he does because it's expected from the butler. You can't look in the character's mind because he's so brilliantly underplayed. The best scene of "Remains Of The Day" comes near the end, when Stevens enters the room of a sobbing Emma Thompson. The climax to that scene (or lack thereof) is so fitting and so amazing. This is not my favorite movie ever because as I said, it isn't even that well-scripted or directed, but it's very compelling nonetheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Remains of the Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unrequited love finds multiple reasons to remain unrequited in The Remains of the Day, a film as beautifully written, acted, and shot (interiors and exteriors), as it is frustrating in its unrepressed examination of repression. Anthony Hopkins plays James Stevens, head butler of Darlington Hall, the residence of Lord Darlington (James Fox), an English aristocrat who hosts interwar dinners and conferences for world politicians, including the prime minister and foreign ambassadors. Darlington wishes to appease Nazi Germany, whom he feels was too harshly treated by the Treaty of Versailles. Christopher Reeve plays Jack Lewis, the American delegate, who invades the proceedings to call the attendees "amateurs." Hugh Grant, in one of his better roles, plays Darlington's godson, Reginald Cardinal, a "news hound" who eventually agrees with Lewis and detects the abuse of Darlington's "good, noble intentions" by the Germans, the intentions of whose leader are not fully comprehended by Darlington, who will later recognize his own gullibility. It is within this context of large-scale moral and political conflict and international affairs that super-butler Stevens toils to keep a good house. Not only does he try, with every fiber of his being, to remain detached from the world-shaking decisions being made around him (he seems more concerned with the return of a chair to its proper place), but he also maintains an ostensible detachment from his feelings (he shows more emotion over the breaking of a wine bottle than over the death of his father). Stevens extends this detachment to his feelings for the housekeeper, Miss Kenton (Emma Thompson), who, compared with Mr. Stevens, wears her emotions on her sleeve. Stevens justifies his detachment by the unwavering "dignity" required of a great butler, especially one in the service of a house carrying the importance of Darlington Hall. Emma Thompson's Oscar-nominated performance is earnest and superb. Her character, who is considered old by the underservants and young by Mr. Stevens, passes through a range of emotions and tactics: she offers matronly advice to a younger maidservant rushing into marriage, plays provocative detective in bringing to light the errors committed by Stevens' father, tenderly comforts Stevens when his father falls ill, chastises Stevens for his moral inertness in the face of his master's racist turn, criticizes herself for placing her needs above her convictions, and, in one of the most brilliant scenes of the film, encroaches upon Stevens' "private time" to pry into the subject matter of his reading material, while walking a fine line between playful mockery and seductive cajoling. The supporting cast, which includes Peter Vaughan in a wonderful performance as Stevens' father, William, is also superb. Richard Robbins' whimsical, enchanting, hypnotic music is like a good wine: somberly intoxicating. The centerpiece of the film is Anthony Hopkins' Oscar-nominated performance as Stevens, a role which requires tremendous inner energy, as we must always see that he is, in fact, affected by events, while the emotional hollowness of his verbal interactions with the other characters belies his concern. The continual bombardment of his stoicism by personal challenges seems almost humorously intentional on the part of the filmmakers, like tourists trying to make a member of the Royal Guard laugh. Stevens, who cracks a nervous smile now and again, never has a real laugh, and never pursues his love for Miss Kenton, until it is too late. Honor, duty, and dignity are the reasons given for his failure to launch, but it seems as though Stevens comes from a long line of married people, including his father, who also worked as a butler and still managed to have a family of his own. There is a fair share of upstairs-downstairs going on in the world of the film, most pronounced in an uncomfortable scene in which Stevens' ignorance of world affairs is used to prove a point against democracy, but it doesn't seem completely antagonistic; when Mr. Stevens, Sr. trips and falls, dropping a full tray of items, the "men of stature" he is waiting on come to his aid quickly and treat him humanely. The cause of Stevens' reluctance to accept love when it presents itself appears to be more personal than societal. Stevens, deserving of the benefit of the doubt, is more a workaholic than a sociopath, although there is a faint, remote comparison drawn between Stevens' blind obedience and that of the Nazi soldiers whom Stevens' master is accused of throwing in with. Whatever the reasona reason that seems to escape Stevens himselfthe unrequited love between Ms. Kenton and Mr. Stevens is a source of heartbreaking regret and sadness for this long-time admirer of the filma feeling that lingers after the final, symbolic scene in which Mr. Stevens, after having assisted Mr. Lewis in releasing a temporarily trapped bird, closes forever the window of opportunity on a chance at love, at unchaining his heart, at escaping Darlington Hall to pursue a life of his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this again recently on cable after many years and it is even better than I remembered. Like many Merchant Ivory movies there are many details that can't all be absorbed one viewing. It helps to know the premise of the plot in advance so the going back and forth in time is not confusing. The story is powerful and the story of appeasement in pre WWII Britain is both chilling and fascinating to watch. Makes one look at the butler's job in a different light - more like running a hotel. The Butler's role felt crucial to support the critical but misguided peace talks. The subplot with his father is touching. The screenplay captures both the grand sweep of the larger events and the intimate personal story. The filming, interiors, scenery and cinematography are all beautiful. It is Emma Thompson's best role. Every emotion is so transparent and clear on her face. Her frustration and sadness are moving and memorable. Anthony Hopkins is so convincing in the character that it's hard to imagine you are not watching a real butler. Hope he is remembered more for this role than "Silence of the Lambs". The scenes between them are loaded with emotion and unspoken feelings. Excellent supporting cast including the regal James Fox and a well cast Christopher Reeve. If not for the stiff competition that year including Schindler's List, Philadelphia, Age of Innocence, I think in any other year this would have swept the table. A truly wonderful result of the combination of a Japanese author, a German screenwriter, an American director and the top British actors. One of the best movies in the last 50 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Ismail Merchant was Indian by birth and James Ivory American, and although many of their film-scripts, including this one, were written by the German-born Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, the Merchant-Ivory partnership came to be seen as quintessentially British film-makers. They were responsible for some of the best-known British films of the eighties and nineties, mostly costume dramas based upon literary sources and dealing with the lives of the well-to-do classes. They did not invent the film genre which has become known as "heritage cinema"- that dates back at least to the late sixties- but are perhaps its best-known practitioners. "The Remains of the Day"- the significance of the title is rather obscure- is in many ways a typical example of their work, although the action takes place in the 1930s and 1950s rather than the late Victorian/Edwardian era with which they are normally associated. The main character is Mr. Stevens, the butler of Darlington Hall, an English stately home, during the 1930s. (Stevens' Christian name is James, but he is rarely referred to as such. By convention, senior servants in a household were referred to by their surnames alone). There are two strands to the plot, one political and the other personal. The political strand involves Stevens' employer Lord Darlington, an influential politician who frequently hosts gatherings of important international figures at this home. The personal strand involves Stevens' relations with Lord Darlington's housekeeper Miss Kenton, who falls in love with him although he fails to reciprocate her sentiments. (Or possibly he does, but fails to show it). The central political theme of the film is the politics of appeasement. Darlington initially appears to be in many ways an admirable character, kindly, honourable and idealistic. Although he served in the First World War he, unlike many veterans of that conflict, bears no hatred or animosity towards the Germans- indeed, he believes that Germany was harshly treated in 1919 by the vindictive Allies. His main fault is that he cannot understand those who are not honourable and idealistic, and this blinds him to the evils of Nazism; in the misguided belief that Hitler is a trustworthy man of honour he becomes an outspoken advocate of appeasement. As the film progresses, however, his own character deteriorates; he openly welcomes outright Nazi sympathisers as guests in his home, and even dismisses two Jewish chambermaids for fear of upsetting such persons. Stevens prides himself on being a model butler. He is calm, courteous and efficient, punctilious in the performance of his duties, unfailingly loyal to his employer. He regards any display of emotion as a weakness, and preserves an iron self-control at all times. Miss Kenton- we learn late on in the film that her name is Sarah, although she prefers to be called Sally- is equally efficient professionally, but is warmer and more openly emotional. The question the film raises is whether one should allow oneself to be defined entirely through one's work and through one's relationship with one's superiors. It is the same question as the great Austrian dramatist Franz Grillparzer was raising in his play "Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn". Like Grillparzer's hero Bancbanus, Stevens is a "faithful servant of his master"- the literal meaning of the German title- but one whose faithful service comes at a cost. In Stevens' case that cost is both personal, in that he sacrifices his chances of finding love, and moral, in that his loyalty leads him to close his eyes to his master's behaviour. When the two Jewish maids are dismissed, Miss Kenton is outraged, but Stevens refuses to utter a word of criticism of his employer, even in private. We are left wondering whether he is simply being diplomatic, or whether he actually does believe that the rich and powerful can do not wrong. When I recently reviewed "84, Charing Cross Road", I stated that while Anthony Hopkins is sometimes regarded in specialising in forceful, flamboyant or monstrous characters such as Hannibal Lecter or Captain Bligh in "The Bounty", he can be equally good as quieter, more restrained individuals, such as Dr Treves in "The Elephant Man", C S Lewis in "Shadowlands" or Frank Doel in "84, Charing Cross Road" itself. "The Remains of the Day" is perhaps Hopkins' finest performance in his vein. It is a superb piece of acting, quiet and unobtrusive, but all the more effective for being so. Emma Thompson is also good as Miss Kenton, as is James Fox as Lord Darlington. There are also good performances in smaller parts from the likes of Peter Vaughan as Stevens' elderly father, although I was less impressed by Christopher Reeve as American Congressman Jack Lewis. (Lewis' part appears to have been expanded beyond that he plays in the novel by Kazuo Ishiguro, doubtless in order to provide a role for a big Hollywood name). The film displays the typical Merchant-Ivory characteristics of high production values and a loving recreation of period detail. It is, to my mind, perhaps too leisurely and slow-moving, which is why I would not rate it as highly as some other Merchant-Ivory productions, such as "A Room with a View" or "Howards End", made the year before and also starring Hopkins and Thompson. It is, however, a well-acted and well-photographed movie, and often a thought-provoking one in its analysis of interwar history and its theme that loyalty often comes with a hidden cost. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching story and another great acting from Anthony Hopkins.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nail Yener
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't I watch this movie before? This is the question that I asked myself after I finished watching The Remains of the Day. I have seen most movies of Anthony Hopkins but I didn't even know this movie existed until yesterday when I was doing some research about 90s movies. It was always a great pleasure for me to see Anthony Hopkins in a movie no matter what his role was. And his performance in this movie once more gives me a reason to watch him again and again and again. But I didn't like this movie just because of him. I liked it because of many things such as its story, the performance of Emma Thompson and other actors/actresses and the atmosphere of the film as a whole. The story of The Remains of the Day focuses on nobility and suppressed feelings. I really felt like as if I was witnessing a real section from that time while watching the movie. At the end, when I go over the whole story in my head once more, although I wished that Mr. Stevens and Miss Kenton would reveal their true feelings to each other, I think I didn't feel sorry for them. Because this is the way Mr. Stevens is and this is the message of this movie in my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A subtle insight into flawed characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Srinivas G Phani
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are a few films that stand out due to their simplicity. Amour was one of those this year. The Remains of the Day falls into the same category. Helmed by James Ivory, known for his moving period pieces, the film stands a few notches above all his previous achievements. I am an ardent Merchant-Ivory fan and Howards End is one of the most exquisitely pictured films and deeply moving within its seemingly shallow screenplay and characters. Remains of the Day is no less an achievement in its exploration of a bunch of flawed characters whose acts are easy to criticize but understanding their inhibitions and regrets, very difficult. Much of the story takes place within a huge country-mansion called Darlington Hall, owned by the pro-Nazi gentleman, Lord Darlington. Mr Stevens is the head butler for the mansion and takes great pride in his excellence and capabilities. And then comes Miss Kenton, only to criticize him first, and then fall in love with him. Not as simple, Mr Stevens gives duties preference and what turns out is a tale of regret of choices and complications in the definition of duty. To sum up a long story short, The Remains of the Day is a fantastic film and is more pertinent to modern-day audience. With World War  II and rise of Nazism in backdrop, it beautifully explores the lives of people who are more indirectly affected by the changing political scenario. Deep within, it is essentially a story of unrequited love with not a single scene of romance! The film has so much to tell, so much happening that one cannot assimilate the film entirely at once. While the romantic angle takes preference in the final reels, the under-currents of success in career and regret over decisions is loud and clear. Agreed most artists associated with the film have limited range  James Ivory, Pierce-Roberts, Prawer Jhabvala, Emma Thompson and to an extent Anthony Hopkins. But what wonderfully they utilize their range, churning out gold within their repertoire. James Ivory's direction is outstanding at places and stays above 'very good' throughout. He builds up the tension so well during the conference is just an example of how good the direction is. Rightly noted in Wikipedia, the film touches a lot of themes and each of them translate smoothly onto the screen all thanks to Ivory and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins rise above the story and direction and give truly heart-felt performances. Their interactions are the best scenes of the film. Especially the one where she is crying within and he blabbers about their routine the next day and the one where she sobs on the floor. I will not reveal what he does in the latter scene for it would be a spoiler but Hopkins is so much in his character that his actions in that scene are easy to empathize although evil in the traditional sense. The scenes of their brief rendezvous after twenty years are truly unwatchable. The film is very depressing and ends without showing any hope of a better future for the characters. Tony Peirce-Roberts' cinematography is strictly functional and nothing compared to his work in Howards End. Every actor gives his very best in the film. Performances, direction and screenplay are of the highest order. The Remains of the Day captures the very essence of its title, thoroughly justifying it, etches out really flawed characters and brings them alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fine film personifies excellence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clehoullier
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We often refer to this film as a reference point when pondering the extreme disappointment with so many of today's movies (it is July 2013). So many movies are released with huge budgets, loads of buzz, and (apparently), stacked ratings on websites. Perhaps it is just a change in taste due to generational shifts..... Wonderful soundtrack, perfect casting, engaging plot, transcendent performances, and complexity - all are here. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins are so good that it is as if it is all real, not an act. There is so much emotion bubbling under the surface. The ending will leave you shaken for many days. We are thankful for films such as Remains of the Day, Out of Africa, Howard's End, Babbette's Feast - films that dig inside of us, films that make us part of their very fabric. All of the sifting through the trash that is mostly what is released today can be washed clean by going back to a beloved film such as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Acting Masterclass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrost71w
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By some happy coincidence, everybody in this film gives one of their best performances, especially the two leads. Anthony Hopkins is breathtaking; he plays a repressed butler who never overtly shows emotion. How on earth do you play such a character and not appear wooden? You have to be Anthony Hopkins, that's how. Somehow, with just a raise of the eyebrow or the down-turn of the mouth he manages to convey hate, love, humour, distaste, horror, regret and every other emotion under the sun in scene after scene. I have never seen anything like it. I knew exactly how he was feeling from just a tiny crinkling of the eyes. He had a thousand slightly different smiles each of which conveyed a different emotion that he was supposed to be feeling. Watch in awe all you wannabe actors for surely THIS is how it is done. And if anyone wants proof that the Oscars are meaningless, the fact that Remains of The Day won no Oscars is a bigger farce that LA Confidential being kept off the win sheet by bloody Titanic
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dense, literary and eloquent..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    American screenwriter, producer and director James Ivory's nineteenth feature film which was written by German author and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, is an adaptation of a novel from 1989 by Japanese author Kazuo Ishiguro. It was shot on locations in England and is a UK-USA co-production which was produced by Indian screenwriter, producer and director Ismail Merchant, American screenwriter, producer and director Mike Nichols and American producer John Calley. It tells the story about a butler named James Stevens who whilst executing his profession with the utmost dignity at a large mansion called Darlington Hall for the Lord of Darlington, hires a housekeeper named Sarah Kenton. Subtly and precisely directed by British filmmaker James Ivory, this quietly paced fictional tale which is narrated from the two main characters viewpoints, draws a heartrending portrayal of a middle-aged man who is courted by a compassionate woman whom he keeps at distance by remaining utterly professional whenever they interact. While notable for it's naturalistic, atmospheric and mostly interior milieu depictions, sterling production design by production designer Luciana Arrighi, cinematography by English cinematographer Tony-Pierce Roberts, costume design by costume designers Jenny Beaven and John Bright and make-up by make-up artist Christine Beveridge, this dialog-driven and narrative-driven story depicts a refined study of character and contains a good score by American composer Richard Robins. This somewhat political, oppressively romantic and conversational period drama which is set on a country estate in post-war England during the 1930s and 1940s where a woman tries to reach into the feelings of a man whom is completely dedicated to his work and where human emotions are disguised by manners, is impelled and reinforced by it's fragmented narrative structure, subtle character development and continuity and understated and memorable acting performances by Welsh actor Anthony Hopkins and English actress Emma Thompson. A dense, literary and eloquent love-story from the early 1990s which gained, among numerous other awards, the award for Best Actor Anthony Hopkins at the 65th NBR Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man shall never regret what he did, only what he didn't do ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Remains of the Day" is the kind of film where you first hope for something to happen then that nothing ever break the serene harmony inhabiting the story. Yet, to say that the film is plot-less would be as unfair as untrue: another successful product of the director and producer's duo: James Ivory and Ismail Merchant, the film offers another riveting slice of the British aristocratic life, this time during the inter-war, this time for a story even more enthralling because it is told from the servants' perspective, from the diary of William Stevens, the butler. As Stevens, Anthony Hopkins delivers such a solid performance, in all nuance and subtlety, that we can't doubt the man has been or could have been anything but a butler, obviously belonging to a tradition as old as the hills and whose William Stevens Sr. (Peter Vaughan) is another living remain. Stevens Jr. has been impregnated his whole life by this impeccable perfectionism, total dedication to the master, and the dilution of his own ego into work; and to a certain extent, the butler's tasks, no matter how prestigious and dignified they seem in the beginning, turn our to be ingrate as the story progresses. This unfortunate hardship is crucial though as an empathy-builder, we see Stevens with eyes of sorrow for he's incapable to demonstrate any hint of freethinking or independent personality. And the power of Hopkins is to portray a man trapped in the one-note performance requested for his job, in a poignantly three-dimensional way. In fact, the main thrills of "The Remains of the Day" consist of spotting the little hints betraying Mr Stevens' capability for feelings. One clue: they mostly happen during the scenes involving directly or indirectly Emma Thompson, the second lead of the film. As Mrs Kenton, Emma Thompson, the smart and pretty housekeeper is educated and trained enough to see in Mr Stevens, a worthy of admiration colleague, and she's equal to him enough, in the household hierarchy, to allow herself some familiarities. Obviously fascinated by this mountain of coldness, she brings some flowers to his private room and then, something interesting happens. While he almost dismisses the flowers as 'distractions', he politely asks Mrs Kenton to display more respect toward his father, by not calling him by his Christian name. The scene can mislead by foreshadowing several clashes between the two servants, when they are only benign misunderstandings. But it does show that that there is a heart beating behind this impeccable costume and demeanor. And when this heart is about to collapse while the father is dying, Stevens continues to serve the Master's guest: no matter what happens, work must go on. This is Stevens' inner conflict, whose paradox is to create a gap between him and Mrs Kenton but in the same time, allows their mutual respect and tacit attraction, to grow patiently and discreetly with the passing of time. But we know that the romance is doomed from the very beginning, the story doesn't leave much for optimism. We know, when the movie opens that Stevens still work in the same manor, that his Master Lord Darlington died, and an American Congressman, played by Christopher Reeve, bought the house. Mrs Kenton left Darlington before the outbreak of the war and got married. The flow of the film conveys an insightful parallel between the romance and the relationship with the Master. James Fox plays Lord Darlington, not a Nazi sympathizer, but an ambiguous well-mannered gentleman who 'understands' the Germans. During a memorable toast, the American Congressman, and future house owner, would call all the assembled European politicians 'amateurs', an allegation that only shocks his audience, but doesn't fool us, not even Darlington's godson (Hugh Grant). The 'amateur' speech, with the same resonance than Churchill's 'dishonour and war' line, foresees the last days of an agonizing order that exploited the guilt of WWI victory, to roll the red carpets to the Nazis. And the tragic choices of Darlington would spill over Stevens' life. Incapable of adopting one defying attitude against his own master, Stevens condemned himself to a standard of life sadly prone to unhappiness and frustration. And it's precisely the kind of life that Mrs Kenton rejected by leaving the house. And her personal tragedy is that she left the only man she truly loved. "The Remains of the Day" chronicles two separate stories, challenging the solemn and unflappably professionalism of Mr Stevens, and interlocking each other until leading Stevens to a dead-end. And twenty years later, Stevens maintains the same level of mystery. People ask him where he stood for regarding his Master's opinion. Invoking the call of duty, he served his Master the best he could. He deplored some uninspired choices, the most significant being the revocation of two Jewish maids. But still, Stevens embraced his master's choices without being an accomplice. A few years later, the seal of infamy marks the name of Darlington, but not Stevens', yet there's no doubt his heart carries some regrets, and maybe, his unfulfilled relationship with Mrs Kenton is a way to make up for his own guilt. To have followed Darlington or not following Mrs Kenton? Looking back on his life, Stevens would understand the value of regrets, whether it's for done or undone choices, maybe by persuading a divorced Mrs Kenton to go back to Darlington? As a character study, the film is a wonderful examination of lives made of unmade choices and 'what if' questions, as a romance, it happens to be admirably poignant and brilliant, because feelings are so intimate and real that they can hardly be expressed, let alone from a man of such a few words like Mr Stevens. And this is why the ending plays as the perfect emotional pay-off for a film so full of frustrating inhibitions, a light of hope after an eternity spent in the Master's shadow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hopkins' finest role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Remains Of The Day" is a script that clearly stood or fell with the casting of the Mr.Stevens character, and thank God they hit that one out of the park. Anthony Hopkins is perfect in this complex role, the writing isn't always that solid but Hopkins can just make any scene work here. Playing a character that's supposed to hide all his emotions is a challenge, but Hopkins still manages to give Stevens amazing depth. It's all in the little things I guess: occasionally Stevens will smile, but you never know if he's really happy or if he just does everything he does because it's expected from the butler. You can't look in the character's mind because he's so brilliantly underplayed. The best scene of "Remains Of The Day" comes near the end, when Stevens enters the room of a sobbing Emma Thompson. The climax to that scene (or lack thereof) is so fitting and so amazing. This is not my favorite movie ever because as I said, it isn't even that well-scripted or directed, but it's very compelling nonetheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Remains of the Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unrequited love finds multiple reasons to remain unrequited in The Remains of the Day, a film as beautifully written, acted, and shot (interiors and exteriors), as it is frustrating in its unrepressed examination of repression. Anthony Hopkins plays James Stevens, head butler of Darlington Hall, the residence of Lord Darlington (James Fox), an English aristocrat who hosts interwar dinners and conferences for world politicians, including the prime minister and foreign ambassadors. Darlington wishes to appease Nazi Germany, whom he feels was too harshly treated by the Treaty of Versailles. Christopher Reeve plays Jack Lewis, the American delegate, who invades the proceedings to call the attendees "amateurs." Hugh Grant, in one of his better roles, plays Darlington's godson, Reginald Cardinal, a "news hound" who eventually agrees with Lewis and detects the abuse of Darlington's "good, noble intentions" by the Germans, the intentions of whose leader are not fully comprehended by Darlington, who will later recognize his own gullibility. It is within this context of large-scale moral and political conflict and international affairs that super-butler Stevens toils to keep a good house. Not only does he try, with every fiber of his being, to remain detached from the world-shaking decisions being made around him (he seems more concerned with the return of a chair to its proper place), but he also maintains an ostensible detachment from his feelings (he shows more emotion over the breaking of a wine bottle than over the death of his father). Stevens extends this detachment to his feelings for the housekeeper, Miss Kenton (Emma Thompson), who, compared with Mr. Stevens, wears her emotions on her sleeve. Stevens justifies his detachment by the unwavering "dignity" required of a great butler, especially one in the service of a house carrying the importance of Darlington Hall. Emma Thompson's Oscar-nominated performance is earnest and superb. Her character, who is considered old by the underservants and young by Mr. Stevens, passes through a range of emotions and tactics: she offers matronly advice to a younger maidservant rushing into marriage, plays provocative detective in bringing to light the errors committed by Stevens' father, tenderly comforts Stevens when his father falls ill, chastises Stevens for his moral inertness in the face of his master's racist turn, criticizes herself for placing her needs above her convictions, and, in one of the most brilliant scenes of the film, encroaches upon Stevens' "private time" to pry into the subject matter of his reading material, while walking a fine line between playful mockery and seductive cajoling. The supporting cast, which includes Peter Vaughan in a wonderful performance as Stevens' father, William, is also superb. Richard Robbins' whimsical, enchanting, hypnotic music is like a good wine: somberly intoxicating. The centerpiece of the film is Anthony Hopkins' Oscar-nominated performance as Stevens, a role which requires tremendous inner energy, as we must always see that he is, in fact, affected by events, while the emotional hollowness of his verbal interactions with the other characters belies his concern. The continual bombardment of his stoicism by personal challenges seems almost humorously intentional on the part of the filmmakers, like tourists trying to make a member of the Royal Guard laugh. Stevens, who cracks a nervous smile now and again, never has a real laugh, and never pursues his love for Miss Kenton, until it is too late. Honor, duty, and dignity are the reasons given for his failure to launch, but it seems as though Stevens comes from a long line of married people, including his father, who also worked as a butler and still managed to have a family of his own. There is a fair share of upstairs-downstairs going on in the world of the film, most pronounced in an uncomfortable scene in which Stevens' ignorance of world affairs is used to prove a point against democracy, but it doesn't seem completely antagonistic; when Mr. Stevens, Sr. trips and falls, dropping a full tray of items, the "men of stature" he is waiting on come to his aid quickly and treat him humanely. The cause of Stevens' reluctance to accept love when it presents itself appears to be more personal than societal. Stevens, deserving of the benefit of the doubt, is more a workaholic than a sociopath, although there is a faint, remote comparison drawn between Stevens' blind obedience and that of the Nazi soldiers whom Stevens' master is accused of throwing in with. Whatever the reasona reason that seems to escape Stevens himselfthe unrequited love between Ms. Kenton and Mr. Stevens is a source of heartbreaking regret and sadness for this long-time admirer of the filma feeling that lingers after the final, symbolic scene in which Mr. Stevens, after having assisted Mr. Lewis in releasing a temporarily trapped bird, closes forever the window of opportunity on a chance at love, at unchaining his heart, at escaping Darlington Hall to pursue a life of his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this again recently on cable after many years and it is even better than I remembered. Like many Merchant Ivory movies there are many details that can't all be absorbed one viewing. It helps to know the premise of the plot in advance so the going back and forth in time is not confusing. The story is powerful and the story of appeasement in pre WWII Britain is both chilling and fascinating to watch. Makes one look at the butler's job in a different light - more like running a hotel. The Butler's role felt crucial to support the critical but misguided peace talks. The subplot with his father is touching. The screenplay captures both the grand sweep of the larger events and the intimate personal story. The filming, interiors, scenery and cinematography are all beautiful. It is Emma Thompson's best role. Every emotion is so transparent and clear on her face. Her frustration and sadness are moving and memorable. Anthony Hopkins is so convincing in the character that it's hard to imagine you are not watching a real butler. Hope he is remembered more for this role than "Silence of the Lambs". The scenes between them are loaded with emotion and unspoken feelings. Excellent supporting cast including the regal James Fox and a well cast Christopher Reeve. If not for the stiff competition that year including Schindler's List, Philadelphia, Age of Innocence, I think in any other year this would have swept the table. A truly wonderful result of the combination of a Japanese author, a German screenwriter, an American director and the top British actors. One of the best movies in the last 50 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Ismail Merchant was Indian by birth and James Ivory American, and although many of their film-scripts, including this one, were written by the German-born Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, the Merchant-Ivory partnership came to be seen as quintessentially British film-makers. They were responsible for some of the best-known British films of the eighties and nineties, mostly costume dramas based upon literary sources and dealing with the lives of the well-to-do classes. They did not invent the film genre which has become known as "heritage cinema"- that dates back at least to the late sixties- but are perhaps its best-known practitioners. "The Remains of the Day"- the significance of the title is rather obscure- is in many ways a typical example of their work, although the action takes place in the 1930s and 1950s rather than the late Victorian/Edwardian era with which they are normally associated. The main character is Mr. Stevens, the butler of Darlington Hall, an English stately home, during the 1930s. (Stevens' Christian name is James, but he is rarely referred to as such. By convention, senior servants in a household were referred to by their surnames alone). There are two strands to the plot, one political and the other personal. The political strand involves Stevens' employer Lord Darlington, an influential politician who frequently hosts gatherings of important international figures at this home. The personal strand involves Stevens' relations with Lord Darlington's housekeeper Miss Kenton, who falls in love with him although he fails to reciprocate her sentiments. (Or possibly he does, but fails to show it). The central political theme of the film is the politics of appeasement. Darlington initially appears to be in many ways an admirable character, kindly, honourable and idealistic. Although he served in the First World War he, unlike many veterans of that conflict, bears no hatred or animosity towards the Germans- indeed, he believes that Germany was harshly treated in 1919 by the vindictive Allies. His main fault is that he cannot understand those who are not honourable and idealistic, and this blinds him to the evils of Nazism; in the misguided belief that Hitler is a trustworthy man of honour he becomes an outspoken advocate of appeasement. As the film progresses, however, his own character deteriorates; he openly welcomes outright Nazi sympathisers as guests in his home, and even dismisses two Jewish chambermaids for fear of upsetting such persons. Stevens prides himself on being a model butler. He is calm, courteous and efficient, punctilious in the performance of his duties, unfailingly loyal to his employer. He regards any display of emotion as a weakness, and preserves an iron self-control at all times. Miss Kenton- we learn late on in the film that her name is Sarah, although she prefers to be called Sally- is equally efficient professionally, but is warmer and more openly emotional. The question the film raises is whether one should allow oneself to be defined entirely through one's work and through one's relationship with one's superiors. It is the same question as the great Austrian dramatist Franz Grillparzer was raising in his play "Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn". Like Grillparzer's hero Bancbanus, Stevens is a "faithful servant of his master"- the literal meaning of the German title- but one whose faithful service comes at a cost. In Stevens' case that cost is both personal, in that he sacrifices his chances of finding love, and moral, in that his loyalty leads him to close his eyes to his master's behaviour. When the two Jewish maids are dismissed, Miss Kenton is outraged, but Stevens refuses to utter a word of criticism of his employer, even in private. We are left wondering whether he is simply being diplomatic, or whether he actually does believe that the rich and powerful can do not wrong. When I recently reviewed "84, Charing Cross Road", I stated that while Anthony Hopkins is sometimes regarded in specialising in forceful, flamboyant or monstrous characters such as Hannibal Lecter or Captain Bligh in "The Bounty", he can be equally good as quieter, more restrained individuals, such as Dr Treves in "The Elephant Man", C S Lewis in "Shadowlands" or Frank Doel in "84, Charing Cross Road" itself. "The Remains of the Day" is perhaps Hopkins' finest performance in his vein. It is a superb piece of acting, quiet and unobtrusive, but all the more effective for being so. Emma Thompson is also good as Miss Kenton, as is James Fox as Lord Darlington. There are also good performances in smaller parts from the likes of Peter Vaughan as Stevens' elderly father, although I was less impressed by Christopher Reeve as American Congressman Jack Lewis. (Lewis' part appears to have been expanded beyond that he plays in the novel by Kazuo Ishiguro, doubtless in order to provide a role for a big Hollywood name). The film displays the typical Merchant-Ivory characteristics of high production values and a loving recreation of period detail. It is, to my mind, perhaps too leisurely and slow-moving, which is why I would not rate it as highly as some other Merchant-Ivory productions, such as "A Room with a View" or "Howards End", made the year before and also starring Hopkins and Thompson. It is, however, a well-acted and well-photographed movie, and often a thought-provoking one in its analysis of interwar history and its theme that loyalty often comes with a hidden cost. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching story and another great acting from Anthony Hopkins.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nail Yener
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't I watch this movie before? This is the question that I asked myself after I finished watching The Remains of the Day. I have seen most movies of Anthony Hopkins but I didn't even know this movie existed until yesterday when I was doing some research about 90s movies. It was always a great pleasure for me to see Anthony Hopkins in a movie no matter what his role was. And his performance in this movie once more gives me a reason to watch him again and again and again. But I didn't like this movie just because of him. I liked it because of many things such as its story, the performance of Emma Thompson and other actors/actresses and the atmosphere of the film as a whole. The story of The Remains of the Day focuses on nobility and suppressed feelings. I really felt like as if I was witnessing a real section from that time while watching the movie. At the end, when I go over the whole story in my head once more, although I wished that Mr. Stevens and Miss Kenton would reveal their true feelings to each other, I think I didn't feel sorry for them. Because this is the way Mr. Stevens is and this is the message of this movie in my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A subtle insight into flawed characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Srinivas G Phani
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are a few films that stand out due to their simplicity. Amour was one of those this year. The Remains of the Day falls into the same category. Helmed by James Ivory, known for his moving period pieces, the film stands a few notches above all his previous achievements. I am an ardent Merchant-Ivory fan and Howards End is one of the most exquisitely pictured films and deeply moving within its seemingly shallow screenplay and characters. Remains of the Day is no less an achievement in its exploration of a bunch of flawed characters whose acts are easy to criticize but understanding their inhibitions and regrets, very difficult. Much of the story takes place within a huge country-mansion called Darlington Hall, owned by the pro-Nazi gentleman, Lord Darlington. Mr Stevens is the head butler for the mansion and takes great pride in his excellence and capabilities. And then comes Miss Kenton, only to criticize him first, and then fall in love with him. Not as simple, Mr Stevens gives duties preference and what turns out is a tale of regret of choices and complications in the definition of duty. To sum up a long story short, The Remains of the Day is a fantastic film and is more pertinent to modern-day audience. With World War  II and rise of Nazism in backdrop, it beautifully explores the lives of people who are more indirectly affected by the changing political scenario. Deep within, it is essentially a story of unrequited love with not a single scene of romance! The film has so much to tell, so much happening that one cannot assimilate the film entirely at once. While the romantic angle takes preference in the final reels, the under-currents of success in career and regret over decisions is loud and clear. Agreed most artists associated with the film have limited range  James Ivory, Pierce-Roberts, Prawer Jhabvala, Emma Thompson and to an extent Anthony Hopkins. But what wonderfully they utilize their range, churning out gold within their repertoire. James Ivory's direction is outstanding at places and stays above 'very good' throughout. He builds up the tension so well during the conference is just an example of how good the direction is. Rightly noted in Wikipedia, the film touches a lot of themes and each of them translate smoothly onto the screen all thanks to Ivory and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins rise above the story and direction and give truly heart-felt performances. Their interactions are the best scenes of the film. Especially the one where she is crying within and he blabbers about their routine the next day and the one where she sobs on the floor. I will not reveal what he does in the latter scene for it would be a spoiler but Hopkins is so much in his character that his actions in that scene are easy to empathize although evil in the traditional sense. The scenes of their brief rendezvous after twenty years are truly unwatchable. The film is very depressing and ends without showing any hope of a better future for the characters. Tony Peirce-Roberts' cinematography is strictly functional and nothing compared to his work in Howards End. Every actor gives his very best in the film. Performances, direction and screenplay are of the highest order. The Remains of the Day captures the very essence of its title, thoroughly justifying it, etches out really flawed characters and brings them alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fine film personifies excellence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clehoullier
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We often refer to this film as a reference point when pondering the extreme disappointment with so many of today's movies (it is July 2013). So many movies are released with huge budgets, loads of buzz, and (apparently), stacked ratings on websites. Perhaps it is just a change in taste due to generational shifts..... Wonderful soundtrack, perfect casting, engaging plot, transcendent performances, and complexity - all are here. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins are so good that it is as if it is all real, not an act. There is so much emotion bubbling under the surface. The ending will leave you shaken for many days. We are thankful for films such as Remains of the Day, Out of Africa, Howard's End, Babbette's Feast - films that dig inside of us, films that make us part of their very fabric. All of the sifting through the trash that is mostly what is released today can be washed clean by going back to a beloved film such as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Acting Masterclass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrost71w
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By some happy coincidence, everybody in this film gives one of their best performances, especially the two leads. Anthony Hopkins is breathtaking; he plays a repressed butler who never overtly shows emotion. How on earth do you play such a character and not appear wooden? You have to be Anthony Hopkins, that's how. Somehow, with just a raise of the eyebrow or the down-turn of the mouth he manages to convey hate, love, humour, distaste, horror, regret and every other emotion under the sun in scene after scene. I have never seen anything like it. I knew exactly how he was feeling from just a tiny crinkling of the eyes. He had a thousand slightly different smiles each of which conveyed a different emotion that he was supposed to be feeling. Watch in awe all you wannabe actors for surely THIS is how it is done. And if anyone wants proof that the Oscars are meaningless, the fact that Remains of The Day won no Oscars is a bigger farce that LA Confidential being kept off the win sheet by bloody Titanic
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dense, literary and eloquent..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    American screenwriter, producer and director James Ivory's nineteenth feature film which was written by German author and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, is an adaptation of a novel from 1989 by Japanese author Kazuo Ishiguro. It was shot on locations in England and is a UK-USA co-production which was produced by Indian screenwriter, producer and director Ismail Merchant, American screenwriter, producer and director Mike Nichols and American producer John Calley. It tells the story about a butler named James Stevens who whilst executing his profession with the utmost dignity at a large mansion called Darlington Hall for the Lord of Darlington, hires a housekeeper named Sarah Kenton. Subtly and precisely directed by British filmmaker James Ivory, this quietly paced fictional tale which is narrated from the two main characters viewpoints, draws a heartrending portrayal of a middle-aged man who is courted by a compassionate woman whom he keeps at distance by remaining utterly professional whenever they interact. While notable for it's naturalistic, atmospheric and mostly interior milieu depictions, sterling production design by production designer Luciana Arrighi, cinematography by English cinematographer Tony-Pierce Roberts, costume design by costume designers Jenny Beaven and John Bright and make-up by make-up artist Christine Beveridge, this dialog-driven and narrative-driven story depicts a refined study of character and contains a good score by American composer Richard Robins. This somewhat political, oppressively romantic and conversational period drama which is set on a country estate in post-war England during the 1930s and 1940s where a woman tries to reach into the feelings of a man whom is completely dedicated to his work and where human emotions are disguised by manners, is impelled and reinforced by it's fragmented narrative structure, subtle character development and continuity and understated and memorable acting performances by Welsh actor Anthony Hopkins and English actress Emma Thompson. A dense, literary and eloquent love-story from the early 1990s which gained, among numerous other awards, the award for Best Actor Anthony Hopkins at the 65th NBR Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man shall never regret what he did, only what he didn't do ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Remains of the Day" is the kind of film where you first hope for something to happen then that nothing ever break the serene harmony inhabiting the story. Yet, to say that the film is plot-less would be as unfair as untrue: another successful product of the director and producer's duo: James Ivory and Ismail Merchant, the film offers another riveting slice of the British aristocratic life, this time during the inter-war, this time for a story even more enthralling because it is told from the servants' perspective, from the diary of William Stevens, the butler. As Stevens, Anthony Hopkins delivers such a solid performance, in all nuance and subtlety, that we can't doubt the man has been or could have been anything but a butler, obviously belonging to a tradition as old as the hills and whose William Stevens Sr. (Peter Vaughan) is another living remain. Stevens Jr. has been impregnated his whole life by this impeccable perfectionism, total dedication to the master, and the dilution of his own ego into work; and to a certain extent, the butler's tasks, no matter how prestigious and dignified they seem in the beginning, turn our to be ingrate as the story progresses. This unfortunate hardship is crucial though as an empathy-builder, we see Stevens with eyes of sorrow for he's incapable to demonstrate any hint of freethinking or independent personality. And the power of Hopkins is to portray a man trapped in the one-note performance requested for his job, in a poignantly three-dimensional way. In fact, the main thrills of "The Remains of the Day" consist of spotting the little hints betraying Mr Stevens' capability for feelings. One clue: they mostly happen during the scenes involving directly or indirectly Emma Thompson, the second lead of the film. As Mrs Kenton, Emma Thompson, the smart and pretty housekeeper is educated and trained enough to see in Mr Stevens, a worthy of admiration colleague, and she's equal to him enough, in the household hierarchy, to allow herself some familiarities. Obviously fascinated by this mountain of coldness, she brings some flowers to his private room and then, something interesting happens. While he almost dismisses the flowers as 'distractions', he politely asks Mrs Kenton to display more respect toward his father, by not calling him by his Christian name. The scene can mislead by foreshadowing several clashes between the two servants, when they are only benign misunderstandings. But it does show that that there is a heart beating behind this impeccable costume and demeanor. And when this heart is about to collapse while the father is dying, Stevens continues to serve the Master's guest: no matter what happens, work must go on. This is Stevens' inner conflict, whose paradox is to create a gap between him and Mrs Kenton but in the same time, allows their mutual respect and tacit attraction, to grow patiently and discreetly with the passing of time. But we know that the romance is doomed from the very beginning, the story doesn't leave much for optimism. We know, when the movie opens that Stevens still work in the same manor, that his Master Lord Darlington died, and an American Congressman, played by Christopher Reeve, bought the house. Mrs Kenton left Darlington before the outbreak of the war and got married. The flow of the film conveys an insightful parallel between the romance and the relationship with the Master. James Fox plays Lord Darlington, not a Nazi sympathizer, but an ambiguous well-mannered gentleman who 'understands' the Germans. During a memorable toast, the American Congressman, and future house owner, would call all the assembled European politicians 'amateurs', an allegation that only shocks his audience, but doesn't fool us, not even Darlington's godson (Hugh Grant). The 'amateur' speech, with the same resonance than Churchill's 'dishonour and war' line, foresees the last days of an agonizing order that exploited the guilt of WWI victory, to roll the red carpets to the Nazis. And the tragic choices of Darlington would spill over Stevens' life. Incapable of adopting one defying attitude against his own master, Stevens condemned himself to a standard of life sadly prone to unhappiness and frustration. And it's precisely the kind of life that Mrs Kenton rejected by leaving the house. And her personal tragedy is that she left the only man she truly loved. "The Remains of the Day" chronicles two separate stories, challenging the solemn and unflappably professionalism of Mr Stevens, and interlocking each other until leading Stevens to a dead-end. And twenty years later, Stevens maintains the same level of mystery. People ask him where he stood for regarding his Master's opinion. Invoking the call of duty, he served his Master the best he could. He deplored some uninspired choices, the most significant being the revocation of two Jewish maids. But still, Stevens embraced his master's choices without being an accomplice. A few years later, the seal of infamy marks the name of Darlington, but not Stevens', yet there's no doubt his heart carries some regrets, and maybe, his unfulfilled relationship with Mrs Kenton is a way to make up for his own guilt. To have followed Darlington or not following Mrs Kenton? Looking back on his life, Stevens would understand the value of regrets, whether it's for done or undone choices, maybe by persuading a divorced Mrs Kenton to go back to Darlington? As a character study, the film is a wonderful examination of lives made of unmade choices and 'what if' questions, as a romance, it happens to be admirably poignant and brilliant, because feelings are so intimate and real that they can hardly be expressed, let alone from a man of such a few words like Mr Stevens. And this is why the ending plays as the perfect emotional pay-off for a film so full of frustrating inhibitions, a light of hope after an eternity spent in the Master's shadow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hopkins' finest role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Remains Of The Day" is a script that clearly stood or fell with the casting of the Mr.Stevens character, and thank God they hit that one out of the park. Anthony Hopkins is perfect in this complex role, the writing isn't always that solid but Hopkins can just make any scene work here. Playing a character that's supposed to hide all his emotions is a challenge, but Hopkins still manages to give Stevens amazing depth. It's all in the little things I guess: occasionally Stevens will smile, but you never know if he's really happy or if he just does everything he does because it's expected from the butler. You can't look in the character's mind because he's so brilliantly underplayed. The best scene of "Remains Of The Day" comes near the end, when Stevens enters the room of a sobbing Emma Thompson. The climax to that scene (or lack thereof) is so fitting and so amazing. This is not my favorite movie ever because as I said, it isn't even that well-scripted or directed, but it's very compelling nonetheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Remains of the Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unrequited love finds multiple reasons to remain unrequited in The Remains of the Day, a film as beautifully written, acted, and shot (interiors and exteriors), as it is frustrating in its unrepressed examination of repression. Anthony Hopkins plays James Stevens, head butler of Darlington Hall, the residence of Lord Darlington (James Fox), an English aristocrat who hosts interwar dinners and conferences for world politicians, including the prime minister and foreign ambassadors. Darlington wishes to appease Nazi Germany, whom he feels was too harshly treated by the Treaty of Versailles. Christopher Reeve plays Jack Lewis, the American delegate, who invades the proceedings to call the attendees "amateurs." Hugh Grant, in one of his better roles, plays Darlington's godson, Reginald Cardinal, a "news hound" who eventually agrees with Lewis and detects the abuse of Darlington's "good, noble intentions" by the Germans, the intentions of whose leader are not fully comprehended by Darlington, who will later recognize his own gullibility. It is within this context of large-scale moral and political conflict and international affairs that super-butler Stevens toils to keep a good house. Not only does he try, with every fiber of his being, to remain detached from the world-shaking decisions being made around him (he seems more concerned with the return of a chair to its proper place), but he also maintains an ostensible detachment from his feelings (he shows more emotion over the breaking of a wine bottle than over the death of his father). Stevens extends this detachment to his feelings for the housekeeper, Miss Kenton (Emma Thompson), who, compared with Mr. Stevens, wears her emotions on her sleeve. Stevens justifies his detachment by the unwavering "dignity" required of a great butler, especially one in the service of a house carrying the importance of Darlington Hall. Emma Thompson's Oscar-nominated performance is earnest and superb. Her character, who is considered old by the underservants and young by Mr. Stevens, passes through a range of emotions and tactics: she offers matronly advice to a younger maidservant rushing into marriage, plays provocative detective in bringing to light the errors committed by Stevens' father, tenderly comforts Stevens when his father falls ill, chastises Stevens for his moral inertness in the face of his master's racist turn, criticizes herself for placing her needs above her convictions, and, in one of the most brilliant scenes of the film, encroaches upon Stevens' "private time" to pry into the subject matter of his reading material, while walking a fine line between playful mockery and seductive cajoling. The supporting cast, which includes Peter Vaughan in a wonderful performance as Stevens' father, William, is also superb. Richard Robbins' whimsical, enchanting, hypnotic music is like a good wine: somberly intoxicating. The centerpiece of the film is Anthony Hopkins' Oscar-nominated performance as Stevens, a role which requires tremendous inner energy, as we must always see that he is, in fact, affected by events, while the emotional hollowness of his verbal interactions with the other characters belies his concern. The continual bombardment of his stoicism by personal challenges seems almost humorously intentional on the part of the filmmakers, like tourists trying to make a member of the Royal Guard laugh. Stevens, who cracks a nervous smile now and again, never has a real laugh, and never pursues his love for Miss Kenton, until it is too late. Honor, duty, and dignity are the reasons given for his failure to launch, but it seems as though Stevens comes from a long line of married people, including his father, who also worked as a butler and still managed to have a family of his own. There is a fair share of upstairs-downstairs going on in the world of the film, most pronounced in an uncomfortable scene in which Stevens' ignorance of world affairs is used to prove a point against democracy, but it doesn't seem completely antagonistic; when Mr. Stevens, Sr. trips and falls, dropping a full tray of items, the "men of stature" he is waiting on come to his aid quickly and treat him humanely. The cause of Stevens' reluctance to accept love when it presents itself appears to be more personal than societal. Stevens, deserving of the benefit of the doubt, is more a workaholic than a sociopath, although there is a faint, remote comparison drawn between Stevens' blind obedience and that of the Nazi soldiers whom Stevens' master is accused of throwing in with. Whatever the reasona reason that seems to escape Stevens himselfthe unrequited love between Ms. Kenton and Mr. Stevens is a source of heartbreaking regret and sadness for this long-time admirer of the filma feeling that lingers after the final, symbolic scene in which Mr. Stevens, after having assisted Mr. Lewis in releasing a temporarily trapped bird, closes forever the window of opportunity on a chance at love, at unchaining his heart, at escaping Darlington Hall to pursue a life of his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this again recently on cable after many years and it is even better than I remembered. Like many Merchant Ivory movies there are many details that can't all be absorbed one viewing. It helps to know the premise of the plot in advance so the going back and forth in time is not confusing. The story is powerful and the story of appeasement in pre WWII Britain is both chilling and fascinating to watch. Makes one look at the butler's job in a different light - more like running a hotel. The Butler's role felt crucial to support the critical but misguided peace talks. The subplot with his father is touching. The screenplay captures both the grand sweep of the larger events and the intimate personal story. The filming, interiors, scenery and cinematography are all beautiful. It is Emma Thompson's best role. Every emotion is so transparent and clear on her face. Her frustration and sadness are moving and memorable. Anthony Hopkins is so convincing in the character that it's hard to imagine you are not watching a real butler. Hope he is remembered more for this role than "Silence of the Lambs". The scenes between them are loaded with emotion and unspoken feelings. Excellent supporting cast including the regal James Fox and a well cast Christopher Reeve. If not for the stiff competition that year including Schindler's List, Philadelphia, Age of Innocence, I think in any other year this would have swept the table. A truly wonderful result of the combination of a Japanese author, a German screenwriter, an American director and the top British actors. One of the best movies in the last 50 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Ismail Merchant was Indian by birth and James Ivory American, and although many of their film-scripts, including this one, were written by the German-born Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, the Merchant-Ivory partnership came to be seen as quintessentially British film-makers. They were responsible for some of the best-known British films of the eighties and nineties, mostly costume dramas based upon literary sources and dealing with the lives of the well-to-do classes. They did not invent the film genre which has become known as "heritage cinema"- that dates back at least to the late sixties- but are perhaps its best-known practitioners. "The Remains of the Day"- the significance of the title is rather obscure- is in many ways a typical example of their work, although the action takes place in the 1930s and 1950s rather than the late Victorian/Edwardian era with which they are normally associated. The main character is Mr. Stevens, the butler of Darlington Hall, an English stately home, during the 1930s. (Stevens' Christian name is James, but he is rarely referred to as such. By convention, senior servants in a household were referred to by their surnames alone). There are two strands to the plot, one political and the other personal. The political strand involves Stevens' employer Lord Darlington, an influential politician who frequently hosts gatherings of important international figures at this home. The personal strand involves Stevens' relations with Lord Darlington's housekeeper Miss Kenton, who falls in love with him although he fails to reciprocate her sentiments. (Or possibly he does, but fails to show it). The central political theme of the film is the politics of appeasement. Darlington initially appears to be in many ways an admirable character, kindly, honourable and idealistic. Although he served in the First World War he, unlike many veterans of that conflict, bears no hatred or animosity towards the Germans- indeed, he believes that Germany was harshly treated in 1919 by the vindictive Allies. His main fault is that he cannot understand those who are not honourable and idealistic, and this blinds him to the evils of Nazism; in the misguided belief that Hitler is a trustworthy man of honour he becomes an outspoken advocate of appeasement. As the film progresses, however, his own character deteriorates; he openly welcomes outright Nazi sympathisers as guests in his home, and even dismisses two Jewish chambermaids for fear of upsetting such persons. Stevens prides himself on being a model butler. He is calm, courteous and efficient, punctilious in the performance of his duties, unfailingly loyal to his employer. He regards any display of emotion as a weakness, and preserves an iron self-control at all times. Miss Kenton- we learn late on in the film that her name is Sarah, although she prefers to be called Sally- is equally efficient professionally, but is warmer and more openly emotional. The question the film raises is whether one should allow oneself to be defined entirely through one's work and through one's relationship with one's superiors. It is the same question as the great Austrian dramatist Franz Grillparzer was raising in his play "Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn". Like Grillparzer's hero Bancbanus, Stevens is a "faithful servant of his master"- the literal meaning of the German title- but one whose faithful service comes at a cost. In Stevens' case that cost is both personal, in that he sacrifices his chances of finding love, and moral, in that his loyalty leads him to close his eyes to his master's behaviour. When the two Jewish maids are dismissed, Miss Kenton is outraged, but Stevens refuses to utter a word of criticism of his employer, even in private. We are left wondering whether he is simply being diplomatic, or whether he actually does believe that the rich and powerful can do not wrong. When I recently reviewed "84, Charing Cross Road", I stated that while Anthony Hopkins is sometimes regarded in specialising in forceful, flamboyant or monstrous characters such as Hannibal Lecter or Captain Bligh in "The Bounty", he can be equally good as quieter, more restrained individuals, such as Dr Treves in "The Elephant Man", C S Lewis in "Shadowlands" or Frank Doel in "84, Charing Cross Road" itself. "The Remains of the Day" is perhaps Hopkins' finest performance in his vein. It is a superb piece of acting, quiet and unobtrusive, but all the more effective for being so. Emma Thompson is also good as Miss Kenton, as is James Fox as Lord Darlington. There are also good performances in smaller parts from the likes of Peter Vaughan as Stevens' elderly father, although I was less impressed by Christopher Reeve as American Congressman Jack Lewis. (Lewis' part appears to have been expanded beyond that he plays in the novel by Kazuo Ishiguro, doubtless in order to provide a role for a big Hollywood name). The film displays the typical Merchant-Ivory characteristics of high production values and a loving recreation of period detail. It is, to my mind, perhaps too leisurely and slow-moving, which is why I would not rate it as highly as some other Merchant-Ivory productions, such as "A Room with a View" or "Howards End", made the year before and also starring Hopkins and Thompson. It is, however, a well-acted and well-photographed movie, and often a thought-provoking one in its analysis of interwar history and its theme that loyalty often comes with a hidden cost. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching story and another great acting from Anthony Hopkins.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nail Yener
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't I watch this movie before? This is the question that I asked myself after I finished watching The Remains of the Day. I have seen most movies of Anthony Hopkins but I didn't even know this movie existed until yesterday when I was doing some research about 90s movies. It was always a great pleasure for me to see Anthony Hopkins in a movie no matter what his role was. And his performance in this movie once more gives me a reason to watch him again and again and again. But I didn't like this movie just because of him. I liked it because of many things such as its story, the performance of Emma Thompson and other actors/actresses and the atmosphere of the film as a whole. The story of The Remains of the Day focuses on nobility and suppressed feelings. I really felt like as if I was witnessing a real section from that time while watching the movie. At the end, when I go over the whole story in my head once more, although I wished that Mr. Stevens and Miss Kenton would reveal their true feelings to each other, I think I didn't feel sorry for them. Because this is the way Mr. Stevens is and this is the message of this movie in my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A subtle insight into flawed characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Srinivas G Phani
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are a few films that stand out due to their simplicity. Amour was one of those this year. The Remains of the Day falls into the same category. Helmed by James Ivory, known for his moving period pieces, the film stands a few notches above all his previous achievements. I am an ardent Merchant-Ivory fan and Howards End is one of the most exquisitely pictured films and deeply moving within its seemingly shallow screenplay and characters. Remains of the Day is no less an achievement in its exploration of a bunch of flawed characters whose acts are easy to criticize but understanding their inhibitions and regrets, very difficult. Much of the story takes place within a huge country-mansion called Darlington Hall, owned by the pro-Nazi gentleman, Lord Darlington. Mr Stevens is the head butler for the mansion and takes great pride in his excellence and capabilities. And then comes Miss Kenton, only to criticize him first, and then fall in love with him. Not as simple, Mr Stevens gives duties preference and what turns out is a tale of regret of choices and complications in the definition of duty. To sum up a long story short, The Remains of the Day is a fantastic film and is more pertinent to modern-day audience. With World War  II and rise of Nazism in backdrop, it beautifully explores the lives of people who are more indirectly affected by the changing political scenario. Deep within, it is essentially a story of unrequited love with not a single scene of romance! The film has so much to tell, so much happening that one cannot assimilate the film entirely at once. While the romantic angle takes preference in the final reels, the under-currents of success in career and regret over decisions is loud and clear. Agreed most artists associated with the film have limited range  James Ivory, Pierce-Roberts, Prawer Jhabvala, Emma Thompson and to an extent Anthony Hopkins. But what wonderfully they utilize their range, churning out gold within their repertoire. James Ivory's direction is outstanding at places and stays above 'very good' throughout. He builds up the tension so well during the conference is just an example of how good the direction is. Rightly noted in Wikipedia, the film touches a lot of themes and each of them translate smoothly onto the screen all thanks to Ivory and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins rise above the story and direction and give truly heart-felt performances. Their interactions are the best scenes of the film. Especially the one where she is crying within and he blabbers about their routine the next day and the one where she sobs on the floor. I will not reveal what he does in the latter scene for it would be a spoiler but Hopkins is so much in his character that his actions in that scene are easy to empathize although evil in the traditional sense. The scenes of their brief rendezvous after twenty years are truly unwatchable. The film is very depressing and ends without showing any hope of a better future for the characters. Tony Peirce-Roberts' cinematography is strictly functional and nothing compared to his work in Howards End. Every actor gives his very best in the film. Performances, direction and screenplay are of the highest order. The Remains of the Day captures the very essence of its title, thoroughly justifying it, etches out really flawed characters and brings them alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This fine film personifies excellence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    clehoullier
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We often refer to this film as a reference point when pondering the extreme disappointment with so many of today's movies (it is July 2013). So many movies are released with huge budgets, loads of buzz, and (apparently), stacked ratings on websites. Perhaps it is just a change in taste due to generational shifts..... Wonderful soundtrack, perfect casting, engaging plot, transcendent performances, and complexity - all are here. Emma Thompson and Anthony Hopkins are so good that it is as if it is all real, not an act. There is so much emotion bubbling under the surface. The ending will leave you shaken for many days. We are thankful for films such as Remains of the Day, Out of Africa, Howard's End, Babbette's Feast - films that dig inside of us, films that make us part of their very fabric. All of the sifting through the trash that is mostly what is released today can be washed clean by going back to a beloved film such as this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Acting Masterclass
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrost71w
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By some happy coincidence, everybody in this film gives one of their best performances, especially the two leads. Anthony Hopkins is breathtaking; he plays a repressed butler who never overtly shows emotion. How on earth do you play such a character and not appear wooden? You have to be Anthony Hopkins, that's how. Somehow, with just a raise of the eyebrow or the down-turn of the mouth he manages to convey hate, love, humour, distaste, horror, regret and every other emotion under the sun in scene after scene. I have never seen anything like it. I knew exactly how he was feeling from just a tiny crinkling of the eyes. He had a thousand slightly different smiles each of which conveyed a different emotion that he was supposed to be feeling. Watch in awe all you wannabe actors for surely THIS is how it is done. And if anyone wants proof that the Oscars are meaningless, the fact that Remains of The Day won no Oscars is a bigger farce that LA Confidential being kept off the win sheet by bloody Titanic
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Dense, literary and eloquent..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    American screenwriter, producer and director James Ivory's nineteenth feature film which was written by German author and screenwriter Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, is an adaptation of a novel from 1989 by Japanese author Kazuo Ishiguro. It was shot on locations in England and is a UK-USA co-production which was produced by Indian screenwriter, producer and director Ismail Merchant, American screenwriter, producer and director Mike Nichols and American producer John Calley. It tells the story about a butler named James Stevens who whilst executing his profession with the utmost dignity at a large mansion called Darlington Hall for the Lord of Darlington, hires a housekeeper named Sarah Kenton. Subtly and precisely directed by British filmmaker James Ivory, this quietly paced fictional tale which is narrated from the two main characters viewpoints, draws a heartrending portrayal of a middle-aged man who is courted by a compassionate woman whom he keeps at distance by remaining utterly professional whenever they interact. While notable for it's naturalistic, atmospheric and mostly interior milieu depictions, sterling production design by production designer Luciana Arrighi, cinematography by English cinematographer Tony-Pierce Roberts, costume design by costume designers Jenny Beaven and John Bright and make-up by make-up artist Christine Beveridge, this dialog-driven and narrative-driven story depicts a refined study of character and contains a good score by American composer Richard Robins. This somewhat political, oppressively romantic and conversational period drama which is set on a country estate in post-war England during the 1930s and 1940s where a woman tries to reach into the feelings of a man whom is completely dedicated to his work and where human emotions are disguised by manners, is impelled and reinforced by it's fragmented narrative structure, subtle character development and continuity and understated and memorable acting performances by Welsh actor Anthony Hopkins and English actress Emma Thompson. A dense, literary and eloquent love-story from the early 1990s which gained, among numerous other awards, the award for Best Actor Anthony Hopkins at the 65th NBR Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A man shall never regret what he did, only what he didn't do ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Remains of the Day" is the kind of film where you first hope for something to happen then that nothing ever break the serene harmony inhabiting the story. Yet, to say that the film is plot-less would be as unfair as untrue: another successful product of the director and producer's duo: James Ivory and Ismail Merchant, the film offers another riveting slice of the British aristocratic life, this time during the inter-war, this time for a story even more enthralling because it is told from the servants' perspective, from the diary of William Stevens, the butler. As Stevens, Anthony Hopkins delivers such a solid performance, in all nuance and subtlety, that we can't doubt the man has been or could have been anything but a butler, obviously belonging to a tradition as old as the hills and whose William Stevens Sr. (Peter Vaughan) is another living remain. Stevens Jr. has been impregnated his whole life by this impeccable perfectionism, total dedication to the master, and the dilution of his own ego into work; and to a certain extent, the butler's tasks, no matter how prestigious and dignified they seem in the beginning, turn our to be ingrate as the story progresses. This unfortunate hardship is crucial though as an empathy-builder, we see Stevens with eyes of sorrow for he's incapable to demonstrate any hint of freethinking or independent personality. And the power of Hopkins is to portray a man trapped in the one-note performance requested for his job, in a poignantly three-dimensional way. In fact, the main thrills of "The Remains of the Day" consist of spotting the little hints betraying Mr Stevens' capability for feelings. One clue: they mostly happen during the scenes involving directly or indirectly Emma Thompson, the second lead of the film. As Mrs Kenton, Emma Thompson, the smart and pretty housekeeper is educated and trained enough to see in Mr Stevens, a worthy of admiration colleague, and she's equal to him enough, in the household hierarchy, to allow herself some familiarities. Obviously fascinated by this mountain of coldness, she brings some flowers to his private room and then, something interesting happens. While he almost dismisses the flowers as 'distractions', he politely asks Mrs Kenton to display more respect toward his father, by not calling him by his Christian name. The scene can mislead by foreshadowing several clashes between the two servants, when they are only benign misunderstandings. But it does show that that there is a heart beating behind this impeccable costume and demeanor. And when this heart is about to collapse while the father is dying, Stevens continues to serve the Master's guest: no matter what happens, work must go on. This is Stevens' inner conflict, whose paradox is to create a gap between him and Mrs Kenton but in the same time, allows their mutual respect and tacit attraction, to grow patiently and discreetly with the passing of time. But we know that the romance is doomed from the very beginning, the story doesn't leave much for optimism. We know, when the movie opens that Stevens still work in the same manor, that his Master Lord Darlington died, and an American Congressman, played by Christopher Reeve, bought the house. Mrs Kenton left Darlington before the outbreak of the war and got married. The flow of the film conveys an insightful parallel between the romance and the relationship with the Master. James Fox plays Lord Darlington, not a Nazi sympathizer, but an ambiguous well-mannered gentleman who 'understands' the Germans. During a memorable toast, the American Congressman, and future house owner, would call all the assembled European politicians 'amateurs', an allegation that only shocks his audience, but doesn't fool us, not even Darlington's godson (Hugh Grant). The 'amateur' speech, with the same resonance than Churchill's 'dishonour and war' line, foresees the last days of an agonizing order that exploited the guilt of WWI victory, to roll the red carpets to the Nazis. And the tragic choices of Darlington would spill over Stevens' life. Incapable of adopting one defying attitude against his own master, Stevens condemned himself to a standard of life sadly prone to unhappiness and frustration. And it's precisely the kind of life that Mrs Kenton rejected by leaving the house. And her personal tragedy is that she left the only man she truly loved. "The Remains of the Day" chronicles two separate stories, challenging the solemn and unflappably professionalism of Mr Stevens, and interlocking each other until leading Stevens to a dead-end. And twenty years later, Stevens maintains the same level of mystery. People ask him where he stood for regarding his Master's opinion. Invoking the call of duty, he served his Master the best he could. He deplored some uninspired choices, the most significant being the revocation of two Jewish maids. But still, Stevens embraced his master's choices without being an accomplice. A few years later, the seal of infamy marks the name of Darlington, but not Stevens', yet there's no doubt his heart carries some regrets, and maybe, his unfulfilled relationship with Mrs Kenton is a way to make up for his own guilt. To have followed Darlington or not following Mrs Kenton? Looking back on his life, Stevens would understand the value of regrets, whether it's for done or undone choices, maybe by persuading a divorced Mrs Kenton to go back to Darlington? As a character study, the film is a wonderful examination of lives made of unmade choices and 'what if' questions, as a romance, it happens to be admirably poignant and brilliant, because feelings are so intimate and real that they can hardly be expressed, let alone from a man of such a few words like Mr Stevens. And this is why the ending plays as the perfect emotional pay-off for a film so full of frustrating inhibitions, a light of hope after an eternity spent in the Master's shadow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hopkins' finest role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandcooler
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Remains Of The Day" is a script that clearly stood or fell with the casting of the Mr.Stevens character, and thank God they hit that one out of the park. Anthony Hopkins is perfect in this complex role, the writing isn't always that solid but Hopkins can just make any scene work here. Playing a character that's supposed to hide all his emotions is a challenge, but Hopkins still manages to give Stevens amazing depth. It's all in the little things I guess: occasionally Stevens will smile, but you never know if he's really happy or if he just does everything he does because it's expected from the butler. You can't look in the character's mind because he's so brilliantly underplayed. The best scene of "Remains Of The Day" comes near the end, when Stevens enters the room of a sobbing Emma Thompson. The climax to that scene (or lack thereof) is so fitting and so amazing. This is not my favorite movie ever because as I said, it isn't even that well-scripted or directed, but it's very compelling nonetheless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Remains of the Day
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShibanPD
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unrequited love finds multiple reasons to remain unrequited in The Remains of the Day, a film as beautifully written, acted, and shot (interiors and exteriors), as it is frustrating in its unrepressed examination of repression. Anthony Hopkins plays James Stevens, head butler of Darlington Hall, the residence of Lord Darlington (James Fox), an English aristocrat who hosts interwar dinners and conferences for world politicians, including the prime minister and foreign ambassadors. Darlington wishes to appease Nazi Germany, whom he feels was too harshly treated by the Treaty of Versailles. Christopher Reeve plays Jack Lewis, the American delegate, who invades the proceedings to call the attendees "amateurs." Hugh Grant, in one of his better roles, plays Darlington's godson, Reginald Cardinal, a "news hound" who eventually agrees with Lewis and detects the abuse of Darlington's "good, noble intentions" by the Germans, the intentions of whose leader are not fully comprehended by Darlington, who will later recognize his own gullibility. It is within this context of large-scale moral and political conflict and international affairs that super-butler Stevens toils to keep a good house. Not only does he try, with every fiber of his being, to remain detached from the world-shaking decisions being made around him (he seems more concerned with the return of a chair to its proper place), but he also maintains an ostensible detachment from his feelings (he shows more emotion over the breaking of a wine bottle than over the death of his father). Stevens extends this detachment to his feelings for the housekeeper, Miss Kenton (Emma Thompson), who, compared with Mr. Stevens, wears her emotions on her sleeve. Stevens justifies his detachment by the unwavering "dignity" required of a great butler, especially one in the service of a house carrying the importance of Darlington Hall. Emma Thompson's Oscar-nominated performance is earnest and superb. Her character, who is considered old by the underservants and young by Mr. Stevens, passes through a range of emotions and tactics: she offers matronly advice to a younger maidservant rushing into marriage, plays provocative detective in bringing to light the errors committed by Stevens' father, tenderly comforts Stevens when his father falls ill, chastises Stevens for his moral inertness in the face of his master's racist turn, criticizes herself for placing her needs above her convictions, and, in one of the most brilliant scenes of the film, encroaches upon Stevens' "private time" to pry into the subject matter of his reading material, while walking a fine line between playful mockery and seductive cajoling. The supporting cast, which includes Peter Vaughan in a wonderful performance as Stevens' father, William, is also superb. Richard Robbins' whimsical, enchanting, hypnotic music is like a good wine: somberly intoxicating. The centerpiece of the film is Anthony Hopkins' Oscar-nominated performance as Stevens, a role which requires tremendous inner energy, as we must always see that he is, in fact, affected by events, while the emotional hollowness of his verbal interactions with the other characters belies his concern. The continual bombardment of his stoicism by personal challenges seems almost humorously intentional on the part of the filmmakers, like tourists trying to make a member of the Royal Guard laugh. Stevens, who cracks a nervous smile now and again, never has a real laugh, and never pursues his love for Miss Kenton, until it is too late. Honor, duty, and dignity are the reasons given for his failure to launch, but it seems as though Stevens comes from a long line of married people, including his father, who also worked as a butler and still managed to have a family of his own. There is a fair share of upstairs-downstairs going on in the world of the film, most pronounced in an uncomfortable scene in which Stevens' ignorance of world affairs is used to prove a point against democracy, but it doesn't seem completely antagonistic; when Mr. Stevens, Sr. trips and falls, dropping a full tray of items, the "men of stature" he is waiting on come to his aid quickly and treat him humanely. The cause of Stevens' reluctance to accept love when it presents itself appears to be more personal than societal. Stevens, deserving of the benefit of the doubt, is more a workaholic than a sociopath, although there is a faint, remote comparison drawn between Stevens' blind obedience and that of the Nazi soldiers whom Stevens' master is accused of throwing in with. Whatever the reasona reason that seems to escape Stevens himselfthe unrequited love between Ms. Kenton and Mr. Stevens is a source of heartbreaking regret and sadness for this long-time admirer of the filma feeling that lingers after the final, symbolic scene in which Mr. Stevens, after having assisted Mr. Lewis in releasing a temporarily trapped bird, closes forever the window of opportunity on a chance at love, at unchaining his heart, at escaping Darlington Hall to pursue a life of his own.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb in every way
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this again recently on cable after many years and it is even better than I remembered. Like many Merchant Ivory movies there are many details that can't all be absorbed one viewing. It helps to know the premise of the plot in advance so the going back and forth in time is not confusing. The story is powerful and the story of appeasement in pre WWII Britain is both chilling and fascinating to watch. Makes one look at the butler's job in a different light - more like running a hotel. The Butler's role felt crucial to support the critical but misguided peace talks. The subplot with his father is touching. The screenplay captures both the grand sweep of the larger events and the intimate personal story. The filming, interiors, scenery and cinematography are all beautiful. It is Emma Thompson's best role. Every emotion is so transparent and clear on her face. Her frustration and sadness are moving and memorable. Anthony Hopkins is so convincing in the character that it's hard to imagine you are not watching a real butler. Hope he is remembered more for this role than "Silence of the Lambs". The scenes between them are loaded with emotion and unspoken feelings. Excellent supporting cast including the regal James Fox and a well cast Christopher Reeve. If not for the stiff competition that year including Schindler's List, Philadelphia, Age of Innocence, I think in any other year this would have swept the table. A truly wonderful result of the combination of a Japanese author, a German screenwriter, an American director and the top British actors. One of the best movies in the last 50 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although Ismail Merchant was Indian by birth and James Ivory American, and although many of their film-scripts, including this one, were written by the German-born Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, the Merchant-Ivory partnership came to be seen as quintessentially British film-makers. They were responsible for some of the best-known British films of the eighties and nineties, mostly costume dramas based upon literary sources and dealing with the lives of the well-to-do classes. They did not invent the film genre which has become known as "heritage cinema"- that dates back at least to the late sixties- but are perhaps its best-known practitioners. "The Remains of the Day"- the significance of the title is rather obscure- is in many ways a typical example of their work, although the action takes place in the 1930s and 1950s rather than the late Victorian/Edwardian era with which they are normally associated. The main character is Mr. Stevens, the butler of Darlington Hall, an English stately home, during the 1930s. (Stevens' Christian name is James, but he is rarely referred to as such. By convention, senior servants in a household were referred to by their surnames alone). There are two strands to the plot, one political and the other personal. The political strand involves Stevens' employer Lord Darlington, an influential politician who frequently hosts gatherings of important international figures at this home. The personal strand involves Stevens' relations with Lord Darlington's housekeeper Miss Kenton, who falls in love with him although he fails to reciprocate her sentiments. (Or possibly he does, but fails to show it). The central political theme of the film is the politics of appeasement. Darlington initially appears to be in many ways an admirable character, kindly, honourable and idealistic. Although he served in the First World War he, unlike many veterans of that conflict, bears no hatred or animosity towards the Germans- indeed, he believes that Germany was harshly treated in 1919 by the vindictive Allies. His main fault is that he cannot understand those who are not honourable and idealistic, and this blinds him to the evils of Nazism; in the misguided belief that Hitler is a trustworthy man of honour he becomes an outspoken advocate of appeasement. As the film progresses, however, his own character deteriorates; he openly welcomes outright Nazi sympathisers as guests in his home, and even dismisses two Jewish chambermaids for fear of upsetting such persons. Stevens prides himself on being a model butler. He is calm, courteous and efficient, punctilious in the performance of his duties, unfailingly loyal to his employer. He regards any display of emotion as a weakness, and preserves an iron self-control at all times. Miss Kenton- we learn late on in the film that her name is Sarah, although she prefers to be called Sally- is equally efficient professionally, but is warmer and more openly emotional. The question the film raises is whether one should allow oneself to be defined entirely through one's work and through one's relationship with one's superiors. It is the same question as the great Austrian dramatist Franz Grillparzer was raising in his play "Ein Treuer Diener Seines Herrn". Like Grillparzer's hero Bancbanus, Stevens is a "faithful servant of his master"- the literal meaning of the German title- but one whose faithful service comes at a cost. In Stevens' case that cost is both personal, in that he sacrifices his chances of finding love, and moral, in that his loyalty leads him to close his eyes to his master's behaviour. When the two Jewish maids are dismissed, Miss Kenton is outraged, but Stevens refuses to utter a word of criticism of his employer, even in private. We are left wondering whether he is simply being diplomatic, or whether he actually does believe that the rich and powerful can do not wrong. When I recently reviewed "84, Charing Cross Road", I stated that while Anthony Hopkins is sometimes regarded in specialising in forceful, flamboyant or monstrous characters such as Hannibal Lecter or Captain Bligh in "The Bounty", he can be equally good as quieter, more restrained individuals, such as Dr Treves in "The Elephant Man", C S Lewis in "Shadowlands" or Frank Doel in "84, Charing Cross Road" itself. "The Remains of the Day" is perhaps Hopkins' finest performance in his vein. It is a superb piece of acting, quiet and unobtrusive, but all the more effective for being so. Emma Thompson is also good as Miss Kenton, as is James Fox as Lord Darlington. There are also good performances in smaller parts from the likes of Peter Vaughan as Stevens' elderly father, although I was less impressed by Christopher Reeve as American Congressman Jack Lewis. (Lewis' part appears to have been expanded beyond that he plays in the novel by Kazuo Ishiguro, doubtless in order to provide a role for a big Hollywood name). The film displays the typical Merchant-Ivory characteristics of high production values and a loving recreation of period detail. It is, to my mind, perhaps too leisurely and slow-moving, which is why I would not rate it as highly as some other Merchant-Ivory productions, such as "A Room with a View" or "Howards End", made the year before and also starring Hopkins and Thompson. It is, however, a well-acted and well-photographed movie, and often a thought-provoking one in its analysis of interwar history and its theme that loyalty often comes with a hidden cost. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A touching story and another great acting from Anthony Hopkins.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nail Yener
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why didn't I watch this movie before? This is the question that I asked myself after I finished watching The Remains of the Day. I have seen most movies of Anthony Hopkins but I didn't even know this movie existed until yesterday when I was doing some research about 90s movies. It was always a great pleasure for me to see Anthony Hopkins in a movie no matter what his role was. And his performance in this movie once more gives me a reason to watch him again and again and again. But I didn't like this movie just because of him. I liked it because of many things such as its story, the performance of Emma Thompson and other actors/actresses and the atmosphere of the film as a whole. The story of The Remains of the Day focuses on nobility and suppressed feelings. I really felt like as if I was witnessing a real section from that time while watching the movie. At the end, when I go over the whole story in my head once more, although I wished that Mr. Stevens and Miss Kenton would reveal their true feelings to each other, I think I didn't feel sorry for them. Because this is the way Mr. Stevens is and this is the message of this movie in my opinion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
