<filme>
 <id>
  865
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119349
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Tempestade de Gelo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  1973, suburban Connecticut: middle class families experimenting with casual sex, drink, etc., find their lives out of control.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In the weekend after thanksgiving 1973 the Hoods are skidding out of control. Benjamin Hood reels from drink to drink, trying not to think about his trouble at the office. His wife, Elena, is reading self help books and losing patience with her husband's lies. Their son, Paul, home for the holidays, escapes to the city to pursue an alluring rich girl from his prep school. And young, budding nymphomaniac, Wendy Hood roams the neighborhood, innocently exploring liquor cabinets and lingerie drawers of her friends' parents, looking for something new. Then an ice storm hits, the worst in a century. Things get bad...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   storm
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ice
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drink
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ice storm
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   thanksgiving
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Ang Lee
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Rick Moody
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   James Schamus
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kevin Kline
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Joan Allen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sigourney Weaver
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ensemble Acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's easy to compare The Ice Storm to American Beauty and Happiness, both of which also dealt with disillusionment and the disintegration of the American Dream and the traditional family cell in the suburbs, and to a lesser extent The Sweet Hereafter which explored some similar themes in small town Canada. The Ice Storm is as cynical as those other films, but it's much more subtle in masking its sardonicism, and has aged much better than American Beauty, which had the appearance of a masterpiece at its release but looks flat and shallow now. The people in The Ice Storm feel more real and more human than the ones in American Beauty and Happiness; and the film walks that fine line between character-based slice-of-life storytelling and metaphorical satire, which works only because the viewer cares for the characters and their fates, while also absorbing the bigger issues under the surface. That would not work without a strong ensemble cast; the actors in The Ice Storm are not among my favorites, yet they all outdo themselves and produce sympathetic, powerful, convincing performances - Kevin Kline, Joan Allen and Sigourney Weaver are all at their very best, and the younger actors (Elijah Wood, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci, Adam Hann-Byrd and - amazingly - even Katie Holmes) all deliver too. In contrast with the (intentionally) despicable characters in Happiness and American Beauty, these actors form a group of very average people that the viewer relates to and cares about - but the dysfunction and sickness is right there beneath the surface, waiting for the right catastrophe to explode. There's an undefinable something that stops The Ice Storm short of becoming one of my favorites. The ending fits the mood of the rest of the film, but doesn't offer the catharsis that is needed, and it left me with a bitter taste. In the end, I found myself wishing that the film said more, and left more of a mark; the fact that it isn't often recognized as one of the best films of the 90's is simply because there's something not quite memorable about it. It's incredibly engaging throughout, though, and is definitely one of the strongest dramas of its time, beautifully shot, and a gem that's well worth discovering.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canadian58
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the thousands of movies I have seen, there are a select few I will remember for the rest of my life as being the worst movies I have ever seen. The Ice Storm tops this list. Nothing is good about it, and I'm sorry that I'll never get that two hours of my life back. I should have trusted my instinct and turned it off after the first 20 minutes of being mind-numbing bored. There are a lot of good actors, all of which the talent is completely wasted. Not one of the characters is likable, except maybe Tobey Maguire. Everyone is cheating on someone, and oh, yeah, there's an ice storm going on outside during the last half an hour of the film. We see one car go in the ditch, one branch fall, and one downed power line, is all it amounts to. Do yourself a favor and avoid this one. And to all you people giving this film a great review, HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MINDS?????!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three drift out of consciousness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is meant to offer a soft contrast as flow, between external life with people (family members gathered for Thanksgiving) anxiously pulled in disparate orbits, and the inner life of unfathomable urges and emotion that gives rise to the firstappearances versus true self, rooted in relationships and attempting connection. Set in 1970's America with Nixon lying on TV, the broader commentary is that the world is organized on deceit, misplaced faith. There is contextual talk of people as intertwined molecules, of inner life as inverted space where the invisible becomes visible. So here's the cinematic gambit, how to make visible a part of that inner life? It's what every filmmaker worth anything has puzzled about in his work, in-sight into human soul, no small challenge for Lee, though the film may otherwise seem typical. There are three connected story lines to that effect, each one culminating in a ritual of seduction as betrayal. Each storyline, climaxes with a loved one drifting out of consciousness in some way (drunk husband, Libbets, the son). This only emphasizes what we've been seeing for the whole film, people drifting apart heedless of one another. It all plays in the latter stages against the backdrop of a coming ice storm, it can't be helped, there's some inevitable unhappiness ahead of us. The overall point? In each case, as loved ones momentarily or not go out of life, those left behind are suddenly surrounded with that negative space of absence, and in that space pour their inner self and effect human connection. It may all seem a little cloying in the finale. But the best part is getting there, the protracted sequence with cross-cutting between the three stories of betrayed seduction. So how to make visible what in life eludes us, the fabric of feelings as cinematic fabric? This was very likely Lee's interest in the project, as well as more broadly the idea of dislocation. I was happy to see a cinematic solution that was nowhere in multithreaded films like Crash or Cloud Atlas. The idea seems to be, show each new scene from a point on, as extension, as in-sight or meditation on previous ones, as though a single soul is dreaming. So this is nice. The film is the empty space, as we think dull, day-to- day life to be. The characters as molecules drifting in the air, often apart. The loss of consciousness not simply as loss, but as meaningful awakening to that empty space where we, as molecules, do not aimlessly drift, but by virtue of being there, hold each other into place giving shape to life. Lee as usual has compromised, enough to deliver a movie with some broad appeal. The overall wrap is a bit too fabricated for my taste. But see how gentle are the contrasts between hard sorrow and soft inner life, where the very similar Melancholia eats at you, this soothes. It's all here natural to Lee, who as a Chinese knows this stuff in meditation and tai chi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Contrived Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thanksgiving weekend in Connecticut in 1973, two families work through their problems. Talk about dysfunctional families! This one has two such clans, and every member of each family is assigned an issue (kleptomaniac, sex addict, social misfit, absentee parent, depression, etc.). It makes for a very contrived drama. The impressive cast manages to overcome some of the shortcomings of the script, but it all seems so heavy-handed. As a couple whose marriage has fizzled, Kline and Allen come off the best. The makeup department went a little overboard trying to evoke the 1970s look, with Weaver looking particularly odd as a woman who's cold as ice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ordinary and uneventful in the most accurate sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is set during Thanksgiving 1973 and centers on two upper middle class Connecticut families who are trying to run their course in the Nixon era and free themselves from their blah feelings through drinking, adultery and sexual experiments. Both the parents and the children have dull lifestyles, they are financially secured, and there is a serious lack of joy and enthusiasm in activities and communication, incl. sexual relations, jobs/studies. The cast is strong: Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, and that-time minors Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, who all give catchy and splendid performances. The title has both direct and indirect meaning and the director Ang Lee has fulfilled another great task, the only problem seemed to be with the release year - 1997 - when, among others, Titanic was released and the movie in question obtained less praise and publicity it should have had. But it is never to late to watch a valuable movie (again), especially if the plot dealt with the past events anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great and overlooked genre movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really sure why this movie got pretty much ignored, at the time of its release. Not just by the movie goers, which is perhaps somewhat understandable but more so by all of big award ceremonies. By all means this movie should had swept a couple of them and it truly earned some more recognition. Drama's normally aren't even really my kind of thing but I just got captivated by this movie and was really liking it. Guess the main reason why I like it was because it wasn't being a pretentious or melodramatic one and it deliberately kept things small, which gave the overall movie also a sense of realism to it. For me it was a movie about people in search of themselves. Basically all of the characters are unhappy with their current situations and are searching for ways to break out and to get more in touch with themselves. This goes for the movie its youngster, which also makes this a sort of coming of age movie but also for their parents. Every character goes through some sort of inner transitions and the movie does a great job at balancing it all out. Basically everybody has a fair share of screen time in this movie. There aren't really one or two main characters but more like five or six of them. Every storyline is about as equally interesting and good to follow as the other. At least in my opinion of course. I personally got grabbed by it all, also since it isn't really being a standard drama, that is being predictable to watch from start till finish. It's also a movie that is being made great and intriguing to watch by its cast-members. It truly has an impressive cast-list, with actors such as Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, among many others. A cast to kill for and everybody did a great job, playing their character. A really overlooked Ang Lee movie, that is definitely worth checking out! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's too vague too vague
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film begins as slowly as it can; until the first hour, nothing much really happens and you have no idea of what to expect about this picture. I believe Ang Lee didn't have a story in mind and just utilized some ideas from Moody's novel. In many scenes we can notice that the filmmakers don't know what to do, so they just have the characters talking to each other. The cast is profession, we can see they really get into their characters, but that's not enough to make this movie any good. The only thing that enjoyed me is the braveness they have at showing how kids start their sexual life. You know, I'm only 19, so I can vaguely remember how these things worked in my mind when I was a kid. You're always worried what would happen if your parents found out, and in the end, they're doing their best to not see it. And let's not be hypocrite and believe that kids don't have sexual tension between themselves...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Film With Great Actors Giving Great Performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elevenangrymen
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved The Ice Storm. It's one of my favorite films. It takes place one thanksgiving, in the early 70's. When we first see the Hood family, they are perfectly normal. Kevin Kline is a loving husband, Joan Allen is a typical wife, Tobey Maguire loves comics, and Christina Ricci doesn't like Nixon. A perfectly normal family, in fact, they are nothing but. Kline is cheating on his wife with Sigourney Weaver, Allen is suspecting, but tries not to show it. Ricci is a fourteen year old experimenting with alcohol and sex. Maguire is in love with a girl, and she likes him too, like a brother. This all culminates during an ice storm. Everyone breaks down, in some form or another. Kline is unable to keep his secret from Allen, and she doesn't react with shock. In fact, she acts relieved. This is before she cheats on Kline during a car-key exchange, that seems right out of the seventies. That being said, every single one of the actors has their moment to shine. From Kline down to Elijah Wood, every actor delivers a masterful performance. This is all done through Ang Lee's direction. Lee is a great director, and here, he shows it. He perfectly captures the decade, in his use of music, costumes and sets. The cinematography is great as well. All being said, The Ice Storm is one of the best films of the nineties, and in my option, the best film of 1997. Watch it and immerse yourself in a world of pain, longing, lust and booze. In other words, just watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tedious exercise in dysfunction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spicyburrito
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First I should say, this movie could have been about my town and my family. I grew up in Connecticut and was 11 years old when the ice storm hit. My family was probably the typical dysfunctional unit of the 70's  emotionally clueless, parents headed for divorce (though we didn't know that yet), so I should have been able to relate to this film. The problem with the movie is there's no humor, no humanity. It's just one dysfunctional, sad, deviant event after another. It's like someone from another planet was assigned a homework exercise to depict dysfunctional families on Earth. I couldn't relate to the characters and there was no one to like. I'll give it 4 stars for the nice cinematography, the all-star cast, the good period sets and clothes. Although Toby Maguire gives his usual staring-into-space, deer-in-headlights, stupid-half-smile, what-am-I-supposed-to-be-doing-again? performance, I thought the rest of the cast did their best with the material  i.e. it wasn't the actors' fault!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sensible Movie That Explains Oedipus Complex In An Easy Way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vikram-ry123
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ice Storm is a metaphor of country life. I do not read the original novel by Rick Moody; but I think the film is an appropriate adaptation of that novel. Every plot is very carefully drawn in the film. A master work by director Ang Lee that I will never forget. The movie is like a fact file of hundreds of truths of our daily life. Every character in the film is a part of us. The storm begins with Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) reading Fantastic Four comic book in a late night empty frozen train. The movie is mostly about the relation between two neighboring families lives in a suburb town. The characters are very life-like that I suddenly feel everything is just happening in front of me. Ben Hood (Kevin Kline) is the father of two child Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) and Wendy Hood (Christina Ricci). The irony is that both of the child are in their adolescent and their parents are unable to guide them at this stage. The same thing we can see in the Carver family. Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver) and Jim Carver (Jamey Sheridan) have two boys Sandy Carver (Adam Hann-Byrd) and Mikey Carver (Elijah Wood). That very night all the guardians went for an ironical Key Party that make them funny and irresistible to control their basic instincts. And the children are children, they follow the way that showed by the society and misguided by their parents. Young Wendy (Christina Ricci) is a grown up girl of 14 and she is in her adolescent but her parents hardly care to guide her in proper way. Paul (Tobey Maguire) 18 years old boy successfully controls his lust inspired by reading Fantastic Four comic is very sentimental. Albeit Ben (Kevin Kline) his father tries to tell him about the duties of a gentleman but he fails to make him understand appropriately. Ben has a bitter relation with his wife Elena (Joan Allen) that comes as an opportunity to grow an extramarital relation with his next door neighbor Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver). The ice storm changed everything in a single night. Janey leaves the party with a young man to fulfill lust and desire. In the lustful late night game played by all the mature men and women of the society where Ben acts like a fool and humiliated. Same night Jim Carver, Janey's husband and Elena Hood Ben's wife become out of control of their basic instinct. The film concluded in a poetic justice with a sacrifice of 14 years old Mikey Carver died in an accident in the ice storm night due to his careless parents. Next day Ben found the dead body. And Elena found her 14 years old daughter Wendy and young Caver boy Sandy (Adam Hann- Byrd) sleeping naked in Caver's house. Caver family lost their one son and Hood family realize that how much careless they are? In a particular scene of this movie carries a good lesson. One day Elena sees her daughter riding bicycle that reminds her own teenage years and next day she rides the bicycle and entered into a shopping mall and stole some products to enjoy her young age behavior but caught by the shop kipper and humiliated. The irony shows the young girl Wendy gets the same behavior like her mother. The movie is very practical and worth to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ensemble Acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's easy to compare The Ice Storm to American Beauty and Happiness, both of which also dealt with disillusionment and the disintegration of the American Dream and the traditional family cell in the suburbs, and to a lesser extent The Sweet Hereafter which explored some similar themes in small town Canada. The Ice Storm is as cynical as those other films, but it's much more subtle in masking its sardonicism, and has aged much better than American Beauty, which had the appearance of a masterpiece at its release but looks flat and shallow now. The people in The Ice Storm feel more real and more human than the ones in American Beauty and Happiness; and the film walks that fine line between character-based slice-of-life storytelling and metaphorical satire, which works only because the viewer cares for the characters and their fates, while also absorbing the bigger issues under the surface. That would not work without a strong ensemble cast; the actors in The Ice Storm are not among my favorites, yet they all outdo themselves and produce sympathetic, powerful, convincing performances - Kevin Kline, Joan Allen and Sigourney Weaver are all at their very best, and the younger actors (Elijah Wood, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci, Adam Hann-Byrd and - amazingly - even Katie Holmes) all deliver too. In contrast with the (intentionally) despicable characters in Happiness and American Beauty, these actors form a group of very average people that the viewer relates to and cares about - but the dysfunction and sickness is right there beneath the surface, waiting for the right catastrophe to explode. There's an undefinable something that stops The Ice Storm short of becoming one of my favorites. The ending fits the mood of the rest of the film, but doesn't offer the catharsis that is needed, and it left me with a bitter taste. In the end, I found myself wishing that the film said more, and left more of a mark; the fact that it isn't often recognized as one of the best films of the 90's is simply because there's something not quite memorable about it. It's incredibly engaging throughout, though, and is definitely one of the strongest dramas of its time, beautifully shot, and a gem that's well worth discovering.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canadian58
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the thousands of movies I have seen, there are a select few I will remember for the rest of my life as being the worst movies I have ever seen. The Ice Storm tops this list. Nothing is good about it, and I'm sorry that I'll never get that two hours of my life back. I should have trusted my instinct and turned it off after the first 20 minutes of being mind-numbing bored. There are a lot of good actors, all of which the talent is completely wasted. Not one of the characters is likable, except maybe Tobey Maguire. Everyone is cheating on someone, and oh, yeah, there's an ice storm going on outside during the last half an hour of the film. We see one car go in the ditch, one branch fall, and one downed power line, is all it amounts to. Do yourself a favor and avoid this one. And to all you people giving this film a great review, HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MINDS?????!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three drift out of consciousness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is meant to offer a soft contrast as flow, between external life with people (family members gathered for Thanksgiving) anxiously pulled in disparate orbits, and the inner life of unfathomable urges and emotion that gives rise to the firstappearances versus true self, rooted in relationships and attempting connection. Set in 1970's America with Nixon lying on TV, the broader commentary is that the world is organized on deceit, misplaced faith. There is contextual talk of people as intertwined molecules, of inner life as inverted space where the invisible becomes visible. So here's the cinematic gambit, how to make visible a part of that inner life? It's what every filmmaker worth anything has puzzled about in his work, in-sight into human soul, no small challenge for Lee, though the film may otherwise seem typical. There are three connected story lines to that effect, each one culminating in a ritual of seduction as betrayal. Each storyline, climaxes with a loved one drifting out of consciousness in some way (drunk husband, Libbets, the son). This only emphasizes what we've been seeing for the whole film, people drifting apart heedless of one another. It all plays in the latter stages against the backdrop of a coming ice storm, it can't be helped, there's some inevitable unhappiness ahead of us. The overall point? In each case, as loved ones momentarily or not go out of life, those left behind are suddenly surrounded with that negative space of absence, and in that space pour their inner self and effect human connection. It may all seem a little cloying in the finale. But the best part is getting there, the protracted sequence with cross-cutting between the three stories of betrayed seduction. So how to make visible what in life eludes us, the fabric of feelings as cinematic fabric? This was very likely Lee's interest in the project, as well as more broadly the idea of dislocation. I was happy to see a cinematic solution that was nowhere in multithreaded films like Crash or Cloud Atlas. The idea seems to be, show each new scene from a point on, as extension, as in-sight or meditation on previous ones, as though a single soul is dreaming. So this is nice. The film is the empty space, as we think dull, day-to- day life to be. The characters as molecules drifting in the air, often apart. The loss of consciousness not simply as loss, but as meaningful awakening to that empty space where we, as molecules, do not aimlessly drift, but by virtue of being there, hold each other into place giving shape to life. Lee as usual has compromised, enough to deliver a movie with some broad appeal. The overall wrap is a bit too fabricated for my taste. But see how gentle are the contrasts between hard sorrow and soft inner life, where the very similar Melancholia eats at you, this soothes. It's all here natural to Lee, who as a Chinese knows this stuff in meditation and tai chi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Contrived Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thanksgiving weekend in Connecticut in 1973, two families work through their problems. Talk about dysfunctional families! This one has two such clans, and every member of each family is assigned an issue (kleptomaniac, sex addict, social misfit, absentee parent, depression, etc.). It makes for a very contrived drama. The impressive cast manages to overcome some of the shortcomings of the script, but it all seems so heavy-handed. As a couple whose marriage has fizzled, Kline and Allen come off the best. The makeup department went a little overboard trying to evoke the 1970s look, with Weaver looking particularly odd as a woman who's cold as ice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ordinary and uneventful in the most accurate sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is set during Thanksgiving 1973 and centers on two upper middle class Connecticut families who are trying to run their course in the Nixon era and free themselves from their blah feelings through drinking, adultery and sexual experiments. Both the parents and the children have dull lifestyles, they are financially secured, and there is a serious lack of joy and enthusiasm in activities and communication, incl. sexual relations, jobs/studies. The cast is strong: Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, and that-time minors Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, who all give catchy and splendid performances. The title has both direct and indirect meaning and the director Ang Lee has fulfilled another great task, the only problem seemed to be with the release year - 1997 - when, among others, Titanic was released and the movie in question obtained less praise and publicity it should have had. But it is never to late to watch a valuable movie (again), especially if the plot dealt with the past events anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great and overlooked genre movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really sure why this movie got pretty much ignored, at the time of its release. Not just by the movie goers, which is perhaps somewhat understandable but more so by all of big award ceremonies. By all means this movie should had swept a couple of them and it truly earned some more recognition. Drama's normally aren't even really my kind of thing but I just got captivated by this movie and was really liking it. Guess the main reason why I like it was because it wasn't being a pretentious or melodramatic one and it deliberately kept things small, which gave the overall movie also a sense of realism to it. For me it was a movie about people in search of themselves. Basically all of the characters are unhappy with their current situations and are searching for ways to break out and to get more in touch with themselves. This goes for the movie its youngster, which also makes this a sort of coming of age movie but also for their parents. Every character goes through some sort of inner transitions and the movie does a great job at balancing it all out. Basically everybody has a fair share of screen time in this movie. There aren't really one or two main characters but more like five or six of them. Every storyline is about as equally interesting and good to follow as the other. At least in my opinion of course. I personally got grabbed by it all, also since it isn't really being a standard drama, that is being predictable to watch from start till finish. It's also a movie that is being made great and intriguing to watch by its cast-members. It truly has an impressive cast-list, with actors such as Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, among many others. A cast to kill for and everybody did a great job, playing their character. A really overlooked Ang Lee movie, that is definitely worth checking out! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's too vague too vague
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film begins as slowly as it can; until the first hour, nothing much really happens and you have no idea of what to expect about this picture. I believe Ang Lee didn't have a story in mind and just utilized some ideas from Moody's novel. In many scenes we can notice that the filmmakers don't know what to do, so they just have the characters talking to each other. The cast is profession, we can see they really get into their characters, but that's not enough to make this movie any good. The only thing that enjoyed me is the braveness they have at showing how kids start their sexual life. You know, I'm only 19, so I can vaguely remember how these things worked in my mind when I was a kid. You're always worried what would happen if your parents found out, and in the end, they're doing their best to not see it. And let's not be hypocrite and believe that kids don't have sexual tension between themselves...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Film With Great Actors Giving Great Performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elevenangrymen
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved The Ice Storm. It's one of my favorite films. It takes place one thanksgiving, in the early 70's. When we first see the Hood family, they are perfectly normal. Kevin Kline is a loving husband, Joan Allen is a typical wife, Tobey Maguire loves comics, and Christina Ricci doesn't like Nixon. A perfectly normal family, in fact, they are nothing but. Kline is cheating on his wife with Sigourney Weaver, Allen is suspecting, but tries not to show it. Ricci is a fourteen year old experimenting with alcohol and sex. Maguire is in love with a girl, and she likes him too, like a brother. This all culminates during an ice storm. Everyone breaks down, in some form or another. Kline is unable to keep his secret from Allen, and she doesn't react with shock. In fact, she acts relieved. This is before she cheats on Kline during a car-key exchange, that seems right out of the seventies. That being said, every single one of the actors has their moment to shine. From Kline down to Elijah Wood, every actor delivers a masterful performance. This is all done through Ang Lee's direction. Lee is a great director, and here, he shows it. He perfectly captures the decade, in his use of music, costumes and sets. The cinematography is great as well. All being said, The Ice Storm is one of the best films of the nineties, and in my option, the best film of 1997. Watch it and immerse yourself in a world of pain, longing, lust and booze. In other words, just watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tedious exercise in dysfunction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spicyburrito
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First I should say, this movie could have been about my town and my family. I grew up in Connecticut and was 11 years old when the ice storm hit. My family was probably the typical dysfunctional unit of the 70's  emotionally clueless, parents headed for divorce (though we didn't know that yet), so I should have been able to relate to this film. The problem with the movie is there's no humor, no humanity. It's just one dysfunctional, sad, deviant event after another. It's like someone from another planet was assigned a homework exercise to depict dysfunctional families on Earth. I couldn't relate to the characters and there was no one to like. I'll give it 4 stars for the nice cinematography, the all-star cast, the good period sets and clothes. Although Toby Maguire gives his usual staring-into-space, deer-in-headlights, stupid-half-smile, what-am-I-supposed-to-be-doing-again? performance, I thought the rest of the cast did their best with the material  i.e. it wasn't the actors' fault!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sensible Movie That Explains Oedipus Complex In An Easy Way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vikram-ry123
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ice Storm is a metaphor of country life. I do not read the original novel by Rick Moody; but I think the film is an appropriate adaptation of that novel. Every plot is very carefully drawn in the film. A master work by director Ang Lee that I will never forget. The movie is like a fact file of hundreds of truths of our daily life. Every character in the film is a part of us. The storm begins with Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) reading Fantastic Four comic book in a late night empty frozen train. The movie is mostly about the relation between two neighboring families lives in a suburb town. The characters are very life-like that I suddenly feel everything is just happening in front of me. Ben Hood (Kevin Kline) is the father of two child Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) and Wendy Hood (Christina Ricci). The irony is that both of the child are in their adolescent and their parents are unable to guide them at this stage. The same thing we can see in the Carver family. Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver) and Jim Carver (Jamey Sheridan) have two boys Sandy Carver (Adam Hann-Byrd) and Mikey Carver (Elijah Wood). That very night all the guardians went for an ironical Key Party that make them funny and irresistible to control their basic instincts. And the children are children, they follow the way that showed by the society and misguided by their parents. Young Wendy (Christina Ricci) is a grown up girl of 14 and she is in her adolescent but her parents hardly care to guide her in proper way. Paul (Tobey Maguire) 18 years old boy successfully controls his lust inspired by reading Fantastic Four comic is very sentimental. Albeit Ben (Kevin Kline) his father tries to tell him about the duties of a gentleman but he fails to make him understand appropriately. Ben has a bitter relation with his wife Elena (Joan Allen) that comes as an opportunity to grow an extramarital relation with his next door neighbor Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver). The ice storm changed everything in a single night. Janey leaves the party with a young man to fulfill lust and desire. In the lustful late night game played by all the mature men and women of the society where Ben acts like a fool and humiliated. Same night Jim Carver, Janey's husband and Elena Hood Ben's wife become out of control of their basic instinct. The film concluded in a poetic justice with a sacrifice of 14 years old Mikey Carver died in an accident in the ice storm night due to his careless parents. Next day Ben found the dead body. And Elena found her 14 years old daughter Wendy and young Caver boy Sandy (Adam Hann- Byrd) sleeping naked in Caver's house. Caver family lost their one son and Hood family realize that how much careless they are? In a particular scene of this movie carries a good lesson. One day Elena sees her daughter riding bicycle that reminds her own teenage years and next day she rides the bicycle and entered into a shopping mall and stole some products to enjoy her young age behavior but caught by the shop kipper and humiliated. The irony shows the young girl Wendy gets the same behavior like her mother. The movie is very practical and worth to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ensemble Acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's easy to compare The Ice Storm to American Beauty and Happiness, both of which also dealt with disillusionment and the disintegration of the American Dream and the traditional family cell in the suburbs, and to a lesser extent The Sweet Hereafter which explored some similar themes in small town Canada. The Ice Storm is as cynical as those other films, but it's much more subtle in masking its sardonicism, and has aged much better than American Beauty, which had the appearance of a masterpiece at its release but looks flat and shallow now. The people in The Ice Storm feel more real and more human than the ones in American Beauty and Happiness; and the film walks that fine line between character-based slice-of-life storytelling and metaphorical satire, which works only because the viewer cares for the characters and their fates, while also absorbing the bigger issues under the surface. That would not work without a strong ensemble cast; the actors in The Ice Storm are not among my favorites, yet they all outdo themselves and produce sympathetic, powerful, convincing performances - Kevin Kline, Joan Allen and Sigourney Weaver are all at their very best, and the younger actors (Elijah Wood, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci, Adam Hann-Byrd and - amazingly - even Katie Holmes) all deliver too. In contrast with the (intentionally) despicable characters in Happiness and American Beauty, these actors form a group of very average people that the viewer relates to and cares about - but the dysfunction and sickness is right there beneath the surface, waiting for the right catastrophe to explode. There's an undefinable something that stops The Ice Storm short of becoming one of my favorites. The ending fits the mood of the rest of the film, but doesn't offer the catharsis that is needed, and it left me with a bitter taste. In the end, I found myself wishing that the film said more, and left more of a mark; the fact that it isn't often recognized as one of the best films of the 90's is simply because there's something not quite memorable about it. It's incredibly engaging throughout, though, and is definitely one of the strongest dramas of its time, beautifully shot, and a gem that's well worth discovering.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canadian58
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the thousands of movies I have seen, there are a select few I will remember for the rest of my life as being the worst movies I have ever seen. The Ice Storm tops this list. Nothing is good about it, and I'm sorry that I'll never get that two hours of my life back. I should have trusted my instinct and turned it off after the first 20 minutes of being mind-numbing bored. There are a lot of good actors, all of which the talent is completely wasted. Not one of the characters is likable, except maybe Tobey Maguire. Everyone is cheating on someone, and oh, yeah, there's an ice storm going on outside during the last half an hour of the film. We see one car go in the ditch, one branch fall, and one downed power line, is all it amounts to. Do yourself a favor and avoid this one. And to all you people giving this film a great review, HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MINDS?????!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three drift out of consciousness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is meant to offer a soft contrast as flow, between external life with people (family members gathered for Thanksgiving) anxiously pulled in disparate orbits, and the inner life of unfathomable urges and emotion that gives rise to the firstappearances versus true self, rooted in relationships and attempting connection. Set in 1970's America with Nixon lying on TV, the broader commentary is that the world is organized on deceit, misplaced faith. There is contextual talk of people as intertwined molecules, of inner life as inverted space where the invisible becomes visible. So here's the cinematic gambit, how to make visible a part of that inner life? It's what every filmmaker worth anything has puzzled about in his work, in-sight into human soul, no small challenge for Lee, though the film may otherwise seem typical. There are three connected story lines to that effect, each one culminating in a ritual of seduction as betrayal. Each storyline, climaxes with a loved one drifting out of consciousness in some way (drunk husband, Libbets, the son). This only emphasizes what we've been seeing for the whole film, people drifting apart heedless of one another. It all plays in the latter stages against the backdrop of a coming ice storm, it can't be helped, there's some inevitable unhappiness ahead of us. The overall point? In each case, as loved ones momentarily or not go out of life, those left behind are suddenly surrounded with that negative space of absence, and in that space pour their inner self and effect human connection. It may all seem a little cloying in the finale. But the best part is getting there, the protracted sequence with cross-cutting between the three stories of betrayed seduction. So how to make visible what in life eludes us, the fabric of feelings as cinematic fabric? This was very likely Lee's interest in the project, as well as more broadly the idea of dislocation. I was happy to see a cinematic solution that was nowhere in multithreaded films like Crash or Cloud Atlas. The idea seems to be, show each new scene from a point on, as extension, as in-sight or meditation on previous ones, as though a single soul is dreaming. So this is nice. The film is the empty space, as we think dull, day-to- day life to be. The characters as molecules drifting in the air, often apart. The loss of consciousness not simply as loss, but as meaningful awakening to that empty space where we, as molecules, do not aimlessly drift, but by virtue of being there, hold each other into place giving shape to life. Lee as usual has compromised, enough to deliver a movie with some broad appeal. The overall wrap is a bit too fabricated for my taste. But see how gentle are the contrasts between hard sorrow and soft inner life, where the very similar Melancholia eats at you, this soothes. It's all here natural to Lee, who as a Chinese knows this stuff in meditation and tai chi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Contrived Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thanksgiving weekend in Connecticut in 1973, two families work through their problems. Talk about dysfunctional families! This one has two such clans, and every member of each family is assigned an issue (kleptomaniac, sex addict, social misfit, absentee parent, depression, etc.). It makes for a very contrived drama. The impressive cast manages to overcome some of the shortcomings of the script, but it all seems so heavy-handed. As a couple whose marriage has fizzled, Kline and Allen come off the best. The makeup department went a little overboard trying to evoke the 1970s look, with Weaver looking particularly odd as a woman who's cold as ice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ordinary and uneventful in the most accurate sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is set during Thanksgiving 1973 and centers on two upper middle class Connecticut families who are trying to run their course in the Nixon era and free themselves from their blah feelings through drinking, adultery and sexual experiments. Both the parents and the children have dull lifestyles, they are financially secured, and there is a serious lack of joy and enthusiasm in activities and communication, incl. sexual relations, jobs/studies. The cast is strong: Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, and that-time minors Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, who all give catchy and splendid performances. The title has both direct and indirect meaning and the director Ang Lee has fulfilled another great task, the only problem seemed to be with the release year - 1997 - when, among others, Titanic was released and the movie in question obtained less praise and publicity it should have had. But it is never to late to watch a valuable movie (again), especially if the plot dealt with the past events anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great and overlooked genre movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really sure why this movie got pretty much ignored, at the time of its release. Not just by the movie goers, which is perhaps somewhat understandable but more so by all of big award ceremonies. By all means this movie should had swept a couple of them and it truly earned some more recognition. Drama's normally aren't even really my kind of thing but I just got captivated by this movie and was really liking it. Guess the main reason why I like it was because it wasn't being a pretentious or melodramatic one and it deliberately kept things small, which gave the overall movie also a sense of realism to it. For me it was a movie about people in search of themselves. Basically all of the characters are unhappy with their current situations and are searching for ways to break out and to get more in touch with themselves. This goes for the movie its youngster, which also makes this a sort of coming of age movie but also for their parents. Every character goes through some sort of inner transitions and the movie does a great job at balancing it all out. Basically everybody has a fair share of screen time in this movie. There aren't really one or two main characters but more like five or six of them. Every storyline is about as equally interesting and good to follow as the other. At least in my opinion of course. I personally got grabbed by it all, also since it isn't really being a standard drama, that is being predictable to watch from start till finish. It's also a movie that is being made great and intriguing to watch by its cast-members. It truly has an impressive cast-list, with actors such as Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, among many others. A cast to kill for and everybody did a great job, playing their character. A really overlooked Ang Lee movie, that is definitely worth checking out! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's too vague too vague
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film begins as slowly as it can; until the first hour, nothing much really happens and you have no idea of what to expect about this picture. I believe Ang Lee didn't have a story in mind and just utilized some ideas from Moody's novel. In many scenes we can notice that the filmmakers don't know what to do, so they just have the characters talking to each other. The cast is profession, we can see they really get into their characters, but that's not enough to make this movie any good. The only thing that enjoyed me is the braveness they have at showing how kids start their sexual life. You know, I'm only 19, so I can vaguely remember how these things worked in my mind when I was a kid. You're always worried what would happen if your parents found out, and in the end, they're doing their best to not see it. And let's not be hypocrite and believe that kids don't have sexual tension between themselves...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Film With Great Actors Giving Great Performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elevenangrymen
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved The Ice Storm. It's one of my favorite films. It takes place one thanksgiving, in the early 70's. When we first see the Hood family, they are perfectly normal. Kevin Kline is a loving husband, Joan Allen is a typical wife, Tobey Maguire loves comics, and Christina Ricci doesn't like Nixon. A perfectly normal family, in fact, they are nothing but. Kline is cheating on his wife with Sigourney Weaver, Allen is suspecting, but tries not to show it. Ricci is a fourteen year old experimenting with alcohol and sex. Maguire is in love with a girl, and she likes him too, like a brother. This all culminates during an ice storm. Everyone breaks down, in some form or another. Kline is unable to keep his secret from Allen, and she doesn't react with shock. In fact, she acts relieved. This is before she cheats on Kline during a car-key exchange, that seems right out of the seventies. That being said, every single one of the actors has their moment to shine. From Kline down to Elijah Wood, every actor delivers a masterful performance. This is all done through Ang Lee's direction. Lee is a great director, and here, he shows it. He perfectly captures the decade, in his use of music, costumes and sets. The cinematography is great as well. All being said, The Ice Storm is one of the best films of the nineties, and in my option, the best film of 1997. Watch it and immerse yourself in a world of pain, longing, lust and booze. In other words, just watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tedious exercise in dysfunction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spicyburrito
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First I should say, this movie could have been about my town and my family. I grew up in Connecticut and was 11 years old when the ice storm hit. My family was probably the typical dysfunctional unit of the 70's  emotionally clueless, parents headed for divorce (though we didn't know that yet), so I should have been able to relate to this film. The problem with the movie is there's no humor, no humanity. It's just one dysfunctional, sad, deviant event after another. It's like someone from another planet was assigned a homework exercise to depict dysfunctional families on Earth. I couldn't relate to the characters and there was no one to like. I'll give it 4 stars for the nice cinematography, the all-star cast, the good period sets and clothes. Although Toby Maguire gives his usual staring-into-space, deer-in-headlights, stupid-half-smile, what-am-I-supposed-to-be-doing-again? performance, I thought the rest of the cast did their best with the material  i.e. it wasn't the actors' fault!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sensible Movie That Explains Oedipus Complex In An Easy Way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vikram-ry123
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ice Storm is a metaphor of country life. I do not read the original novel by Rick Moody; but I think the film is an appropriate adaptation of that novel. Every plot is very carefully drawn in the film. A master work by director Ang Lee that I will never forget. The movie is like a fact file of hundreds of truths of our daily life. Every character in the film is a part of us. The storm begins with Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) reading Fantastic Four comic book in a late night empty frozen train. The movie is mostly about the relation between two neighboring families lives in a suburb town. The characters are very life-like that I suddenly feel everything is just happening in front of me. Ben Hood (Kevin Kline) is the father of two child Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) and Wendy Hood (Christina Ricci). The irony is that both of the child are in their adolescent and their parents are unable to guide them at this stage. The same thing we can see in the Carver family. Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver) and Jim Carver (Jamey Sheridan) have two boys Sandy Carver (Adam Hann-Byrd) and Mikey Carver (Elijah Wood). That very night all the guardians went for an ironical Key Party that make them funny and irresistible to control their basic instincts. And the children are children, they follow the way that showed by the society and misguided by their parents. Young Wendy (Christina Ricci) is a grown up girl of 14 and she is in her adolescent but her parents hardly care to guide her in proper way. Paul (Tobey Maguire) 18 years old boy successfully controls his lust inspired by reading Fantastic Four comic is very sentimental. Albeit Ben (Kevin Kline) his father tries to tell him about the duties of a gentleman but he fails to make him understand appropriately. Ben has a bitter relation with his wife Elena (Joan Allen) that comes as an opportunity to grow an extramarital relation with his next door neighbor Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver). The ice storm changed everything in a single night. Janey leaves the party with a young man to fulfill lust and desire. In the lustful late night game played by all the mature men and women of the society where Ben acts like a fool and humiliated. Same night Jim Carver, Janey's husband and Elena Hood Ben's wife become out of control of their basic instinct. The film concluded in a poetic justice with a sacrifice of 14 years old Mikey Carver died in an accident in the ice storm night due to his careless parents. Next day Ben found the dead body. And Elena found her 14 years old daughter Wendy and young Caver boy Sandy (Adam Hann- Byrd) sleeping naked in Caver's house. Caver family lost their one son and Hood family realize that how much careless they are? In a particular scene of this movie carries a good lesson. One day Elena sees her daughter riding bicycle that reminds her own teenage years and next day she rides the bicycle and entered into a shopping mall and stole some products to enjoy her young age behavior but caught by the shop kipper and humiliated. The irony shows the young girl Wendy gets the same behavior like her mother. The movie is very practical and worth to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ensemble Acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's easy to compare The Ice Storm to American Beauty and Happiness, both of which also dealt with disillusionment and the disintegration of the American Dream and the traditional family cell in the suburbs, and to a lesser extent The Sweet Hereafter which explored some similar themes in small town Canada. The Ice Storm is as cynical as those other films, but it's much more subtle in masking its sardonicism, and has aged much better than American Beauty, which had the appearance of a masterpiece at its release but looks flat and shallow now. The people in The Ice Storm feel more real and more human than the ones in American Beauty and Happiness; and the film walks that fine line between character-based slice-of-life storytelling and metaphorical satire, which works only because the viewer cares for the characters and their fates, while also absorbing the bigger issues under the surface. That would not work without a strong ensemble cast; the actors in The Ice Storm are not among my favorites, yet they all outdo themselves and produce sympathetic, powerful, convincing performances - Kevin Kline, Joan Allen and Sigourney Weaver are all at their very best, and the younger actors (Elijah Wood, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci, Adam Hann-Byrd and - amazingly - even Katie Holmes) all deliver too. In contrast with the (intentionally) despicable characters in Happiness and American Beauty, these actors form a group of very average people that the viewer relates to and cares about - but the dysfunction and sickness is right there beneath the surface, waiting for the right catastrophe to explode. There's an undefinable something that stops The Ice Storm short of becoming one of my favorites. The ending fits the mood of the rest of the film, but doesn't offer the catharsis that is needed, and it left me with a bitter taste. In the end, I found myself wishing that the film said more, and left more of a mark; the fact that it isn't often recognized as one of the best films of the 90's is simply because there's something not quite memorable about it. It's incredibly engaging throughout, though, and is definitely one of the strongest dramas of its time, beautifully shot, and a gem that's well worth discovering.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canadian58
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the thousands of movies I have seen, there are a select few I will remember for the rest of my life as being the worst movies I have ever seen. The Ice Storm tops this list. Nothing is good about it, and I'm sorry that I'll never get that two hours of my life back. I should have trusted my instinct and turned it off after the first 20 minutes of being mind-numbing bored. There are a lot of good actors, all of which the talent is completely wasted. Not one of the characters is likable, except maybe Tobey Maguire. Everyone is cheating on someone, and oh, yeah, there's an ice storm going on outside during the last half an hour of the film. We see one car go in the ditch, one branch fall, and one downed power line, is all it amounts to. Do yourself a favor and avoid this one. And to all you people giving this film a great review, HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MINDS?????!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three drift out of consciousness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is meant to offer a soft contrast as flow, between external life with people (family members gathered for Thanksgiving) anxiously pulled in disparate orbits, and the inner life of unfathomable urges and emotion that gives rise to the firstappearances versus true self, rooted in relationships and attempting connection. Set in 1970's America with Nixon lying on TV, the broader commentary is that the world is organized on deceit, misplaced faith. There is contextual talk of people as intertwined molecules, of inner life as inverted space where the invisible becomes visible. So here's the cinematic gambit, how to make visible a part of that inner life? It's what every filmmaker worth anything has puzzled about in his work, in-sight into human soul, no small challenge for Lee, though the film may otherwise seem typical. There are three connected story lines to that effect, each one culminating in a ritual of seduction as betrayal. Each storyline, climaxes with a loved one drifting out of consciousness in some way (drunk husband, Libbets, the son). This only emphasizes what we've been seeing for the whole film, people drifting apart heedless of one another. It all plays in the latter stages against the backdrop of a coming ice storm, it can't be helped, there's some inevitable unhappiness ahead of us. The overall point? In each case, as loved ones momentarily or not go out of life, those left behind are suddenly surrounded with that negative space of absence, and in that space pour their inner self and effect human connection. It may all seem a little cloying in the finale. But the best part is getting there, the protracted sequence with cross-cutting between the three stories of betrayed seduction. So how to make visible what in life eludes us, the fabric of feelings as cinematic fabric? This was very likely Lee's interest in the project, as well as more broadly the idea of dislocation. I was happy to see a cinematic solution that was nowhere in multithreaded films like Crash or Cloud Atlas. The idea seems to be, show each new scene from a point on, as extension, as in-sight or meditation on previous ones, as though a single soul is dreaming. So this is nice. The film is the empty space, as we think dull, day-to- day life to be. The characters as molecules drifting in the air, often apart. The loss of consciousness not simply as loss, but as meaningful awakening to that empty space where we, as molecules, do not aimlessly drift, but by virtue of being there, hold each other into place giving shape to life. Lee as usual has compromised, enough to deliver a movie with some broad appeal. The overall wrap is a bit too fabricated for my taste. But see how gentle are the contrasts between hard sorrow and soft inner life, where the very similar Melancholia eats at you, this soothes. It's all here natural to Lee, who as a Chinese knows this stuff in meditation and tai chi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Contrived Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thanksgiving weekend in Connecticut in 1973, two families work through their problems. Talk about dysfunctional families! This one has two such clans, and every member of each family is assigned an issue (kleptomaniac, sex addict, social misfit, absentee parent, depression, etc.). It makes for a very contrived drama. The impressive cast manages to overcome some of the shortcomings of the script, but it all seems so heavy-handed. As a couple whose marriage has fizzled, Kline and Allen come off the best. The makeup department went a little overboard trying to evoke the 1970s look, with Weaver looking particularly odd as a woman who's cold as ice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ordinary and uneventful in the most accurate sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is set during Thanksgiving 1973 and centers on two upper middle class Connecticut families who are trying to run their course in the Nixon era and free themselves from their blah feelings through drinking, adultery and sexual experiments. Both the parents and the children have dull lifestyles, they are financially secured, and there is a serious lack of joy and enthusiasm in activities and communication, incl. sexual relations, jobs/studies. The cast is strong: Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, and that-time minors Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, who all give catchy and splendid performances. The title has both direct and indirect meaning and the director Ang Lee has fulfilled another great task, the only problem seemed to be with the release year - 1997 - when, among others, Titanic was released and the movie in question obtained less praise and publicity it should have had. But it is never to late to watch a valuable movie (again), especially if the plot dealt with the past events anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great and overlooked genre movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really sure why this movie got pretty much ignored, at the time of its release. Not just by the movie goers, which is perhaps somewhat understandable but more so by all of big award ceremonies. By all means this movie should had swept a couple of them and it truly earned some more recognition. Drama's normally aren't even really my kind of thing but I just got captivated by this movie and was really liking it. Guess the main reason why I like it was because it wasn't being a pretentious or melodramatic one and it deliberately kept things small, which gave the overall movie also a sense of realism to it. For me it was a movie about people in search of themselves. Basically all of the characters are unhappy with their current situations and are searching for ways to break out and to get more in touch with themselves. This goes for the movie its youngster, which also makes this a sort of coming of age movie but also for their parents. Every character goes through some sort of inner transitions and the movie does a great job at balancing it all out. Basically everybody has a fair share of screen time in this movie. There aren't really one or two main characters but more like five or six of them. Every storyline is about as equally interesting and good to follow as the other. At least in my opinion of course. I personally got grabbed by it all, also since it isn't really being a standard drama, that is being predictable to watch from start till finish. It's also a movie that is being made great and intriguing to watch by its cast-members. It truly has an impressive cast-list, with actors such as Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, among many others. A cast to kill for and everybody did a great job, playing their character. A really overlooked Ang Lee movie, that is definitely worth checking out! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's too vague too vague
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film begins as slowly as it can; until the first hour, nothing much really happens and you have no idea of what to expect about this picture. I believe Ang Lee didn't have a story in mind and just utilized some ideas from Moody's novel. In many scenes we can notice that the filmmakers don't know what to do, so they just have the characters talking to each other. The cast is profession, we can see they really get into their characters, but that's not enough to make this movie any good. The only thing that enjoyed me is the braveness they have at showing how kids start their sexual life. You know, I'm only 19, so I can vaguely remember how these things worked in my mind when I was a kid. You're always worried what would happen if your parents found out, and in the end, they're doing their best to not see it. And let's not be hypocrite and believe that kids don't have sexual tension between themselves...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Film With Great Actors Giving Great Performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elevenangrymen
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved The Ice Storm. It's one of my favorite films. It takes place one thanksgiving, in the early 70's. When we first see the Hood family, they are perfectly normal. Kevin Kline is a loving husband, Joan Allen is a typical wife, Tobey Maguire loves comics, and Christina Ricci doesn't like Nixon. A perfectly normal family, in fact, they are nothing but. Kline is cheating on his wife with Sigourney Weaver, Allen is suspecting, but tries not to show it. Ricci is a fourteen year old experimenting with alcohol and sex. Maguire is in love with a girl, and she likes him too, like a brother. This all culminates during an ice storm. Everyone breaks down, in some form or another. Kline is unable to keep his secret from Allen, and she doesn't react with shock. In fact, she acts relieved. This is before she cheats on Kline during a car-key exchange, that seems right out of the seventies. That being said, every single one of the actors has their moment to shine. From Kline down to Elijah Wood, every actor delivers a masterful performance. This is all done through Ang Lee's direction. Lee is a great director, and here, he shows it. He perfectly captures the decade, in his use of music, costumes and sets. The cinematography is great as well. All being said, The Ice Storm is one of the best films of the nineties, and in my option, the best film of 1997. Watch it and immerse yourself in a world of pain, longing, lust and booze. In other words, just watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tedious exercise in dysfunction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spicyburrito
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First I should say, this movie could have been about my town and my family. I grew up in Connecticut and was 11 years old when the ice storm hit. My family was probably the typical dysfunctional unit of the 70's  emotionally clueless, parents headed for divorce (though we didn't know that yet), so I should have been able to relate to this film. The problem with the movie is there's no humor, no humanity. It's just one dysfunctional, sad, deviant event after another. It's like someone from another planet was assigned a homework exercise to depict dysfunctional families on Earth. I couldn't relate to the characters and there was no one to like. I'll give it 4 stars for the nice cinematography, the all-star cast, the good period sets and clothes. Although Toby Maguire gives his usual staring-into-space, deer-in-headlights, stupid-half-smile, what-am-I-supposed-to-be-doing-again? performance, I thought the rest of the cast did their best with the material  i.e. it wasn't the actors' fault!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sensible Movie That Explains Oedipus Complex In An Easy Way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vikram-ry123
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ice Storm is a metaphor of country life. I do not read the original novel by Rick Moody; but I think the film is an appropriate adaptation of that novel. Every plot is very carefully drawn in the film. A master work by director Ang Lee that I will never forget. The movie is like a fact file of hundreds of truths of our daily life. Every character in the film is a part of us. The storm begins with Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) reading Fantastic Four comic book in a late night empty frozen train. The movie is mostly about the relation between two neighboring families lives in a suburb town. The characters are very life-like that I suddenly feel everything is just happening in front of me. Ben Hood (Kevin Kline) is the father of two child Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) and Wendy Hood (Christina Ricci). The irony is that both of the child are in their adolescent and their parents are unable to guide them at this stage. The same thing we can see in the Carver family. Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver) and Jim Carver (Jamey Sheridan) have two boys Sandy Carver (Adam Hann-Byrd) and Mikey Carver (Elijah Wood). That very night all the guardians went for an ironical Key Party that make them funny and irresistible to control their basic instincts. And the children are children, they follow the way that showed by the society and misguided by their parents. Young Wendy (Christina Ricci) is a grown up girl of 14 and she is in her adolescent but her parents hardly care to guide her in proper way. Paul (Tobey Maguire) 18 years old boy successfully controls his lust inspired by reading Fantastic Four comic is very sentimental. Albeit Ben (Kevin Kline) his father tries to tell him about the duties of a gentleman but he fails to make him understand appropriately. Ben has a bitter relation with his wife Elena (Joan Allen) that comes as an opportunity to grow an extramarital relation with his next door neighbor Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver). The ice storm changed everything in a single night. Janey leaves the party with a young man to fulfill lust and desire. In the lustful late night game played by all the mature men and women of the society where Ben acts like a fool and humiliated. Same night Jim Carver, Janey's husband and Elena Hood Ben's wife become out of control of their basic instinct. The film concluded in a poetic justice with a sacrifice of 14 years old Mikey Carver died in an accident in the ice storm night due to his careless parents. Next day Ben found the dead body. And Elena found her 14 years old daughter Wendy and young Caver boy Sandy (Adam Hann- Byrd) sleeping naked in Caver's house. Caver family lost their one son and Hood family realize that how much careless they are? In a particular scene of this movie carries a good lesson. One day Elena sees her daughter riding bicycle that reminds her own teenage years and next day she rides the bicycle and entered into a shopping mall and stole some products to enjoy her young age behavior but caught by the shop kipper and humiliated. The irony shows the young girl Wendy gets the same behavior like her mother. The movie is very practical and worth to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ensemble Acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's easy to compare The Ice Storm to American Beauty and Happiness, both of which also dealt with disillusionment and the disintegration of the American Dream and the traditional family cell in the suburbs, and to a lesser extent The Sweet Hereafter which explored some similar themes in small town Canada. The Ice Storm is as cynical as those other films, but it's much more subtle in masking its sardonicism, and has aged much better than American Beauty, which had the appearance of a masterpiece at its release but looks flat and shallow now. The people in The Ice Storm feel more real and more human than the ones in American Beauty and Happiness; and the film walks that fine line between character-based slice-of-life storytelling and metaphorical satire, which works only because the viewer cares for the characters and their fates, while also absorbing the bigger issues under the surface. That would not work without a strong ensemble cast; the actors in The Ice Storm are not among my favorites, yet they all outdo themselves and produce sympathetic, powerful, convincing performances - Kevin Kline, Joan Allen and Sigourney Weaver are all at their very best, and the younger actors (Elijah Wood, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci, Adam Hann-Byrd and - amazingly - even Katie Holmes) all deliver too. In contrast with the (intentionally) despicable characters in Happiness and American Beauty, these actors form a group of very average people that the viewer relates to and cares about - but the dysfunction and sickness is right there beneath the surface, waiting for the right catastrophe to explode. There's an undefinable something that stops The Ice Storm short of becoming one of my favorites. The ending fits the mood of the rest of the film, but doesn't offer the catharsis that is needed, and it left me with a bitter taste. In the end, I found myself wishing that the film said more, and left more of a mark; the fact that it isn't often recognized as one of the best films of the 90's is simply because there's something not quite memorable about it. It's incredibly engaging throughout, though, and is definitely one of the strongest dramas of its time, beautifully shot, and a gem that's well worth discovering.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canadian58
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the thousands of movies I have seen, there are a select few I will remember for the rest of my life as being the worst movies I have ever seen. The Ice Storm tops this list. Nothing is good about it, and I'm sorry that I'll never get that two hours of my life back. I should have trusted my instinct and turned it off after the first 20 minutes of being mind-numbing bored. There are a lot of good actors, all of which the talent is completely wasted. Not one of the characters is likable, except maybe Tobey Maguire. Everyone is cheating on someone, and oh, yeah, there's an ice storm going on outside during the last half an hour of the film. We see one car go in the ditch, one branch fall, and one downed power line, is all it amounts to. Do yourself a favor and avoid this one. And to all you people giving this film a great review, HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MINDS?????!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three drift out of consciousness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is meant to offer a soft contrast as flow, between external life with people (family members gathered for Thanksgiving) anxiously pulled in disparate orbits, and the inner life of unfathomable urges and emotion that gives rise to the firstappearances versus true self, rooted in relationships and attempting connection. Set in 1970's America with Nixon lying on TV, the broader commentary is that the world is organized on deceit, misplaced faith. There is contextual talk of people as intertwined molecules, of inner life as inverted space where the invisible becomes visible. So here's the cinematic gambit, how to make visible a part of that inner life? It's what every filmmaker worth anything has puzzled about in his work, in-sight into human soul, no small challenge for Lee, though the film may otherwise seem typical. There are three connected story lines to that effect, each one culminating in a ritual of seduction as betrayal. Each storyline, climaxes with a loved one drifting out of consciousness in some way (drunk husband, Libbets, the son). This only emphasizes what we've been seeing for the whole film, people drifting apart heedless of one another. It all plays in the latter stages against the backdrop of a coming ice storm, it can't be helped, there's some inevitable unhappiness ahead of us. The overall point? In each case, as loved ones momentarily or not go out of life, those left behind are suddenly surrounded with that negative space of absence, and in that space pour their inner self and effect human connection. It may all seem a little cloying in the finale. But the best part is getting there, the protracted sequence with cross-cutting between the three stories of betrayed seduction. So how to make visible what in life eludes us, the fabric of feelings as cinematic fabric? This was very likely Lee's interest in the project, as well as more broadly the idea of dislocation. I was happy to see a cinematic solution that was nowhere in multithreaded films like Crash or Cloud Atlas. The idea seems to be, show each new scene from a point on, as extension, as in-sight or meditation on previous ones, as though a single soul is dreaming. So this is nice. The film is the empty space, as we think dull, day-to- day life to be. The characters as molecules drifting in the air, often apart. The loss of consciousness not simply as loss, but as meaningful awakening to that empty space where we, as molecules, do not aimlessly drift, but by virtue of being there, hold each other into place giving shape to life. Lee as usual has compromised, enough to deliver a movie with some broad appeal. The overall wrap is a bit too fabricated for my taste. But see how gentle are the contrasts between hard sorrow and soft inner life, where the very similar Melancholia eats at you, this soothes. It's all here natural to Lee, who as a Chinese knows this stuff in meditation and tai chi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Contrived Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thanksgiving weekend in Connecticut in 1973, two families work through their problems. Talk about dysfunctional families! This one has two such clans, and every member of each family is assigned an issue (kleptomaniac, sex addict, social misfit, absentee parent, depression, etc.). It makes for a very contrived drama. The impressive cast manages to overcome some of the shortcomings of the script, but it all seems so heavy-handed. As a couple whose marriage has fizzled, Kline and Allen come off the best. The makeup department went a little overboard trying to evoke the 1970s look, with Weaver looking particularly odd as a woman who's cold as ice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ordinary and uneventful in the most accurate sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is set during Thanksgiving 1973 and centers on two upper middle class Connecticut families who are trying to run their course in the Nixon era and free themselves from their blah feelings through drinking, adultery and sexual experiments. Both the parents and the children have dull lifestyles, they are financially secured, and there is a serious lack of joy and enthusiasm in activities and communication, incl. sexual relations, jobs/studies. The cast is strong: Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, and that-time minors Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, who all give catchy and splendid performances. The title has both direct and indirect meaning and the director Ang Lee has fulfilled another great task, the only problem seemed to be with the release year - 1997 - when, among others, Titanic was released and the movie in question obtained less praise and publicity it should have had. But it is never to late to watch a valuable movie (again), especially if the plot dealt with the past events anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great and overlooked genre movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really sure why this movie got pretty much ignored, at the time of its release. Not just by the movie goers, which is perhaps somewhat understandable but more so by all of big award ceremonies. By all means this movie should had swept a couple of them and it truly earned some more recognition. Drama's normally aren't even really my kind of thing but I just got captivated by this movie and was really liking it. Guess the main reason why I like it was because it wasn't being a pretentious or melodramatic one and it deliberately kept things small, which gave the overall movie also a sense of realism to it. For me it was a movie about people in search of themselves. Basically all of the characters are unhappy with their current situations and are searching for ways to break out and to get more in touch with themselves. This goes for the movie its youngster, which also makes this a sort of coming of age movie but also for their parents. Every character goes through some sort of inner transitions and the movie does a great job at balancing it all out. Basically everybody has a fair share of screen time in this movie. There aren't really one or two main characters but more like five or six of them. Every storyline is about as equally interesting and good to follow as the other. At least in my opinion of course. I personally got grabbed by it all, also since it isn't really being a standard drama, that is being predictable to watch from start till finish. It's also a movie that is being made great and intriguing to watch by its cast-members. It truly has an impressive cast-list, with actors such as Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, among many others. A cast to kill for and everybody did a great job, playing their character. A really overlooked Ang Lee movie, that is definitely worth checking out! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's too vague too vague
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film begins as slowly as it can; until the first hour, nothing much really happens and you have no idea of what to expect about this picture. I believe Ang Lee didn't have a story in mind and just utilized some ideas from Moody's novel. In many scenes we can notice that the filmmakers don't know what to do, so they just have the characters talking to each other. The cast is profession, we can see they really get into their characters, but that's not enough to make this movie any good. The only thing that enjoyed me is the braveness they have at showing how kids start their sexual life. You know, I'm only 19, so I can vaguely remember how these things worked in my mind when I was a kid. You're always worried what would happen if your parents found out, and in the end, they're doing their best to not see it. And let's not be hypocrite and believe that kids don't have sexual tension between themselves...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Film With Great Actors Giving Great Performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elevenangrymen
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved The Ice Storm. It's one of my favorite films. It takes place one thanksgiving, in the early 70's. When we first see the Hood family, they are perfectly normal. Kevin Kline is a loving husband, Joan Allen is a typical wife, Tobey Maguire loves comics, and Christina Ricci doesn't like Nixon. A perfectly normal family, in fact, they are nothing but. Kline is cheating on his wife with Sigourney Weaver, Allen is suspecting, but tries not to show it. Ricci is a fourteen year old experimenting with alcohol and sex. Maguire is in love with a girl, and she likes him too, like a brother. This all culminates during an ice storm. Everyone breaks down, in some form or another. Kline is unable to keep his secret from Allen, and she doesn't react with shock. In fact, she acts relieved. This is before she cheats on Kline during a car-key exchange, that seems right out of the seventies. That being said, every single one of the actors has their moment to shine. From Kline down to Elijah Wood, every actor delivers a masterful performance. This is all done through Ang Lee's direction. Lee is a great director, and here, he shows it. He perfectly captures the decade, in his use of music, costumes and sets. The cinematography is great as well. All being said, The Ice Storm is one of the best films of the nineties, and in my option, the best film of 1997. Watch it and immerse yourself in a world of pain, longing, lust and booze. In other words, just watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tedious exercise in dysfunction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spicyburrito
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First I should say, this movie could have been about my town and my family. I grew up in Connecticut and was 11 years old when the ice storm hit. My family was probably the typical dysfunctional unit of the 70's  emotionally clueless, parents headed for divorce (though we didn't know that yet), so I should have been able to relate to this film. The problem with the movie is there's no humor, no humanity. It's just one dysfunctional, sad, deviant event after another. It's like someone from another planet was assigned a homework exercise to depict dysfunctional families on Earth. I couldn't relate to the characters and there was no one to like. I'll give it 4 stars for the nice cinematography, the all-star cast, the good period sets and clothes. Although Toby Maguire gives his usual staring-into-space, deer-in-headlights, stupid-half-smile, what-am-I-supposed-to-be-doing-again? performance, I thought the rest of the cast did their best with the material  i.e. it wasn't the actors' fault!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sensible Movie That Explains Oedipus Complex In An Easy Way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vikram-ry123
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ice Storm is a metaphor of country life. I do not read the original novel by Rick Moody; but I think the film is an appropriate adaptation of that novel. Every plot is very carefully drawn in the film. A master work by director Ang Lee that I will never forget. The movie is like a fact file of hundreds of truths of our daily life. Every character in the film is a part of us. The storm begins with Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) reading Fantastic Four comic book in a late night empty frozen train. The movie is mostly about the relation between two neighboring families lives in a suburb town. The characters are very life-like that I suddenly feel everything is just happening in front of me. Ben Hood (Kevin Kline) is the father of two child Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) and Wendy Hood (Christina Ricci). The irony is that both of the child are in their adolescent and their parents are unable to guide them at this stage. The same thing we can see in the Carver family. Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver) and Jim Carver (Jamey Sheridan) have two boys Sandy Carver (Adam Hann-Byrd) and Mikey Carver (Elijah Wood). That very night all the guardians went for an ironical Key Party that make them funny and irresistible to control their basic instincts. And the children are children, they follow the way that showed by the society and misguided by their parents. Young Wendy (Christina Ricci) is a grown up girl of 14 and she is in her adolescent but her parents hardly care to guide her in proper way. Paul (Tobey Maguire) 18 years old boy successfully controls his lust inspired by reading Fantastic Four comic is very sentimental. Albeit Ben (Kevin Kline) his father tries to tell him about the duties of a gentleman but he fails to make him understand appropriately. Ben has a bitter relation with his wife Elena (Joan Allen) that comes as an opportunity to grow an extramarital relation with his next door neighbor Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver). The ice storm changed everything in a single night. Janey leaves the party with a young man to fulfill lust and desire. In the lustful late night game played by all the mature men and women of the society where Ben acts like a fool and humiliated. Same night Jim Carver, Janey's husband and Elena Hood Ben's wife become out of control of their basic instinct. The film concluded in a poetic justice with a sacrifice of 14 years old Mikey Carver died in an accident in the ice storm night due to his careless parents. Next day Ben found the dead body. And Elena found her 14 years old daughter Wendy and young Caver boy Sandy (Adam Hann- Byrd) sleeping naked in Caver's house. Caver family lost their one son and Hood family realize that how much careless they are? In a particular scene of this movie carries a good lesson. One day Elena sees her daughter riding bicycle that reminds her own teenage years and next day she rides the bicycle and entered into a shopping mall and stole some products to enjoy her young age behavior but caught by the shop kipper and humiliated. The irony shows the young girl Wendy gets the same behavior like her mother. The movie is very practical and worth to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ensemble Acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's easy to compare The Ice Storm to American Beauty and Happiness, both of which also dealt with disillusionment and the disintegration of the American Dream and the traditional family cell in the suburbs, and to a lesser extent The Sweet Hereafter which explored some similar themes in small town Canada. The Ice Storm is as cynical as those other films, but it's much more subtle in masking its sardonicism, and has aged much better than American Beauty, which had the appearance of a masterpiece at its release but looks flat and shallow now. The people in The Ice Storm feel more real and more human than the ones in American Beauty and Happiness; and the film walks that fine line between character-based slice-of-life storytelling and metaphorical satire, which works only because the viewer cares for the characters and their fates, while also absorbing the bigger issues under the surface. That would not work without a strong ensemble cast; the actors in The Ice Storm are not among my favorites, yet they all outdo themselves and produce sympathetic, powerful, convincing performances - Kevin Kline, Joan Allen and Sigourney Weaver are all at their very best, and the younger actors (Elijah Wood, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci, Adam Hann-Byrd and - amazingly - even Katie Holmes) all deliver too. In contrast with the (intentionally) despicable characters in Happiness and American Beauty, these actors form a group of very average people that the viewer relates to and cares about - but the dysfunction and sickness is right there beneath the surface, waiting for the right catastrophe to explode. There's an undefinable something that stops The Ice Storm short of becoming one of my favorites. The ending fits the mood of the rest of the film, but doesn't offer the catharsis that is needed, and it left me with a bitter taste. In the end, I found myself wishing that the film said more, and left more of a mark; the fact that it isn't often recognized as one of the best films of the 90's is simply because there's something not quite memorable about it. It's incredibly engaging throughout, though, and is definitely one of the strongest dramas of its time, beautifully shot, and a gem that's well worth discovering.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canadian58
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the thousands of movies I have seen, there are a select few I will remember for the rest of my life as being the worst movies I have ever seen. The Ice Storm tops this list. Nothing is good about it, and I'm sorry that I'll never get that two hours of my life back. I should have trusted my instinct and turned it off after the first 20 minutes of being mind-numbing bored. There are a lot of good actors, all of which the talent is completely wasted. Not one of the characters is likable, except maybe Tobey Maguire. Everyone is cheating on someone, and oh, yeah, there's an ice storm going on outside during the last half an hour of the film. We see one car go in the ditch, one branch fall, and one downed power line, is all it amounts to. Do yourself a favor and avoid this one. And to all you people giving this film a great review, HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MINDS?????!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three drift out of consciousness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is meant to offer a soft contrast as flow, between external life with people (family members gathered for Thanksgiving) anxiously pulled in disparate orbits, and the inner life of unfathomable urges and emotion that gives rise to the firstappearances versus true self, rooted in relationships and attempting connection. Set in 1970's America with Nixon lying on TV, the broader commentary is that the world is organized on deceit, misplaced faith. There is contextual talk of people as intertwined molecules, of inner life as inverted space where the invisible becomes visible. So here's the cinematic gambit, how to make visible a part of that inner life? It's what every filmmaker worth anything has puzzled about in his work, in-sight into human soul, no small challenge for Lee, though the film may otherwise seem typical. There are three connected story lines to that effect, each one culminating in a ritual of seduction as betrayal. Each storyline, climaxes with a loved one drifting out of consciousness in some way (drunk husband, Libbets, the son). This only emphasizes what we've been seeing for the whole film, people drifting apart heedless of one another. It all plays in the latter stages against the backdrop of a coming ice storm, it can't be helped, there's some inevitable unhappiness ahead of us. The overall point? In each case, as loved ones momentarily or not go out of life, those left behind are suddenly surrounded with that negative space of absence, and in that space pour their inner self and effect human connection. It may all seem a little cloying in the finale. But the best part is getting there, the protracted sequence with cross-cutting between the three stories of betrayed seduction. So how to make visible what in life eludes us, the fabric of feelings as cinematic fabric? This was very likely Lee's interest in the project, as well as more broadly the idea of dislocation. I was happy to see a cinematic solution that was nowhere in multithreaded films like Crash or Cloud Atlas. The idea seems to be, show each new scene from a point on, as extension, as in-sight or meditation on previous ones, as though a single soul is dreaming. So this is nice. The film is the empty space, as we think dull, day-to- day life to be. The characters as molecules drifting in the air, often apart. The loss of consciousness not simply as loss, but as meaningful awakening to that empty space where we, as molecules, do not aimlessly drift, but by virtue of being there, hold each other into place giving shape to life. Lee as usual has compromised, enough to deliver a movie with some broad appeal. The overall wrap is a bit too fabricated for my taste. But see how gentle are the contrasts between hard sorrow and soft inner life, where the very similar Melancholia eats at you, this soothes. It's all here natural to Lee, who as a Chinese knows this stuff in meditation and tai chi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Contrived Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thanksgiving weekend in Connecticut in 1973, two families work through their problems. Talk about dysfunctional families! This one has two such clans, and every member of each family is assigned an issue (kleptomaniac, sex addict, social misfit, absentee parent, depression, etc.). It makes for a very contrived drama. The impressive cast manages to overcome some of the shortcomings of the script, but it all seems so heavy-handed. As a couple whose marriage has fizzled, Kline and Allen come off the best. The makeup department went a little overboard trying to evoke the 1970s look, with Weaver looking particularly odd as a woman who's cold as ice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ordinary and uneventful in the most accurate sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is set during Thanksgiving 1973 and centers on two upper middle class Connecticut families who are trying to run their course in the Nixon era and free themselves from their blah feelings through drinking, adultery and sexual experiments. Both the parents and the children have dull lifestyles, they are financially secured, and there is a serious lack of joy and enthusiasm in activities and communication, incl. sexual relations, jobs/studies. The cast is strong: Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, and that-time minors Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, who all give catchy and splendid performances. The title has both direct and indirect meaning and the director Ang Lee has fulfilled another great task, the only problem seemed to be with the release year - 1997 - when, among others, Titanic was released and the movie in question obtained less praise and publicity it should have had. But it is never to late to watch a valuable movie (again), especially if the plot dealt with the past events anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great and overlooked genre movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really sure why this movie got pretty much ignored, at the time of its release. Not just by the movie goers, which is perhaps somewhat understandable but more so by all of big award ceremonies. By all means this movie should had swept a couple of them and it truly earned some more recognition. Drama's normally aren't even really my kind of thing but I just got captivated by this movie and was really liking it. Guess the main reason why I like it was because it wasn't being a pretentious or melodramatic one and it deliberately kept things small, which gave the overall movie also a sense of realism to it. For me it was a movie about people in search of themselves. Basically all of the characters are unhappy with their current situations and are searching for ways to break out and to get more in touch with themselves. This goes for the movie its youngster, which also makes this a sort of coming of age movie but also for their parents. Every character goes through some sort of inner transitions and the movie does a great job at balancing it all out. Basically everybody has a fair share of screen time in this movie. There aren't really one or two main characters but more like five or six of them. Every storyline is about as equally interesting and good to follow as the other. At least in my opinion of course. I personally got grabbed by it all, also since it isn't really being a standard drama, that is being predictable to watch from start till finish. It's also a movie that is being made great and intriguing to watch by its cast-members. It truly has an impressive cast-list, with actors such as Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, among many others. A cast to kill for and everybody did a great job, playing their character. A really overlooked Ang Lee movie, that is definitely worth checking out! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's too vague too vague
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film begins as slowly as it can; until the first hour, nothing much really happens and you have no idea of what to expect about this picture. I believe Ang Lee didn't have a story in mind and just utilized some ideas from Moody's novel. In many scenes we can notice that the filmmakers don't know what to do, so they just have the characters talking to each other. The cast is profession, we can see they really get into their characters, but that's not enough to make this movie any good. The only thing that enjoyed me is the braveness they have at showing how kids start their sexual life. You know, I'm only 19, so I can vaguely remember how these things worked in my mind when I was a kid. You're always worried what would happen if your parents found out, and in the end, they're doing their best to not see it. And let's not be hypocrite and believe that kids don't have sexual tension between themselves...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Film With Great Actors Giving Great Performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elevenangrymen
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved The Ice Storm. It's one of my favorite films. It takes place one thanksgiving, in the early 70's. When we first see the Hood family, they are perfectly normal. Kevin Kline is a loving husband, Joan Allen is a typical wife, Tobey Maguire loves comics, and Christina Ricci doesn't like Nixon. A perfectly normal family, in fact, they are nothing but. Kline is cheating on his wife with Sigourney Weaver, Allen is suspecting, but tries not to show it. Ricci is a fourteen year old experimenting with alcohol and sex. Maguire is in love with a girl, and she likes him too, like a brother. This all culminates during an ice storm. Everyone breaks down, in some form or another. Kline is unable to keep his secret from Allen, and she doesn't react with shock. In fact, she acts relieved. This is before she cheats on Kline during a car-key exchange, that seems right out of the seventies. That being said, every single one of the actors has their moment to shine. From Kline down to Elijah Wood, every actor delivers a masterful performance. This is all done through Ang Lee's direction. Lee is a great director, and here, he shows it. He perfectly captures the decade, in his use of music, costumes and sets. The cinematography is great as well. All being said, The Ice Storm is one of the best films of the nineties, and in my option, the best film of 1997. Watch it and immerse yourself in a world of pain, longing, lust and booze. In other words, just watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tedious exercise in dysfunction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spicyburrito
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First I should say, this movie could have been about my town and my family. I grew up in Connecticut and was 11 years old when the ice storm hit. My family was probably the typical dysfunctional unit of the 70's  emotionally clueless, parents headed for divorce (though we didn't know that yet), so I should have been able to relate to this film. The problem with the movie is there's no humor, no humanity. It's just one dysfunctional, sad, deviant event after another. It's like someone from another planet was assigned a homework exercise to depict dysfunctional families on Earth. I couldn't relate to the characters and there was no one to like. I'll give it 4 stars for the nice cinematography, the all-star cast, the good period sets and clothes. Although Toby Maguire gives his usual staring-into-space, deer-in-headlights, stupid-half-smile, what-am-I-supposed-to-be-doing-again? performance, I thought the rest of the cast did their best with the material  i.e. it wasn't the actors' fault!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sensible Movie That Explains Oedipus Complex In An Easy Way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vikram-ry123
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ice Storm is a metaphor of country life. I do not read the original novel by Rick Moody; but I think the film is an appropriate adaptation of that novel. Every plot is very carefully drawn in the film. A master work by director Ang Lee that I will never forget. The movie is like a fact file of hundreds of truths of our daily life. Every character in the film is a part of us. The storm begins with Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) reading Fantastic Four comic book in a late night empty frozen train. The movie is mostly about the relation between two neighboring families lives in a suburb town. The characters are very life-like that I suddenly feel everything is just happening in front of me. Ben Hood (Kevin Kline) is the father of two child Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) and Wendy Hood (Christina Ricci). The irony is that both of the child are in their adolescent and their parents are unable to guide them at this stage. The same thing we can see in the Carver family. Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver) and Jim Carver (Jamey Sheridan) have two boys Sandy Carver (Adam Hann-Byrd) and Mikey Carver (Elijah Wood). That very night all the guardians went for an ironical Key Party that make them funny and irresistible to control their basic instincts. And the children are children, they follow the way that showed by the society and misguided by their parents. Young Wendy (Christina Ricci) is a grown up girl of 14 and she is in her adolescent but her parents hardly care to guide her in proper way. Paul (Tobey Maguire) 18 years old boy successfully controls his lust inspired by reading Fantastic Four comic is very sentimental. Albeit Ben (Kevin Kline) his father tries to tell him about the duties of a gentleman but he fails to make him understand appropriately. Ben has a bitter relation with his wife Elena (Joan Allen) that comes as an opportunity to grow an extramarital relation with his next door neighbor Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver). The ice storm changed everything in a single night. Janey leaves the party with a young man to fulfill lust and desire. In the lustful late night game played by all the mature men and women of the society where Ben acts like a fool and humiliated. Same night Jim Carver, Janey's husband and Elena Hood Ben's wife become out of control of their basic instinct. The film concluded in a poetic justice with a sacrifice of 14 years old Mikey Carver died in an accident in the ice storm night due to his careless parents. Next day Ben found the dead body. And Elena found her 14 years old daughter Wendy and young Caver boy Sandy (Adam Hann- Byrd) sleeping naked in Caver's house. Caver family lost their one son and Hood family realize that how much careless they are? In a particular scene of this movie carries a good lesson. One day Elena sees her daughter riding bicycle that reminds her own teenage years and next day she rides the bicycle and entered into a shopping mall and stole some products to enjoy her young age behavior but caught by the shop kipper and humiliated. The irony shows the young girl Wendy gets the same behavior like her mother. The movie is very practical and worth to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ensemble Acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's easy to compare The Ice Storm to American Beauty and Happiness, both of which also dealt with disillusionment and the disintegration of the American Dream and the traditional family cell in the suburbs, and to a lesser extent The Sweet Hereafter which explored some similar themes in small town Canada. The Ice Storm is as cynical as those other films, but it's much more subtle in masking its sardonicism, and has aged much better than American Beauty, which had the appearance of a masterpiece at its release but looks flat and shallow now. The people in The Ice Storm feel more real and more human than the ones in American Beauty and Happiness; and the film walks that fine line between character-based slice-of-life storytelling and metaphorical satire, which works only because the viewer cares for the characters and their fates, while also absorbing the bigger issues under the surface. That would not work without a strong ensemble cast; the actors in The Ice Storm are not among my favorites, yet they all outdo themselves and produce sympathetic, powerful, convincing performances - Kevin Kline, Joan Allen and Sigourney Weaver are all at their very best, and the younger actors (Elijah Wood, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci, Adam Hann-Byrd and - amazingly - even Katie Holmes) all deliver too. In contrast with the (intentionally) despicable characters in Happiness and American Beauty, these actors form a group of very average people that the viewer relates to and cares about - but the dysfunction and sickness is right there beneath the surface, waiting for the right catastrophe to explode. There's an undefinable something that stops The Ice Storm short of becoming one of my favorites. The ending fits the mood of the rest of the film, but doesn't offer the catharsis that is needed, and it left me with a bitter taste. In the end, I found myself wishing that the film said more, and left more of a mark; the fact that it isn't often recognized as one of the best films of the 90's is simply because there's something not quite memorable about it. It's incredibly engaging throughout, though, and is definitely one of the strongest dramas of its time, beautifully shot, and a gem that's well worth discovering.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canadian58
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the thousands of movies I have seen, there are a select few I will remember for the rest of my life as being the worst movies I have ever seen. The Ice Storm tops this list. Nothing is good about it, and I'm sorry that I'll never get that two hours of my life back. I should have trusted my instinct and turned it off after the first 20 minutes of being mind-numbing bored. There are a lot of good actors, all of which the talent is completely wasted. Not one of the characters is likable, except maybe Tobey Maguire. Everyone is cheating on someone, and oh, yeah, there's an ice storm going on outside during the last half an hour of the film. We see one car go in the ditch, one branch fall, and one downed power line, is all it amounts to. Do yourself a favor and avoid this one. And to all you people giving this film a great review, HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MINDS?????!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three drift out of consciousness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is meant to offer a soft contrast as flow, between external life with people (family members gathered for Thanksgiving) anxiously pulled in disparate orbits, and the inner life of unfathomable urges and emotion that gives rise to the firstappearances versus true self, rooted in relationships and attempting connection. Set in 1970's America with Nixon lying on TV, the broader commentary is that the world is organized on deceit, misplaced faith. There is contextual talk of people as intertwined molecules, of inner life as inverted space where the invisible becomes visible. So here's the cinematic gambit, how to make visible a part of that inner life? It's what every filmmaker worth anything has puzzled about in his work, in-sight into human soul, no small challenge for Lee, though the film may otherwise seem typical. There are three connected story lines to that effect, each one culminating in a ritual of seduction as betrayal. Each storyline, climaxes with a loved one drifting out of consciousness in some way (drunk husband, Libbets, the son). This only emphasizes what we've been seeing for the whole film, people drifting apart heedless of one another. It all plays in the latter stages against the backdrop of a coming ice storm, it can't be helped, there's some inevitable unhappiness ahead of us. The overall point? In each case, as loved ones momentarily or not go out of life, those left behind are suddenly surrounded with that negative space of absence, and in that space pour their inner self and effect human connection. It may all seem a little cloying in the finale. But the best part is getting there, the protracted sequence with cross-cutting between the three stories of betrayed seduction. So how to make visible what in life eludes us, the fabric of feelings as cinematic fabric? This was very likely Lee's interest in the project, as well as more broadly the idea of dislocation. I was happy to see a cinematic solution that was nowhere in multithreaded films like Crash or Cloud Atlas. The idea seems to be, show each new scene from a point on, as extension, as in-sight or meditation on previous ones, as though a single soul is dreaming. So this is nice. The film is the empty space, as we think dull, day-to- day life to be. The characters as molecules drifting in the air, often apart. The loss of consciousness not simply as loss, but as meaningful awakening to that empty space where we, as molecules, do not aimlessly drift, but by virtue of being there, hold each other into place giving shape to life. Lee as usual has compromised, enough to deliver a movie with some broad appeal. The overall wrap is a bit too fabricated for my taste. But see how gentle are the contrasts between hard sorrow and soft inner life, where the very similar Melancholia eats at you, this soothes. It's all here natural to Lee, who as a Chinese knows this stuff in meditation and tai chi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Contrived Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thanksgiving weekend in Connecticut in 1973, two families work through their problems. Talk about dysfunctional families! This one has two such clans, and every member of each family is assigned an issue (kleptomaniac, sex addict, social misfit, absentee parent, depression, etc.). It makes for a very contrived drama. The impressive cast manages to overcome some of the shortcomings of the script, but it all seems so heavy-handed. As a couple whose marriage has fizzled, Kline and Allen come off the best. The makeup department went a little overboard trying to evoke the 1970s look, with Weaver looking particularly odd as a woman who's cold as ice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ordinary and uneventful in the most accurate sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is set during Thanksgiving 1973 and centers on two upper middle class Connecticut families who are trying to run their course in the Nixon era and free themselves from their blah feelings through drinking, adultery and sexual experiments. Both the parents and the children have dull lifestyles, they are financially secured, and there is a serious lack of joy and enthusiasm in activities and communication, incl. sexual relations, jobs/studies. The cast is strong: Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, and that-time minors Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, who all give catchy and splendid performances. The title has both direct and indirect meaning and the director Ang Lee has fulfilled another great task, the only problem seemed to be with the release year - 1997 - when, among others, Titanic was released and the movie in question obtained less praise and publicity it should have had. But it is never to late to watch a valuable movie (again), especially if the plot dealt with the past events anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great and overlooked genre movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really sure why this movie got pretty much ignored, at the time of its release. Not just by the movie goers, which is perhaps somewhat understandable but more so by all of big award ceremonies. By all means this movie should had swept a couple of them and it truly earned some more recognition. Drama's normally aren't even really my kind of thing but I just got captivated by this movie and was really liking it. Guess the main reason why I like it was because it wasn't being a pretentious or melodramatic one and it deliberately kept things small, which gave the overall movie also a sense of realism to it. For me it was a movie about people in search of themselves. Basically all of the characters are unhappy with their current situations and are searching for ways to break out and to get more in touch with themselves. This goes for the movie its youngster, which also makes this a sort of coming of age movie but also for their parents. Every character goes through some sort of inner transitions and the movie does a great job at balancing it all out. Basically everybody has a fair share of screen time in this movie. There aren't really one or two main characters but more like five or six of them. Every storyline is about as equally interesting and good to follow as the other. At least in my opinion of course. I personally got grabbed by it all, also since it isn't really being a standard drama, that is being predictable to watch from start till finish. It's also a movie that is being made great and intriguing to watch by its cast-members. It truly has an impressive cast-list, with actors such as Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, among many others. A cast to kill for and everybody did a great job, playing their character. A really overlooked Ang Lee movie, that is definitely worth checking out! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's too vague too vague
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film begins as slowly as it can; until the first hour, nothing much really happens and you have no idea of what to expect about this picture. I believe Ang Lee didn't have a story in mind and just utilized some ideas from Moody's novel. In many scenes we can notice that the filmmakers don't know what to do, so they just have the characters talking to each other. The cast is profession, we can see they really get into their characters, but that's not enough to make this movie any good. The only thing that enjoyed me is the braveness they have at showing how kids start their sexual life. You know, I'm only 19, so I can vaguely remember how these things worked in my mind when I was a kid. You're always worried what would happen if your parents found out, and in the end, they're doing their best to not see it. And let's not be hypocrite and believe that kids don't have sexual tension between themselves...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Film With Great Actors Giving Great Performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elevenangrymen
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved The Ice Storm. It's one of my favorite films. It takes place one thanksgiving, in the early 70's. When we first see the Hood family, they are perfectly normal. Kevin Kline is a loving husband, Joan Allen is a typical wife, Tobey Maguire loves comics, and Christina Ricci doesn't like Nixon. A perfectly normal family, in fact, they are nothing but. Kline is cheating on his wife with Sigourney Weaver, Allen is suspecting, but tries not to show it. Ricci is a fourteen year old experimenting with alcohol and sex. Maguire is in love with a girl, and she likes him too, like a brother. This all culminates during an ice storm. Everyone breaks down, in some form or another. Kline is unable to keep his secret from Allen, and she doesn't react with shock. In fact, she acts relieved. This is before she cheats on Kline during a car-key exchange, that seems right out of the seventies. That being said, every single one of the actors has their moment to shine. From Kline down to Elijah Wood, every actor delivers a masterful performance. This is all done through Ang Lee's direction. Lee is a great director, and here, he shows it. He perfectly captures the decade, in his use of music, costumes and sets. The cinematography is great as well. All being said, The Ice Storm is one of the best films of the nineties, and in my option, the best film of 1997. Watch it and immerse yourself in a world of pain, longing, lust and booze. In other words, just watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tedious exercise in dysfunction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spicyburrito
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First I should say, this movie could have been about my town and my family. I grew up in Connecticut and was 11 years old when the ice storm hit. My family was probably the typical dysfunctional unit of the 70's  emotionally clueless, parents headed for divorce (though we didn't know that yet), so I should have been able to relate to this film. The problem with the movie is there's no humor, no humanity. It's just one dysfunctional, sad, deviant event after another. It's like someone from another planet was assigned a homework exercise to depict dysfunctional families on Earth. I couldn't relate to the characters and there was no one to like. I'll give it 4 stars for the nice cinematography, the all-star cast, the good period sets and clothes. Although Toby Maguire gives his usual staring-into-space, deer-in-headlights, stupid-half-smile, what-am-I-supposed-to-be-doing-again? performance, I thought the rest of the cast did their best with the material  i.e. it wasn't the actors' fault!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sensible Movie That Explains Oedipus Complex In An Easy Way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vikram-ry123
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ice Storm is a metaphor of country life. I do not read the original novel by Rick Moody; but I think the film is an appropriate adaptation of that novel. Every plot is very carefully drawn in the film. A master work by director Ang Lee that I will never forget. The movie is like a fact file of hundreds of truths of our daily life. Every character in the film is a part of us. The storm begins with Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) reading Fantastic Four comic book in a late night empty frozen train. The movie is mostly about the relation between two neighboring families lives in a suburb town. The characters are very life-like that I suddenly feel everything is just happening in front of me. Ben Hood (Kevin Kline) is the father of two child Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) and Wendy Hood (Christina Ricci). The irony is that both of the child are in their adolescent and their parents are unable to guide them at this stage. The same thing we can see in the Carver family. Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver) and Jim Carver (Jamey Sheridan) have two boys Sandy Carver (Adam Hann-Byrd) and Mikey Carver (Elijah Wood). That very night all the guardians went for an ironical Key Party that make them funny and irresistible to control their basic instincts. And the children are children, they follow the way that showed by the society and misguided by their parents. Young Wendy (Christina Ricci) is a grown up girl of 14 and she is in her adolescent but her parents hardly care to guide her in proper way. Paul (Tobey Maguire) 18 years old boy successfully controls his lust inspired by reading Fantastic Four comic is very sentimental. Albeit Ben (Kevin Kline) his father tries to tell him about the duties of a gentleman but he fails to make him understand appropriately. Ben has a bitter relation with his wife Elena (Joan Allen) that comes as an opportunity to grow an extramarital relation with his next door neighbor Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver). The ice storm changed everything in a single night. Janey leaves the party with a young man to fulfill lust and desire. In the lustful late night game played by all the mature men and women of the society where Ben acts like a fool and humiliated. Same night Jim Carver, Janey's husband and Elena Hood Ben's wife become out of control of their basic instinct. The film concluded in a poetic justice with a sacrifice of 14 years old Mikey Carver died in an accident in the ice storm night due to his careless parents. Next day Ben found the dead body. And Elena found her 14 years old daughter Wendy and young Caver boy Sandy (Adam Hann- Byrd) sleeping naked in Caver's house. Caver family lost their one son and Hood family realize that how much careless they are? In a particular scene of this movie carries a good lesson. One day Elena sees her daughter riding bicycle that reminds her own teenage years and next day she rides the bicycle and entered into a shopping mall and stole some products to enjoy her young age behavior but caught by the shop kipper and humiliated. The irony shows the young girl Wendy gets the same behavior like her mother. The movie is very practical and worth to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ensemble Acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's easy to compare The Ice Storm to American Beauty and Happiness, both of which also dealt with disillusionment and the disintegration of the American Dream and the traditional family cell in the suburbs, and to a lesser extent The Sweet Hereafter which explored some similar themes in small town Canada. The Ice Storm is as cynical as those other films, but it's much more subtle in masking its sardonicism, and has aged much better than American Beauty, which had the appearance of a masterpiece at its release but looks flat and shallow now. The people in The Ice Storm feel more real and more human than the ones in American Beauty and Happiness; and the film walks that fine line between character-based slice-of-life storytelling and metaphorical satire, which works only because the viewer cares for the characters and their fates, while also absorbing the bigger issues under the surface. That would not work without a strong ensemble cast; the actors in The Ice Storm are not among my favorites, yet they all outdo themselves and produce sympathetic, powerful, convincing performances - Kevin Kline, Joan Allen and Sigourney Weaver are all at their very best, and the younger actors (Elijah Wood, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci, Adam Hann-Byrd and - amazingly - even Katie Holmes) all deliver too. In contrast with the (intentionally) despicable characters in Happiness and American Beauty, these actors form a group of very average people that the viewer relates to and cares about - but the dysfunction and sickness is right there beneath the surface, waiting for the right catastrophe to explode. There's an undefinable something that stops The Ice Storm short of becoming one of my favorites. The ending fits the mood of the rest of the film, but doesn't offer the catharsis that is needed, and it left me with a bitter taste. In the end, I found myself wishing that the film said more, and left more of a mark; the fact that it isn't often recognized as one of the best films of the 90's is simply because there's something not quite memorable about it. It's incredibly engaging throughout, though, and is definitely one of the strongest dramas of its time, beautifully shot, and a gem that's well worth discovering.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canadian58
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the thousands of movies I have seen, there are a select few I will remember for the rest of my life as being the worst movies I have ever seen. The Ice Storm tops this list. Nothing is good about it, and I'm sorry that I'll never get that two hours of my life back. I should have trusted my instinct and turned it off after the first 20 minutes of being mind-numbing bored. There are a lot of good actors, all of which the talent is completely wasted. Not one of the characters is likable, except maybe Tobey Maguire. Everyone is cheating on someone, and oh, yeah, there's an ice storm going on outside during the last half an hour of the film. We see one car go in the ditch, one branch fall, and one downed power line, is all it amounts to. Do yourself a favor and avoid this one. And to all you people giving this film a great review, HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MINDS?????!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three drift out of consciousness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is meant to offer a soft contrast as flow, between external life with people (family members gathered for Thanksgiving) anxiously pulled in disparate orbits, and the inner life of unfathomable urges and emotion that gives rise to the firstappearances versus true self, rooted in relationships and attempting connection. Set in 1970's America with Nixon lying on TV, the broader commentary is that the world is organized on deceit, misplaced faith. There is contextual talk of people as intertwined molecules, of inner life as inverted space where the invisible becomes visible. So here's the cinematic gambit, how to make visible a part of that inner life? It's what every filmmaker worth anything has puzzled about in his work, in-sight into human soul, no small challenge for Lee, though the film may otherwise seem typical. There are three connected story lines to that effect, each one culminating in a ritual of seduction as betrayal. Each storyline, climaxes with a loved one drifting out of consciousness in some way (drunk husband, Libbets, the son). This only emphasizes what we've been seeing for the whole film, people drifting apart heedless of one another. It all plays in the latter stages against the backdrop of a coming ice storm, it can't be helped, there's some inevitable unhappiness ahead of us. The overall point? In each case, as loved ones momentarily or not go out of life, those left behind are suddenly surrounded with that negative space of absence, and in that space pour their inner self and effect human connection. It may all seem a little cloying in the finale. But the best part is getting there, the protracted sequence with cross-cutting between the three stories of betrayed seduction. So how to make visible what in life eludes us, the fabric of feelings as cinematic fabric? This was very likely Lee's interest in the project, as well as more broadly the idea of dislocation. I was happy to see a cinematic solution that was nowhere in multithreaded films like Crash or Cloud Atlas. The idea seems to be, show each new scene from a point on, as extension, as in-sight or meditation on previous ones, as though a single soul is dreaming. So this is nice. The film is the empty space, as we think dull, day-to- day life to be. The characters as molecules drifting in the air, often apart. The loss of consciousness not simply as loss, but as meaningful awakening to that empty space where we, as molecules, do not aimlessly drift, but by virtue of being there, hold each other into place giving shape to life. Lee as usual has compromised, enough to deliver a movie with some broad appeal. The overall wrap is a bit too fabricated for my taste. But see how gentle are the contrasts between hard sorrow and soft inner life, where the very similar Melancholia eats at you, this soothes. It's all here natural to Lee, who as a Chinese knows this stuff in meditation and tai chi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Contrived Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thanksgiving weekend in Connecticut in 1973, two families work through their problems. Talk about dysfunctional families! This one has two such clans, and every member of each family is assigned an issue (kleptomaniac, sex addict, social misfit, absentee parent, depression, etc.). It makes for a very contrived drama. The impressive cast manages to overcome some of the shortcomings of the script, but it all seems so heavy-handed. As a couple whose marriage has fizzled, Kline and Allen come off the best. The makeup department went a little overboard trying to evoke the 1970s look, with Weaver looking particularly odd as a woman who's cold as ice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ordinary and uneventful in the most accurate sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is set during Thanksgiving 1973 and centers on two upper middle class Connecticut families who are trying to run their course in the Nixon era and free themselves from their blah feelings through drinking, adultery and sexual experiments. Both the parents and the children have dull lifestyles, they are financially secured, and there is a serious lack of joy and enthusiasm in activities and communication, incl. sexual relations, jobs/studies. The cast is strong: Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, and that-time minors Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, who all give catchy and splendid performances. The title has both direct and indirect meaning and the director Ang Lee has fulfilled another great task, the only problem seemed to be with the release year - 1997 - when, among others, Titanic was released and the movie in question obtained less praise and publicity it should have had. But it is never to late to watch a valuable movie (again), especially if the plot dealt with the past events anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great and overlooked genre movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really sure why this movie got pretty much ignored, at the time of its release. Not just by the movie goers, which is perhaps somewhat understandable but more so by all of big award ceremonies. By all means this movie should had swept a couple of them and it truly earned some more recognition. Drama's normally aren't even really my kind of thing but I just got captivated by this movie and was really liking it. Guess the main reason why I like it was because it wasn't being a pretentious or melodramatic one and it deliberately kept things small, which gave the overall movie also a sense of realism to it. For me it was a movie about people in search of themselves. Basically all of the characters are unhappy with their current situations and are searching for ways to break out and to get more in touch with themselves. This goes for the movie its youngster, which also makes this a sort of coming of age movie but also for their parents. Every character goes through some sort of inner transitions and the movie does a great job at balancing it all out. Basically everybody has a fair share of screen time in this movie. There aren't really one or two main characters but more like five or six of them. Every storyline is about as equally interesting and good to follow as the other. At least in my opinion of course. I personally got grabbed by it all, also since it isn't really being a standard drama, that is being predictable to watch from start till finish. It's also a movie that is being made great and intriguing to watch by its cast-members. It truly has an impressive cast-list, with actors such as Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, among many others. A cast to kill for and everybody did a great job, playing their character. A really overlooked Ang Lee movie, that is definitely worth checking out! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's too vague too vague
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film begins as slowly as it can; until the first hour, nothing much really happens and you have no idea of what to expect about this picture. I believe Ang Lee didn't have a story in mind and just utilized some ideas from Moody's novel. In many scenes we can notice that the filmmakers don't know what to do, so they just have the characters talking to each other. The cast is profession, we can see they really get into their characters, but that's not enough to make this movie any good. The only thing that enjoyed me is the braveness they have at showing how kids start their sexual life. You know, I'm only 19, so I can vaguely remember how these things worked in my mind when I was a kid. You're always worried what would happen if your parents found out, and in the end, they're doing their best to not see it. And let's not be hypocrite and believe that kids don't have sexual tension between themselves...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Film With Great Actors Giving Great Performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elevenangrymen
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved The Ice Storm. It's one of my favorite films. It takes place one thanksgiving, in the early 70's. When we first see the Hood family, they are perfectly normal. Kevin Kline is a loving husband, Joan Allen is a typical wife, Tobey Maguire loves comics, and Christina Ricci doesn't like Nixon. A perfectly normal family, in fact, they are nothing but. Kline is cheating on his wife with Sigourney Weaver, Allen is suspecting, but tries not to show it. Ricci is a fourteen year old experimenting with alcohol and sex. Maguire is in love with a girl, and she likes him too, like a brother. This all culminates during an ice storm. Everyone breaks down, in some form or another. Kline is unable to keep his secret from Allen, and she doesn't react with shock. In fact, she acts relieved. This is before she cheats on Kline during a car-key exchange, that seems right out of the seventies. That being said, every single one of the actors has their moment to shine. From Kline down to Elijah Wood, every actor delivers a masterful performance. This is all done through Ang Lee's direction. Lee is a great director, and here, he shows it. He perfectly captures the decade, in his use of music, costumes and sets. The cinematography is great as well. All being said, The Ice Storm is one of the best films of the nineties, and in my option, the best film of 1997. Watch it and immerse yourself in a world of pain, longing, lust and booze. In other words, just watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tedious exercise in dysfunction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spicyburrito
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First I should say, this movie could have been about my town and my family. I grew up in Connecticut and was 11 years old when the ice storm hit. My family was probably the typical dysfunctional unit of the 70's  emotionally clueless, parents headed for divorce (though we didn't know that yet), so I should have been able to relate to this film. The problem with the movie is there's no humor, no humanity. It's just one dysfunctional, sad, deviant event after another. It's like someone from another planet was assigned a homework exercise to depict dysfunctional families on Earth. I couldn't relate to the characters and there was no one to like. I'll give it 4 stars for the nice cinematography, the all-star cast, the good period sets and clothes. Although Toby Maguire gives his usual staring-into-space, deer-in-headlights, stupid-half-smile, what-am-I-supposed-to-be-doing-again? performance, I thought the rest of the cast did their best with the material  i.e. it wasn't the actors' fault!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sensible Movie That Explains Oedipus Complex In An Easy Way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vikram-ry123
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ice Storm is a metaphor of country life. I do not read the original novel by Rick Moody; but I think the film is an appropriate adaptation of that novel. Every plot is very carefully drawn in the film. A master work by director Ang Lee that I will never forget. The movie is like a fact file of hundreds of truths of our daily life. Every character in the film is a part of us. The storm begins with Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) reading Fantastic Four comic book in a late night empty frozen train. The movie is mostly about the relation between two neighboring families lives in a suburb town. The characters are very life-like that I suddenly feel everything is just happening in front of me. Ben Hood (Kevin Kline) is the father of two child Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) and Wendy Hood (Christina Ricci). The irony is that both of the child are in their adolescent and their parents are unable to guide them at this stage. The same thing we can see in the Carver family. Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver) and Jim Carver (Jamey Sheridan) have two boys Sandy Carver (Adam Hann-Byrd) and Mikey Carver (Elijah Wood). That very night all the guardians went for an ironical Key Party that make them funny and irresistible to control their basic instincts. And the children are children, they follow the way that showed by the society and misguided by their parents. Young Wendy (Christina Ricci) is a grown up girl of 14 and she is in her adolescent but her parents hardly care to guide her in proper way. Paul (Tobey Maguire) 18 years old boy successfully controls his lust inspired by reading Fantastic Four comic is very sentimental. Albeit Ben (Kevin Kline) his father tries to tell him about the duties of a gentleman but he fails to make him understand appropriately. Ben has a bitter relation with his wife Elena (Joan Allen) that comes as an opportunity to grow an extramarital relation with his next door neighbor Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver). The ice storm changed everything in a single night. Janey leaves the party with a young man to fulfill lust and desire. In the lustful late night game played by all the mature men and women of the society where Ben acts like a fool and humiliated. Same night Jim Carver, Janey's husband and Elena Hood Ben's wife become out of control of their basic instinct. The film concluded in a poetic justice with a sacrifice of 14 years old Mikey Carver died in an accident in the ice storm night due to his careless parents. Next day Ben found the dead body. And Elena found her 14 years old daughter Wendy and young Caver boy Sandy (Adam Hann- Byrd) sleeping naked in Caver's house. Caver family lost their one son and Hood family realize that how much careless they are? In a particular scene of this movie carries a good lesson. One day Elena sees her daughter riding bicycle that reminds her own teenage years and next day she rides the bicycle and entered into a shopping mall and stole some products to enjoy her young age behavior but caught by the shop kipper and humiliated. The irony shows the young girl Wendy gets the same behavior like her mother. The movie is very practical and worth to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ensemble Acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's easy to compare The Ice Storm to American Beauty and Happiness, both of which also dealt with disillusionment and the disintegration of the American Dream and the traditional family cell in the suburbs, and to a lesser extent The Sweet Hereafter which explored some similar themes in small town Canada. The Ice Storm is as cynical as those other films, but it's much more subtle in masking its sardonicism, and has aged much better than American Beauty, which had the appearance of a masterpiece at its release but looks flat and shallow now. The people in The Ice Storm feel more real and more human than the ones in American Beauty and Happiness; and the film walks that fine line between character-based slice-of-life storytelling and metaphorical satire, which works only because the viewer cares for the characters and their fates, while also absorbing the bigger issues under the surface. That would not work without a strong ensemble cast; the actors in The Ice Storm are not among my favorites, yet they all outdo themselves and produce sympathetic, powerful, convincing performances - Kevin Kline, Joan Allen and Sigourney Weaver are all at their very best, and the younger actors (Elijah Wood, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci, Adam Hann-Byrd and - amazingly - even Katie Holmes) all deliver too. In contrast with the (intentionally) despicable characters in Happiness and American Beauty, these actors form a group of very average people that the viewer relates to and cares about - but the dysfunction and sickness is right there beneath the surface, waiting for the right catastrophe to explode. There's an undefinable something that stops The Ice Storm short of becoming one of my favorites. The ending fits the mood of the rest of the film, but doesn't offer the catharsis that is needed, and it left me with a bitter taste. In the end, I found myself wishing that the film said more, and left more of a mark; the fact that it isn't often recognized as one of the best films of the 90's is simply because there's something not quite memorable about it. It's incredibly engaging throughout, though, and is definitely one of the strongest dramas of its time, beautifully shot, and a gem that's well worth discovering.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canadian58
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the thousands of movies I have seen, there are a select few I will remember for the rest of my life as being the worst movies I have ever seen. The Ice Storm tops this list. Nothing is good about it, and I'm sorry that I'll never get that two hours of my life back. I should have trusted my instinct and turned it off after the first 20 minutes of being mind-numbing bored. There are a lot of good actors, all of which the talent is completely wasted. Not one of the characters is likable, except maybe Tobey Maguire. Everyone is cheating on someone, and oh, yeah, there's an ice storm going on outside during the last half an hour of the film. We see one car go in the ditch, one branch fall, and one downed power line, is all it amounts to. Do yourself a favor and avoid this one. And to all you people giving this film a great review, HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MINDS?????!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three drift out of consciousness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is meant to offer a soft contrast as flow, between external life with people (family members gathered for Thanksgiving) anxiously pulled in disparate orbits, and the inner life of unfathomable urges and emotion that gives rise to the firstappearances versus true self, rooted in relationships and attempting connection. Set in 1970's America with Nixon lying on TV, the broader commentary is that the world is organized on deceit, misplaced faith. There is contextual talk of people as intertwined molecules, of inner life as inverted space where the invisible becomes visible. So here's the cinematic gambit, how to make visible a part of that inner life? It's what every filmmaker worth anything has puzzled about in his work, in-sight into human soul, no small challenge for Lee, though the film may otherwise seem typical. There are three connected story lines to that effect, each one culminating in a ritual of seduction as betrayal. Each storyline, climaxes with a loved one drifting out of consciousness in some way (drunk husband, Libbets, the son). This only emphasizes what we've been seeing for the whole film, people drifting apart heedless of one another. It all plays in the latter stages against the backdrop of a coming ice storm, it can't be helped, there's some inevitable unhappiness ahead of us. The overall point? In each case, as loved ones momentarily or not go out of life, those left behind are suddenly surrounded with that negative space of absence, and in that space pour their inner self and effect human connection. It may all seem a little cloying in the finale. But the best part is getting there, the protracted sequence with cross-cutting between the three stories of betrayed seduction. So how to make visible what in life eludes us, the fabric of feelings as cinematic fabric? This was very likely Lee's interest in the project, as well as more broadly the idea of dislocation. I was happy to see a cinematic solution that was nowhere in multithreaded films like Crash or Cloud Atlas. The idea seems to be, show each new scene from a point on, as extension, as in-sight or meditation on previous ones, as though a single soul is dreaming. So this is nice. The film is the empty space, as we think dull, day-to- day life to be. The characters as molecules drifting in the air, often apart. The loss of consciousness not simply as loss, but as meaningful awakening to that empty space where we, as molecules, do not aimlessly drift, but by virtue of being there, hold each other into place giving shape to life. Lee as usual has compromised, enough to deliver a movie with some broad appeal. The overall wrap is a bit too fabricated for my taste. But see how gentle are the contrasts between hard sorrow and soft inner life, where the very similar Melancholia eats at you, this soothes. It's all here natural to Lee, who as a Chinese knows this stuff in meditation and tai chi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Contrived Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thanksgiving weekend in Connecticut in 1973, two families work through their problems. Talk about dysfunctional families! This one has two such clans, and every member of each family is assigned an issue (kleptomaniac, sex addict, social misfit, absentee parent, depression, etc.). It makes for a very contrived drama. The impressive cast manages to overcome some of the shortcomings of the script, but it all seems so heavy-handed. As a couple whose marriage has fizzled, Kline and Allen come off the best. The makeup department went a little overboard trying to evoke the 1970s look, with Weaver looking particularly odd as a woman who's cold as ice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ordinary and uneventful in the most accurate sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is set during Thanksgiving 1973 and centers on two upper middle class Connecticut families who are trying to run their course in the Nixon era and free themselves from their blah feelings through drinking, adultery and sexual experiments. Both the parents and the children have dull lifestyles, they are financially secured, and there is a serious lack of joy and enthusiasm in activities and communication, incl. sexual relations, jobs/studies. The cast is strong: Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, and that-time minors Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, who all give catchy and splendid performances. The title has both direct and indirect meaning and the director Ang Lee has fulfilled another great task, the only problem seemed to be with the release year - 1997 - when, among others, Titanic was released and the movie in question obtained less praise and publicity it should have had. But it is never to late to watch a valuable movie (again), especially if the plot dealt with the past events anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great and overlooked genre movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really sure why this movie got pretty much ignored, at the time of its release. Not just by the movie goers, which is perhaps somewhat understandable but more so by all of big award ceremonies. By all means this movie should had swept a couple of them and it truly earned some more recognition. Drama's normally aren't even really my kind of thing but I just got captivated by this movie and was really liking it. Guess the main reason why I like it was because it wasn't being a pretentious or melodramatic one and it deliberately kept things small, which gave the overall movie also a sense of realism to it. For me it was a movie about people in search of themselves. Basically all of the characters are unhappy with their current situations and are searching for ways to break out and to get more in touch with themselves. This goes for the movie its youngster, which also makes this a sort of coming of age movie but also for their parents. Every character goes through some sort of inner transitions and the movie does a great job at balancing it all out. Basically everybody has a fair share of screen time in this movie. There aren't really one or two main characters but more like five or six of them. Every storyline is about as equally interesting and good to follow as the other. At least in my opinion of course. I personally got grabbed by it all, also since it isn't really being a standard drama, that is being predictable to watch from start till finish. It's also a movie that is being made great and intriguing to watch by its cast-members. It truly has an impressive cast-list, with actors such as Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, among many others. A cast to kill for and everybody did a great job, playing their character. A really overlooked Ang Lee movie, that is definitely worth checking out! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's too vague too vague
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film begins as slowly as it can; until the first hour, nothing much really happens and you have no idea of what to expect about this picture. I believe Ang Lee didn't have a story in mind and just utilized some ideas from Moody's novel. In many scenes we can notice that the filmmakers don't know what to do, so they just have the characters talking to each other. The cast is profession, we can see they really get into their characters, but that's not enough to make this movie any good. The only thing that enjoyed me is the braveness they have at showing how kids start their sexual life. You know, I'm only 19, so I can vaguely remember how these things worked in my mind when I was a kid. You're always worried what would happen if your parents found out, and in the end, they're doing their best to not see it. And let's not be hypocrite and believe that kids don't have sexual tension between themselves...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Film With Great Actors Giving Great Performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elevenangrymen
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved The Ice Storm. It's one of my favorite films. It takes place one thanksgiving, in the early 70's. When we first see the Hood family, they are perfectly normal. Kevin Kline is a loving husband, Joan Allen is a typical wife, Tobey Maguire loves comics, and Christina Ricci doesn't like Nixon. A perfectly normal family, in fact, they are nothing but. Kline is cheating on his wife with Sigourney Weaver, Allen is suspecting, but tries not to show it. Ricci is a fourteen year old experimenting with alcohol and sex. Maguire is in love with a girl, and she likes him too, like a brother. This all culminates during an ice storm. Everyone breaks down, in some form or another. Kline is unable to keep his secret from Allen, and she doesn't react with shock. In fact, she acts relieved. This is before she cheats on Kline during a car-key exchange, that seems right out of the seventies. That being said, every single one of the actors has their moment to shine. From Kline down to Elijah Wood, every actor delivers a masterful performance. This is all done through Ang Lee's direction. Lee is a great director, and here, he shows it. He perfectly captures the decade, in his use of music, costumes and sets. The cinematography is great as well. All being said, The Ice Storm is one of the best films of the nineties, and in my option, the best film of 1997. Watch it and immerse yourself in a world of pain, longing, lust and booze. In other words, just watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tedious exercise in dysfunction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spicyburrito
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First I should say, this movie could have been about my town and my family. I grew up in Connecticut and was 11 years old when the ice storm hit. My family was probably the typical dysfunctional unit of the 70's  emotionally clueless, parents headed for divorce (though we didn't know that yet), so I should have been able to relate to this film. The problem with the movie is there's no humor, no humanity. It's just one dysfunctional, sad, deviant event after another. It's like someone from another planet was assigned a homework exercise to depict dysfunctional families on Earth. I couldn't relate to the characters and there was no one to like. I'll give it 4 stars for the nice cinematography, the all-star cast, the good period sets and clothes. Although Toby Maguire gives his usual staring-into-space, deer-in-headlights, stupid-half-smile, what-am-I-supposed-to-be-doing-again? performance, I thought the rest of the cast did their best with the material  i.e. it wasn't the actors' fault!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sensible Movie That Explains Oedipus Complex In An Easy Way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vikram-ry123
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ice Storm is a metaphor of country life. I do not read the original novel by Rick Moody; but I think the film is an appropriate adaptation of that novel. Every plot is very carefully drawn in the film. A master work by director Ang Lee that I will never forget. The movie is like a fact file of hundreds of truths of our daily life. Every character in the film is a part of us. The storm begins with Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) reading Fantastic Four comic book in a late night empty frozen train. The movie is mostly about the relation between two neighboring families lives in a suburb town. The characters are very life-like that I suddenly feel everything is just happening in front of me. Ben Hood (Kevin Kline) is the father of two child Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) and Wendy Hood (Christina Ricci). The irony is that both of the child are in their adolescent and their parents are unable to guide them at this stage. The same thing we can see in the Carver family. Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver) and Jim Carver (Jamey Sheridan) have two boys Sandy Carver (Adam Hann-Byrd) and Mikey Carver (Elijah Wood). That very night all the guardians went for an ironical Key Party that make them funny and irresistible to control their basic instincts. And the children are children, they follow the way that showed by the society and misguided by their parents. Young Wendy (Christina Ricci) is a grown up girl of 14 and she is in her adolescent but her parents hardly care to guide her in proper way. Paul (Tobey Maguire) 18 years old boy successfully controls his lust inspired by reading Fantastic Four comic is very sentimental. Albeit Ben (Kevin Kline) his father tries to tell him about the duties of a gentleman but he fails to make him understand appropriately. Ben has a bitter relation with his wife Elena (Joan Allen) that comes as an opportunity to grow an extramarital relation with his next door neighbor Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver). The ice storm changed everything in a single night. Janey leaves the party with a young man to fulfill lust and desire. In the lustful late night game played by all the mature men and women of the society where Ben acts like a fool and humiliated. Same night Jim Carver, Janey's husband and Elena Hood Ben's wife become out of control of their basic instinct. The film concluded in a poetic justice with a sacrifice of 14 years old Mikey Carver died in an accident in the ice storm night due to his careless parents. Next day Ben found the dead body. And Elena found her 14 years old daughter Wendy and young Caver boy Sandy (Adam Hann- Byrd) sleeping naked in Caver's house. Caver family lost their one son and Hood family realize that how much careless they are? In a particular scene of this movie carries a good lesson. One day Elena sees her daughter riding bicycle that reminds her own teenage years and next day she rides the bicycle and entered into a shopping mall and stole some products to enjoy her young age behavior but caught by the shop kipper and humiliated. The irony shows the young girl Wendy gets the same behavior like her mother. The movie is very practical and worth to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ensemble Acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's easy to compare The Ice Storm to American Beauty and Happiness, both of which also dealt with disillusionment and the disintegration of the American Dream and the traditional family cell in the suburbs, and to a lesser extent The Sweet Hereafter which explored some similar themes in small town Canada. The Ice Storm is as cynical as those other films, but it's much more subtle in masking its sardonicism, and has aged much better than American Beauty, which had the appearance of a masterpiece at its release but looks flat and shallow now. The people in The Ice Storm feel more real and more human than the ones in American Beauty and Happiness; and the film walks that fine line between character-based slice-of-life storytelling and metaphorical satire, which works only because the viewer cares for the characters and their fates, while also absorbing the bigger issues under the surface. That would not work without a strong ensemble cast; the actors in The Ice Storm are not among my favorites, yet they all outdo themselves and produce sympathetic, powerful, convincing performances - Kevin Kline, Joan Allen and Sigourney Weaver are all at their very best, and the younger actors (Elijah Wood, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci, Adam Hann-Byrd and - amazingly - even Katie Holmes) all deliver too. In contrast with the (intentionally) despicable characters in Happiness and American Beauty, these actors form a group of very average people that the viewer relates to and cares about - but the dysfunction and sickness is right there beneath the surface, waiting for the right catastrophe to explode. There's an undefinable something that stops The Ice Storm short of becoming one of my favorites. The ending fits the mood of the rest of the film, but doesn't offer the catharsis that is needed, and it left me with a bitter taste. In the end, I found myself wishing that the film said more, and left more of a mark; the fact that it isn't often recognized as one of the best films of the 90's is simply because there's something not quite memorable about it. It's incredibly engaging throughout, though, and is definitely one of the strongest dramas of its time, beautifully shot, and a gem that's well worth discovering.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Garbage
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canadian58
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the thousands of movies I have seen, there are a select few I will remember for the rest of my life as being the worst movies I have ever seen. The Ice Storm tops this list. Nothing is good about it, and I'm sorry that I'll never get that two hours of my life back. I should have trusted my instinct and turned it off after the first 20 minutes of being mind-numbing bored. There are a lot of good actors, all of which the talent is completely wasted. Not one of the characters is likable, except maybe Tobey Maguire. Everyone is cheating on someone, and oh, yeah, there's an ice storm going on outside during the last half an hour of the film. We see one car go in the ditch, one branch fall, and one downed power line, is all it amounts to. Do yourself a favor and avoid this one. And to all you people giving this film a great review, HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MINDS?????!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Three drift out of consciousness
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is meant to offer a soft contrast as flow, between external life with people (family members gathered for Thanksgiving) anxiously pulled in disparate orbits, and the inner life of unfathomable urges and emotion that gives rise to the firstappearances versus true self, rooted in relationships and attempting connection. Set in 1970's America with Nixon lying on TV, the broader commentary is that the world is organized on deceit, misplaced faith. There is contextual talk of people as intertwined molecules, of inner life as inverted space where the invisible becomes visible. So here's the cinematic gambit, how to make visible a part of that inner life? It's what every filmmaker worth anything has puzzled about in his work, in-sight into human soul, no small challenge for Lee, though the film may otherwise seem typical. There are three connected story lines to that effect, each one culminating in a ritual of seduction as betrayal. Each storyline, climaxes with a loved one drifting out of consciousness in some way (drunk husband, Libbets, the son). This only emphasizes what we've been seeing for the whole film, people drifting apart heedless of one another. It all plays in the latter stages against the backdrop of a coming ice storm, it can't be helped, there's some inevitable unhappiness ahead of us. The overall point? In each case, as loved ones momentarily or not go out of life, those left behind are suddenly surrounded with that negative space of absence, and in that space pour their inner self and effect human connection. It may all seem a little cloying in the finale. But the best part is getting there, the protracted sequence with cross-cutting between the three stories of betrayed seduction. So how to make visible what in life eludes us, the fabric of feelings as cinematic fabric? This was very likely Lee's interest in the project, as well as more broadly the idea of dislocation. I was happy to see a cinematic solution that was nowhere in multithreaded films like Crash or Cloud Atlas. The idea seems to be, show each new scene from a point on, as extension, as in-sight or meditation on previous ones, as though a single soul is dreaming. So this is nice. The film is the empty space, as we think dull, day-to- day life to be. The characters as molecules drifting in the air, often apart. The loss of consciousness not simply as loss, but as meaningful awakening to that empty space where we, as molecules, do not aimlessly drift, but by virtue of being there, hold each other into place giving shape to life. Lee as usual has compromised, enough to deliver a movie with some broad appeal. The overall wrap is a bit too fabricated for my taste. But see how gentle are the contrasts between hard sorrow and soft inner life, where the very similar Melancholia eats at you, this soothes. It's all here natural to Lee, who as a Chinese knows this stuff in meditation and tai chi.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Contrived Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenjha
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thanksgiving weekend in Connecticut in 1973, two families work through their problems. Talk about dysfunctional families! This one has two such clans, and every member of each family is assigned an issue (kleptomaniac, sex addict, social misfit, absentee parent, depression, etc.). It makes for a very contrived drama. The impressive cast manages to overcome some of the shortcomings of the script, but it all seems so heavy-handed. As a couple whose marriage has fizzled, Kline and Allen come off the best. The makeup department went a little overboard trying to evoke the 1970s look, with Weaver looking particularly odd as a woman who's cold as ice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ordinary and uneventful in the most accurate sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bene Cumb
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie is set during Thanksgiving 1973 and centers on two upper middle class Connecticut families who are trying to run their course in the Nixon era and free themselves from their blah feelings through drinking, adultery and sexual experiments. Both the parents and the children have dull lifestyles, they are financially secured, and there is a serious lack of joy and enthusiasm in activities and communication, incl. sexual relations, jobs/studies. The cast is strong: Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, and that-time minors Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, who all give catchy and splendid performances. The title has both direct and indirect meaning and the director Ang Lee has fulfilled another great task, the only problem seemed to be with the release year - 1997 - when, among others, Titanic was released and the movie in question obtained less praise and publicity it should have had. But it is never to late to watch a valuable movie (again), especially if the plot dealt with the past events anyway.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great and overlooked genre movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Boba_Fett1138
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not really sure why this movie got pretty much ignored, at the time of its release. Not just by the movie goers, which is perhaps somewhat understandable but more so by all of big award ceremonies. By all means this movie should had swept a couple of them and it truly earned some more recognition. Drama's normally aren't even really my kind of thing but I just got captivated by this movie and was really liking it. Guess the main reason why I like it was because it wasn't being a pretentious or melodramatic one and it deliberately kept things small, which gave the overall movie also a sense of realism to it. For me it was a movie about people in search of themselves. Basically all of the characters are unhappy with their current situations and are searching for ways to break out and to get more in touch with themselves. This goes for the movie its youngster, which also makes this a sort of coming of age movie but also for their parents. Every character goes through some sort of inner transitions and the movie does a great job at balancing it all out. Basically everybody has a fair share of screen time in this movie. There aren't really one or two main characters but more like five or six of them. Every storyline is about as equally interesting and good to follow as the other. At least in my opinion of course. I personally got grabbed by it all, also since it isn't really being a standard drama, that is being predictable to watch from start till finish. It's also a movie that is being made great and intriguing to watch by its cast-members. It truly has an impressive cast-list, with actors such as Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Sigourney Weaver, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci and Elijah Wood, among many others. A cast to kill for and everybody did a great job, playing their character. A really overlooked Ang Lee movie, that is definitely worth checking out! 8/10 http://bobafett1138.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's too vague too vague
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film begins as slowly as it can; until the first hour, nothing much really happens and you have no idea of what to expect about this picture. I believe Ang Lee didn't have a story in mind and just utilized some ideas from Moody's novel. In many scenes we can notice that the filmmakers don't know what to do, so they just have the characters talking to each other. The cast is profession, we can see they really get into their characters, but that's not enough to make this movie any good. The only thing that enjoyed me is the braveness they have at showing how kids start their sexual life. You know, I'm only 19, so I can vaguely remember how these things worked in my mind when I was a kid. You're always worried what would happen if your parents found out, and in the end, they're doing their best to not see it. And let's not be hypocrite and believe that kids don't have sexual tension between themselves...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Film With Great Actors Giving Great Performances
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elevenangrymen
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved The Ice Storm. It's one of my favorite films. It takes place one thanksgiving, in the early 70's. When we first see the Hood family, they are perfectly normal. Kevin Kline is a loving husband, Joan Allen is a typical wife, Tobey Maguire loves comics, and Christina Ricci doesn't like Nixon. A perfectly normal family, in fact, they are nothing but. Kline is cheating on his wife with Sigourney Weaver, Allen is suspecting, but tries not to show it. Ricci is a fourteen year old experimenting with alcohol and sex. Maguire is in love with a girl, and she likes him too, like a brother. This all culminates during an ice storm. Everyone breaks down, in some form or another. Kline is unable to keep his secret from Allen, and she doesn't react with shock. In fact, she acts relieved. This is before she cheats on Kline during a car-key exchange, that seems right out of the seventies. That being said, every single one of the actors has their moment to shine. From Kline down to Elijah Wood, every actor delivers a masterful performance. This is all done through Ang Lee's direction. Lee is a great director, and here, he shows it. He perfectly captures the decade, in his use of music, costumes and sets. The cinematography is great as well. All being said, The Ice Storm is one of the best films of the nineties, and in my option, the best film of 1997. Watch it and immerse yourself in a world of pain, longing, lust and booze. In other words, just watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tedious exercise in dysfunction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spicyburrito
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First I should say, this movie could have been about my town and my family. I grew up in Connecticut and was 11 years old when the ice storm hit. My family was probably the typical dysfunctional unit of the 70's  emotionally clueless, parents headed for divorce (though we didn't know that yet), so I should have been able to relate to this film. The problem with the movie is there's no humor, no humanity. It's just one dysfunctional, sad, deviant event after another. It's like someone from another planet was assigned a homework exercise to depict dysfunctional families on Earth. I couldn't relate to the characters and there was no one to like. I'll give it 4 stars for the nice cinematography, the all-star cast, the good period sets and clothes. Although Toby Maguire gives his usual staring-into-space, deer-in-headlights, stupid-half-smile, what-am-I-supposed-to-be-doing-again? performance, I thought the rest of the cast did their best with the material  i.e. it wasn't the actors' fault!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sensible Movie That Explains Oedipus Complex In An Easy Way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vikram-ry123
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ice Storm is a metaphor of country life. I do not read the original novel by Rick Moody; but I think the film is an appropriate adaptation of that novel. Every plot is very carefully drawn in the film. A master work by director Ang Lee that I will never forget. The movie is like a fact file of hundreds of truths of our daily life. Every character in the film is a part of us. The storm begins with Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) reading Fantastic Four comic book in a late night empty frozen train. The movie is mostly about the relation between two neighboring families lives in a suburb town. The characters are very life-like that I suddenly feel everything is just happening in front of me. Ben Hood (Kevin Kline) is the father of two child Paul Hood (Tobey Maguire) and Wendy Hood (Christina Ricci). The irony is that both of the child are in their adolescent and their parents are unable to guide them at this stage. The same thing we can see in the Carver family. Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver) and Jim Carver (Jamey Sheridan) have two boys Sandy Carver (Adam Hann-Byrd) and Mikey Carver (Elijah Wood). That very night all the guardians went for an ironical Key Party that make them funny and irresistible to control their basic instincts. And the children are children, they follow the way that showed by the society and misguided by their parents. Young Wendy (Christina Ricci) is a grown up girl of 14 and she is in her adolescent but her parents hardly care to guide her in proper way. Paul (Tobey Maguire) 18 years old boy successfully controls his lust inspired by reading Fantastic Four comic is very sentimental. Albeit Ben (Kevin Kline) his father tries to tell him about the duties of a gentleman but he fails to make him understand appropriately. Ben has a bitter relation with his wife Elena (Joan Allen) that comes as an opportunity to grow an extramarital relation with his next door neighbor Janey Carver (Sigourney Weaver). The ice storm changed everything in a single night. Janey leaves the party with a young man to fulfill lust and desire. In the lustful late night game played by all the mature men and women of the society where Ben acts like a fool and humiliated. Same night Jim Carver, Janey's husband and Elena Hood Ben's wife become out of control of their basic instinct. The film concluded in a poetic justice with a sacrifice of 14 years old Mikey Carver died in an accident in the ice storm night due to his careless parents. Next day Ben found the dead body. And Elena found her 14 years old daughter Wendy and young Caver boy Sandy (Adam Hann- Byrd) sleeping naked in Caver's house. Caver family lost their one son and Hood family realize that how much careless they are? In a particular scene of this movie carries a good lesson. One day Elena sees her daughter riding bicycle that reminds her own teenage years and next day she rides the bicycle and entered into a shopping mall and stole some products to enjoy her young age behavior but caught by the shop kipper and humiliated. The irony shows the young girl Wendy gets the same behavior like her mother. The movie is very practical and worth to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
