<filme>
 <id>
  866
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117038
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Michael - Anjo e Sedutor
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Two tabloid reporters checking out a report of the Archangel Michael living with an old woman find that it's true. But that's not the only surprise.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Frank Quinlan and Huey Driscoll, two reporters from a Chicago-based tabloid, along with Dorothy Winters, an 'angel expert', are asked to travel to rural Iowa to investigate a claim from an old woman that she shares her house with a real, live archangel named Michael. Upon arrival, they see that her claims are true - but Michael is not what they expected: he smokes, drinks beer, has a very active libido and has a rather colourful vocabulary. In fact, they would never believe it were it not for the two feathery wings protruding from his back. Michael agrees to travel to Chicago with the threesome, but what they don't realise is that the journey they are about to undertake will change their lives forever.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   tabloid
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   reporter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   archangel michael
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   iowa
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   angel
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Nora Ephron
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Peter Dexter
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jim Quinlan
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   John Travolta
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Andie MacDowell
  </ator>
  <ator>
   William Hurt
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Kind Of Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patsworld
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, I've watched this movie a dozen times. My all time favorite John Travolta film. The cast in this touching but vastly amusing movie are all a joy to behold. Jean Stapleton as Pansy is a love...no, seriously, you will love her. William Hurt and Robert Pastorelli as reporters are played to perfection. Andie MacDowell is splendid as a song-writing, many-times married fellow skeptic of the fact that Michael is, indeed, an angel. There is a scene in this movie that never fails to bring me to tears - and one that never fails to make me laugh out loud. "He's not that kind of an angel".....ah, but he sure is mine. This movie is one I'd never pass by if it shows up on TV, even though I own a copy of my own. And if I didn't, I seek out and find one to buy. This is what entertainment is all about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It is not my area..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rodneyrf@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thumbs up! This silly yet enriching picture makes us travel back in time, enabling us to naively live up a story as we commonly did in Frank Capra's movies. Michael, the angel, says many times: "It is not my area...", for many of the questions and doubts people have. We must live life without worrying too much. That's why the angel is sent down. He shows that we should live up life lightly, trying to share happiness and content with others.. It's something each and every one of us should try to do, step outside ourselves see just what our contributions can be. As I always say: Good movies never leave us. Take your time having authentic and original laughs in this light yet profound comedy. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A delightful heartwarming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Travoltas portrayal of an this angel is an interesting one. What we know of angels is that they are great warriors, messengers of god and always seem to be perfect. What if they aren't. He plays a rude obnoxious, womanizer who will fulfill your wishes, and make you care enough about the world that you will be touched. So what happens when you don't believe in anything and you are sent to investigate a story, only to meet one with wings and looks less then angelic. William Hurt plays a cynic who is out to write about a possible hoax who ends up becoming a believer by the end. Andie MacDowell and the rest of the cast play great parts. It is enjoyable that the film unapologetically illustrates how wonderful like is and the little things that we take for granted, and we should enjoy every moment like it was our last. With some of the scenes in this movie that changes the different characters views on the reality of angels may make you wonder if our vision of angels could be changed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very sweet.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it. Below is a repeat of the lines I've written above. I really don't feel like I need to say more, but IMDb requires at least 10 lines, so here you go... This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Film..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nora Ephron's Box-Office Super-Hit 'Michael' is A Decent Film, that manages to pass-off as a light-entertainer, that also packs in some fine acting. 'Michael' Synopsis: Two tabloid reporters checking out a report of the Archangel Michael living with an old woman find that it's true. But that's not the only surprise. 'Michael' is a fantasy film, but, the Angel here is not shown doing "The Impossible". Actually, the depiction of it's Angel Michael, over-here is portrayed as a boozing, smoking, oversexed slob혰yet capable of imparting unexpected wisdom. But, Despite those aspects, Michael does come across as a free-soul & oozes excitement. Screenplay by Nora Ephron & Delia Ephron is decent & fast. However, the culmination to this story, is not convincing. It just doesn't leave an impact. Nora Ephron's Direction, is polite. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are proper. Performance-Wise: John Travolta as the Archangel Michael, is lively. William Hurt, like always, does wonders. Andie MacDowell is routine. Robert Pastorelli supports well. Bob Hoskins appears in a brief role. On the whole, 'Michael' is a decent entertainer, that doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lighthearted Romance, Flawed but still very Enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have seen angels coming to earth before, but never like this. Well at least I haven't. John Travolta as Micheal has done an amazing job in portraying Michael. Travolta has madcap style of his own in acting and it can be grating in some movies. But fortunately it suits him in Michael really well. He is really able to make the character his own. Micheal is an angel who has come to earth for an assignment. But as the poster say he is no saint. He loves womanizing and drinking. William Hurt, Andie MacDowell and Robert Pastorelli are sent by the National Mirror to verify the story of an angel and to get the interview. William Hurt plays Frank Quinlan, a reporter whose career is on skids. And Andie MacDowell plays a newbie who has been assigned to this case. To tell the truth the setup just seemed a little contrived to me and I was preparing for a disappointment. But the characters and the actors saved the film. Characters are finely etched and felt real and everybody has done a fabulous job. Still I can't give it a higher score because sometimes I found some plot gaps. I am not sure really whether they were plot holes or bad editing. It first appears that William Hurt suspects Andie Macdowell of being somebody else. It is shown like that twice where he vocalizes his doubts. But when she finally reveals the truth, he is still shocked. Such small details marred the experience a little for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A x-files episode starring MacDowell (dvd)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see that this movie is actually a supernatural road-movie in rural America as the best episodes of the "x-files". It could have been Mulder and Scully go into Iowa to bring back an angel. If Andie is a great add, Travolta as an angel sucks! Maybe it's his part, maybe it's his characterization or surely it's his personality but i found him pretty irritating. He hopes to be funny but he doesn't make me laugh; he tries to be compassionate but he is freaking nuts. Thus, each emotion he wants to give, he finally delivers the opposite: that's not the definition of a talented actor! On the opposite, Andie is as sweet and fragile than ever and she makes a good team with Hurt. Unfortunately, their romance is not well scripted as the myth of angel: there isn't a decent speech about religion, faith, heaven just a winged crazy man with paranormal powers. Except for "you've got mail", Ephron never convinces me as a writer / director and i rather find her movies dull and sleepy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot depends on your point of view.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moxie-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have done a lot of international travel, both on business and as a tourist. For both types I assure you the best advice is also the oldest: Always drink the wine of the country. In this movie the archangel Michael comes to Earth on business, wraps it up quickly and decides to hang around for a little touring. Boy! Does he "drink the wine of the country." Could man be drunk forever with liquor, love and fights He'd lief rise up of mornings and lief lie down of nights. These are things you can't do in Heaven so he enjoys them while he's here! Of course it turns out he had a couple of other jobs to tackle and, if he is less direct about them than he was about the first one, he is just as successful. The final scene is a little schmaltzy but it is also wonderful. Jean Stapleton gets to dance with John Travolta.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easily enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I think the overall average rating of this film on this site is incredibly low. There's really no reason to dislike this film. "Michael" is a simple, but fairly original, and easily enjoyable romantic comedy. The plot involves a group of reporters/experts going to examine the mysterious appearance of an angel (John Travolta) in the midwest. The angel proves to be less saintly and more worldly than we would expect, and that's what makes it entertaining. His interest in women and the Beatles takes a new spin on the angel thing. The romantic side of this film involves Michael the angel trying to get Andie MacDowell and William Hurt together. The two of them may not have the all-time greatest on-screen chemistry, but they certainly have enough to make it work well. Everyone who has rated this film so low (a 5.4??), come on! The film is not that bad. In fact, I found it quite funny and memorable. Sure, it's not the best thing you'll ever see, but it's still good. This is a film I feel has been remarkably underrated. It's fun, romantic, and recommended by me. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    #5 on my top ten worst film list
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonpics-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My website (theflickguy.org) lists "Michael" as one of the worst films of the modern era. The following is an excerpt: "Everyone slums some time in their lives, this was Travolta's turn. I still don't know what the point of this terrible film was. Nora Efron has proved to be a competent writer and director, so what the hell happened here? The Archangel Michael takes a new spin here and is portrayed as a ham-fisted, chain-smoking sugar addicted fornicating slob whose biggest contribution to humanity (after sending Lucifer to hell) was that he invented "standing in line". Yes, how funny and charming. I don't find this offensive, I find it stupid. In its defense, I can say that the ending was ever bit unsatisfying as the rest of this painful attempt at story telling."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Kind Of Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patsworld
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, I've watched this movie a dozen times. My all time favorite John Travolta film. The cast in this touching but vastly amusing movie are all a joy to behold. Jean Stapleton as Pansy is a love...no, seriously, you will love her. William Hurt and Robert Pastorelli as reporters are played to perfection. Andie MacDowell is splendid as a song-writing, many-times married fellow skeptic of the fact that Michael is, indeed, an angel. There is a scene in this movie that never fails to bring me to tears - and one that never fails to make me laugh out loud. "He's not that kind of an angel".....ah, but he sure is mine. This movie is one I'd never pass by if it shows up on TV, even though I own a copy of my own. And if I didn't, I seek out and find one to buy. This is what entertainment is all about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It is not my area..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rodneyrf@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thumbs up! This silly yet enriching picture makes us travel back in time, enabling us to naively live up a story as we commonly did in Frank Capra's movies. Michael, the angel, says many times: "It is not my area...", for many of the questions and doubts people have. We must live life without worrying too much. That's why the angel is sent down. He shows that we should live up life lightly, trying to share happiness and content with others.. It's something each and every one of us should try to do, step outside ourselves see just what our contributions can be. As I always say: Good movies never leave us. Take your time having authentic and original laughs in this light yet profound comedy. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A delightful heartwarming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Travoltas portrayal of an this angel is an interesting one. What we know of angels is that they are great warriors, messengers of god and always seem to be perfect. What if they aren't. He plays a rude obnoxious, womanizer who will fulfill your wishes, and make you care enough about the world that you will be touched. So what happens when you don't believe in anything and you are sent to investigate a story, only to meet one with wings and looks less then angelic. William Hurt plays a cynic who is out to write about a possible hoax who ends up becoming a believer by the end. Andie MacDowell and the rest of the cast play great parts. It is enjoyable that the film unapologetically illustrates how wonderful like is and the little things that we take for granted, and we should enjoy every moment like it was our last. With some of the scenes in this movie that changes the different characters views on the reality of angels may make you wonder if our vision of angels could be changed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very sweet.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it. Below is a repeat of the lines I've written above. I really don't feel like I need to say more, but IMDb requires at least 10 lines, so here you go... This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Film..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nora Ephron's Box-Office Super-Hit 'Michael' is A Decent Film, that manages to pass-off as a light-entertainer, that also packs in some fine acting. 'Michael' Synopsis: Two tabloid reporters checking out a report of the Archangel Michael living with an old woman find that it's true. But that's not the only surprise. 'Michael' is a fantasy film, but, the Angel here is not shown doing "The Impossible". Actually, the depiction of it's Angel Michael, over-here is portrayed as a boozing, smoking, oversexed slob혰yet capable of imparting unexpected wisdom. But, Despite those aspects, Michael does come across as a free-soul & oozes excitement. Screenplay by Nora Ephron & Delia Ephron is decent & fast. However, the culmination to this story, is not convincing. It just doesn't leave an impact. Nora Ephron's Direction, is polite. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are proper. Performance-Wise: John Travolta as the Archangel Michael, is lively. William Hurt, like always, does wonders. Andie MacDowell is routine. Robert Pastorelli supports well. Bob Hoskins appears in a brief role. On the whole, 'Michael' is a decent entertainer, that doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lighthearted Romance, Flawed but still very Enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have seen angels coming to earth before, but never like this. Well at least I haven't. John Travolta as Micheal has done an amazing job in portraying Michael. Travolta has madcap style of his own in acting and it can be grating in some movies. But fortunately it suits him in Michael really well. He is really able to make the character his own. Micheal is an angel who has come to earth for an assignment. But as the poster say he is no saint. He loves womanizing and drinking. William Hurt, Andie MacDowell and Robert Pastorelli are sent by the National Mirror to verify the story of an angel and to get the interview. William Hurt plays Frank Quinlan, a reporter whose career is on skids. And Andie MacDowell plays a newbie who has been assigned to this case. To tell the truth the setup just seemed a little contrived to me and I was preparing for a disappointment. But the characters and the actors saved the film. Characters are finely etched and felt real and everybody has done a fabulous job. Still I can't give it a higher score because sometimes I found some plot gaps. I am not sure really whether they were plot holes or bad editing. It first appears that William Hurt suspects Andie Macdowell of being somebody else. It is shown like that twice where he vocalizes his doubts. But when she finally reveals the truth, he is still shocked. Such small details marred the experience a little for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A x-files episode starring MacDowell (dvd)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see that this movie is actually a supernatural road-movie in rural America as the best episodes of the "x-files". It could have been Mulder and Scully go into Iowa to bring back an angel. If Andie is a great add, Travolta as an angel sucks! Maybe it's his part, maybe it's his characterization or surely it's his personality but i found him pretty irritating. He hopes to be funny but he doesn't make me laugh; he tries to be compassionate but he is freaking nuts. Thus, each emotion he wants to give, he finally delivers the opposite: that's not the definition of a talented actor! On the opposite, Andie is as sweet and fragile than ever and she makes a good team with Hurt. Unfortunately, their romance is not well scripted as the myth of angel: there isn't a decent speech about religion, faith, heaven just a winged crazy man with paranormal powers. Except for "you've got mail", Ephron never convinces me as a writer / director and i rather find her movies dull and sleepy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot depends on your point of view.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moxie-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have done a lot of international travel, both on business and as a tourist. For both types I assure you the best advice is also the oldest: Always drink the wine of the country. In this movie the archangel Michael comes to Earth on business, wraps it up quickly and decides to hang around for a little touring. Boy! Does he "drink the wine of the country." Could man be drunk forever with liquor, love and fights He'd lief rise up of mornings and lief lie down of nights. These are things you can't do in Heaven so he enjoys them while he's here! Of course it turns out he had a couple of other jobs to tackle and, if he is less direct about them than he was about the first one, he is just as successful. The final scene is a little schmaltzy but it is also wonderful. Jean Stapleton gets to dance with John Travolta.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easily enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I think the overall average rating of this film on this site is incredibly low. There's really no reason to dislike this film. "Michael" is a simple, but fairly original, and easily enjoyable romantic comedy. The plot involves a group of reporters/experts going to examine the mysterious appearance of an angel (John Travolta) in the midwest. The angel proves to be less saintly and more worldly than we would expect, and that's what makes it entertaining. His interest in women and the Beatles takes a new spin on the angel thing. The romantic side of this film involves Michael the angel trying to get Andie MacDowell and William Hurt together. The two of them may not have the all-time greatest on-screen chemistry, but they certainly have enough to make it work well. Everyone who has rated this film so low (a 5.4??), come on! The film is not that bad. In fact, I found it quite funny and memorable. Sure, it's not the best thing you'll ever see, but it's still good. This is a film I feel has been remarkably underrated. It's fun, romantic, and recommended by me. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    #5 on my top ten worst film list
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonpics-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My website (theflickguy.org) lists "Michael" as one of the worst films of the modern era. The following is an excerpt: "Everyone slums some time in their lives, this was Travolta's turn. I still don't know what the point of this terrible film was. Nora Efron has proved to be a competent writer and director, so what the hell happened here? The Archangel Michael takes a new spin here and is portrayed as a ham-fisted, chain-smoking sugar addicted fornicating slob whose biggest contribution to humanity (after sending Lucifer to hell) was that he invented "standing in line". Yes, how funny and charming. I don't find this offensive, I find it stupid. In its defense, I can say that the ending was ever bit unsatisfying as the rest of this painful attempt at story telling."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Kind Of Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patsworld
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, I've watched this movie a dozen times. My all time favorite John Travolta film. The cast in this touching but vastly amusing movie are all a joy to behold. Jean Stapleton as Pansy is a love...no, seriously, you will love her. William Hurt and Robert Pastorelli as reporters are played to perfection. Andie MacDowell is splendid as a song-writing, many-times married fellow skeptic of the fact that Michael is, indeed, an angel. There is a scene in this movie that never fails to bring me to tears - and one that never fails to make me laugh out loud. "He's not that kind of an angel".....ah, but he sure is mine. This movie is one I'd never pass by if it shows up on TV, even though I own a copy of my own. And if I didn't, I seek out and find one to buy. This is what entertainment is all about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It is not my area..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rodneyrf@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thumbs up! This silly yet enriching picture makes us travel back in time, enabling us to naively live up a story as we commonly did in Frank Capra's movies. Michael, the angel, says many times: "It is not my area...", for many of the questions and doubts people have. We must live life without worrying too much. That's why the angel is sent down. He shows that we should live up life lightly, trying to share happiness and content with others.. It's something each and every one of us should try to do, step outside ourselves see just what our contributions can be. As I always say: Good movies never leave us. Take your time having authentic and original laughs in this light yet profound comedy. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A delightful heartwarming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Travoltas portrayal of an this angel is an interesting one. What we know of angels is that they are great warriors, messengers of god and always seem to be perfect. What if they aren't. He plays a rude obnoxious, womanizer who will fulfill your wishes, and make you care enough about the world that you will be touched. So what happens when you don't believe in anything and you are sent to investigate a story, only to meet one with wings and looks less then angelic. William Hurt plays a cynic who is out to write about a possible hoax who ends up becoming a believer by the end. Andie MacDowell and the rest of the cast play great parts. It is enjoyable that the film unapologetically illustrates how wonderful like is and the little things that we take for granted, and we should enjoy every moment like it was our last. With some of the scenes in this movie that changes the different characters views on the reality of angels may make you wonder if our vision of angels could be changed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very sweet.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it. Below is a repeat of the lines I've written above. I really don't feel like I need to say more, but IMDb requires at least 10 lines, so here you go... This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Film..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nora Ephron's Box-Office Super-Hit 'Michael' is A Decent Film, that manages to pass-off as a light-entertainer, that also packs in some fine acting. 'Michael' Synopsis: Two tabloid reporters checking out a report of the Archangel Michael living with an old woman find that it's true. But that's not the only surprise. 'Michael' is a fantasy film, but, the Angel here is not shown doing "The Impossible". Actually, the depiction of it's Angel Michael, over-here is portrayed as a boozing, smoking, oversexed slob혰yet capable of imparting unexpected wisdom. But, Despite those aspects, Michael does come across as a free-soul & oozes excitement. Screenplay by Nora Ephron & Delia Ephron is decent & fast. However, the culmination to this story, is not convincing. It just doesn't leave an impact. Nora Ephron's Direction, is polite. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are proper. Performance-Wise: John Travolta as the Archangel Michael, is lively. William Hurt, like always, does wonders. Andie MacDowell is routine. Robert Pastorelli supports well. Bob Hoskins appears in a brief role. On the whole, 'Michael' is a decent entertainer, that doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lighthearted Romance, Flawed but still very Enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have seen angels coming to earth before, but never like this. Well at least I haven't. John Travolta as Micheal has done an amazing job in portraying Michael. Travolta has madcap style of his own in acting and it can be grating in some movies. But fortunately it suits him in Michael really well. He is really able to make the character his own. Micheal is an angel who has come to earth for an assignment. But as the poster say he is no saint. He loves womanizing and drinking. William Hurt, Andie MacDowell and Robert Pastorelli are sent by the National Mirror to verify the story of an angel and to get the interview. William Hurt plays Frank Quinlan, a reporter whose career is on skids. And Andie MacDowell plays a newbie who has been assigned to this case. To tell the truth the setup just seemed a little contrived to me and I was preparing for a disappointment. But the characters and the actors saved the film. Characters are finely etched and felt real and everybody has done a fabulous job. Still I can't give it a higher score because sometimes I found some plot gaps. I am not sure really whether they were plot holes or bad editing. It first appears that William Hurt suspects Andie Macdowell of being somebody else. It is shown like that twice where he vocalizes his doubts. But when she finally reveals the truth, he is still shocked. Such small details marred the experience a little for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A x-files episode starring MacDowell (dvd)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see that this movie is actually a supernatural road-movie in rural America as the best episodes of the "x-files". It could have been Mulder and Scully go into Iowa to bring back an angel. If Andie is a great add, Travolta as an angel sucks! Maybe it's his part, maybe it's his characterization or surely it's his personality but i found him pretty irritating. He hopes to be funny but he doesn't make me laugh; he tries to be compassionate but he is freaking nuts. Thus, each emotion he wants to give, he finally delivers the opposite: that's not the definition of a talented actor! On the opposite, Andie is as sweet and fragile than ever and she makes a good team with Hurt. Unfortunately, their romance is not well scripted as the myth of angel: there isn't a decent speech about religion, faith, heaven just a winged crazy man with paranormal powers. Except for "you've got mail", Ephron never convinces me as a writer / director and i rather find her movies dull and sleepy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot depends on your point of view.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moxie-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have done a lot of international travel, both on business and as a tourist. For both types I assure you the best advice is also the oldest: Always drink the wine of the country. In this movie the archangel Michael comes to Earth on business, wraps it up quickly and decides to hang around for a little touring. Boy! Does he "drink the wine of the country." Could man be drunk forever with liquor, love and fights He'd lief rise up of mornings and lief lie down of nights. These are things you can't do in Heaven so he enjoys them while he's here! Of course it turns out he had a couple of other jobs to tackle and, if he is less direct about them than he was about the first one, he is just as successful. The final scene is a little schmaltzy but it is also wonderful. Jean Stapleton gets to dance with John Travolta.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easily enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I think the overall average rating of this film on this site is incredibly low. There's really no reason to dislike this film. "Michael" is a simple, but fairly original, and easily enjoyable romantic comedy. The plot involves a group of reporters/experts going to examine the mysterious appearance of an angel (John Travolta) in the midwest. The angel proves to be less saintly and more worldly than we would expect, and that's what makes it entertaining. His interest in women and the Beatles takes a new spin on the angel thing. The romantic side of this film involves Michael the angel trying to get Andie MacDowell and William Hurt together. The two of them may not have the all-time greatest on-screen chemistry, but they certainly have enough to make it work well. Everyone who has rated this film so low (a 5.4??), come on! The film is not that bad. In fact, I found it quite funny and memorable. Sure, it's not the best thing you'll ever see, but it's still good. This is a film I feel has been remarkably underrated. It's fun, romantic, and recommended by me. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    #5 on my top ten worst film list
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonpics-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My website (theflickguy.org) lists "Michael" as one of the worst films of the modern era. The following is an excerpt: "Everyone slums some time in their lives, this was Travolta's turn. I still don't know what the point of this terrible film was. Nora Efron has proved to be a competent writer and director, so what the hell happened here? The Archangel Michael takes a new spin here and is portrayed as a ham-fisted, chain-smoking sugar addicted fornicating slob whose biggest contribution to humanity (after sending Lucifer to hell) was that he invented "standing in line". Yes, how funny and charming. I don't find this offensive, I find it stupid. In its defense, I can say that the ending was ever bit unsatisfying as the rest of this painful attempt at story telling."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Kind Of Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patsworld
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, I've watched this movie a dozen times. My all time favorite John Travolta film. The cast in this touching but vastly amusing movie are all a joy to behold. Jean Stapleton as Pansy is a love...no, seriously, you will love her. William Hurt and Robert Pastorelli as reporters are played to perfection. Andie MacDowell is splendid as a song-writing, many-times married fellow skeptic of the fact that Michael is, indeed, an angel. There is a scene in this movie that never fails to bring me to tears - and one that never fails to make me laugh out loud. "He's not that kind of an angel".....ah, but he sure is mine. This movie is one I'd never pass by if it shows up on TV, even though I own a copy of my own. And if I didn't, I seek out and find one to buy. This is what entertainment is all about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It is not my area..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rodneyrf@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thumbs up! This silly yet enriching picture makes us travel back in time, enabling us to naively live up a story as we commonly did in Frank Capra's movies. Michael, the angel, says many times: "It is not my area...", for many of the questions and doubts people have. We must live life without worrying too much. That's why the angel is sent down. He shows that we should live up life lightly, trying to share happiness and content with others.. It's something each and every one of us should try to do, step outside ourselves see just what our contributions can be. As I always say: Good movies never leave us. Take your time having authentic and original laughs in this light yet profound comedy. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A delightful heartwarming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Travoltas portrayal of an this angel is an interesting one. What we know of angels is that they are great warriors, messengers of god and always seem to be perfect. What if they aren't. He plays a rude obnoxious, womanizer who will fulfill your wishes, and make you care enough about the world that you will be touched. So what happens when you don't believe in anything and you are sent to investigate a story, only to meet one with wings and looks less then angelic. William Hurt plays a cynic who is out to write about a possible hoax who ends up becoming a believer by the end. Andie MacDowell and the rest of the cast play great parts. It is enjoyable that the film unapologetically illustrates how wonderful like is and the little things that we take for granted, and we should enjoy every moment like it was our last. With some of the scenes in this movie that changes the different characters views on the reality of angels may make you wonder if our vision of angels could be changed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very sweet.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it. Below is a repeat of the lines I've written above. I really don't feel like I need to say more, but IMDb requires at least 10 lines, so here you go... This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Film..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nora Ephron's Box-Office Super-Hit 'Michael' is A Decent Film, that manages to pass-off as a light-entertainer, that also packs in some fine acting. 'Michael' Synopsis: Two tabloid reporters checking out a report of the Archangel Michael living with an old woman find that it's true. But that's not the only surprise. 'Michael' is a fantasy film, but, the Angel here is not shown doing "The Impossible". Actually, the depiction of it's Angel Michael, over-here is portrayed as a boozing, smoking, oversexed slob혰yet capable of imparting unexpected wisdom. But, Despite those aspects, Michael does come across as a free-soul & oozes excitement. Screenplay by Nora Ephron & Delia Ephron is decent & fast. However, the culmination to this story, is not convincing. It just doesn't leave an impact. Nora Ephron's Direction, is polite. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are proper. Performance-Wise: John Travolta as the Archangel Michael, is lively. William Hurt, like always, does wonders. Andie MacDowell is routine. Robert Pastorelli supports well. Bob Hoskins appears in a brief role. On the whole, 'Michael' is a decent entertainer, that doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lighthearted Romance, Flawed but still very Enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have seen angels coming to earth before, but never like this. Well at least I haven't. John Travolta as Micheal has done an amazing job in portraying Michael. Travolta has madcap style of his own in acting and it can be grating in some movies. But fortunately it suits him in Michael really well. He is really able to make the character his own. Micheal is an angel who has come to earth for an assignment. But as the poster say he is no saint. He loves womanizing and drinking. William Hurt, Andie MacDowell and Robert Pastorelli are sent by the National Mirror to verify the story of an angel and to get the interview. William Hurt plays Frank Quinlan, a reporter whose career is on skids. And Andie MacDowell plays a newbie who has been assigned to this case. To tell the truth the setup just seemed a little contrived to me and I was preparing for a disappointment. But the characters and the actors saved the film. Characters are finely etched and felt real and everybody has done a fabulous job. Still I can't give it a higher score because sometimes I found some plot gaps. I am not sure really whether they were plot holes or bad editing. It first appears that William Hurt suspects Andie Macdowell of being somebody else. It is shown like that twice where he vocalizes his doubts. But when she finally reveals the truth, he is still shocked. Such small details marred the experience a little for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A x-files episode starring MacDowell (dvd)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see that this movie is actually a supernatural road-movie in rural America as the best episodes of the "x-files". It could have been Mulder and Scully go into Iowa to bring back an angel. If Andie is a great add, Travolta as an angel sucks! Maybe it's his part, maybe it's his characterization or surely it's his personality but i found him pretty irritating. He hopes to be funny but he doesn't make me laugh; he tries to be compassionate but he is freaking nuts. Thus, each emotion he wants to give, he finally delivers the opposite: that's not the definition of a talented actor! On the opposite, Andie is as sweet and fragile than ever and she makes a good team with Hurt. Unfortunately, their romance is not well scripted as the myth of angel: there isn't a decent speech about religion, faith, heaven just a winged crazy man with paranormal powers. Except for "you've got mail", Ephron never convinces me as a writer / director and i rather find her movies dull and sleepy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot depends on your point of view.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moxie-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have done a lot of international travel, both on business and as a tourist. For both types I assure you the best advice is also the oldest: Always drink the wine of the country. In this movie the archangel Michael comes to Earth on business, wraps it up quickly and decides to hang around for a little touring. Boy! Does he "drink the wine of the country." Could man be drunk forever with liquor, love and fights He'd lief rise up of mornings and lief lie down of nights. These are things you can't do in Heaven so he enjoys them while he's here! Of course it turns out he had a couple of other jobs to tackle and, if he is less direct about them than he was about the first one, he is just as successful. The final scene is a little schmaltzy but it is also wonderful. Jean Stapleton gets to dance with John Travolta.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easily enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I think the overall average rating of this film on this site is incredibly low. There's really no reason to dislike this film. "Michael" is a simple, but fairly original, and easily enjoyable romantic comedy. The plot involves a group of reporters/experts going to examine the mysterious appearance of an angel (John Travolta) in the midwest. The angel proves to be less saintly and more worldly than we would expect, and that's what makes it entertaining. His interest in women and the Beatles takes a new spin on the angel thing. The romantic side of this film involves Michael the angel trying to get Andie MacDowell and William Hurt together. The two of them may not have the all-time greatest on-screen chemistry, but they certainly have enough to make it work well. Everyone who has rated this film so low (a 5.4??), come on! The film is not that bad. In fact, I found it quite funny and memorable. Sure, it's not the best thing you'll ever see, but it's still good. This is a film I feel has been remarkably underrated. It's fun, romantic, and recommended by me. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    #5 on my top ten worst film list
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonpics-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My website (theflickguy.org) lists "Michael" as one of the worst films of the modern era. The following is an excerpt: "Everyone slums some time in their lives, this was Travolta's turn. I still don't know what the point of this terrible film was. Nora Efron has proved to be a competent writer and director, so what the hell happened here? The Archangel Michael takes a new spin here and is portrayed as a ham-fisted, chain-smoking sugar addicted fornicating slob whose biggest contribution to humanity (after sending Lucifer to hell) was that he invented "standing in line". Yes, how funny and charming. I don't find this offensive, I find it stupid. In its defense, I can say that the ending was ever bit unsatisfying as the rest of this painful attempt at story telling."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Kind Of Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patsworld
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, I've watched this movie a dozen times. My all time favorite John Travolta film. The cast in this touching but vastly amusing movie are all a joy to behold. Jean Stapleton as Pansy is a love...no, seriously, you will love her. William Hurt and Robert Pastorelli as reporters are played to perfection. Andie MacDowell is splendid as a song-writing, many-times married fellow skeptic of the fact that Michael is, indeed, an angel. There is a scene in this movie that never fails to bring me to tears - and one that never fails to make me laugh out loud. "He's not that kind of an angel".....ah, but he sure is mine. This movie is one I'd never pass by if it shows up on TV, even though I own a copy of my own. And if I didn't, I seek out and find one to buy. This is what entertainment is all about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It is not my area..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rodneyrf@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thumbs up! This silly yet enriching picture makes us travel back in time, enabling us to naively live up a story as we commonly did in Frank Capra's movies. Michael, the angel, says many times: "It is not my area...", for many of the questions and doubts people have. We must live life without worrying too much. That's why the angel is sent down. He shows that we should live up life lightly, trying to share happiness and content with others.. It's something each and every one of us should try to do, step outside ourselves see just what our contributions can be. As I always say: Good movies never leave us. Take your time having authentic and original laughs in this light yet profound comedy. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A delightful heartwarming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Travoltas portrayal of an this angel is an interesting one. What we know of angels is that they are great warriors, messengers of god and always seem to be perfect. What if they aren't. He plays a rude obnoxious, womanizer who will fulfill your wishes, and make you care enough about the world that you will be touched. So what happens when you don't believe in anything and you are sent to investigate a story, only to meet one with wings and looks less then angelic. William Hurt plays a cynic who is out to write about a possible hoax who ends up becoming a believer by the end. Andie MacDowell and the rest of the cast play great parts. It is enjoyable that the film unapologetically illustrates how wonderful like is and the little things that we take for granted, and we should enjoy every moment like it was our last. With some of the scenes in this movie that changes the different characters views on the reality of angels may make you wonder if our vision of angels could be changed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very sweet.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it. Below is a repeat of the lines I've written above. I really don't feel like I need to say more, but IMDb requires at least 10 lines, so here you go... This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Film..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nora Ephron's Box-Office Super-Hit 'Michael' is A Decent Film, that manages to pass-off as a light-entertainer, that also packs in some fine acting. 'Michael' Synopsis: Two tabloid reporters checking out a report of the Archangel Michael living with an old woman find that it's true. But that's not the only surprise. 'Michael' is a fantasy film, but, the Angel here is not shown doing "The Impossible". Actually, the depiction of it's Angel Michael, over-here is portrayed as a boozing, smoking, oversexed slob혰yet capable of imparting unexpected wisdom. But, Despite those aspects, Michael does come across as a free-soul & oozes excitement. Screenplay by Nora Ephron & Delia Ephron is decent & fast. However, the culmination to this story, is not convincing. It just doesn't leave an impact. Nora Ephron's Direction, is polite. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are proper. Performance-Wise: John Travolta as the Archangel Michael, is lively. William Hurt, like always, does wonders. Andie MacDowell is routine. Robert Pastorelli supports well. Bob Hoskins appears in a brief role. On the whole, 'Michael' is a decent entertainer, that doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lighthearted Romance, Flawed but still very Enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have seen angels coming to earth before, but never like this. Well at least I haven't. John Travolta as Micheal has done an amazing job in portraying Michael. Travolta has madcap style of his own in acting and it can be grating in some movies. But fortunately it suits him in Michael really well. He is really able to make the character his own. Micheal is an angel who has come to earth for an assignment. But as the poster say he is no saint. He loves womanizing and drinking. William Hurt, Andie MacDowell and Robert Pastorelli are sent by the National Mirror to verify the story of an angel and to get the interview. William Hurt plays Frank Quinlan, a reporter whose career is on skids. And Andie MacDowell plays a newbie who has been assigned to this case. To tell the truth the setup just seemed a little contrived to me and I was preparing for a disappointment. But the characters and the actors saved the film. Characters are finely etched and felt real and everybody has done a fabulous job. Still I can't give it a higher score because sometimes I found some plot gaps. I am not sure really whether they were plot holes or bad editing. It first appears that William Hurt suspects Andie Macdowell of being somebody else. It is shown like that twice where he vocalizes his doubts. But when she finally reveals the truth, he is still shocked. Such small details marred the experience a little for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A x-files episode starring MacDowell (dvd)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see that this movie is actually a supernatural road-movie in rural America as the best episodes of the "x-files". It could have been Mulder and Scully go into Iowa to bring back an angel. If Andie is a great add, Travolta as an angel sucks! Maybe it's his part, maybe it's his characterization or surely it's his personality but i found him pretty irritating. He hopes to be funny but he doesn't make me laugh; he tries to be compassionate but he is freaking nuts. Thus, each emotion he wants to give, he finally delivers the opposite: that's not the definition of a talented actor! On the opposite, Andie is as sweet and fragile than ever and she makes a good team with Hurt. Unfortunately, their romance is not well scripted as the myth of angel: there isn't a decent speech about religion, faith, heaven just a winged crazy man with paranormal powers. Except for "you've got mail", Ephron never convinces me as a writer / director and i rather find her movies dull and sleepy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot depends on your point of view.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moxie-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have done a lot of international travel, both on business and as a tourist. For both types I assure you the best advice is also the oldest: Always drink the wine of the country. In this movie the archangel Michael comes to Earth on business, wraps it up quickly and decides to hang around for a little touring. Boy! Does he "drink the wine of the country." Could man be drunk forever with liquor, love and fights He'd lief rise up of mornings and lief lie down of nights. These are things you can't do in Heaven so he enjoys them while he's here! Of course it turns out he had a couple of other jobs to tackle and, if he is less direct about them than he was about the first one, he is just as successful. The final scene is a little schmaltzy but it is also wonderful. Jean Stapleton gets to dance with John Travolta.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easily enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I think the overall average rating of this film on this site is incredibly low. There's really no reason to dislike this film. "Michael" is a simple, but fairly original, and easily enjoyable romantic comedy. The plot involves a group of reporters/experts going to examine the mysterious appearance of an angel (John Travolta) in the midwest. The angel proves to be less saintly and more worldly than we would expect, and that's what makes it entertaining. His interest in women and the Beatles takes a new spin on the angel thing. The romantic side of this film involves Michael the angel trying to get Andie MacDowell and William Hurt together. The two of them may not have the all-time greatest on-screen chemistry, but they certainly have enough to make it work well. Everyone who has rated this film so low (a 5.4??), come on! The film is not that bad. In fact, I found it quite funny and memorable. Sure, it's not the best thing you'll ever see, but it's still good. This is a film I feel has been remarkably underrated. It's fun, romantic, and recommended by me. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    #5 on my top ten worst film list
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonpics-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My website (theflickguy.org) lists "Michael" as one of the worst films of the modern era. The following is an excerpt: "Everyone slums some time in their lives, this was Travolta's turn. I still don't know what the point of this terrible film was. Nora Efron has proved to be a competent writer and director, so what the hell happened here? The Archangel Michael takes a new spin here and is portrayed as a ham-fisted, chain-smoking sugar addicted fornicating slob whose biggest contribution to humanity (after sending Lucifer to hell) was that he invented "standing in line". Yes, how funny and charming. I don't find this offensive, I find it stupid. In its defense, I can say that the ending was ever bit unsatisfying as the rest of this painful attempt at story telling."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Kind Of Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patsworld
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, I've watched this movie a dozen times. My all time favorite John Travolta film. The cast in this touching but vastly amusing movie are all a joy to behold. Jean Stapleton as Pansy is a love...no, seriously, you will love her. William Hurt and Robert Pastorelli as reporters are played to perfection. Andie MacDowell is splendid as a song-writing, many-times married fellow skeptic of the fact that Michael is, indeed, an angel. There is a scene in this movie that never fails to bring me to tears - and one that never fails to make me laugh out loud. "He's not that kind of an angel".....ah, but he sure is mine. This movie is one I'd never pass by if it shows up on TV, even though I own a copy of my own. And if I didn't, I seek out and find one to buy. This is what entertainment is all about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It is not my area..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rodneyrf@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thumbs up! This silly yet enriching picture makes us travel back in time, enabling us to naively live up a story as we commonly did in Frank Capra's movies. Michael, the angel, says many times: "It is not my area...", for many of the questions and doubts people have. We must live life without worrying too much. That's why the angel is sent down. He shows that we should live up life lightly, trying to share happiness and content with others.. It's something each and every one of us should try to do, step outside ourselves see just what our contributions can be. As I always say: Good movies never leave us. Take your time having authentic and original laughs in this light yet profound comedy. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A delightful heartwarming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Travoltas portrayal of an this angel is an interesting one. What we know of angels is that they are great warriors, messengers of god and always seem to be perfect. What if they aren't. He plays a rude obnoxious, womanizer who will fulfill your wishes, and make you care enough about the world that you will be touched. So what happens when you don't believe in anything and you are sent to investigate a story, only to meet one with wings and looks less then angelic. William Hurt plays a cynic who is out to write about a possible hoax who ends up becoming a believer by the end. Andie MacDowell and the rest of the cast play great parts. It is enjoyable that the film unapologetically illustrates how wonderful like is and the little things that we take for granted, and we should enjoy every moment like it was our last. With some of the scenes in this movie that changes the different characters views on the reality of angels may make you wonder if our vision of angels could be changed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very sweet.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it. Below is a repeat of the lines I've written above. I really don't feel like I need to say more, but IMDb requires at least 10 lines, so here you go... This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Film..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nora Ephron's Box-Office Super-Hit 'Michael' is A Decent Film, that manages to pass-off as a light-entertainer, that also packs in some fine acting. 'Michael' Synopsis: Two tabloid reporters checking out a report of the Archangel Michael living with an old woman find that it's true. But that's not the only surprise. 'Michael' is a fantasy film, but, the Angel here is not shown doing "The Impossible". Actually, the depiction of it's Angel Michael, over-here is portrayed as a boozing, smoking, oversexed slob혰yet capable of imparting unexpected wisdom. But, Despite those aspects, Michael does come across as a free-soul & oozes excitement. Screenplay by Nora Ephron & Delia Ephron is decent & fast. However, the culmination to this story, is not convincing. It just doesn't leave an impact. Nora Ephron's Direction, is polite. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are proper. Performance-Wise: John Travolta as the Archangel Michael, is lively. William Hurt, like always, does wonders. Andie MacDowell is routine. Robert Pastorelli supports well. Bob Hoskins appears in a brief role. On the whole, 'Michael' is a decent entertainer, that doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lighthearted Romance, Flawed but still very Enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have seen angels coming to earth before, but never like this. Well at least I haven't. John Travolta as Micheal has done an amazing job in portraying Michael. Travolta has madcap style of his own in acting and it can be grating in some movies. But fortunately it suits him in Michael really well. He is really able to make the character his own. Micheal is an angel who has come to earth for an assignment. But as the poster say he is no saint. He loves womanizing and drinking. William Hurt, Andie MacDowell and Robert Pastorelli are sent by the National Mirror to verify the story of an angel and to get the interview. William Hurt plays Frank Quinlan, a reporter whose career is on skids. And Andie MacDowell plays a newbie who has been assigned to this case. To tell the truth the setup just seemed a little contrived to me and I was preparing for a disappointment. But the characters and the actors saved the film. Characters are finely etched and felt real and everybody has done a fabulous job. Still I can't give it a higher score because sometimes I found some plot gaps. I am not sure really whether they were plot holes or bad editing. It first appears that William Hurt suspects Andie Macdowell of being somebody else. It is shown like that twice where he vocalizes his doubts. But when she finally reveals the truth, he is still shocked. Such small details marred the experience a little for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A x-files episode starring MacDowell (dvd)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see that this movie is actually a supernatural road-movie in rural America as the best episodes of the "x-files". It could have been Mulder and Scully go into Iowa to bring back an angel. If Andie is a great add, Travolta as an angel sucks! Maybe it's his part, maybe it's his characterization or surely it's his personality but i found him pretty irritating. He hopes to be funny but he doesn't make me laugh; he tries to be compassionate but he is freaking nuts. Thus, each emotion he wants to give, he finally delivers the opposite: that's not the definition of a talented actor! On the opposite, Andie is as sweet and fragile than ever and she makes a good team with Hurt. Unfortunately, their romance is not well scripted as the myth of angel: there isn't a decent speech about religion, faith, heaven just a winged crazy man with paranormal powers. Except for "you've got mail", Ephron never convinces me as a writer / director and i rather find her movies dull and sleepy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot depends on your point of view.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moxie-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have done a lot of international travel, both on business and as a tourist. For both types I assure you the best advice is also the oldest: Always drink the wine of the country. In this movie the archangel Michael comes to Earth on business, wraps it up quickly and decides to hang around for a little touring. Boy! Does he "drink the wine of the country." Could man be drunk forever with liquor, love and fights He'd lief rise up of mornings and lief lie down of nights. These are things you can't do in Heaven so he enjoys them while he's here! Of course it turns out he had a couple of other jobs to tackle and, if he is less direct about them than he was about the first one, he is just as successful. The final scene is a little schmaltzy but it is also wonderful. Jean Stapleton gets to dance with John Travolta.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easily enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I think the overall average rating of this film on this site is incredibly low. There's really no reason to dislike this film. "Michael" is a simple, but fairly original, and easily enjoyable romantic comedy. The plot involves a group of reporters/experts going to examine the mysterious appearance of an angel (John Travolta) in the midwest. The angel proves to be less saintly and more worldly than we would expect, and that's what makes it entertaining. His interest in women and the Beatles takes a new spin on the angel thing. The romantic side of this film involves Michael the angel trying to get Andie MacDowell and William Hurt together. The two of them may not have the all-time greatest on-screen chemistry, but they certainly have enough to make it work well. Everyone who has rated this film so low (a 5.4??), come on! The film is not that bad. In fact, I found it quite funny and memorable. Sure, it's not the best thing you'll ever see, but it's still good. This is a film I feel has been remarkably underrated. It's fun, romantic, and recommended by me. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    #5 on my top ten worst film list
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonpics-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My website (theflickguy.org) lists "Michael" as one of the worst films of the modern era. The following is an excerpt: "Everyone slums some time in their lives, this was Travolta's turn. I still don't know what the point of this terrible film was. Nora Efron has proved to be a competent writer and director, so what the hell happened here? The Archangel Michael takes a new spin here and is portrayed as a ham-fisted, chain-smoking sugar addicted fornicating slob whose biggest contribution to humanity (after sending Lucifer to hell) was that he invented "standing in line". Yes, how funny and charming. I don't find this offensive, I find it stupid. In its defense, I can say that the ending was ever bit unsatisfying as the rest of this painful attempt at story telling."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Kind Of Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patsworld
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, I've watched this movie a dozen times. My all time favorite John Travolta film. The cast in this touching but vastly amusing movie are all a joy to behold. Jean Stapleton as Pansy is a love...no, seriously, you will love her. William Hurt and Robert Pastorelli as reporters are played to perfection. Andie MacDowell is splendid as a song-writing, many-times married fellow skeptic of the fact that Michael is, indeed, an angel. There is a scene in this movie that never fails to bring me to tears - and one that never fails to make me laugh out loud. "He's not that kind of an angel".....ah, but he sure is mine. This movie is one I'd never pass by if it shows up on TV, even though I own a copy of my own. And if I didn't, I seek out and find one to buy. This is what entertainment is all about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It is not my area..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rodneyrf@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thumbs up! This silly yet enriching picture makes us travel back in time, enabling us to naively live up a story as we commonly did in Frank Capra's movies. Michael, the angel, says many times: "It is not my area...", for many of the questions and doubts people have. We must live life without worrying too much. That's why the angel is sent down. He shows that we should live up life lightly, trying to share happiness and content with others.. It's something each and every one of us should try to do, step outside ourselves see just what our contributions can be. As I always say: Good movies never leave us. Take your time having authentic and original laughs in this light yet profound comedy. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A delightful heartwarming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Travoltas portrayal of an this angel is an interesting one. What we know of angels is that they are great warriors, messengers of god and always seem to be perfect. What if they aren't. He plays a rude obnoxious, womanizer who will fulfill your wishes, and make you care enough about the world that you will be touched. So what happens when you don't believe in anything and you are sent to investigate a story, only to meet one with wings and looks less then angelic. William Hurt plays a cynic who is out to write about a possible hoax who ends up becoming a believer by the end. Andie MacDowell and the rest of the cast play great parts. It is enjoyable that the film unapologetically illustrates how wonderful like is and the little things that we take for granted, and we should enjoy every moment like it was our last. With some of the scenes in this movie that changes the different characters views on the reality of angels may make you wonder if our vision of angels could be changed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very sweet.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it. Below is a repeat of the lines I've written above. I really don't feel like I need to say more, but IMDb requires at least 10 lines, so here you go... This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Film..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nora Ephron's Box-Office Super-Hit 'Michael' is A Decent Film, that manages to pass-off as a light-entertainer, that also packs in some fine acting. 'Michael' Synopsis: Two tabloid reporters checking out a report of the Archangel Michael living with an old woman find that it's true. But that's not the only surprise. 'Michael' is a fantasy film, but, the Angel here is not shown doing "The Impossible". Actually, the depiction of it's Angel Michael, over-here is portrayed as a boozing, smoking, oversexed slob혰yet capable of imparting unexpected wisdom. But, Despite those aspects, Michael does come across as a free-soul & oozes excitement. Screenplay by Nora Ephron & Delia Ephron is decent & fast. However, the culmination to this story, is not convincing. It just doesn't leave an impact. Nora Ephron's Direction, is polite. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are proper. Performance-Wise: John Travolta as the Archangel Michael, is lively. William Hurt, like always, does wonders. Andie MacDowell is routine. Robert Pastorelli supports well. Bob Hoskins appears in a brief role. On the whole, 'Michael' is a decent entertainer, that doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lighthearted Romance, Flawed but still very Enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have seen angels coming to earth before, but never like this. Well at least I haven't. John Travolta as Micheal has done an amazing job in portraying Michael. Travolta has madcap style of his own in acting and it can be grating in some movies. But fortunately it suits him in Michael really well. He is really able to make the character his own. Micheal is an angel who has come to earth for an assignment. But as the poster say he is no saint. He loves womanizing and drinking. William Hurt, Andie MacDowell and Robert Pastorelli are sent by the National Mirror to verify the story of an angel and to get the interview. William Hurt plays Frank Quinlan, a reporter whose career is on skids. And Andie MacDowell plays a newbie who has been assigned to this case. To tell the truth the setup just seemed a little contrived to me and I was preparing for a disappointment. But the characters and the actors saved the film. Characters are finely etched and felt real and everybody has done a fabulous job. Still I can't give it a higher score because sometimes I found some plot gaps. I am not sure really whether they were plot holes or bad editing. It first appears that William Hurt suspects Andie Macdowell of being somebody else. It is shown like that twice where he vocalizes his doubts. But when she finally reveals the truth, he is still shocked. Such small details marred the experience a little for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A x-files episode starring MacDowell (dvd)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see that this movie is actually a supernatural road-movie in rural America as the best episodes of the "x-files". It could have been Mulder and Scully go into Iowa to bring back an angel. If Andie is a great add, Travolta as an angel sucks! Maybe it's his part, maybe it's his characterization or surely it's his personality but i found him pretty irritating. He hopes to be funny but he doesn't make me laugh; he tries to be compassionate but he is freaking nuts. Thus, each emotion he wants to give, he finally delivers the opposite: that's not the definition of a talented actor! On the opposite, Andie is as sweet and fragile than ever and she makes a good team with Hurt. Unfortunately, their romance is not well scripted as the myth of angel: there isn't a decent speech about religion, faith, heaven just a winged crazy man with paranormal powers. Except for "you've got mail", Ephron never convinces me as a writer / director and i rather find her movies dull and sleepy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot depends on your point of view.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moxie-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have done a lot of international travel, both on business and as a tourist. For both types I assure you the best advice is also the oldest: Always drink the wine of the country. In this movie the archangel Michael comes to Earth on business, wraps it up quickly and decides to hang around for a little touring. Boy! Does he "drink the wine of the country." Could man be drunk forever with liquor, love and fights He'd lief rise up of mornings and lief lie down of nights. These are things you can't do in Heaven so he enjoys them while he's here! Of course it turns out he had a couple of other jobs to tackle and, if he is less direct about them than he was about the first one, he is just as successful. The final scene is a little schmaltzy but it is also wonderful. Jean Stapleton gets to dance with John Travolta.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easily enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I think the overall average rating of this film on this site is incredibly low. There's really no reason to dislike this film. "Michael" is a simple, but fairly original, and easily enjoyable romantic comedy. The plot involves a group of reporters/experts going to examine the mysterious appearance of an angel (John Travolta) in the midwest. The angel proves to be less saintly and more worldly than we would expect, and that's what makes it entertaining. His interest in women and the Beatles takes a new spin on the angel thing. The romantic side of this film involves Michael the angel trying to get Andie MacDowell and William Hurt together. The two of them may not have the all-time greatest on-screen chemistry, but they certainly have enough to make it work well. Everyone who has rated this film so low (a 5.4??), come on! The film is not that bad. In fact, I found it quite funny and memorable. Sure, it's not the best thing you'll ever see, but it's still good. This is a film I feel has been remarkably underrated. It's fun, romantic, and recommended by me. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    #5 on my top ten worst film list
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonpics-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My website (theflickguy.org) lists "Michael" as one of the worst films of the modern era. The following is an excerpt: "Everyone slums some time in their lives, this was Travolta's turn. I still don't know what the point of this terrible film was. Nora Efron has proved to be a competent writer and director, so what the hell happened here? The Archangel Michael takes a new spin here and is portrayed as a ham-fisted, chain-smoking sugar addicted fornicating slob whose biggest contribution to humanity (after sending Lucifer to hell) was that he invented "standing in line". Yes, how funny and charming. I don't find this offensive, I find it stupid. In its defense, I can say that the ending was ever bit unsatisfying as the rest of this painful attempt at story telling."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Kind Of Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patsworld
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, I've watched this movie a dozen times. My all time favorite John Travolta film. The cast in this touching but vastly amusing movie are all a joy to behold. Jean Stapleton as Pansy is a love...no, seriously, you will love her. William Hurt and Robert Pastorelli as reporters are played to perfection. Andie MacDowell is splendid as a song-writing, many-times married fellow skeptic of the fact that Michael is, indeed, an angel. There is a scene in this movie that never fails to bring me to tears - and one that never fails to make me laugh out loud. "He's not that kind of an angel".....ah, but he sure is mine. This movie is one I'd never pass by if it shows up on TV, even though I own a copy of my own. And if I didn't, I seek out and find one to buy. This is what entertainment is all about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It is not my area..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rodneyrf@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thumbs up! This silly yet enriching picture makes us travel back in time, enabling us to naively live up a story as we commonly did in Frank Capra's movies. Michael, the angel, says many times: "It is not my area...", for many of the questions and doubts people have. We must live life without worrying too much. That's why the angel is sent down. He shows that we should live up life lightly, trying to share happiness and content with others.. It's something each and every one of us should try to do, step outside ourselves see just what our contributions can be. As I always say: Good movies never leave us. Take your time having authentic and original laughs in this light yet profound comedy. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A delightful heartwarming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Travoltas portrayal of an this angel is an interesting one. What we know of angels is that they are great warriors, messengers of god and always seem to be perfect. What if they aren't. He plays a rude obnoxious, womanizer who will fulfill your wishes, and make you care enough about the world that you will be touched. So what happens when you don't believe in anything and you are sent to investigate a story, only to meet one with wings and looks less then angelic. William Hurt plays a cynic who is out to write about a possible hoax who ends up becoming a believer by the end. Andie MacDowell and the rest of the cast play great parts. It is enjoyable that the film unapologetically illustrates how wonderful like is and the little things that we take for granted, and we should enjoy every moment like it was our last. With some of the scenes in this movie that changes the different characters views on the reality of angels may make you wonder if our vision of angels could be changed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very sweet.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it. Below is a repeat of the lines I've written above. I really don't feel like I need to say more, but IMDb requires at least 10 lines, so here you go... This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Film..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nora Ephron's Box-Office Super-Hit 'Michael' is A Decent Film, that manages to pass-off as a light-entertainer, that also packs in some fine acting. 'Michael' Synopsis: Two tabloid reporters checking out a report of the Archangel Michael living with an old woman find that it's true. But that's not the only surprise. 'Michael' is a fantasy film, but, the Angel here is not shown doing "The Impossible". Actually, the depiction of it's Angel Michael, over-here is portrayed as a boozing, smoking, oversexed slob혰yet capable of imparting unexpected wisdom. But, Despite those aspects, Michael does come across as a free-soul & oozes excitement. Screenplay by Nora Ephron & Delia Ephron is decent & fast. However, the culmination to this story, is not convincing. It just doesn't leave an impact. Nora Ephron's Direction, is polite. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are proper. Performance-Wise: John Travolta as the Archangel Michael, is lively. William Hurt, like always, does wonders. Andie MacDowell is routine. Robert Pastorelli supports well. Bob Hoskins appears in a brief role. On the whole, 'Michael' is a decent entertainer, that doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lighthearted Romance, Flawed but still very Enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have seen angels coming to earth before, but never like this. Well at least I haven't. John Travolta as Micheal has done an amazing job in portraying Michael. Travolta has madcap style of his own in acting and it can be grating in some movies. But fortunately it suits him in Michael really well. He is really able to make the character his own. Micheal is an angel who has come to earth for an assignment. But as the poster say he is no saint. He loves womanizing and drinking. William Hurt, Andie MacDowell and Robert Pastorelli are sent by the National Mirror to verify the story of an angel and to get the interview. William Hurt plays Frank Quinlan, a reporter whose career is on skids. And Andie MacDowell plays a newbie who has been assigned to this case. To tell the truth the setup just seemed a little contrived to me and I was preparing for a disappointment. But the characters and the actors saved the film. Characters are finely etched and felt real and everybody has done a fabulous job. Still I can't give it a higher score because sometimes I found some plot gaps. I am not sure really whether they were plot holes or bad editing. It first appears that William Hurt suspects Andie Macdowell of being somebody else. It is shown like that twice where he vocalizes his doubts. But when she finally reveals the truth, he is still shocked. Such small details marred the experience a little for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A x-files episode starring MacDowell (dvd)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see that this movie is actually a supernatural road-movie in rural America as the best episodes of the "x-files". It could have been Mulder and Scully go into Iowa to bring back an angel. If Andie is a great add, Travolta as an angel sucks! Maybe it's his part, maybe it's his characterization or surely it's his personality but i found him pretty irritating. He hopes to be funny but he doesn't make me laugh; he tries to be compassionate but he is freaking nuts. Thus, each emotion he wants to give, he finally delivers the opposite: that's not the definition of a talented actor! On the opposite, Andie is as sweet and fragile than ever and she makes a good team with Hurt. Unfortunately, their romance is not well scripted as the myth of angel: there isn't a decent speech about religion, faith, heaven just a winged crazy man with paranormal powers. Except for "you've got mail", Ephron never convinces me as a writer / director and i rather find her movies dull and sleepy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot depends on your point of view.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moxie-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have done a lot of international travel, both on business and as a tourist. For both types I assure you the best advice is also the oldest: Always drink the wine of the country. In this movie the archangel Michael comes to Earth on business, wraps it up quickly and decides to hang around for a little touring. Boy! Does he "drink the wine of the country." Could man be drunk forever with liquor, love and fights He'd lief rise up of mornings and lief lie down of nights. These are things you can't do in Heaven so he enjoys them while he's here! Of course it turns out he had a couple of other jobs to tackle and, if he is less direct about them than he was about the first one, he is just as successful. The final scene is a little schmaltzy but it is also wonderful. Jean Stapleton gets to dance with John Travolta.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easily enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I think the overall average rating of this film on this site is incredibly low. There's really no reason to dislike this film. "Michael" is a simple, but fairly original, and easily enjoyable romantic comedy. The plot involves a group of reporters/experts going to examine the mysterious appearance of an angel (John Travolta) in the midwest. The angel proves to be less saintly and more worldly than we would expect, and that's what makes it entertaining. His interest in women and the Beatles takes a new spin on the angel thing. The romantic side of this film involves Michael the angel trying to get Andie MacDowell and William Hurt together. The two of them may not have the all-time greatest on-screen chemistry, but they certainly have enough to make it work well. Everyone who has rated this film so low (a 5.4??), come on! The film is not that bad. In fact, I found it quite funny and memorable. Sure, it's not the best thing you'll ever see, but it's still good. This is a film I feel has been remarkably underrated. It's fun, romantic, and recommended by me. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    #5 on my top ten worst film list
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonpics-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My website (theflickguy.org) lists "Michael" as one of the worst films of the modern era. The following is an excerpt: "Everyone slums some time in their lives, this was Travolta's turn. I still don't know what the point of this terrible film was. Nora Efron has proved to be a competent writer and director, so what the hell happened here? The Archangel Michael takes a new spin here and is portrayed as a ham-fisted, chain-smoking sugar addicted fornicating slob whose biggest contribution to humanity (after sending Lucifer to hell) was that he invented "standing in line". Yes, how funny and charming. I don't find this offensive, I find it stupid. In its defense, I can say that the ending was ever bit unsatisfying as the rest of this painful attempt at story telling."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Kind Of Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patsworld
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, I've watched this movie a dozen times. My all time favorite John Travolta film. The cast in this touching but vastly amusing movie are all a joy to behold. Jean Stapleton as Pansy is a love...no, seriously, you will love her. William Hurt and Robert Pastorelli as reporters are played to perfection. Andie MacDowell is splendid as a song-writing, many-times married fellow skeptic of the fact that Michael is, indeed, an angel. There is a scene in this movie that never fails to bring me to tears - and one that never fails to make me laugh out loud. "He's not that kind of an angel".....ah, but he sure is mine. This movie is one I'd never pass by if it shows up on TV, even though I own a copy of my own. And if I didn't, I seek out and find one to buy. This is what entertainment is all about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It is not my area..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rodneyrf@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thumbs up! This silly yet enriching picture makes us travel back in time, enabling us to naively live up a story as we commonly did in Frank Capra's movies. Michael, the angel, says many times: "It is not my area...", for many of the questions and doubts people have. We must live life without worrying too much. That's why the angel is sent down. He shows that we should live up life lightly, trying to share happiness and content with others.. It's something each and every one of us should try to do, step outside ourselves see just what our contributions can be. As I always say: Good movies never leave us. Take your time having authentic and original laughs in this light yet profound comedy. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A delightful heartwarming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Travoltas portrayal of an this angel is an interesting one. What we know of angels is that they are great warriors, messengers of god and always seem to be perfect. What if they aren't. He plays a rude obnoxious, womanizer who will fulfill your wishes, and make you care enough about the world that you will be touched. So what happens when you don't believe in anything and you are sent to investigate a story, only to meet one with wings and looks less then angelic. William Hurt plays a cynic who is out to write about a possible hoax who ends up becoming a believer by the end. Andie MacDowell and the rest of the cast play great parts. It is enjoyable that the film unapologetically illustrates how wonderful like is and the little things that we take for granted, and we should enjoy every moment like it was our last. With some of the scenes in this movie that changes the different characters views on the reality of angels may make you wonder if our vision of angels could be changed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very sweet.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it. Below is a repeat of the lines I've written above. I really don't feel like I need to say more, but IMDb requires at least 10 lines, so here you go... This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Film..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nora Ephron's Box-Office Super-Hit 'Michael' is A Decent Film, that manages to pass-off as a light-entertainer, that also packs in some fine acting. 'Michael' Synopsis: Two tabloid reporters checking out a report of the Archangel Michael living with an old woman find that it's true. But that's not the only surprise. 'Michael' is a fantasy film, but, the Angel here is not shown doing "The Impossible". Actually, the depiction of it's Angel Michael, over-here is portrayed as a boozing, smoking, oversexed slob혰yet capable of imparting unexpected wisdom. But, Despite those aspects, Michael does come across as a free-soul & oozes excitement. Screenplay by Nora Ephron & Delia Ephron is decent & fast. However, the culmination to this story, is not convincing. It just doesn't leave an impact. Nora Ephron's Direction, is polite. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are proper. Performance-Wise: John Travolta as the Archangel Michael, is lively. William Hurt, like always, does wonders. Andie MacDowell is routine. Robert Pastorelli supports well. Bob Hoskins appears in a brief role. On the whole, 'Michael' is a decent entertainer, that doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lighthearted Romance, Flawed but still very Enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have seen angels coming to earth before, but never like this. Well at least I haven't. John Travolta as Micheal has done an amazing job in portraying Michael. Travolta has madcap style of his own in acting and it can be grating in some movies. But fortunately it suits him in Michael really well. He is really able to make the character his own. Micheal is an angel who has come to earth for an assignment. But as the poster say he is no saint. He loves womanizing and drinking. William Hurt, Andie MacDowell and Robert Pastorelli are sent by the National Mirror to verify the story of an angel and to get the interview. William Hurt plays Frank Quinlan, a reporter whose career is on skids. And Andie MacDowell plays a newbie who has been assigned to this case. To tell the truth the setup just seemed a little contrived to me and I was preparing for a disappointment. But the characters and the actors saved the film. Characters are finely etched and felt real and everybody has done a fabulous job. Still I can't give it a higher score because sometimes I found some plot gaps. I am not sure really whether they were plot holes or bad editing. It first appears that William Hurt suspects Andie Macdowell of being somebody else. It is shown like that twice where he vocalizes his doubts. But when she finally reveals the truth, he is still shocked. Such small details marred the experience a little for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A x-files episode starring MacDowell (dvd)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see that this movie is actually a supernatural road-movie in rural America as the best episodes of the "x-files". It could have been Mulder and Scully go into Iowa to bring back an angel. If Andie is a great add, Travolta as an angel sucks! Maybe it's his part, maybe it's his characterization or surely it's his personality but i found him pretty irritating. He hopes to be funny but he doesn't make me laugh; he tries to be compassionate but he is freaking nuts. Thus, each emotion he wants to give, he finally delivers the opposite: that's not the definition of a talented actor! On the opposite, Andie is as sweet and fragile than ever and she makes a good team with Hurt. Unfortunately, their romance is not well scripted as the myth of angel: there isn't a decent speech about religion, faith, heaven just a winged crazy man with paranormal powers. Except for "you've got mail", Ephron never convinces me as a writer / director and i rather find her movies dull and sleepy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot depends on your point of view.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moxie-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have done a lot of international travel, both on business and as a tourist. For both types I assure you the best advice is also the oldest: Always drink the wine of the country. In this movie the archangel Michael comes to Earth on business, wraps it up quickly and decides to hang around for a little touring. Boy! Does he "drink the wine of the country." Could man be drunk forever with liquor, love and fights He'd lief rise up of mornings and lief lie down of nights. These are things you can't do in Heaven so he enjoys them while he's here! Of course it turns out he had a couple of other jobs to tackle and, if he is less direct about them than he was about the first one, he is just as successful. The final scene is a little schmaltzy but it is also wonderful. Jean Stapleton gets to dance with John Travolta.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easily enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I think the overall average rating of this film on this site is incredibly low. There's really no reason to dislike this film. "Michael" is a simple, but fairly original, and easily enjoyable romantic comedy. The plot involves a group of reporters/experts going to examine the mysterious appearance of an angel (John Travolta) in the midwest. The angel proves to be less saintly and more worldly than we would expect, and that's what makes it entertaining. His interest in women and the Beatles takes a new spin on the angel thing. The romantic side of this film involves Michael the angel trying to get Andie MacDowell and William Hurt together. The two of them may not have the all-time greatest on-screen chemistry, but they certainly have enough to make it work well. Everyone who has rated this film so low (a 5.4??), come on! The film is not that bad. In fact, I found it quite funny and memorable. Sure, it's not the best thing you'll ever see, but it's still good. This is a film I feel has been remarkably underrated. It's fun, romantic, and recommended by me. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    #5 on my top ten worst film list
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonpics-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My website (theflickguy.org) lists "Michael" as one of the worst films of the modern era. The following is an excerpt: "Everyone slums some time in their lives, this was Travolta's turn. I still don't know what the point of this terrible film was. Nora Efron has proved to be a competent writer and director, so what the hell happened here? The Archangel Michael takes a new spin here and is portrayed as a ham-fisted, chain-smoking sugar addicted fornicating slob whose biggest contribution to humanity (after sending Lucifer to hell) was that he invented "standing in line". Yes, how funny and charming. I don't find this offensive, I find it stupid. In its defense, I can say that the ending was ever bit unsatisfying as the rest of this painful attempt at story telling."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Kind Of Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patsworld
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ah, I've watched this movie a dozen times. My all time favorite John Travolta film. The cast in this touching but vastly amusing movie are all a joy to behold. Jean Stapleton as Pansy is a love...no, seriously, you will love her. William Hurt and Robert Pastorelli as reporters are played to perfection. Andie MacDowell is splendid as a song-writing, many-times married fellow skeptic of the fact that Michael is, indeed, an angel. There is a scene in this movie that never fails to bring me to tears - and one that never fails to make me laugh out loud. "He's not that kind of an angel".....ah, but he sure is mine. This movie is one I'd never pass by if it shows up on TV, even though I own a copy of my own. And if I didn't, I seek out and find one to buy. This is what entertainment is all about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "It is not my area..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rodneyrf@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thumbs up! This silly yet enriching picture makes us travel back in time, enabling us to naively live up a story as we commonly did in Frank Capra's movies. Michael, the angel, says many times: "It is not my area...", for many of the questions and doubts people have. We must live life without worrying too much. That's why the angel is sent down. He shows that we should live up life lightly, trying to share happiness and content with others.. It's something each and every one of us should try to do, step outside ourselves see just what our contributions can be. As I always say: Good movies never leave us. Take your time having authentic and original laughs in this light yet profound comedy. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A delightful heartwarming movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jason Del gado
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Travoltas portrayal of an this angel is an interesting one. What we know of angels is that they are great warriors, messengers of god and always seem to be perfect. What if they aren't. He plays a rude obnoxious, womanizer who will fulfill your wishes, and make you care enough about the world that you will be touched. So what happens when you don't believe in anything and you are sent to investigate a story, only to meet one with wings and looks less then angelic. William Hurt plays a cynic who is out to write about a possible hoax who ends up becoming a believer by the end. Andie MacDowell and the rest of the cast play great parts. It is enjoyable that the film unapologetically illustrates how wonderful like is and the little things that we take for granted, and we should enjoy every moment like it was our last. With some of the scenes in this movie that changes the different characters views on the reality of angels may make you wonder if our vision of angels could be changed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very sweet.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gpickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it. Below is a repeat of the lines I've written above. I really don't feel like I need to say more, but IMDb requires at least 10 lines, so here you go... This movie is severely underrated. It has tons of charm and sincerity. There are many quiet details that make this movie worth watching -- enjoying, really. I have very high standards, and occasionally a movie is worthy in its heartfelt simplicity. This is really an enjoyable film, and if a viewer can just give one's inner critic the night off, it's truly an enjoyable ride. Watch it (again perhaps, with kinder eyes). It's worth it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Decent Film..
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nora Ephron's Box-Office Super-Hit 'Michael' is A Decent Film, that manages to pass-off as a light-entertainer, that also packs in some fine acting. 'Michael' Synopsis: Two tabloid reporters checking out a report of the Archangel Michael living with an old woman find that it's true. But that's not the only surprise. 'Michael' is a fantasy film, but, the Angel here is not shown doing "The Impossible". Actually, the depiction of it's Angel Michael, over-here is portrayed as a boozing, smoking, oversexed slob혰yet capable of imparting unexpected wisdom. But, Despite those aspects, Michael does come across as a free-soul & oozes excitement. Screenplay by Nora Ephron & Delia Ephron is decent & fast. However, the culmination to this story, is not convincing. It just doesn't leave an impact. Nora Ephron's Direction, is polite. Cinematography, Editing & Art Design, are proper. Performance-Wise: John Travolta as the Archangel Michael, is lively. William Hurt, like always, does wonders. Andie MacDowell is routine. Robert Pastorelli supports well. Bob Hoskins appears in a brief role. On the whole, 'Michael' is a decent entertainer, that doesn't disappoint.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lighthearted Romance, Flawed but still very Enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We have seen angels coming to earth before, but never like this. Well at least I haven't. John Travolta as Micheal has done an amazing job in portraying Michael. Travolta has madcap style of his own in acting and it can be grating in some movies. But fortunately it suits him in Michael really well. He is really able to make the character his own. Micheal is an angel who has come to earth for an assignment. But as the poster say he is no saint. He loves womanizing and drinking. William Hurt, Andie MacDowell and Robert Pastorelli are sent by the National Mirror to verify the story of an angel and to get the interview. William Hurt plays Frank Quinlan, a reporter whose career is on skids. And Andie MacDowell plays a newbie who has been assigned to this case. To tell the truth the setup just seemed a little contrived to me and I was preparing for a disappointment. But the characters and the actors saved the film. Characters are finely etched and felt real and everybody has done a fabulous job. Still I can't give it a higher score because sometimes I found some plot gaps. I am not sure really whether they were plot holes or bad editing. It first appears that William Hurt suspects Andie Macdowell of being somebody else. It is shown like that twice where he vocalizes his doubts. But when she finally reveals the truth, he is still shocked. Such small details marred the experience a little for me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A x-files episode starring MacDowell (dvd)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see that this movie is actually a supernatural road-movie in rural America as the best episodes of the "x-files". It could have been Mulder and Scully go into Iowa to bring back an angel. If Andie is a great add, Travolta as an angel sucks! Maybe it's his part, maybe it's his characterization or surely it's his personality but i found him pretty irritating. He hopes to be funny but he doesn't make me laugh; he tries to be compassionate but he is freaking nuts. Thus, each emotion he wants to give, he finally delivers the opposite: that's not the definition of a talented actor! On the opposite, Andie is as sweet and fragile than ever and she makes a good team with Hurt. Unfortunately, their romance is not well scripted as the myth of angel: there isn't a decent speech about religion, faith, heaven just a winged crazy man with paranormal powers. Except for "you've got mail", Ephron never convinces me as a writer / director and i rather find her movies dull and sleepy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot depends on your point of view.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moxie-7
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have done a lot of international travel, both on business and as a tourist. For both types I assure you the best advice is also the oldest: Always drink the wine of the country. In this movie the archangel Michael comes to Earth on business, wraps it up quickly and decides to hang around for a little touring. Boy! Does he "drink the wine of the country." Could man be drunk forever with liquor, love and fights He'd lief rise up of mornings and lief lie down of nights. These are things you can't do in Heaven so he enjoys them while he's here! Of course it turns out he had a couple of other jobs to tackle and, if he is less direct about them than he was about the first one, he is just as successful. The final scene is a little schmaltzy but it is also wonderful. Jean Stapleton gets to dance with John Travolta.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easily enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wow, I think the overall average rating of this film on this site is incredibly low. There's really no reason to dislike this film. "Michael" is a simple, but fairly original, and easily enjoyable romantic comedy. The plot involves a group of reporters/experts going to examine the mysterious appearance of an angel (John Travolta) in the midwest. The angel proves to be less saintly and more worldly than we would expect, and that's what makes it entertaining. His interest in women and the Beatles takes a new spin on the angel thing. The romantic side of this film involves Michael the angel trying to get Andie MacDowell and William Hurt together. The two of them may not have the all-time greatest on-screen chemistry, but they certainly have enough to make it work well. Everyone who has rated this film so low (a 5.4??), come on! The film is not that bad. In fact, I found it quite funny and memorable. Sure, it's not the best thing you'll ever see, but it's still good. This is a film I feel has been remarkably underrated. It's fun, romantic, and recommended by me. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    #5 on my top ten worst film list
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonpics-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My website (theflickguy.org) lists "Michael" as one of the worst films of the modern era. The following is an excerpt: "Everyone slums some time in their lives, this was Travolta's turn. I still don't know what the point of this terrible film was. Nora Efron has proved to be a competent writer and director, so what the hell happened here? The Archangel Michael takes a new spin here and is portrayed as a ham-fisted, chain-smoking sugar addicted fornicating slob whose biggest contribution to humanity (after sending Lucifer to hell) was that he invented "standing in line". Yes, how funny and charming. I don't find this offensive, I find it stupid. In its defense, I can say that the ending was ever bit unsatisfying as the rest of this painful attempt at story telling."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
