<filme>
 <id>
  87
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0108065
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Lances Inocentes
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A prepubescent chess prodigy refuses to harden himself in order to become a champion like the famous but unlikable Bobby Fischer.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Josh Waitzkin is just a typical American boy interested in baseball when one day he challenges his father at chess and wins. Showing unusual precocity at the outdoor matches at Washington Square in New York City, he quickly makes friends with a hustler named Vinnie who teaches him speed chess. Josh's parents hire a renowned chess coach, Bruce, who teaches Josh the usefulness of measured planning. Along the way Josh becomes tired of Bruce's system and chess in general and purposely throws a match, leaving the prospects of winning a national championship in serious jeopardy.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   chess
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   baseball
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hustler
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new york city
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   speed chess
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Steven Zaillian
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Fred Waitzkin
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Steven Zaillian
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Joe Mantegna
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ben Kingsley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Max Pomeranc
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Knight to C-8, Checkmate!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a true story the feature focuses upon a child chess prodigy, Josh Waitzkin. Oh, the lad does enjoy things like baseball, but as soon as he discovers his gift for chess, then it is a new beginning. We often see child masterminds in music and in art and in the sciences, including mathematics. For instance, didn't Mozart make his debut at age four? And what about Pascal, who wrote a treatise at age nine? Anyway, our seven year-old chess genius has a grasp of complicated moves that exceeds that of adults. Still, he is just a boy; he simply has not lived. In the film, we see clips of the great chess grandmaster, Bobby Fischer, who won the US Chess Championship at age 14. He could play (and win) many board games at once. He became official world champion in 1972 when he defeated Soviet champ Boris Spassky. After his victory, he appeared on a Bob Hope TV special. But after 1975 he became a recluse and practically disappeared from the planet. Fischer had controversial beliefs. For instance, he believed in a worldwide Jewish conspiracy, and favored the Palestinians over Israel. In any case, the film's title refers not to Bobby Fischer, but to a potential American successor, one who plays like him (like Josh). And hopefully not one who had lived such an abnormal life like Fischer. Josh Waitzkin, well-played by Max Pomeranc, a real chess player, was born with his gift, which he discovers at an early age. He enjoys going to Washington Park in NYC to play with the dregs and hustlers who hang out there. Note that one of the Russian players there once defeated Tal, who was world champ in 1960-61. The Washington Park folks play a fast game ("blitz"), use unorthodox moves, and intimate their opponents. Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne), a drug addict, is one of the hustlers in the park. He seems to like Josh. As he parents discover Josh's gift, they seem oblivious of what to do with it. For instance, is winning at chess the only thing in life? Eventually, Josh's sports-writer father Fred (Joe Mantegna, in a luminous performance), hires Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley) a brilliant chess-master and former national champion, to coach his son. Bruce's style, in contrast to Vinnie's, is to use the planned approach. But Bruce seems to be almost as difficult to deal with as Fischer. He says that Josh's personality is represented by the KING chess piece, and reminds Josh that "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt." Bruce wants to keep the boy away from Washington Park, which is a hindrance to his understanding of the finer points of chess even though Josh loves the place. When Bruce later tries to teach Josh the cutthroat style of chess, Josh's mother (Bonnie = Joan Allen), becomes chagrined and states, "He's decent!" (Translation = He does not hate his opponents.) When a patronizing teacher (Laura Linney) tries to belittle Josh's achievement  his string of victories  Fred indignantly proclaims, "He's better at this than I've ever been at anything in my life. He's better at this than you'll ever be at anything. My son has a gift. He has a gift, and when you acknowledge that, then maybe we will have something to talk about." There is a point where one may ask what happens when the need to win consumes all of the fun. In the course of the movie, we learn much about tournament chess, as Josh works his way to the top. We see what happens when he begins to lose interest and sustains a series of reverses before he regains his position. In the end it comes down to the two best players  Josh and Jonathan Poe  for the junior national championship. Who will win? The movie is based upon Fred Waitzkin's autobiographical book. Our feature does not focus on any one game or on individual piece moves, so that one does not need to know how to play chess to enjoy the film. Ben Kingsley, as usual, is great in his portrayal of Bruce Pandolfini, a real New York personality who teaches chess, writes columns, and has authored many books. He actually coached young Waitzkin for quite a long time. Apparently the real Pandolfini is milder and has a more easygoing style, unlike the movie's portrayal. But that's Hollywood. An error is the film was a reference to former world champion Casablanca; that grandmaster's real name was Jose Raul Capablanca (In 1921 Capablanca defeated Emanuel Lasker, who had held the world championship since 1894, when he bested Wilhelm Steinitz). Despite minor issues, the movie exudes both realism and fascination. Postscript: Josh Waitzkin became an International Master at age 16. He developed into the highest rated American chess player under age 18, and was national chess champion eight times. Waitzkin authored two books. He moved on into the martial arts field, and won championships. The youngest grandmaster in American history is now Fabiano Luigi Caruana, who was not quite 15 when he won in 2007.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close to flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robyn Nesbitt (nesfilmreviews)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Searching for Bobby Fischer" contains in its title a reminder of a time that was. Bobby Fischer was arguably the greatest chess player of all time. As a boy, he faced and defeated the greatest players of his time. In 1972, after a prelude of countless controversies, he won the world chess championship away from the Russians for the first time in years. Then he essentially disappeared and went off the deep end-- into a underworld of rented rooms, phantom sightings, and paranoid outbursts. "Searching for Bobby Fischer"-a film of remarkable sensitivity and insight, tells a story based on fact, about a "new" Bobby Fischer - a young boy named Josh Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc), who was born with a gift for chess--which he nurtured in the rough-and- tumble world of of chess hustlers in New York's Washington Square Park. His parents acknowledge his gift, but are concerned about how he can develop it without stunting the other areas of his life. After realizing what his son is capable of, Fred seeks out a chess player--a once highly regarded grand master named Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley), and hires him to tutor Josh. Bruce tries to teach his pupil a regimented, cerebral approach to the game, while Josh's mentor from the park, Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne) favors a fast paced and aggressive style used by hustlers to intimidate their opponents. Josh proves so adept at the game that Fred enters his son in a tournament. Bruce advises against this, believing that "winning and losing" has nothing to do with chess. Caught up in his son's gift and the thrill of competition, Fred pushes Josh to excel. Josh's weakness as a sportsman is his kindness, which Bonnie fears Fred will beat out of him in his efforts to make his son a winner. When he encounters another prodigy (Michael Nirenberg), who dispatches his opponents with cold-blooded efficiency. Josh has to decide for himself how important winning and losing is. The movie succeeds with the heart-warming, honest acting of the film's protagonist Max Pomeranc. Steven Zaillian, the director, made a conscious choice when he cast the film to find kids who actually could play chess. He wanted chess players first and foremost- - and who also could handle the demands of the script. His face is expressive, open - and yet strangely inscrutable when he plays chess. The criteria Zaillian demands of his protagonist ultimately defines whether this film works or not- -and Max delivers a truly natural performance. The audiences' enjoyment of this film pivots on his character-- and Pomeranc is wonderful. Zaillian's superb script attracted a fantasitc cast that includes: Joe Mantegna, Joan Allen, Ben Kingsley, and Laurence Fishburne. Supported in minor roes by David Paymer, William H. Macy, Tony Shalhoub, Dan Hedaya, Laura Linney, and Austin Pendleton. Of all those Renowned cinematographer Conrad Hall referred to the film in what he called "magical naturalism" - conveying a child's sense of imagination - while James Horner's music reflects that spirit with equal mastery. "Searching for Bobby Fischer" is an intensely fascinating movie capable of involving those who are not familiar about chess, as well as those who love it. Steven Zaillian effectively integrates the actual story and footage of Bobby Fischer throughout the film--running parallel to Josh's story, only enhancing the fascinating storyline. The focus of the film is less on the actual game than it is on the people, emotions, and pressures surrounding Josh. It is a tale of the human spirit and triumph. By the end of "Searching for Bobby Fischer", we have gained insight about the intensity and competitiveness nature of chess tournaments, and a great deal about human nature. The film's implications are many. Think of it as a very smart sports film that substitutes quiet intensity for physical action. There's no denying "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is one film in which every major element - writing, directing, casting, photography, music - is perfectly in tune, exploring the nature of competition with humor, intelligence, and depth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Winning's Not The Only Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bill Slocum (bill.slocum@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "You've got to go to the edge of defeat," one player tells another in the second half of "Searching For Bobby Fischer." That seemed to be the guiding strategy behind the movie as well. Writer-director Steven Zaillian takes an unfilmable subject (chess), bases it on a book few read, names it after a guy nobody had seen in 20 years, and puts it all in the lap of an eight-year-old actor who never starred in a film before and would star in only one after. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" does all it can to stack the board against itself, yet succeeds quite well despite, and indeed, because of all that. Joshua Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc) is celebrating his seventh birthday in Washington Square Park when he catches sight of some rough-looking characters moving what look like his Lego figures on tables of black-and-white squares. Chess is a game few master, yet Josh learns it just from watching them. Soon he is amazing parents and wizened grandmasters alike with his skill at the game, but is Josh really a prodigy on the scale of Bobby Fischer, the New York youngster who went on to win the world championship - then disappear? "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is a fairly formulaic film in many ways. It presents us with stock situations like an adorable boy who only wants to be good; a father (Joe Mantegna) who is too concerned with winning; a mother (Joan Allen) afraid her son is being turned into a machine; and a streetwise black man (Laurence Fishburne) who sees things in the child before anyone else. There's even a villain who appears shrouded in darkness, and who glares at Josh so menacingly its easy to forget this dark figure isn't quite four feet tall. But the formula really works in this one, in part because it serves such a strange cause (how many other chess movies can you think of?) and mostly because of Pomeranc's unaffected work in the lead role. Pomeranc seems preternaturally aware of his fragility on camera and plays to it in ways that reflect not precociousness but depth. You just feel for the guy, exult with his triumphs and feel his disappointments so much you resent Mantegna when his character rides Josh about doing better. Pomeranc also does great ensemble work with the other characters, especially Ben Kingsley as Josh's instructor Bruce, a fellow who seems to have been somebody's idea of Josh a generation ago only for it to collapse on him. Bruce doesn't want Josh to show mercy, you sense because he blames his own softness for his post-child ruination. "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt," he tells Josh. "I'm not him," Josh replies. That's the whole movie right there. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" feels incomplete in parts. Maybe it's just zen-like in its comfort with koan-like plot holes. We never get a real chance to see Josh learning much with Vinnie, the Fishburne character, in a way that would better explain their later closeness. Mantagna's transformation into hard-driving parent (he has a funny but nasty scene with a teacher played by Laura Linney, one of many future talents on display here) isn't laid out convincingly. But thanks both to Zaillian's affecting script and superlative camera work by the incomparable Conrad Hall working close to his zenith, you sense many things lying just beneath the surface of your view, there to be pondered when the rush of the film dissipates. And what a rush! Josh learns that winning isn't everything, but he also comes to care enough to give it his best shot in a climax both thrilling and heartwarming, even if it plays a bit to conventions. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" suggests something redemptive and perhaps even romantic in a game it dares to compare to art. In the process, it winds up presenting us with art both in theory and in practice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Family movie disguised as chess movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmoujik
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're a chess player, you should know: I saw that there were some goofs regarding chess in this movie, but I didn't know that NONE OF THE CHESS RELATED SEQUENCES MADE SENSE. What's the point of making such a movie? How hard is it to get a chess adviser for the editing process. It doesn't have to be a GM. Any decent player would suffice. You could just go a block from the Washington sq. to a chess caf&eacute; and find someone who'd have time to help not to make this movie an embarrassment. Only good parts were documentary ones showing Bobby Fischer, and I would recommend to see "Bobby Fischer against the world" for a chess cinematic fix. Otherwise this family movie is pretty banal, and I wish, someone had written this review before I considered spending time watching this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought-provoking gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Troye Dchgl
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a parent, how do you strike a balance between supporting your children and pushing your children too hard? As a teacher, what is the "correct" way to teach your pupils? There is no certain answer. But the film has the ability of making you think while delivering an exciting plot. Searching for Bobby Fischer is truly an inspiration. It is a reflection for parents to rethink how they should raise their kids, and how to give them the right message to pursue their interests. The film also shows there is no single "correct" way of teaching. A child should learn from all aspects, from different people and via different methods. "Maybe it's better not to be the best. Then you can lose and it's OK." Josh gives us a peek of the pressure of all the constant winners - it is hard for an all-time winner to lose, and sometimes you would rather be "not the best" so you can actually lose without feeling too bad. The only advisable solution is probably to give yourself less pressure when it comes to competitions by loving the game rather than forcing yourself to win. After all, it is just a game in which you are supposed to seek interest, and you should be enjoying the moment. This is highly recommended for all ages. Beautifully written is the script. There is nothing to criticize on the acting. The background music throughout the movie is highly enjoyable and appropriate. The simplicity of the movie is also great. For kids, this is a great adventure about a unknown chess prodigy becoming a champion. For grown-ups, this is also a story that gives something to learn and something to think about. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the kind of movie that can stand the test of time. Although it was made almost 20 years ago, I don't feel a bit of antiquatedness at all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This goes beyond chess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cstotlar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a pianist and classical performer, I've seen a great number of young prodigies in the field of musical performance. The large majority of them never make it past adolescence. In many cases, some of them didn't get beyond the point of doing something quite well at a very early age and were dismissed when the age factor no longer applied. This said, the parents pushed so many of them mercilessly - and rather unashamedly. The kids wanted to please their parents and the parents wanted to please themselves. It's as simple and as tragic as that and it goes on everywhere, with sports near the top, for example. The film then came as no particular surprise. It could be a valuable wake-up call to overly ambitious parents who haven't noticed who their kids ARE rather than what they can do. In this respect the film was spot on and quite frank and sincere. It went on for too long. There were too many "re-wordings" throughout which made the effort seem pedantic at times. The actors, too often shown in semi-obscurity, did their parts beautifully and I would agree with another reviewer who found the wife's contribution essential and beautifully underplayed. The game of chess doesn't have much attraction for those who don't know the game and the director and writer kept this firmly in mind by speeding up the rounds and focusing on the facial expressions. The film could definitely be "tightened up" and pared down a bit. Curtis Stotlar
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice movie for all, but great for chess fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film itself is not as great as the story behind it. Frankly, the plot is the typical American sports movie with the good hearted champion that has both talent and decency and that works hard for his art. I guess it would have been worse if it wasn't based on the book written by Josh Waitzkin's father. Josh Waitzkin has a fascinating story that I recommend you read on. He was the highest rated chess player in the US since he was 8 years old, then his father wrote the book that this movie is based on, then all the sudden celebrity messed with his chess game. Instead of clinging to chess, Josh decides to stop playing, and takes up Ju-Jitsu. He does great at it as well. His book, The Art of Learning, describes the process. Josh Waitzkin is also the guy from the "Waitzkin Academy" tutorial in the ChessMaster XI chess game. But back to the film. At the time, Josh was the next Bobby Fischer, only nicer. Everybody loved a true American hero, especially in a game that was dominated by Russians. The Art of Learning was not out yet, so the people that made the movie saw no problem in portraying the boy as a chess prodigy that did not lose to anyone unless he chose to. In reality, the wonder of Josh Waitzkin is that he really was brilliant and even as a kid he realised that losing is the true teacher. Losing in a finals of a championship defined his life, as he saw the true value of humility and confidence. Having all that information in the background had me see the movie with completely different eyes and I rather liked it. I wish it was more technical, but then no one would watch it except a few Russians, so... Funny trivia: three chess players depicted in the movie were the real people: Kamran Shirazi, Joel Benjamin and Roman DzinDziChashvili, while a girl identified as "82nd girl", which means one of Josh's opponents in the game who ranked the 82nd, is Katya Waitzkin, Josh's real life sister. Bottom line: it has some valuable lessons in there, but hidden in the usual Hollywood bull. It is nice to watch and has a lot more meaning to chess players than people not playing. I liked it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Just for Chess Geeks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Benik
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when it first came out, and I was in my mid-twenties and just getting started in the world. I saw it then as a movie about chess, and what young chess prodigies go through in order to reach the top levels. I saw it again last night, eighteen years later. The movie is the same, but I am different. I am about the age of Josh Waitzkin's father, and I have a daughter who is the same age as Josh. And although my daughter is not a prodigy of chess or anything else, I can see a lot of her in Josh, and a lot of me in his father. This is actually not a film about chess; it is a film about raising children. We live in the Dallas suburbs, where there are a lot of families and a lot of activities for children. I see parents take their children to soccer games, gymnastics camps and acting classes, and I see the obsession in their eyes. They want to expose their kids to many different pursuits, but once they see a talent forming, they focus on only that pursuit, to the exclusion of all others. They sink their money, their time, and all of their child's energy into developing that talent, at the expense of all other interests. Maybe it is pressure to earn a scholarship. Maybe it is the availability of year-round seasons and elite leagues. Maybe it is the unbelievable salaries that top athletes are earning. But I think that the problem that this movie points out -- that pushing kids to be the best at something at any cost -- has gotten worse instead of better. This movie could just as easily been about gymnastics or golf or music as it is about chess. The issues raised are the same. I just hope that more parents can see this film, and recognize that if our goal is raise happy, balanced people, pushing our kids to become elite performers is not the way to get there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern Classic with life lessons, engaging history, great story telling.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-2829
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much more than a movie about chess, this movie deals with childhood geniuses, the difficult choices of parents in how far to push their "prodigy" and the challenge of finding balance in a life filled with difficult choices. I have watched this movie a few times now, and have gleaned different things from it depending on where I am in my own life. This time around had new meaning as I have a child very gifted with piano. I've had similar challenges to Josh Waitzkin's parents in trying to decide how much to push your children - and for what purposes. Most parents probably feel that pull, even without "geniuses" - finding balance in what kids CAN do, what they SHOULD do, and what they WANT to do. We want our children to be happy, but we also know that part of being happy is doing something they are good at and helping them find meaning. I'm also a fan of chess and so really enjoy the glimpses into the chess world this movie portrays. The brilliance of those who stand even above the best minds in their field is the stuff of legends. Bobby Fischer, Garry Kasparov, Anatoly Karpov, Emmanuel Lasker... every bit leaders in their elite worlds as the likes of say Michael Jordan, Mike Tyson, Tiger Woods. Always interesting to me. Great performances all around, from the young (and skinny) Laurence Fishburne to the always stately Ben Kingsley. From the interested and caring parents to the young Josh Waitzskin... even the "enemy" chess player are all well cast and enjoyable throughout the movie. A modern classic in my opinion, and great for the whole family (probably at least 7 or 8 years old is a good lower limit). I appreciate the lessons it teaches, the story of Josh and the truths we discover.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you know anything about chess, or even if you don't, chances are you've heard the name Bobby Fischer. He was the most renowned and most skilled chess master who ever lived. His level of expertise at the game of chess could be matched by no one but himself. He was a legend to that world, but only revered because of his ability at chess. Apart from that he was a detached and solitary individual who obviously had some sort of mental deficiency that kept him from connecting with the real world. Thus his world was all chess. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the story of Josh Waitzkin, another chess master who was discovered long after Bobby Fischer. Josh unexpectedly discovers that he has a unique gift in playing chess and so the pressure from all different people sets in for him to become the best. The title of the film is Searching for Bobby Fischer, but in the context of the film the title literally means searching for the next Bobby Fischer. These pressures and goals Josh must face send us through an interesting, yet very subdued story. Searching for Bobby Fischer is very slow, but appropriately slow. Not a ton actually happens in the film as it is much more character driven. There are a lot of different characters in the film that each drive different plot lines. The film takes a while to get going because of the different characters that have be introduced, and are introduced very slowly and drawn out. Because of this early character development, there's a lot of build up necessary before the first actual conflicts of the film arise. It is almost an hour into the film before we get to see these conflicts start to take shape and affect the storyline. You have to stick with this film to get the full effect of it, which is worth it in the end. I can also commend the story for being very focused but also broad. The stories obviously centers around chess, but as it goes along it becomes more about Josh's relationships with the various people in his life, more so than anything else. The main theme of the film eventually molds into character relationships, as each character seems to have a clear cut relation with the others in order to fully flesh them all out and make them interesting. The storyline works in such a way that it is easy for it to elicit emotional responses out of its audience, so because of this I felt a little less drawn in. I didn't feel much emotion throughout the film and most of the time I just had to take it for what it was. Speaking from a personal standpoint, it isn't the most fascinating kind of story for me, but it doesn't mean it wasn't a well made film. It is very high quality with all the necessary aspects to make it a notable film. The direction is very subdued and avoids anything flashy or grand, but it keeps the flow of the film nice and smooth. The dialouge also keeps with the silky smooth theme of the film, and it is delivered by some very fine actors. All the actors do a very nice job in their respective roles. The main character, Josh Waitzkin, is only seven years old and for a child actor does a decent job. He was very sophisticated for his age and didn't always feel like a kid, but maybe that was the intention of the film. He probably was a fairly detached boy, just like Bobby Fischer, and so he didn't seem like what we think of when we think seven year old boy. And yet the film also spent a lot of time focusing on Josh's balance between chess and growing up like a normal kid, so his attitude wasn't always fitting. Plus he seems like he is on depressants for the entire film. The rest of the cast is A-list and does a great job. Joe Mantegna as Josh's father does a great job as a character trying to balance out his life much in the same way Josh is balancing his. His father must balance his want for his son to be a great chess player, but he also wants his son to live a normal childhood without all of the extreme pressures of chess. Ben Kingsley and Laurence Fishburne both play mentors to Josh, but with very different personalities. Kingsley is an old retired chess master who is very by the book and rigid in his teaching. Fishburne is much more free and sees the game of chess as a much more surreal and introspective experience. The contrast between these two characters is very interesting to watch unfold. Searching for Bobby Fischer is a good film, not a great film, just a good film. It has all the necessary components that make good films. The direction is smart, the dialouge is crisp, and the acting is fantastic. From a personal standpoint this wasn't the most gripping or emotionally moving film for me, but for others I can definitely see how it would be. This film can be enjoyed a lot more than I enjoyed it because it is a good film and there are a lot of good things going for it. But as far as I'm concerned, it was one of those films that I watch, enjoy enough to feel like it was worth my two hours, but then I never watch it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Knight to C-8, Checkmate!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a true story the feature focuses upon a child chess prodigy, Josh Waitzkin. Oh, the lad does enjoy things like baseball, but as soon as he discovers his gift for chess, then it is a new beginning. We often see child masterminds in music and in art and in the sciences, including mathematics. For instance, didn't Mozart make his debut at age four? And what about Pascal, who wrote a treatise at age nine? Anyway, our seven year-old chess genius has a grasp of complicated moves that exceeds that of adults. Still, he is just a boy; he simply has not lived. In the film, we see clips of the great chess grandmaster, Bobby Fischer, who won the US Chess Championship at age 14. He could play (and win) many board games at once. He became official world champion in 1972 when he defeated Soviet champ Boris Spassky. After his victory, he appeared on a Bob Hope TV special. But after 1975 he became a recluse and practically disappeared from the planet. Fischer had controversial beliefs. For instance, he believed in a worldwide Jewish conspiracy, and favored the Palestinians over Israel. In any case, the film's title refers not to Bobby Fischer, but to a potential American successor, one who plays like him (like Josh). And hopefully not one who had lived such an abnormal life like Fischer. Josh Waitzkin, well-played by Max Pomeranc, a real chess player, was born with his gift, which he discovers at an early age. He enjoys going to Washington Park in NYC to play with the dregs and hustlers who hang out there. Note that one of the Russian players there once defeated Tal, who was world champ in 1960-61. The Washington Park folks play a fast game ("blitz"), use unorthodox moves, and intimate their opponents. Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne), a drug addict, is one of the hustlers in the park. He seems to like Josh. As he parents discover Josh's gift, they seem oblivious of what to do with it. For instance, is winning at chess the only thing in life? Eventually, Josh's sports-writer father Fred (Joe Mantegna, in a luminous performance), hires Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley) a brilliant chess-master and former national champion, to coach his son. Bruce's style, in contrast to Vinnie's, is to use the planned approach. But Bruce seems to be almost as difficult to deal with as Fischer. He says that Josh's personality is represented by the KING chess piece, and reminds Josh that "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt." Bruce wants to keep the boy away from Washington Park, which is a hindrance to his understanding of the finer points of chess even though Josh loves the place. When Bruce later tries to teach Josh the cutthroat style of chess, Josh's mother (Bonnie = Joan Allen), becomes chagrined and states, "He's decent!" (Translation = He does not hate his opponents.) When a patronizing teacher (Laura Linney) tries to belittle Josh's achievement  his string of victories  Fred indignantly proclaims, "He's better at this than I've ever been at anything in my life. He's better at this than you'll ever be at anything. My son has a gift. He has a gift, and when you acknowledge that, then maybe we will have something to talk about." There is a point where one may ask what happens when the need to win consumes all of the fun. In the course of the movie, we learn much about tournament chess, as Josh works his way to the top. We see what happens when he begins to lose interest and sustains a series of reverses before he regains his position. In the end it comes down to the two best players  Josh and Jonathan Poe  for the junior national championship. Who will win? The movie is based upon Fred Waitzkin's autobiographical book. Our feature does not focus on any one game or on individual piece moves, so that one does not need to know how to play chess to enjoy the film. Ben Kingsley, as usual, is great in his portrayal of Bruce Pandolfini, a real New York personality who teaches chess, writes columns, and has authored many books. He actually coached young Waitzkin for quite a long time. Apparently the real Pandolfini is milder and has a more easygoing style, unlike the movie's portrayal. But that's Hollywood. An error is the film was a reference to former world champion Casablanca; that grandmaster's real name was Jose Raul Capablanca (In 1921 Capablanca defeated Emanuel Lasker, who had held the world championship since 1894, when he bested Wilhelm Steinitz). Despite minor issues, the movie exudes both realism and fascination. Postscript: Josh Waitzkin became an International Master at age 16. He developed into the highest rated American chess player under age 18, and was national chess champion eight times. Waitzkin authored two books. He moved on into the martial arts field, and won championships. The youngest grandmaster in American history is now Fabiano Luigi Caruana, who was not quite 15 when he won in 2007.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close to flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robyn Nesbitt (nesfilmreviews)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Searching for Bobby Fischer" contains in its title a reminder of a time that was. Bobby Fischer was arguably the greatest chess player of all time. As a boy, he faced and defeated the greatest players of his time. In 1972, after a prelude of countless controversies, he won the world chess championship away from the Russians for the first time in years. Then he essentially disappeared and went off the deep end-- into a underworld of rented rooms, phantom sightings, and paranoid outbursts. "Searching for Bobby Fischer"-a film of remarkable sensitivity and insight, tells a story based on fact, about a "new" Bobby Fischer - a young boy named Josh Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc), who was born with a gift for chess--which he nurtured in the rough-and- tumble world of of chess hustlers in New York's Washington Square Park. His parents acknowledge his gift, but are concerned about how he can develop it without stunting the other areas of his life. After realizing what his son is capable of, Fred seeks out a chess player--a once highly regarded grand master named Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley), and hires him to tutor Josh. Bruce tries to teach his pupil a regimented, cerebral approach to the game, while Josh's mentor from the park, Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne) favors a fast paced and aggressive style used by hustlers to intimidate their opponents. Josh proves so adept at the game that Fred enters his son in a tournament. Bruce advises against this, believing that "winning and losing" has nothing to do with chess. Caught up in his son's gift and the thrill of competition, Fred pushes Josh to excel. Josh's weakness as a sportsman is his kindness, which Bonnie fears Fred will beat out of him in his efforts to make his son a winner. When he encounters another prodigy (Michael Nirenberg), who dispatches his opponents with cold-blooded efficiency. Josh has to decide for himself how important winning and losing is. The movie succeeds with the heart-warming, honest acting of the film's protagonist Max Pomeranc. Steven Zaillian, the director, made a conscious choice when he cast the film to find kids who actually could play chess. He wanted chess players first and foremost- - and who also could handle the demands of the script. His face is expressive, open - and yet strangely inscrutable when he plays chess. The criteria Zaillian demands of his protagonist ultimately defines whether this film works or not- -and Max delivers a truly natural performance. The audiences' enjoyment of this film pivots on his character-- and Pomeranc is wonderful. Zaillian's superb script attracted a fantasitc cast that includes: Joe Mantegna, Joan Allen, Ben Kingsley, and Laurence Fishburne. Supported in minor roes by David Paymer, William H. Macy, Tony Shalhoub, Dan Hedaya, Laura Linney, and Austin Pendleton. Of all those Renowned cinematographer Conrad Hall referred to the film in what he called "magical naturalism" - conveying a child's sense of imagination - while James Horner's music reflects that spirit with equal mastery. "Searching for Bobby Fischer" is an intensely fascinating movie capable of involving those who are not familiar about chess, as well as those who love it. Steven Zaillian effectively integrates the actual story and footage of Bobby Fischer throughout the film--running parallel to Josh's story, only enhancing the fascinating storyline. The focus of the film is less on the actual game than it is on the people, emotions, and pressures surrounding Josh. It is a tale of the human spirit and triumph. By the end of "Searching for Bobby Fischer", we have gained insight about the intensity and competitiveness nature of chess tournaments, and a great deal about human nature. The film's implications are many. Think of it as a very smart sports film that substitutes quiet intensity for physical action. There's no denying "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is one film in which every major element - writing, directing, casting, photography, music - is perfectly in tune, exploring the nature of competition with humor, intelligence, and depth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Winning's Not The Only Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bill Slocum (bill.slocum@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "You've got to go to the edge of defeat," one player tells another in the second half of "Searching For Bobby Fischer." That seemed to be the guiding strategy behind the movie as well. Writer-director Steven Zaillian takes an unfilmable subject (chess), bases it on a book few read, names it after a guy nobody had seen in 20 years, and puts it all in the lap of an eight-year-old actor who never starred in a film before and would star in only one after. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" does all it can to stack the board against itself, yet succeeds quite well despite, and indeed, because of all that. Joshua Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc) is celebrating his seventh birthday in Washington Square Park when he catches sight of some rough-looking characters moving what look like his Lego figures on tables of black-and-white squares. Chess is a game few master, yet Josh learns it just from watching them. Soon he is amazing parents and wizened grandmasters alike with his skill at the game, but is Josh really a prodigy on the scale of Bobby Fischer, the New York youngster who went on to win the world championship - then disappear? "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is a fairly formulaic film in many ways. It presents us with stock situations like an adorable boy who only wants to be good; a father (Joe Mantegna) who is too concerned with winning; a mother (Joan Allen) afraid her son is being turned into a machine; and a streetwise black man (Laurence Fishburne) who sees things in the child before anyone else. There's even a villain who appears shrouded in darkness, and who glares at Josh so menacingly its easy to forget this dark figure isn't quite four feet tall. But the formula really works in this one, in part because it serves such a strange cause (how many other chess movies can you think of?) and mostly because of Pomeranc's unaffected work in the lead role. Pomeranc seems preternaturally aware of his fragility on camera and plays to it in ways that reflect not precociousness but depth. You just feel for the guy, exult with his triumphs and feel his disappointments so much you resent Mantegna when his character rides Josh about doing better. Pomeranc also does great ensemble work with the other characters, especially Ben Kingsley as Josh's instructor Bruce, a fellow who seems to have been somebody's idea of Josh a generation ago only for it to collapse on him. Bruce doesn't want Josh to show mercy, you sense because he blames his own softness for his post-child ruination. "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt," he tells Josh. "I'm not him," Josh replies. That's the whole movie right there. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" feels incomplete in parts. Maybe it's just zen-like in its comfort with koan-like plot holes. We never get a real chance to see Josh learning much with Vinnie, the Fishburne character, in a way that would better explain their later closeness. Mantagna's transformation into hard-driving parent (he has a funny but nasty scene with a teacher played by Laura Linney, one of many future talents on display here) isn't laid out convincingly. But thanks both to Zaillian's affecting script and superlative camera work by the incomparable Conrad Hall working close to his zenith, you sense many things lying just beneath the surface of your view, there to be pondered when the rush of the film dissipates. And what a rush! Josh learns that winning isn't everything, but he also comes to care enough to give it his best shot in a climax both thrilling and heartwarming, even if it plays a bit to conventions. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" suggests something redemptive and perhaps even romantic in a game it dares to compare to art. In the process, it winds up presenting us with art both in theory and in practice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Family movie disguised as chess movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmoujik
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're a chess player, you should know: I saw that there were some goofs regarding chess in this movie, but I didn't know that NONE OF THE CHESS RELATED SEQUENCES MADE SENSE. What's the point of making such a movie? How hard is it to get a chess adviser for the editing process. It doesn't have to be a GM. Any decent player would suffice. You could just go a block from the Washington sq. to a chess caf&eacute; and find someone who'd have time to help not to make this movie an embarrassment. Only good parts were documentary ones showing Bobby Fischer, and I would recommend to see "Bobby Fischer against the world" for a chess cinematic fix. Otherwise this family movie is pretty banal, and I wish, someone had written this review before I considered spending time watching this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought-provoking gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Troye Dchgl
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a parent, how do you strike a balance between supporting your children and pushing your children too hard? As a teacher, what is the "correct" way to teach your pupils? There is no certain answer. But the film has the ability of making you think while delivering an exciting plot. Searching for Bobby Fischer is truly an inspiration. It is a reflection for parents to rethink how they should raise their kids, and how to give them the right message to pursue their interests. The film also shows there is no single "correct" way of teaching. A child should learn from all aspects, from different people and via different methods. "Maybe it's better not to be the best. Then you can lose and it's OK." Josh gives us a peek of the pressure of all the constant winners - it is hard for an all-time winner to lose, and sometimes you would rather be "not the best" so you can actually lose without feeling too bad. The only advisable solution is probably to give yourself less pressure when it comes to competitions by loving the game rather than forcing yourself to win. After all, it is just a game in which you are supposed to seek interest, and you should be enjoying the moment. This is highly recommended for all ages. Beautifully written is the script. There is nothing to criticize on the acting. The background music throughout the movie is highly enjoyable and appropriate. The simplicity of the movie is also great. For kids, this is a great adventure about a unknown chess prodigy becoming a champion. For grown-ups, this is also a story that gives something to learn and something to think about. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the kind of movie that can stand the test of time. Although it was made almost 20 years ago, I don't feel a bit of antiquatedness at all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This goes beyond chess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cstotlar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a pianist and classical performer, I've seen a great number of young prodigies in the field of musical performance. The large majority of them never make it past adolescence. In many cases, some of them didn't get beyond the point of doing something quite well at a very early age and were dismissed when the age factor no longer applied. This said, the parents pushed so many of them mercilessly - and rather unashamedly. The kids wanted to please their parents and the parents wanted to please themselves. It's as simple and as tragic as that and it goes on everywhere, with sports near the top, for example. The film then came as no particular surprise. It could be a valuable wake-up call to overly ambitious parents who haven't noticed who their kids ARE rather than what they can do. In this respect the film was spot on and quite frank and sincere. It went on for too long. There were too many "re-wordings" throughout which made the effort seem pedantic at times. The actors, too often shown in semi-obscurity, did their parts beautifully and I would agree with another reviewer who found the wife's contribution essential and beautifully underplayed. The game of chess doesn't have much attraction for those who don't know the game and the director and writer kept this firmly in mind by speeding up the rounds and focusing on the facial expressions. The film could definitely be "tightened up" and pared down a bit. Curtis Stotlar
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice movie for all, but great for chess fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film itself is not as great as the story behind it. Frankly, the plot is the typical American sports movie with the good hearted champion that has both talent and decency and that works hard for his art. I guess it would have been worse if it wasn't based on the book written by Josh Waitzkin's father. Josh Waitzkin has a fascinating story that I recommend you read on. He was the highest rated chess player in the US since he was 8 years old, then his father wrote the book that this movie is based on, then all the sudden celebrity messed with his chess game. Instead of clinging to chess, Josh decides to stop playing, and takes up Ju-Jitsu. He does great at it as well. His book, The Art of Learning, describes the process. Josh Waitzkin is also the guy from the "Waitzkin Academy" tutorial in the ChessMaster XI chess game. But back to the film. At the time, Josh was the next Bobby Fischer, only nicer. Everybody loved a true American hero, especially in a game that was dominated by Russians. The Art of Learning was not out yet, so the people that made the movie saw no problem in portraying the boy as a chess prodigy that did not lose to anyone unless he chose to. In reality, the wonder of Josh Waitzkin is that he really was brilliant and even as a kid he realised that losing is the true teacher. Losing in a finals of a championship defined his life, as he saw the true value of humility and confidence. Having all that information in the background had me see the movie with completely different eyes and I rather liked it. I wish it was more technical, but then no one would watch it except a few Russians, so... Funny trivia: three chess players depicted in the movie were the real people: Kamran Shirazi, Joel Benjamin and Roman DzinDziChashvili, while a girl identified as "82nd girl", which means one of Josh's opponents in the game who ranked the 82nd, is Katya Waitzkin, Josh's real life sister. Bottom line: it has some valuable lessons in there, but hidden in the usual Hollywood bull. It is nice to watch and has a lot more meaning to chess players than people not playing. I liked it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Just for Chess Geeks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Benik
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when it first came out, and I was in my mid-twenties and just getting started in the world. I saw it then as a movie about chess, and what young chess prodigies go through in order to reach the top levels. I saw it again last night, eighteen years later. The movie is the same, but I am different. I am about the age of Josh Waitzkin's father, and I have a daughter who is the same age as Josh. And although my daughter is not a prodigy of chess or anything else, I can see a lot of her in Josh, and a lot of me in his father. This is actually not a film about chess; it is a film about raising children. We live in the Dallas suburbs, where there are a lot of families and a lot of activities for children. I see parents take their children to soccer games, gymnastics camps and acting classes, and I see the obsession in their eyes. They want to expose their kids to many different pursuits, but once they see a talent forming, they focus on only that pursuit, to the exclusion of all others. They sink their money, their time, and all of their child's energy into developing that talent, at the expense of all other interests. Maybe it is pressure to earn a scholarship. Maybe it is the availability of year-round seasons and elite leagues. Maybe it is the unbelievable salaries that top athletes are earning. But I think that the problem that this movie points out -- that pushing kids to be the best at something at any cost -- has gotten worse instead of better. This movie could just as easily been about gymnastics or golf or music as it is about chess. The issues raised are the same. I just hope that more parents can see this film, and recognize that if our goal is raise happy, balanced people, pushing our kids to become elite performers is not the way to get there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern Classic with life lessons, engaging history, great story telling.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-2829
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much more than a movie about chess, this movie deals with childhood geniuses, the difficult choices of parents in how far to push their "prodigy" and the challenge of finding balance in a life filled with difficult choices. I have watched this movie a few times now, and have gleaned different things from it depending on where I am in my own life. This time around had new meaning as I have a child very gifted with piano. I've had similar challenges to Josh Waitzkin's parents in trying to decide how much to push your children - and for what purposes. Most parents probably feel that pull, even without "geniuses" - finding balance in what kids CAN do, what they SHOULD do, and what they WANT to do. We want our children to be happy, but we also know that part of being happy is doing something they are good at and helping them find meaning. I'm also a fan of chess and so really enjoy the glimpses into the chess world this movie portrays. The brilliance of those who stand even above the best minds in their field is the stuff of legends. Bobby Fischer, Garry Kasparov, Anatoly Karpov, Emmanuel Lasker... every bit leaders in their elite worlds as the likes of say Michael Jordan, Mike Tyson, Tiger Woods. Always interesting to me. Great performances all around, from the young (and skinny) Laurence Fishburne to the always stately Ben Kingsley. From the interested and caring parents to the young Josh Waitzskin... even the "enemy" chess player are all well cast and enjoyable throughout the movie. A modern classic in my opinion, and great for the whole family (probably at least 7 or 8 years old is a good lower limit). I appreciate the lessons it teaches, the story of Josh and the truths we discover.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you know anything about chess, or even if you don't, chances are you've heard the name Bobby Fischer. He was the most renowned and most skilled chess master who ever lived. His level of expertise at the game of chess could be matched by no one but himself. He was a legend to that world, but only revered because of his ability at chess. Apart from that he was a detached and solitary individual who obviously had some sort of mental deficiency that kept him from connecting with the real world. Thus his world was all chess. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the story of Josh Waitzkin, another chess master who was discovered long after Bobby Fischer. Josh unexpectedly discovers that he has a unique gift in playing chess and so the pressure from all different people sets in for him to become the best. The title of the film is Searching for Bobby Fischer, but in the context of the film the title literally means searching for the next Bobby Fischer. These pressures and goals Josh must face send us through an interesting, yet very subdued story. Searching for Bobby Fischer is very slow, but appropriately slow. Not a ton actually happens in the film as it is much more character driven. There are a lot of different characters in the film that each drive different plot lines. The film takes a while to get going because of the different characters that have be introduced, and are introduced very slowly and drawn out. Because of this early character development, there's a lot of build up necessary before the first actual conflicts of the film arise. It is almost an hour into the film before we get to see these conflicts start to take shape and affect the storyline. You have to stick with this film to get the full effect of it, which is worth it in the end. I can also commend the story for being very focused but also broad. The stories obviously centers around chess, but as it goes along it becomes more about Josh's relationships with the various people in his life, more so than anything else. The main theme of the film eventually molds into character relationships, as each character seems to have a clear cut relation with the others in order to fully flesh them all out and make them interesting. The storyline works in such a way that it is easy for it to elicit emotional responses out of its audience, so because of this I felt a little less drawn in. I didn't feel much emotion throughout the film and most of the time I just had to take it for what it was. Speaking from a personal standpoint, it isn't the most fascinating kind of story for me, but it doesn't mean it wasn't a well made film. It is very high quality with all the necessary aspects to make it a notable film. The direction is very subdued and avoids anything flashy or grand, but it keeps the flow of the film nice and smooth. The dialouge also keeps with the silky smooth theme of the film, and it is delivered by some very fine actors. All the actors do a very nice job in their respective roles. The main character, Josh Waitzkin, is only seven years old and for a child actor does a decent job. He was very sophisticated for his age and didn't always feel like a kid, but maybe that was the intention of the film. He probably was a fairly detached boy, just like Bobby Fischer, and so he didn't seem like what we think of when we think seven year old boy. And yet the film also spent a lot of time focusing on Josh's balance between chess and growing up like a normal kid, so his attitude wasn't always fitting. Plus he seems like he is on depressants for the entire film. The rest of the cast is A-list and does a great job. Joe Mantegna as Josh's father does a great job as a character trying to balance out his life much in the same way Josh is balancing his. His father must balance his want for his son to be a great chess player, but he also wants his son to live a normal childhood without all of the extreme pressures of chess. Ben Kingsley and Laurence Fishburne both play mentors to Josh, but with very different personalities. Kingsley is an old retired chess master who is very by the book and rigid in his teaching. Fishburne is much more free and sees the game of chess as a much more surreal and introspective experience. The contrast between these two characters is very interesting to watch unfold. Searching for Bobby Fischer is a good film, not a great film, just a good film. It has all the necessary components that make good films. The direction is smart, the dialouge is crisp, and the acting is fantastic. From a personal standpoint this wasn't the most gripping or emotionally moving film for me, but for others I can definitely see how it would be. This film can be enjoyed a lot more than I enjoyed it because it is a good film and there are a lot of good things going for it. But as far as I'm concerned, it was one of those films that I watch, enjoy enough to feel like it was worth my two hours, but then I never watch it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Knight to C-8, Checkmate!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a true story the feature focuses upon a child chess prodigy, Josh Waitzkin. Oh, the lad does enjoy things like baseball, but as soon as he discovers his gift for chess, then it is a new beginning. We often see child masterminds in music and in art and in the sciences, including mathematics. For instance, didn't Mozart make his debut at age four? And what about Pascal, who wrote a treatise at age nine? Anyway, our seven year-old chess genius has a grasp of complicated moves that exceeds that of adults. Still, he is just a boy; he simply has not lived. In the film, we see clips of the great chess grandmaster, Bobby Fischer, who won the US Chess Championship at age 14. He could play (and win) many board games at once. He became official world champion in 1972 when he defeated Soviet champ Boris Spassky. After his victory, he appeared on a Bob Hope TV special. But after 1975 he became a recluse and practically disappeared from the planet. Fischer had controversial beliefs. For instance, he believed in a worldwide Jewish conspiracy, and favored the Palestinians over Israel. In any case, the film's title refers not to Bobby Fischer, but to a potential American successor, one who plays like him (like Josh). And hopefully not one who had lived such an abnormal life like Fischer. Josh Waitzkin, well-played by Max Pomeranc, a real chess player, was born with his gift, which he discovers at an early age. He enjoys going to Washington Park in NYC to play with the dregs and hustlers who hang out there. Note that one of the Russian players there once defeated Tal, who was world champ in 1960-61. The Washington Park folks play a fast game ("blitz"), use unorthodox moves, and intimate their opponents. Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne), a drug addict, is one of the hustlers in the park. He seems to like Josh. As he parents discover Josh's gift, they seem oblivious of what to do with it. For instance, is winning at chess the only thing in life? Eventually, Josh's sports-writer father Fred (Joe Mantegna, in a luminous performance), hires Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley) a brilliant chess-master and former national champion, to coach his son. Bruce's style, in contrast to Vinnie's, is to use the planned approach. But Bruce seems to be almost as difficult to deal with as Fischer. He says that Josh's personality is represented by the KING chess piece, and reminds Josh that "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt." Bruce wants to keep the boy away from Washington Park, which is a hindrance to his understanding of the finer points of chess even though Josh loves the place. When Bruce later tries to teach Josh the cutthroat style of chess, Josh's mother (Bonnie = Joan Allen), becomes chagrined and states, "He's decent!" (Translation = He does not hate his opponents.) When a patronizing teacher (Laura Linney) tries to belittle Josh's achievement  his string of victories  Fred indignantly proclaims, "He's better at this than I've ever been at anything in my life. He's better at this than you'll ever be at anything. My son has a gift. He has a gift, and when you acknowledge that, then maybe we will have something to talk about." There is a point where one may ask what happens when the need to win consumes all of the fun. In the course of the movie, we learn much about tournament chess, as Josh works his way to the top. We see what happens when he begins to lose interest and sustains a series of reverses before he regains his position. In the end it comes down to the two best players  Josh and Jonathan Poe  for the junior national championship. Who will win? The movie is based upon Fred Waitzkin's autobiographical book. Our feature does not focus on any one game or on individual piece moves, so that one does not need to know how to play chess to enjoy the film. Ben Kingsley, as usual, is great in his portrayal of Bruce Pandolfini, a real New York personality who teaches chess, writes columns, and has authored many books. He actually coached young Waitzkin for quite a long time. Apparently the real Pandolfini is milder and has a more easygoing style, unlike the movie's portrayal. But that's Hollywood. An error is the film was a reference to former world champion Casablanca; that grandmaster's real name was Jose Raul Capablanca (In 1921 Capablanca defeated Emanuel Lasker, who had held the world championship since 1894, when he bested Wilhelm Steinitz). Despite minor issues, the movie exudes both realism and fascination. Postscript: Josh Waitzkin became an International Master at age 16. He developed into the highest rated American chess player under age 18, and was national chess champion eight times. Waitzkin authored two books. He moved on into the martial arts field, and won championships. The youngest grandmaster in American history is now Fabiano Luigi Caruana, who was not quite 15 when he won in 2007.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close to flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robyn Nesbitt (nesfilmreviews)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Searching for Bobby Fischer" contains in its title a reminder of a time that was. Bobby Fischer was arguably the greatest chess player of all time. As a boy, he faced and defeated the greatest players of his time. In 1972, after a prelude of countless controversies, he won the world chess championship away from the Russians for the first time in years. Then he essentially disappeared and went off the deep end-- into a underworld of rented rooms, phantom sightings, and paranoid outbursts. "Searching for Bobby Fischer"-a film of remarkable sensitivity and insight, tells a story based on fact, about a "new" Bobby Fischer - a young boy named Josh Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc), who was born with a gift for chess--which he nurtured in the rough-and- tumble world of of chess hustlers in New York's Washington Square Park. His parents acknowledge his gift, but are concerned about how he can develop it without stunting the other areas of his life. After realizing what his son is capable of, Fred seeks out a chess player--a once highly regarded grand master named Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley), and hires him to tutor Josh. Bruce tries to teach his pupil a regimented, cerebral approach to the game, while Josh's mentor from the park, Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne) favors a fast paced and aggressive style used by hustlers to intimidate their opponents. Josh proves so adept at the game that Fred enters his son in a tournament. Bruce advises against this, believing that "winning and losing" has nothing to do with chess. Caught up in his son's gift and the thrill of competition, Fred pushes Josh to excel. Josh's weakness as a sportsman is his kindness, which Bonnie fears Fred will beat out of him in his efforts to make his son a winner. When he encounters another prodigy (Michael Nirenberg), who dispatches his opponents with cold-blooded efficiency. Josh has to decide for himself how important winning and losing is. The movie succeeds with the heart-warming, honest acting of the film's protagonist Max Pomeranc. Steven Zaillian, the director, made a conscious choice when he cast the film to find kids who actually could play chess. He wanted chess players first and foremost- - and who also could handle the demands of the script. His face is expressive, open - and yet strangely inscrutable when he plays chess. The criteria Zaillian demands of his protagonist ultimately defines whether this film works or not- -and Max delivers a truly natural performance. The audiences' enjoyment of this film pivots on his character-- and Pomeranc is wonderful. Zaillian's superb script attracted a fantasitc cast that includes: Joe Mantegna, Joan Allen, Ben Kingsley, and Laurence Fishburne. Supported in minor roes by David Paymer, William H. Macy, Tony Shalhoub, Dan Hedaya, Laura Linney, and Austin Pendleton. Of all those Renowned cinematographer Conrad Hall referred to the film in what he called "magical naturalism" - conveying a child's sense of imagination - while James Horner's music reflects that spirit with equal mastery. "Searching for Bobby Fischer" is an intensely fascinating movie capable of involving those who are not familiar about chess, as well as those who love it. Steven Zaillian effectively integrates the actual story and footage of Bobby Fischer throughout the film--running parallel to Josh's story, only enhancing the fascinating storyline. The focus of the film is less on the actual game than it is on the people, emotions, and pressures surrounding Josh. It is a tale of the human spirit and triumph. By the end of "Searching for Bobby Fischer", we have gained insight about the intensity and competitiveness nature of chess tournaments, and a great deal about human nature. The film's implications are many. Think of it as a very smart sports film that substitutes quiet intensity for physical action. There's no denying "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is one film in which every major element - writing, directing, casting, photography, music - is perfectly in tune, exploring the nature of competition with humor, intelligence, and depth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Winning's Not The Only Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bill Slocum (bill.slocum@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "You've got to go to the edge of defeat," one player tells another in the second half of "Searching For Bobby Fischer." That seemed to be the guiding strategy behind the movie as well. Writer-director Steven Zaillian takes an unfilmable subject (chess), bases it on a book few read, names it after a guy nobody had seen in 20 years, and puts it all in the lap of an eight-year-old actor who never starred in a film before and would star in only one after. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" does all it can to stack the board against itself, yet succeeds quite well despite, and indeed, because of all that. Joshua Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc) is celebrating his seventh birthday in Washington Square Park when he catches sight of some rough-looking characters moving what look like his Lego figures on tables of black-and-white squares. Chess is a game few master, yet Josh learns it just from watching them. Soon he is amazing parents and wizened grandmasters alike with his skill at the game, but is Josh really a prodigy on the scale of Bobby Fischer, the New York youngster who went on to win the world championship - then disappear? "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is a fairly formulaic film in many ways. It presents us with stock situations like an adorable boy who only wants to be good; a father (Joe Mantegna) who is too concerned with winning; a mother (Joan Allen) afraid her son is being turned into a machine; and a streetwise black man (Laurence Fishburne) who sees things in the child before anyone else. There's even a villain who appears shrouded in darkness, and who glares at Josh so menacingly its easy to forget this dark figure isn't quite four feet tall. But the formula really works in this one, in part because it serves such a strange cause (how many other chess movies can you think of?) and mostly because of Pomeranc's unaffected work in the lead role. Pomeranc seems preternaturally aware of his fragility on camera and plays to it in ways that reflect not precociousness but depth. You just feel for the guy, exult with his triumphs and feel his disappointments so much you resent Mantegna when his character rides Josh about doing better. Pomeranc also does great ensemble work with the other characters, especially Ben Kingsley as Josh's instructor Bruce, a fellow who seems to have been somebody's idea of Josh a generation ago only for it to collapse on him. Bruce doesn't want Josh to show mercy, you sense because he blames his own softness for his post-child ruination. "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt," he tells Josh. "I'm not him," Josh replies. That's the whole movie right there. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" feels incomplete in parts. Maybe it's just zen-like in its comfort with koan-like plot holes. We never get a real chance to see Josh learning much with Vinnie, the Fishburne character, in a way that would better explain their later closeness. Mantagna's transformation into hard-driving parent (he has a funny but nasty scene with a teacher played by Laura Linney, one of many future talents on display here) isn't laid out convincingly. But thanks both to Zaillian's affecting script and superlative camera work by the incomparable Conrad Hall working close to his zenith, you sense many things lying just beneath the surface of your view, there to be pondered when the rush of the film dissipates. And what a rush! Josh learns that winning isn't everything, but he also comes to care enough to give it his best shot in a climax both thrilling and heartwarming, even if it plays a bit to conventions. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" suggests something redemptive and perhaps even romantic in a game it dares to compare to art. In the process, it winds up presenting us with art both in theory and in practice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Family movie disguised as chess movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmoujik
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're a chess player, you should know: I saw that there were some goofs regarding chess in this movie, but I didn't know that NONE OF THE CHESS RELATED SEQUENCES MADE SENSE. What's the point of making such a movie? How hard is it to get a chess adviser for the editing process. It doesn't have to be a GM. Any decent player would suffice. You could just go a block from the Washington sq. to a chess caf&eacute; and find someone who'd have time to help not to make this movie an embarrassment. Only good parts were documentary ones showing Bobby Fischer, and I would recommend to see "Bobby Fischer against the world" for a chess cinematic fix. Otherwise this family movie is pretty banal, and I wish, someone had written this review before I considered spending time watching this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought-provoking gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Troye Dchgl
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a parent, how do you strike a balance between supporting your children and pushing your children too hard? As a teacher, what is the "correct" way to teach your pupils? There is no certain answer. But the film has the ability of making you think while delivering an exciting plot. Searching for Bobby Fischer is truly an inspiration. It is a reflection for parents to rethink how they should raise their kids, and how to give them the right message to pursue their interests. The film also shows there is no single "correct" way of teaching. A child should learn from all aspects, from different people and via different methods. "Maybe it's better not to be the best. Then you can lose and it's OK." Josh gives us a peek of the pressure of all the constant winners - it is hard for an all-time winner to lose, and sometimes you would rather be "not the best" so you can actually lose without feeling too bad. The only advisable solution is probably to give yourself less pressure when it comes to competitions by loving the game rather than forcing yourself to win. After all, it is just a game in which you are supposed to seek interest, and you should be enjoying the moment. This is highly recommended for all ages. Beautifully written is the script. There is nothing to criticize on the acting. The background music throughout the movie is highly enjoyable and appropriate. The simplicity of the movie is also great. For kids, this is a great adventure about a unknown chess prodigy becoming a champion. For grown-ups, this is also a story that gives something to learn and something to think about. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the kind of movie that can stand the test of time. Although it was made almost 20 years ago, I don't feel a bit of antiquatedness at all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This goes beyond chess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cstotlar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a pianist and classical performer, I've seen a great number of young prodigies in the field of musical performance. The large majority of them never make it past adolescence. In many cases, some of them didn't get beyond the point of doing something quite well at a very early age and were dismissed when the age factor no longer applied. This said, the parents pushed so many of them mercilessly - and rather unashamedly. The kids wanted to please their parents and the parents wanted to please themselves. It's as simple and as tragic as that and it goes on everywhere, with sports near the top, for example. The film then came as no particular surprise. It could be a valuable wake-up call to overly ambitious parents who haven't noticed who their kids ARE rather than what they can do. In this respect the film was spot on and quite frank and sincere. It went on for too long. There were too many "re-wordings" throughout which made the effort seem pedantic at times. The actors, too often shown in semi-obscurity, did their parts beautifully and I would agree with another reviewer who found the wife's contribution essential and beautifully underplayed. The game of chess doesn't have much attraction for those who don't know the game and the director and writer kept this firmly in mind by speeding up the rounds and focusing on the facial expressions. The film could definitely be "tightened up" and pared down a bit. Curtis Stotlar
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice movie for all, but great for chess fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film itself is not as great as the story behind it. Frankly, the plot is the typical American sports movie with the good hearted champion that has both talent and decency and that works hard for his art. I guess it would have been worse if it wasn't based on the book written by Josh Waitzkin's father. Josh Waitzkin has a fascinating story that I recommend you read on. He was the highest rated chess player in the US since he was 8 years old, then his father wrote the book that this movie is based on, then all the sudden celebrity messed with his chess game. Instead of clinging to chess, Josh decides to stop playing, and takes up Ju-Jitsu. He does great at it as well. His book, The Art of Learning, describes the process. Josh Waitzkin is also the guy from the "Waitzkin Academy" tutorial in the ChessMaster XI chess game. But back to the film. At the time, Josh was the next Bobby Fischer, only nicer. Everybody loved a true American hero, especially in a game that was dominated by Russians. The Art of Learning was not out yet, so the people that made the movie saw no problem in portraying the boy as a chess prodigy that did not lose to anyone unless he chose to. In reality, the wonder of Josh Waitzkin is that he really was brilliant and even as a kid he realised that losing is the true teacher. Losing in a finals of a championship defined his life, as he saw the true value of humility and confidence. Having all that information in the background had me see the movie with completely different eyes and I rather liked it. I wish it was more technical, but then no one would watch it except a few Russians, so... Funny trivia: three chess players depicted in the movie were the real people: Kamran Shirazi, Joel Benjamin and Roman DzinDziChashvili, while a girl identified as "82nd girl", which means one of Josh's opponents in the game who ranked the 82nd, is Katya Waitzkin, Josh's real life sister. Bottom line: it has some valuable lessons in there, but hidden in the usual Hollywood bull. It is nice to watch and has a lot more meaning to chess players than people not playing. I liked it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Just for Chess Geeks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Benik
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when it first came out, and I was in my mid-twenties and just getting started in the world. I saw it then as a movie about chess, and what young chess prodigies go through in order to reach the top levels. I saw it again last night, eighteen years later. The movie is the same, but I am different. I am about the age of Josh Waitzkin's father, and I have a daughter who is the same age as Josh. And although my daughter is not a prodigy of chess or anything else, I can see a lot of her in Josh, and a lot of me in his father. This is actually not a film about chess; it is a film about raising children. We live in the Dallas suburbs, where there are a lot of families and a lot of activities for children. I see parents take their children to soccer games, gymnastics camps and acting classes, and I see the obsession in their eyes. They want to expose their kids to many different pursuits, but once they see a talent forming, they focus on only that pursuit, to the exclusion of all others. They sink their money, their time, and all of their child's energy into developing that talent, at the expense of all other interests. Maybe it is pressure to earn a scholarship. Maybe it is the availability of year-round seasons and elite leagues. Maybe it is the unbelievable salaries that top athletes are earning. But I think that the problem that this movie points out -- that pushing kids to be the best at something at any cost -- has gotten worse instead of better. This movie could just as easily been about gymnastics or golf or music as it is about chess. The issues raised are the same. I just hope that more parents can see this film, and recognize that if our goal is raise happy, balanced people, pushing our kids to become elite performers is not the way to get there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern Classic with life lessons, engaging history, great story telling.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-2829
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much more than a movie about chess, this movie deals with childhood geniuses, the difficult choices of parents in how far to push their "prodigy" and the challenge of finding balance in a life filled with difficult choices. I have watched this movie a few times now, and have gleaned different things from it depending on where I am in my own life. This time around had new meaning as I have a child very gifted with piano. I've had similar challenges to Josh Waitzkin's parents in trying to decide how much to push your children - and for what purposes. Most parents probably feel that pull, even without "geniuses" - finding balance in what kids CAN do, what they SHOULD do, and what they WANT to do. We want our children to be happy, but we also know that part of being happy is doing something they are good at and helping them find meaning. I'm also a fan of chess and so really enjoy the glimpses into the chess world this movie portrays. The brilliance of those who stand even above the best minds in their field is the stuff of legends. Bobby Fischer, Garry Kasparov, Anatoly Karpov, Emmanuel Lasker... every bit leaders in their elite worlds as the likes of say Michael Jordan, Mike Tyson, Tiger Woods. Always interesting to me. Great performances all around, from the young (and skinny) Laurence Fishburne to the always stately Ben Kingsley. From the interested and caring parents to the young Josh Waitzskin... even the "enemy" chess player are all well cast and enjoyable throughout the movie. A modern classic in my opinion, and great for the whole family (probably at least 7 or 8 years old is a good lower limit). I appreciate the lessons it teaches, the story of Josh and the truths we discover.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you know anything about chess, or even if you don't, chances are you've heard the name Bobby Fischer. He was the most renowned and most skilled chess master who ever lived. His level of expertise at the game of chess could be matched by no one but himself. He was a legend to that world, but only revered because of his ability at chess. Apart from that he was a detached and solitary individual who obviously had some sort of mental deficiency that kept him from connecting with the real world. Thus his world was all chess. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the story of Josh Waitzkin, another chess master who was discovered long after Bobby Fischer. Josh unexpectedly discovers that he has a unique gift in playing chess and so the pressure from all different people sets in for him to become the best. The title of the film is Searching for Bobby Fischer, but in the context of the film the title literally means searching for the next Bobby Fischer. These pressures and goals Josh must face send us through an interesting, yet very subdued story. Searching for Bobby Fischer is very slow, but appropriately slow. Not a ton actually happens in the film as it is much more character driven. There are a lot of different characters in the film that each drive different plot lines. The film takes a while to get going because of the different characters that have be introduced, and are introduced very slowly and drawn out. Because of this early character development, there's a lot of build up necessary before the first actual conflicts of the film arise. It is almost an hour into the film before we get to see these conflicts start to take shape and affect the storyline. You have to stick with this film to get the full effect of it, which is worth it in the end. I can also commend the story for being very focused but also broad. The stories obviously centers around chess, but as it goes along it becomes more about Josh's relationships with the various people in his life, more so than anything else. The main theme of the film eventually molds into character relationships, as each character seems to have a clear cut relation with the others in order to fully flesh them all out and make them interesting. The storyline works in such a way that it is easy for it to elicit emotional responses out of its audience, so because of this I felt a little less drawn in. I didn't feel much emotion throughout the film and most of the time I just had to take it for what it was. Speaking from a personal standpoint, it isn't the most fascinating kind of story for me, but it doesn't mean it wasn't a well made film. It is very high quality with all the necessary aspects to make it a notable film. The direction is very subdued and avoids anything flashy or grand, but it keeps the flow of the film nice and smooth. The dialouge also keeps with the silky smooth theme of the film, and it is delivered by some very fine actors. All the actors do a very nice job in their respective roles. The main character, Josh Waitzkin, is only seven years old and for a child actor does a decent job. He was very sophisticated for his age and didn't always feel like a kid, but maybe that was the intention of the film. He probably was a fairly detached boy, just like Bobby Fischer, and so he didn't seem like what we think of when we think seven year old boy. And yet the film also spent a lot of time focusing on Josh's balance between chess and growing up like a normal kid, so his attitude wasn't always fitting. Plus he seems like he is on depressants for the entire film. The rest of the cast is A-list and does a great job. Joe Mantegna as Josh's father does a great job as a character trying to balance out his life much in the same way Josh is balancing his. His father must balance his want for his son to be a great chess player, but he also wants his son to live a normal childhood without all of the extreme pressures of chess. Ben Kingsley and Laurence Fishburne both play mentors to Josh, but with very different personalities. Kingsley is an old retired chess master who is very by the book and rigid in his teaching. Fishburne is much more free and sees the game of chess as a much more surreal and introspective experience. The contrast between these two characters is very interesting to watch unfold. Searching for Bobby Fischer is a good film, not a great film, just a good film. It has all the necessary components that make good films. The direction is smart, the dialouge is crisp, and the acting is fantastic. From a personal standpoint this wasn't the most gripping or emotionally moving film for me, but for others I can definitely see how it would be. This film can be enjoyed a lot more than I enjoyed it because it is a good film and there are a lot of good things going for it. But as far as I'm concerned, it was one of those films that I watch, enjoy enough to feel like it was worth my two hours, but then I never watch it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Knight to C-8, Checkmate!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a true story the feature focuses upon a child chess prodigy, Josh Waitzkin. Oh, the lad does enjoy things like baseball, but as soon as he discovers his gift for chess, then it is a new beginning. We often see child masterminds in music and in art and in the sciences, including mathematics. For instance, didn't Mozart make his debut at age four? And what about Pascal, who wrote a treatise at age nine? Anyway, our seven year-old chess genius has a grasp of complicated moves that exceeds that of adults. Still, he is just a boy; he simply has not lived. In the film, we see clips of the great chess grandmaster, Bobby Fischer, who won the US Chess Championship at age 14. He could play (and win) many board games at once. He became official world champion in 1972 when he defeated Soviet champ Boris Spassky. After his victory, he appeared on a Bob Hope TV special. But after 1975 he became a recluse and practically disappeared from the planet. Fischer had controversial beliefs. For instance, he believed in a worldwide Jewish conspiracy, and favored the Palestinians over Israel. In any case, the film's title refers not to Bobby Fischer, but to a potential American successor, one who plays like him (like Josh). And hopefully not one who had lived such an abnormal life like Fischer. Josh Waitzkin, well-played by Max Pomeranc, a real chess player, was born with his gift, which he discovers at an early age. He enjoys going to Washington Park in NYC to play with the dregs and hustlers who hang out there. Note that one of the Russian players there once defeated Tal, who was world champ in 1960-61. The Washington Park folks play a fast game ("blitz"), use unorthodox moves, and intimate their opponents. Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne), a drug addict, is one of the hustlers in the park. He seems to like Josh. As he parents discover Josh's gift, they seem oblivious of what to do with it. For instance, is winning at chess the only thing in life? Eventually, Josh's sports-writer father Fred (Joe Mantegna, in a luminous performance), hires Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley) a brilliant chess-master and former national champion, to coach his son. Bruce's style, in contrast to Vinnie's, is to use the planned approach. But Bruce seems to be almost as difficult to deal with as Fischer. He says that Josh's personality is represented by the KING chess piece, and reminds Josh that "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt." Bruce wants to keep the boy away from Washington Park, which is a hindrance to his understanding of the finer points of chess even though Josh loves the place. When Bruce later tries to teach Josh the cutthroat style of chess, Josh's mother (Bonnie = Joan Allen), becomes chagrined and states, "He's decent!" (Translation = He does not hate his opponents.) When a patronizing teacher (Laura Linney) tries to belittle Josh's achievement  his string of victories  Fred indignantly proclaims, "He's better at this than I've ever been at anything in my life. He's better at this than you'll ever be at anything. My son has a gift. He has a gift, and when you acknowledge that, then maybe we will have something to talk about." There is a point where one may ask what happens when the need to win consumes all of the fun. In the course of the movie, we learn much about tournament chess, as Josh works his way to the top. We see what happens when he begins to lose interest and sustains a series of reverses before he regains his position. In the end it comes down to the two best players  Josh and Jonathan Poe  for the junior national championship. Who will win? The movie is based upon Fred Waitzkin's autobiographical book. Our feature does not focus on any one game or on individual piece moves, so that one does not need to know how to play chess to enjoy the film. Ben Kingsley, as usual, is great in his portrayal of Bruce Pandolfini, a real New York personality who teaches chess, writes columns, and has authored many books. He actually coached young Waitzkin for quite a long time. Apparently the real Pandolfini is milder and has a more easygoing style, unlike the movie's portrayal. But that's Hollywood. An error is the film was a reference to former world champion Casablanca; that grandmaster's real name was Jose Raul Capablanca (In 1921 Capablanca defeated Emanuel Lasker, who had held the world championship since 1894, when he bested Wilhelm Steinitz). Despite minor issues, the movie exudes both realism and fascination. Postscript: Josh Waitzkin became an International Master at age 16. He developed into the highest rated American chess player under age 18, and was national chess champion eight times. Waitzkin authored two books. He moved on into the martial arts field, and won championships. The youngest grandmaster in American history is now Fabiano Luigi Caruana, who was not quite 15 when he won in 2007.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close to flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robyn Nesbitt (nesfilmreviews)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Searching for Bobby Fischer" contains in its title a reminder of a time that was. Bobby Fischer was arguably the greatest chess player of all time. As a boy, he faced and defeated the greatest players of his time. In 1972, after a prelude of countless controversies, he won the world chess championship away from the Russians for the first time in years. Then he essentially disappeared and went off the deep end-- into a underworld of rented rooms, phantom sightings, and paranoid outbursts. "Searching for Bobby Fischer"-a film of remarkable sensitivity and insight, tells a story based on fact, about a "new" Bobby Fischer - a young boy named Josh Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc), who was born with a gift for chess--which he nurtured in the rough-and- tumble world of of chess hustlers in New York's Washington Square Park. His parents acknowledge his gift, but are concerned about how he can develop it without stunting the other areas of his life. After realizing what his son is capable of, Fred seeks out a chess player--a once highly regarded grand master named Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley), and hires him to tutor Josh. Bruce tries to teach his pupil a regimented, cerebral approach to the game, while Josh's mentor from the park, Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne) favors a fast paced and aggressive style used by hustlers to intimidate their opponents. Josh proves so adept at the game that Fred enters his son in a tournament. Bruce advises against this, believing that "winning and losing" has nothing to do with chess. Caught up in his son's gift and the thrill of competition, Fred pushes Josh to excel. Josh's weakness as a sportsman is his kindness, which Bonnie fears Fred will beat out of him in his efforts to make his son a winner. When he encounters another prodigy (Michael Nirenberg), who dispatches his opponents with cold-blooded efficiency. Josh has to decide for himself how important winning and losing is. The movie succeeds with the heart-warming, honest acting of the film's protagonist Max Pomeranc. Steven Zaillian, the director, made a conscious choice when he cast the film to find kids who actually could play chess. He wanted chess players first and foremost- - and who also could handle the demands of the script. His face is expressive, open - and yet strangely inscrutable when he plays chess. The criteria Zaillian demands of his protagonist ultimately defines whether this film works or not- -and Max delivers a truly natural performance. The audiences' enjoyment of this film pivots on his character-- and Pomeranc is wonderful. Zaillian's superb script attracted a fantasitc cast that includes: Joe Mantegna, Joan Allen, Ben Kingsley, and Laurence Fishburne. Supported in minor roes by David Paymer, William H. Macy, Tony Shalhoub, Dan Hedaya, Laura Linney, and Austin Pendleton. Of all those Renowned cinematographer Conrad Hall referred to the film in what he called "magical naturalism" - conveying a child's sense of imagination - while James Horner's music reflects that spirit with equal mastery. "Searching for Bobby Fischer" is an intensely fascinating movie capable of involving those who are not familiar about chess, as well as those who love it. Steven Zaillian effectively integrates the actual story and footage of Bobby Fischer throughout the film--running parallel to Josh's story, only enhancing the fascinating storyline. The focus of the film is less on the actual game than it is on the people, emotions, and pressures surrounding Josh. It is a tale of the human spirit and triumph. By the end of "Searching for Bobby Fischer", we have gained insight about the intensity and competitiveness nature of chess tournaments, and a great deal about human nature. The film's implications are many. Think of it as a very smart sports film that substitutes quiet intensity for physical action. There's no denying "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is one film in which every major element - writing, directing, casting, photography, music - is perfectly in tune, exploring the nature of competition with humor, intelligence, and depth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Winning's Not The Only Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bill Slocum (bill.slocum@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "You've got to go to the edge of defeat," one player tells another in the second half of "Searching For Bobby Fischer." That seemed to be the guiding strategy behind the movie as well. Writer-director Steven Zaillian takes an unfilmable subject (chess), bases it on a book few read, names it after a guy nobody had seen in 20 years, and puts it all in the lap of an eight-year-old actor who never starred in a film before and would star in only one after. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" does all it can to stack the board against itself, yet succeeds quite well despite, and indeed, because of all that. Joshua Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc) is celebrating his seventh birthday in Washington Square Park when he catches sight of some rough-looking characters moving what look like his Lego figures on tables of black-and-white squares. Chess is a game few master, yet Josh learns it just from watching them. Soon he is amazing parents and wizened grandmasters alike with his skill at the game, but is Josh really a prodigy on the scale of Bobby Fischer, the New York youngster who went on to win the world championship - then disappear? "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is a fairly formulaic film in many ways. It presents us with stock situations like an adorable boy who only wants to be good; a father (Joe Mantegna) who is too concerned with winning; a mother (Joan Allen) afraid her son is being turned into a machine; and a streetwise black man (Laurence Fishburne) who sees things in the child before anyone else. There's even a villain who appears shrouded in darkness, and who glares at Josh so menacingly its easy to forget this dark figure isn't quite four feet tall. But the formula really works in this one, in part because it serves such a strange cause (how many other chess movies can you think of?) and mostly because of Pomeranc's unaffected work in the lead role. Pomeranc seems preternaturally aware of his fragility on camera and plays to it in ways that reflect not precociousness but depth. You just feel for the guy, exult with his triumphs and feel his disappointments so much you resent Mantegna when his character rides Josh about doing better. Pomeranc also does great ensemble work with the other characters, especially Ben Kingsley as Josh's instructor Bruce, a fellow who seems to have been somebody's idea of Josh a generation ago only for it to collapse on him. Bruce doesn't want Josh to show mercy, you sense because he blames his own softness for his post-child ruination. "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt," he tells Josh. "I'm not him," Josh replies. That's the whole movie right there. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" feels incomplete in parts. Maybe it's just zen-like in its comfort with koan-like plot holes. We never get a real chance to see Josh learning much with Vinnie, the Fishburne character, in a way that would better explain their later closeness. Mantagna's transformation into hard-driving parent (he has a funny but nasty scene with a teacher played by Laura Linney, one of many future talents on display here) isn't laid out convincingly. But thanks both to Zaillian's affecting script and superlative camera work by the incomparable Conrad Hall working close to his zenith, you sense many things lying just beneath the surface of your view, there to be pondered when the rush of the film dissipates. And what a rush! Josh learns that winning isn't everything, but he also comes to care enough to give it his best shot in a climax both thrilling and heartwarming, even if it plays a bit to conventions. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" suggests something redemptive and perhaps even romantic in a game it dares to compare to art. In the process, it winds up presenting us with art both in theory and in practice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Family movie disguised as chess movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmoujik
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're a chess player, you should know: I saw that there were some goofs regarding chess in this movie, but I didn't know that NONE OF THE CHESS RELATED SEQUENCES MADE SENSE. What's the point of making such a movie? How hard is it to get a chess adviser for the editing process. It doesn't have to be a GM. Any decent player would suffice. You could just go a block from the Washington sq. to a chess caf&eacute; and find someone who'd have time to help not to make this movie an embarrassment. Only good parts were documentary ones showing Bobby Fischer, and I would recommend to see "Bobby Fischer against the world" for a chess cinematic fix. Otherwise this family movie is pretty banal, and I wish, someone had written this review before I considered spending time watching this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought-provoking gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Troye Dchgl
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a parent, how do you strike a balance between supporting your children and pushing your children too hard? As a teacher, what is the "correct" way to teach your pupils? There is no certain answer. But the film has the ability of making you think while delivering an exciting plot. Searching for Bobby Fischer is truly an inspiration. It is a reflection for parents to rethink how they should raise their kids, and how to give them the right message to pursue their interests. The film also shows there is no single "correct" way of teaching. A child should learn from all aspects, from different people and via different methods. "Maybe it's better not to be the best. Then you can lose and it's OK." Josh gives us a peek of the pressure of all the constant winners - it is hard for an all-time winner to lose, and sometimes you would rather be "not the best" so you can actually lose without feeling too bad. The only advisable solution is probably to give yourself less pressure when it comes to competitions by loving the game rather than forcing yourself to win. After all, it is just a game in which you are supposed to seek interest, and you should be enjoying the moment. This is highly recommended for all ages. Beautifully written is the script. There is nothing to criticize on the acting. The background music throughout the movie is highly enjoyable and appropriate. The simplicity of the movie is also great. For kids, this is a great adventure about a unknown chess prodigy becoming a champion. For grown-ups, this is also a story that gives something to learn and something to think about. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the kind of movie that can stand the test of time. Although it was made almost 20 years ago, I don't feel a bit of antiquatedness at all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This goes beyond chess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cstotlar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a pianist and classical performer, I've seen a great number of young prodigies in the field of musical performance. The large majority of them never make it past adolescence. In many cases, some of them didn't get beyond the point of doing something quite well at a very early age and were dismissed when the age factor no longer applied. This said, the parents pushed so many of them mercilessly - and rather unashamedly. The kids wanted to please their parents and the parents wanted to please themselves. It's as simple and as tragic as that and it goes on everywhere, with sports near the top, for example. The film then came as no particular surprise. It could be a valuable wake-up call to overly ambitious parents who haven't noticed who their kids ARE rather than what they can do. In this respect the film was spot on and quite frank and sincere. It went on for too long. There were too many "re-wordings" throughout which made the effort seem pedantic at times. The actors, too often shown in semi-obscurity, did their parts beautifully and I would agree with another reviewer who found the wife's contribution essential and beautifully underplayed. The game of chess doesn't have much attraction for those who don't know the game and the director and writer kept this firmly in mind by speeding up the rounds and focusing on the facial expressions. The film could definitely be "tightened up" and pared down a bit. Curtis Stotlar
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice movie for all, but great for chess fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film itself is not as great as the story behind it. Frankly, the plot is the typical American sports movie with the good hearted champion that has both talent and decency and that works hard for his art. I guess it would have been worse if it wasn't based on the book written by Josh Waitzkin's father. Josh Waitzkin has a fascinating story that I recommend you read on. He was the highest rated chess player in the US since he was 8 years old, then his father wrote the book that this movie is based on, then all the sudden celebrity messed with his chess game. Instead of clinging to chess, Josh decides to stop playing, and takes up Ju-Jitsu. He does great at it as well. His book, The Art of Learning, describes the process. Josh Waitzkin is also the guy from the "Waitzkin Academy" tutorial in the ChessMaster XI chess game. But back to the film. At the time, Josh was the next Bobby Fischer, only nicer. Everybody loved a true American hero, especially in a game that was dominated by Russians. The Art of Learning was not out yet, so the people that made the movie saw no problem in portraying the boy as a chess prodigy that did not lose to anyone unless he chose to. In reality, the wonder of Josh Waitzkin is that he really was brilliant and even as a kid he realised that losing is the true teacher. Losing in a finals of a championship defined his life, as he saw the true value of humility and confidence. Having all that information in the background had me see the movie with completely different eyes and I rather liked it. I wish it was more technical, but then no one would watch it except a few Russians, so... Funny trivia: three chess players depicted in the movie were the real people: Kamran Shirazi, Joel Benjamin and Roman DzinDziChashvili, while a girl identified as "82nd girl", which means one of Josh's opponents in the game who ranked the 82nd, is Katya Waitzkin, Josh's real life sister. Bottom line: it has some valuable lessons in there, but hidden in the usual Hollywood bull. It is nice to watch and has a lot more meaning to chess players than people not playing. I liked it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Just for Chess Geeks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Benik
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when it first came out, and I was in my mid-twenties and just getting started in the world. I saw it then as a movie about chess, and what young chess prodigies go through in order to reach the top levels. I saw it again last night, eighteen years later. The movie is the same, but I am different. I am about the age of Josh Waitzkin's father, and I have a daughter who is the same age as Josh. And although my daughter is not a prodigy of chess or anything else, I can see a lot of her in Josh, and a lot of me in his father. This is actually not a film about chess; it is a film about raising children. We live in the Dallas suburbs, where there are a lot of families and a lot of activities for children. I see parents take their children to soccer games, gymnastics camps and acting classes, and I see the obsession in their eyes. They want to expose their kids to many different pursuits, but once they see a talent forming, they focus on only that pursuit, to the exclusion of all others. They sink their money, their time, and all of their child's energy into developing that talent, at the expense of all other interests. Maybe it is pressure to earn a scholarship. Maybe it is the availability of year-round seasons and elite leagues. Maybe it is the unbelievable salaries that top athletes are earning. But I think that the problem that this movie points out -- that pushing kids to be the best at something at any cost -- has gotten worse instead of better. This movie could just as easily been about gymnastics or golf or music as it is about chess. The issues raised are the same. I just hope that more parents can see this film, and recognize that if our goal is raise happy, balanced people, pushing our kids to become elite performers is not the way to get there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern Classic with life lessons, engaging history, great story telling.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-2829
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much more than a movie about chess, this movie deals with childhood geniuses, the difficult choices of parents in how far to push their "prodigy" and the challenge of finding balance in a life filled with difficult choices. I have watched this movie a few times now, and have gleaned different things from it depending on where I am in my own life. This time around had new meaning as I have a child very gifted with piano. I've had similar challenges to Josh Waitzkin's parents in trying to decide how much to push your children - and for what purposes. Most parents probably feel that pull, even without "geniuses" - finding balance in what kids CAN do, what they SHOULD do, and what they WANT to do. We want our children to be happy, but we also know that part of being happy is doing something they are good at and helping them find meaning. I'm also a fan of chess and so really enjoy the glimpses into the chess world this movie portrays. The brilliance of those who stand even above the best minds in their field is the stuff of legends. Bobby Fischer, Garry Kasparov, Anatoly Karpov, Emmanuel Lasker... every bit leaders in their elite worlds as the likes of say Michael Jordan, Mike Tyson, Tiger Woods. Always interesting to me. Great performances all around, from the young (and skinny) Laurence Fishburne to the always stately Ben Kingsley. From the interested and caring parents to the young Josh Waitzskin... even the "enemy" chess player are all well cast and enjoyable throughout the movie. A modern classic in my opinion, and great for the whole family (probably at least 7 or 8 years old is a good lower limit). I appreciate the lessons it teaches, the story of Josh and the truths we discover.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you know anything about chess, or even if you don't, chances are you've heard the name Bobby Fischer. He was the most renowned and most skilled chess master who ever lived. His level of expertise at the game of chess could be matched by no one but himself. He was a legend to that world, but only revered because of his ability at chess. Apart from that he was a detached and solitary individual who obviously had some sort of mental deficiency that kept him from connecting with the real world. Thus his world was all chess. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the story of Josh Waitzkin, another chess master who was discovered long after Bobby Fischer. Josh unexpectedly discovers that he has a unique gift in playing chess and so the pressure from all different people sets in for him to become the best. The title of the film is Searching for Bobby Fischer, but in the context of the film the title literally means searching for the next Bobby Fischer. These pressures and goals Josh must face send us through an interesting, yet very subdued story. Searching for Bobby Fischer is very slow, but appropriately slow. Not a ton actually happens in the film as it is much more character driven. There are a lot of different characters in the film that each drive different plot lines. The film takes a while to get going because of the different characters that have be introduced, and are introduced very slowly and drawn out. Because of this early character development, there's a lot of build up necessary before the first actual conflicts of the film arise. It is almost an hour into the film before we get to see these conflicts start to take shape and affect the storyline. You have to stick with this film to get the full effect of it, which is worth it in the end. I can also commend the story for being very focused but also broad. The stories obviously centers around chess, but as it goes along it becomes more about Josh's relationships with the various people in his life, more so than anything else. The main theme of the film eventually molds into character relationships, as each character seems to have a clear cut relation with the others in order to fully flesh them all out and make them interesting. The storyline works in such a way that it is easy for it to elicit emotional responses out of its audience, so because of this I felt a little less drawn in. I didn't feel much emotion throughout the film and most of the time I just had to take it for what it was. Speaking from a personal standpoint, it isn't the most fascinating kind of story for me, but it doesn't mean it wasn't a well made film. It is very high quality with all the necessary aspects to make it a notable film. The direction is very subdued and avoids anything flashy or grand, but it keeps the flow of the film nice and smooth. The dialouge also keeps with the silky smooth theme of the film, and it is delivered by some very fine actors. All the actors do a very nice job in their respective roles. The main character, Josh Waitzkin, is only seven years old and for a child actor does a decent job. He was very sophisticated for his age and didn't always feel like a kid, but maybe that was the intention of the film. He probably was a fairly detached boy, just like Bobby Fischer, and so he didn't seem like what we think of when we think seven year old boy. And yet the film also spent a lot of time focusing on Josh's balance between chess and growing up like a normal kid, so his attitude wasn't always fitting. Plus he seems like he is on depressants for the entire film. The rest of the cast is A-list and does a great job. Joe Mantegna as Josh's father does a great job as a character trying to balance out his life much in the same way Josh is balancing his. His father must balance his want for his son to be a great chess player, but he also wants his son to live a normal childhood without all of the extreme pressures of chess. Ben Kingsley and Laurence Fishburne both play mentors to Josh, but with very different personalities. Kingsley is an old retired chess master who is very by the book and rigid in his teaching. Fishburne is much more free and sees the game of chess as a much more surreal and introspective experience. The contrast between these two characters is very interesting to watch unfold. Searching for Bobby Fischer is a good film, not a great film, just a good film. It has all the necessary components that make good films. The direction is smart, the dialouge is crisp, and the acting is fantastic. From a personal standpoint this wasn't the most gripping or emotionally moving film for me, but for others I can definitely see how it would be. This film can be enjoyed a lot more than I enjoyed it because it is a good film and there are a lot of good things going for it. But as far as I'm concerned, it was one of those films that I watch, enjoy enough to feel like it was worth my two hours, but then I never watch it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Knight to C-8, Checkmate!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a true story the feature focuses upon a child chess prodigy, Josh Waitzkin. Oh, the lad does enjoy things like baseball, but as soon as he discovers his gift for chess, then it is a new beginning. We often see child masterminds in music and in art and in the sciences, including mathematics. For instance, didn't Mozart make his debut at age four? And what about Pascal, who wrote a treatise at age nine? Anyway, our seven year-old chess genius has a grasp of complicated moves that exceeds that of adults. Still, he is just a boy; he simply has not lived. In the film, we see clips of the great chess grandmaster, Bobby Fischer, who won the US Chess Championship at age 14. He could play (and win) many board games at once. He became official world champion in 1972 when he defeated Soviet champ Boris Spassky. After his victory, he appeared on a Bob Hope TV special. But after 1975 he became a recluse and practically disappeared from the planet. Fischer had controversial beliefs. For instance, he believed in a worldwide Jewish conspiracy, and favored the Palestinians over Israel. In any case, the film's title refers not to Bobby Fischer, but to a potential American successor, one who plays like him (like Josh). And hopefully not one who had lived such an abnormal life like Fischer. Josh Waitzkin, well-played by Max Pomeranc, a real chess player, was born with his gift, which he discovers at an early age. He enjoys going to Washington Park in NYC to play with the dregs and hustlers who hang out there. Note that one of the Russian players there once defeated Tal, who was world champ in 1960-61. The Washington Park folks play a fast game ("blitz"), use unorthodox moves, and intimate their opponents. Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne), a drug addict, is one of the hustlers in the park. He seems to like Josh. As he parents discover Josh's gift, they seem oblivious of what to do with it. For instance, is winning at chess the only thing in life? Eventually, Josh's sports-writer father Fred (Joe Mantegna, in a luminous performance), hires Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley) a brilliant chess-master and former national champion, to coach his son. Bruce's style, in contrast to Vinnie's, is to use the planned approach. But Bruce seems to be almost as difficult to deal with as Fischer. He says that Josh's personality is represented by the KING chess piece, and reminds Josh that "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt." Bruce wants to keep the boy away from Washington Park, which is a hindrance to his understanding of the finer points of chess even though Josh loves the place. When Bruce later tries to teach Josh the cutthroat style of chess, Josh's mother (Bonnie = Joan Allen), becomes chagrined and states, "He's decent!" (Translation = He does not hate his opponents.) When a patronizing teacher (Laura Linney) tries to belittle Josh's achievement  his string of victories  Fred indignantly proclaims, "He's better at this than I've ever been at anything in my life. He's better at this than you'll ever be at anything. My son has a gift. He has a gift, and when you acknowledge that, then maybe we will have something to talk about." There is a point where one may ask what happens when the need to win consumes all of the fun. In the course of the movie, we learn much about tournament chess, as Josh works his way to the top. We see what happens when he begins to lose interest and sustains a series of reverses before he regains his position. In the end it comes down to the two best players  Josh and Jonathan Poe  for the junior national championship. Who will win? The movie is based upon Fred Waitzkin's autobiographical book. Our feature does not focus on any one game or on individual piece moves, so that one does not need to know how to play chess to enjoy the film. Ben Kingsley, as usual, is great in his portrayal of Bruce Pandolfini, a real New York personality who teaches chess, writes columns, and has authored many books. He actually coached young Waitzkin for quite a long time. Apparently the real Pandolfini is milder and has a more easygoing style, unlike the movie's portrayal. But that's Hollywood. An error is the film was a reference to former world champion Casablanca; that grandmaster's real name was Jose Raul Capablanca (In 1921 Capablanca defeated Emanuel Lasker, who had held the world championship since 1894, when he bested Wilhelm Steinitz). Despite minor issues, the movie exudes both realism and fascination. Postscript: Josh Waitzkin became an International Master at age 16. He developed into the highest rated American chess player under age 18, and was national chess champion eight times. Waitzkin authored two books. He moved on into the martial arts field, and won championships. The youngest grandmaster in American history is now Fabiano Luigi Caruana, who was not quite 15 when he won in 2007.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close to flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robyn Nesbitt (nesfilmreviews)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Searching for Bobby Fischer" contains in its title a reminder of a time that was. Bobby Fischer was arguably the greatest chess player of all time. As a boy, he faced and defeated the greatest players of his time. In 1972, after a prelude of countless controversies, he won the world chess championship away from the Russians for the first time in years. Then he essentially disappeared and went off the deep end-- into a underworld of rented rooms, phantom sightings, and paranoid outbursts. "Searching for Bobby Fischer"-a film of remarkable sensitivity and insight, tells a story based on fact, about a "new" Bobby Fischer - a young boy named Josh Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc), who was born with a gift for chess--which he nurtured in the rough-and- tumble world of of chess hustlers in New York's Washington Square Park. His parents acknowledge his gift, but are concerned about how he can develop it without stunting the other areas of his life. After realizing what his son is capable of, Fred seeks out a chess player--a once highly regarded grand master named Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley), and hires him to tutor Josh. Bruce tries to teach his pupil a regimented, cerebral approach to the game, while Josh's mentor from the park, Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne) favors a fast paced and aggressive style used by hustlers to intimidate their opponents. Josh proves so adept at the game that Fred enters his son in a tournament. Bruce advises against this, believing that "winning and losing" has nothing to do with chess. Caught up in his son's gift and the thrill of competition, Fred pushes Josh to excel. Josh's weakness as a sportsman is his kindness, which Bonnie fears Fred will beat out of him in his efforts to make his son a winner. When he encounters another prodigy (Michael Nirenberg), who dispatches his opponents with cold-blooded efficiency. Josh has to decide for himself how important winning and losing is. The movie succeeds with the heart-warming, honest acting of the film's protagonist Max Pomeranc. Steven Zaillian, the director, made a conscious choice when he cast the film to find kids who actually could play chess. He wanted chess players first and foremost- - and who also could handle the demands of the script. His face is expressive, open - and yet strangely inscrutable when he plays chess. The criteria Zaillian demands of his protagonist ultimately defines whether this film works or not- -and Max delivers a truly natural performance. The audiences' enjoyment of this film pivots on his character-- and Pomeranc is wonderful. Zaillian's superb script attracted a fantasitc cast that includes: Joe Mantegna, Joan Allen, Ben Kingsley, and Laurence Fishburne. Supported in minor roes by David Paymer, William H. Macy, Tony Shalhoub, Dan Hedaya, Laura Linney, and Austin Pendleton. Of all those Renowned cinematographer Conrad Hall referred to the film in what he called "magical naturalism" - conveying a child's sense of imagination - while James Horner's music reflects that spirit with equal mastery. "Searching for Bobby Fischer" is an intensely fascinating movie capable of involving those who are not familiar about chess, as well as those who love it. Steven Zaillian effectively integrates the actual story and footage of Bobby Fischer throughout the film--running parallel to Josh's story, only enhancing the fascinating storyline. The focus of the film is less on the actual game than it is on the people, emotions, and pressures surrounding Josh. It is a tale of the human spirit and triumph. By the end of "Searching for Bobby Fischer", we have gained insight about the intensity and competitiveness nature of chess tournaments, and a great deal about human nature. The film's implications are many. Think of it as a very smart sports film that substitutes quiet intensity for physical action. There's no denying "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is one film in which every major element - writing, directing, casting, photography, music - is perfectly in tune, exploring the nature of competition with humor, intelligence, and depth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Winning's Not The Only Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bill Slocum (bill.slocum@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "You've got to go to the edge of defeat," one player tells another in the second half of "Searching For Bobby Fischer." That seemed to be the guiding strategy behind the movie as well. Writer-director Steven Zaillian takes an unfilmable subject (chess), bases it on a book few read, names it after a guy nobody had seen in 20 years, and puts it all in the lap of an eight-year-old actor who never starred in a film before and would star in only one after. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" does all it can to stack the board against itself, yet succeeds quite well despite, and indeed, because of all that. Joshua Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc) is celebrating his seventh birthday in Washington Square Park when he catches sight of some rough-looking characters moving what look like his Lego figures on tables of black-and-white squares. Chess is a game few master, yet Josh learns it just from watching them. Soon he is amazing parents and wizened grandmasters alike with his skill at the game, but is Josh really a prodigy on the scale of Bobby Fischer, the New York youngster who went on to win the world championship - then disappear? "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is a fairly formulaic film in many ways. It presents us with stock situations like an adorable boy who only wants to be good; a father (Joe Mantegna) who is too concerned with winning; a mother (Joan Allen) afraid her son is being turned into a machine; and a streetwise black man (Laurence Fishburne) who sees things in the child before anyone else. There's even a villain who appears shrouded in darkness, and who glares at Josh so menacingly its easy to forget this dark figure isn't quite four feet tall. But the formula really works in this one, in part because it serves such a strange cause (how many other chess movies can you think of?) and mostly because of Pomeranc's unaffected work in the lead role. Pomeranc seems preternaturally aware of his fragility on camera and plays to it in ways that reflect not precociousness but depth. You just feel for the guy, exult with his triumphs and feel his disappointments so much you resent Mantegna when his character rides Josh about doing better. Pomeranc also does great ensemble work with the other characters, especially Ben Kingsley as Josh's instructor Bruce, a fellow who seems to have been somebody's idea of Josh a generation ago only for it to collapse on him. Bruce doesn't want Josh to show mercy, you sense because he blames his own softness for his post-child ruination. "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt," he tells Josh. "I'm not him," Josh replies. That's the whole movie right there. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" feels incomplete in parts. Maybe it's just zen-like in its comfort with koan-like plot holes. We never get a real chance to see Josh learning much with Vinnie, the Fishburne character, in a way that would better explain their later closeness. Mantagna's transformation into hard-driving parent (he has a funny but nasty scene with a teacher played by Laura Linney, one of many future talents on display here) isn't laid out convincingly. But thanks both to Zaillian's affecting script and superlative camera work by the incomparable Conrad Hall working close to his zenith, you sense many things lying just beneath the surface of your view, there to be pondered when the rush of the film dissipates. And what a rush! Josh learns that winning isn't everything, but he also comes to care enough to give it his best shot in a climax both thrilling and heartwarming, even if it plays a bit to conventions. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" suggests something redemptive and perhaps even romantic in a game it dares to compare to art. In the process, it winds up presenting us with art both in theory and in practice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Family movie disguised as chess movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmoujik
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're a chess player, you should know: I saw that there were some goofs regarding chess in this movie, but I didn't know that NONE OF THE CHESS RELATED SEQUENCES MADE SENSE. What's the point of making such a movie? How hard is it to get a chess adviser for the editing process. It doesn't have to be a GM. Any decent player would suffice. You could just go a block from the Washington sq. to a chess caf&eacute; and find someone who'd have time to help not to make this movie an embarrassment. Only good parts were documentary ones showing Bobby Fischer, and I would recommend to see "Bobby Fischer against the world" for a chess cinematic fix. Otherwise this family movie is pretty banal, and I wish, someone had written this review before I considered spending time watching this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought-provoking gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Troye Dchgl
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a parent, how do you strike a balance between supporting your children and pushing your children too hard? As a teacher, what is the "correct" way to teach your pupils? There is no certain answer. But the film has the ability of making you think while delivering an exciting plot. Searching for Bobby Fischer is truly an inspiration. It is a reflection for parents to rethink how they should raise their kids, and how to give them the right message to pursue their interests. The film also shows there is no single "correct" way of teaching. A child should learn from all aspects, from different people and via different methods. "Maybe it's better not to be the best. Then you can lose and it's OK." Josh gives us a peek of the pressure of all the constant winners - it is hard for an all-time winner to lose, and sometimes you would rather be "not the best" so you can actually lose without feeling too bad. The only advisable solution is probably to give yourself less pressure when it comes to competitions by loving the game rather than forcing yourself to win. After all, it is just a game in which you are supposed to seek interest, and you should be enjoying the moment. This is highly recommended for all ages. Beautifully written is the script. There is nothing to criticize on the acting. The background music throughout the movie is highly enjoyable and appropriate. The simplicity of the movie is also great. For kids, this is a great adventure about a unknown chess prodigy becoming a champion. For grown-ups, this is also a story that gives something to learn and something to think about. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the kind of movie that can stand the test of time. Although it was made almost 20 years ago, I don't feel a bit of antiquatedness at all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This goes beyond chess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cstotlar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a pianist and classical performer, I've seen a great number of young prodigies in the field of musical performance. The large majority of them never make it past adolescence. In many cases, some of them didn't get beyond the point of doing something quite well at a very early age and were dismissed when the age factor no longer applied. This said, the parents pushed so many of them mercilessly - and rather unashamedly. The kids wanted to please their parents and the parents wanted to please themselves. It's as simple and as tragic as that and it goes on everywhere, with sports near the top, for example. The film then came as no particular surprise. It could be a valuable wake-up call to overly ambitious parents who haven't noticed who their kids ARE rather than what they can do. In this respect the film was spot on and quite frank and sincere. It went on for too long. There were too many "re-wordings" throughout which made the effort seem pedantic at times. The actors, too often shown in semi-obscurity, did their parts beautifully and I would agree with another reviewer who found the wife's contribution essential and beautifully underplayed. The game of chess doesn't have much attraction for those who don't know the game and the director and writer kept this firmly in mind by speeding up the rounds and focusing on the facial expressions. The film could definitely be "tightened up" and pared down a bit. Curtis Stotlar
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice movie for all, but great for chess fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film itself is not as great as the story behind it. Frankly, the plot is the typical American sports movie with the good hearted champion that has both talent and decency and that works hard for his art. I guess it would have been worse if it wasn't based on the book written by Josh Waitzkin's father. Josh Waitzkin has a fascinating story that I recommend you read on. He was the highest rated chess player in the US since he was 8 years old, then his father wrote the book that this movie is based on, then all the sudden celebrity messed with his chess game. Instead of clinging to chess, Josh decides to stop playing, and takes up Ju-Jitsu. He does great at it as well. His book, The Art of Learning, describes the process. Josh Waitzkin is also the guy from the "Waitzkin Academy" tutorial in the ChessMaster XI chess game. But back to the film. At the time, Josh was the next Bobby Fischer, only nicer. Everybody loved a true American hero, especially in a game that was dominated by Russians. The Art of Learning was not out yet, so the people that made the movie saw no problem in portraying the boy as a chess prodigy that did not lose to anyone unless he chose to. In reality, the wonder of Josh Waitzkin is that he really was brilliant and even as a kid he realised that losing is the true teacher. Losing in a finals of a championship defined his life, as he saw the true value of humility and confidence. Having all that information in the background had me see the movie with completely different eyes and I rather liked it. I wish it was more technical, but then no one would watch it except a few Russians, so... Funny trivia: three chess players depicted in the movie were the real people: Kamran Shirazi, Joel Benjamin and Roman DzinDziChashvili, while a girl identified as "82nd girl", which means one of Josh's opponents in the game who ranked the 82nd, is Katya Waitzkin, Josh's real life sister. Bottom line: it has some valuable lessons in there, but hidden in the usual Hollywood bull. It is nice to watch and has a lot more meaning to chess players than people not playing. I liked it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Just for Chess Geeks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Benik
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when it first came out, and I was in my mid-twenties and just getting started in the world. I saw it then as a movie about chess, and what young chess prodigies go through in order to reach the top levels. I saw it again last night, eighteen years later. The movie is the same, but I am different. I am about the age of Josh Waitzkin's father, and I have a daughter who is the same age as Josh. And although my daughter is not a prodigy of chess or anything else, I can see a lot of her in Josh, and a lot of me in his father. This is actually not a film about chess; it is a film about raising children. We live in the Dallas suburbs, where there are a lot of families and a lot of activities for children. I see parents take their children to soccer games, gymnastics camps and acting classes, and I see the obsession in their eyes. They want to expose their kids to many different pursuits, but once they see a talent forming, they focus on only that pursuit, to the exclusion of all others. They sink their money, their time, and all of their child's energy into developing that talent, at the expense of all other interests. Maybe it is pressure to earn a scholarship. Maybe it is the availability of year-round seasons and elite leagues. Maybe it is the unbelievable salaries that top athletes are earning. But I think that the problem that this movie points out -- that pushing kids to be the best at something at any cost -- has gotten worse instead of better. This movie could just as easily been about gymnastics or golf or music as it is about chess. The issues raised are the same. I just hope that more parents can see this film, and recognize that if our goal is raise happy, balanced people, pushing our kids to become elite performers is not the way to get there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern Classic with life lessons, engaging history, great story telling.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-2829
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much more than a movie about chess, this movie deals with childhood geniuses, the difficult choices of parents in how far to push their "prodigy" and the challenge of finding balance in a life filled with difficult choices. I have watched this movie a few times now, and have gleaned different things from it depending on where I am in my own life. This time around had new meaning as I have a child very gifted with piano. I've had similar challenges to Josh Waitzkin's parents in trying to decide how much to push your children - and for what purposes. Most parents probably feel that pull, even without "geniuses" - finding balance in what kids CAN do, what they SHOULD do, and what they WANT to do. We want our children to be happy, but we also know that part of being happy is doing something they are good at and helping them find meaning. I'm also a fan of chess and so really enjoy the glimpses into the chess world this movie portrays. The brilliance of those who stand even above the best minds in their field is the stuff of legends. Bobby Fischer, Garry Kasparov, Anatoly Karpov, Emmanuel Lasker... every bit leaders in their elite worlds as the likes of say Michael Jordan, Mike Tyson, Tiger Woods. Always interesting to me. Great performances all around, from the young (and skinny) Laurence Fishburne to the always stately Ben Kingsley. From the interested and caring parents to the young Josh Waitzskin... even the "enemy" chess player are all well cast and enjoyable throughout the movie. A modern classic in my opinion, and great for the whole family (probably at least 7 or 8 years old is a good lower limit). I appreciate the lessons it teaches, the story of Josh and the truths we discover.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you know anything about chess, or even if you don't, chances are you've heard the name Bobby Fischer. He was the most renowned and most skilled chess master who ever lived. His level of expertise at the game of chess could be matched by no one but himself. He was a legend to that world, but only revered because of his ability at chess. Apart from that he was a detached and solitary individual who obviously had some sort of mental deficiency that kept him from connecting with the real world. Thus his world was all chess. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the story of Josh Waitzkin, another chess master who was discovered long after Bobby Fischer. Josh unexpectedly discovers that he has a unique gift in playing chess and so the pressure from all different people sets in for him to become the best. The title of the film is Searching for Bobby Fischer, but in the context of the film the title literally means searching for the next Bobby Fischer. These pressures and goals Josh must face send us through an interesting, yet very subdued story. Searching for Bobby Fischer is very slow, but appropriately slow. Not a ton actually happens in the film as it is much more character driven. There are a lot of different characters in the film that each drive different plot lines. The film takes a while to get going because of the different characters that have be introduced, and are introduced very slowly and drawn out. Because of this early character development, there's a lot of build up necessary before the first actual conflicts of the film arise. It is almost an hour into the film before we get to see these conflicts start to take shape and affect the storyline. You have to stick with this film to get the full effect of it, which is worth it in the end. I can also commend the story for being very focused but also broad. The stories obviously centers around chess, but as it goes along it becomes more about Josh's relationships with the various people in his life, more so than anything else. The main theme of the film eventually molds into character relationships, as each character seems to have a clear cut relation with the others in order to fully flesh them all out and make them interesting. The storyline works in such a way that it is easy for it to elicit emotional responses out of its audience, so because of this I felt a little less drawn in. I didn't feel much emotion throughout the film and most of the time I just had to take it for what it was. Speaking from a personal standpoint, it isn't the most fascinating kind of story for me, but it doesn't mean it wasn't a well made film. It is very high quality with all the necessary aspects to make it a notable film. The direction is very subdued and avoids anything flashy or grand, but it keeps the flow of the film nice and smooth. The dialouge also keeps with the silky smooth theme of the film, and it is delivered by some very fine actors. All the actors do a very nice job in their respective roles. The main character, Josh Waitzkin, is only seven years old and for a child actor does a decent job. He was very sophisticated for his age and didn't always feel like a kid, but maybe that was the intention of the film. He probably was a fairly detached boy, just like Bobby Fischer, and so he didn't seem like what we think of when we think seven year old boy. And yet the film also spent a lot of time focusing on Josh's balance between chess and growing up like a normal kid, so his attitude wasn't always fitting. Plus he seems like he is on depressants for the entire film. The rest of the cast is A-list and does a great job. Joe Mantegna as Josh's father does a great job as a character trying to balance out his life much in the same way Josh is balancing his. His father must balance his want for his son to be a great chess player, but he also wants his son to live a normal childhood without all of the extreme pressures of chess. Ben Kingsley and Laurence Fishburne both play mentors to Josh, but with very different personalities. Kingsley is an old retired chess master who is very by the book and rigid in his teaching. Fishburne is much more free and sees the game of chess as a much more surreal and introspective experience. The contrast between these two characters is very interesting to watch unfold. Searching for Bobby Fischer is a good film, not a great film, just a good film. It has all the necessary components that make good films. The direction is smart, the dialouge is crisp, and the acting is fantastic. From a personal standpoint this wasn't the most gripping or emotionally moving film for me, but for others I can definitely see how it would be. This film can be enjoyed a lot more than I enjoyed it because it is a good film and there are a lot of good things going for it. But as far as I'm concerned, it was one of those films that I watch, enjoy enough to feel like it was worth my two hours, but then I never watch it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Knight to C-8, Checkmate!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a true story the feature focuses upon a child chess prodigy, Josh Waitzkin. Oh, the lad does enjoy things like baseball, but as soon as he discovers his gift for chess, then it is a new beginning. We often see child masterminds in music and in art and in the sciences, including mathematics. For instance, didn't Mozart make his debut at age four? And what about Pascal, who wrote a treatise at age nine? Anyway, our seven year-old chess genius has a grasp of complicated moves that exceeds that of adults. Still, he is just a boy; he simply has not lived. In the film, we see clips of the great chess grandmaster, Bobby Fischer, who won the US Chess Championship at age 14. He could play (and win) many board games at once. He became official world champion in 1972 when he defeated Soviet champ Boris Spassky. After his victory, he appeared on a Bob Hope TV special. But after 1975 he became a recluse and practically disappeared from the planet. Fischer had controversial beliefs. For instance, he believed in a worldwide Jewish conspiracy, and favored the Palestinians over Israel. In any case, the film's title refers not to Bobby Fischer, but to a potential American successor, one who plays like him (like Josh). And hopefully not one who had lived such an abnormal life like Fischer. Josh Waitzkin, well-played by Max Pomeranc, a real chess player, was born with his gift, which he discovers at an early age. He enjoys going to Washington Park in NYC to play with the dregs and hustlers who hang out there. Note that one of the Russian players there once defeated Tal, who was world champ in 1960-61. The Washington Park folks play a fast game ("blitz"), use unorthodox moves, and intimate their opponents. Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne), a drug addict, is one of the hustlers in the park. He seems to like Josh. As he parents discover Josh's gift, they seem oblivious of what to do with it. For instance, is winning at chess the only thing in life? Eventually, Josh's sports-writer father Fred (Joe Mantegna, in a luminous performance), hires Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley) a brilliant chess-master and former national champion, to coach his son. Bruce's style, in contrast to Vinnie's, is to use the planned approach. But Bruce seems to be almost as difficult to deal with as Fischer. He says that Josh's personality is represented by the KING chess piece, and reminds Josh that "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt." Bruce wants to keep the boy away from Washington Park, which is a hindrance to his understanding of the finer points of chess even though Josh loves the place. When Bruce later tries to teach Josh the cutthroat style of chess, Josh's mother (Bonnie = Joan Allen), becomes chagrined and states, "He's decent!" (Translation = He does not hate his opponents.) When a patronizing teacher (Laura Linney) tries to belittle Josh's achievement  his string of victories  Fred indignantly proclaims, "He's better at this than I've ever been at anything in my life. He's better at this than you'll ever be at anything. My son has a gift. He has a gift, and when you acknowledge that, then maybe we will have something to talk about." There is a point where one may ask what happens when the need to win consumes all of the fun. In the course of the movie, we learn much about tournament chess, as Josh works his way to the top. We see what happens when he begins to lose interest and sustains a series of reverses before he regains his position. In the end it comes down to the two best players  Josh and Jonathan Poe  for the junior national championship. Who will win? The movie is based upon Fred Waitzkin's autobiographical book. Our feature does not focus on any one game or on individual piece moves, so that one does not need to know how to play chess to enjoy the film. Ben Kingsley, as usual, is great in his portrayal of Bruce Pandolfini, a real New York personality who teaches chess, writes columns, and has authored many books. He actually coached young Waitzkin for quite a long time. Apparently the real Pandolfini is milder and has a more easygoing style, unlike the movie's portrayal. But that's Hollywood. An error is the film was a reference to former world champion Casablanca; that grandmaster's real name was Jose Raul Capablanca (In 1921 Capablanca defeated Emanuel Lasker, who had held the world championship since 1894, when he bested Wilhelm Steinitz). Despite minor issues, the movie exudes both realism and fascination. Postscript: Josh Waitzkin became an International Master at age 16. He developed into the highest rated American chess player under age 18, and was national chess champion eight times. Waitzkin authored two books. He moved on into the martial arts field, and won championships. The youngest grandmaster in American history is now Fabiano Luigi Caruana, who was not quite 15 when he won in 2007.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close to flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robyn Nesbitt (nesfilmreviews)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Searching for Bobby Fischer" contains in its title a reminder of a time that was. Bobby Fischer was arguably the greatest chess player of all time. As a boy, he faced and defeated the greatest players of his time. In 1972, after a prelude of countless controversies, he won the world chess championship away from the Russians for the first time in years. Then he essentially disappeared and went off the deep end-- into a underworld of rented rooms, phantom sightings, and paranoid outbursts. "Searching for Bobby Fischer"-a film of remarkable sensitivity and insight, tells a story based on fact, about a "new" Bobby Fischer - a young boy named Josh Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc), who was born with a gift for chess--which he nurtured in the rough-and- tumble world of of chess hustlers in New York's Washington Square Park. His parents acknowledge his gift, but are concerned about how he can develop it without stunting the other areas of his life. After realizing what his son is capable of, Fred seeks out a chess player--a once highly regarded grand master named Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley), and hires him to tutor Josh. Bruce tries to teach his pupil a regimented, cerebral approach to the game, while Josh's mentor from the park, Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne) favors a fast paced and aggressive style used by hustlers to intimidate their opponents. Josh proves so adept at the game that Fred enters his son in a tournament. Bruce advises against this, believing that "winning and losing" has nothing to do with chess. Caught up in his son's gift and the thrill of competition, Fred pushes Josh to excel. Josh's weakness as a sportsman is his kindness, which Bonnie fears Fred will beat out of him in his efforts to make his son a winner. When he encounters another prodigy (Michael Nirenberg), who dispatches his opponents with cold-blooded efficiency. Josh has to decide for himself how important winning and losing is. The movie succeeds with the heart-warming, honest acting of the film's protagonist Max Pomeranc. Steven Zaillian, the director, made a conscious choice when he cast the film to find kids who actually could play chess. He wanted chess players first and foremost- - and who also could handle the demands of the script. His face is expressive, open - and yet strangely inscrutable when he plays chess. The criteria Zaillian demands of his protagonist ultimately defines whether this film works or not- -and Max delivers a truly natural performance. The audiences' enjoyment of this film pivots on his character-- and Pomeranc is wonderful. Zaillian's superb script attracted a fantasitc cast that includes: Joe Mantegna, Joan Allen, Ben Kingsley, and Laurence Fishburne. Supported in minor roes by David Paymer, William H. Macy, Tony Shalhoub, Dan Hedaya, Laura Linney, and Austin Pendleton. Of all those Renowned cinematographer Conrad Hall referred to the film in what he called "magical naturalism" - conveying a child's sense of imagination - while James Horner's music reflects that spirit with equal mastery. "Searching for Bobby Fischer" is an intensely fascinating movie capable of involving those who are not familiar about chess, as well as those who love it. Steven Zaillian effectively integrates the actual story and footage of Bobby Fischer throughout the film--running parallel to Josh's story, only enhancing the fascinating storyline. The focus of the film is less on the actual game than it is on the people, emotions, and pressures surrounding Josh. It is a tale of the human spirit and triumph. By the end of "Searching for Bobby Fischer", we have gained insight about the intensity and competitiveness nature of chess tournaments, and a great deal about human nature. The film's implications are many. Think of it as a very smart sports film that substitutes quiet intensity for physical action. There's no denying "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is one film in which every major element - writing, directing, casting, photography, music - is perfectly in tune, exploring the nature of competition with humor, intelligence, and depth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Winning's Not The Only Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bill Slocum (bill.slocum@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "You've got to go to the edge of defeat," one player tells another in the second half of "Searching For Bobby Fischer." That seemed to be the guiding strategy behind the movie as well. Writer-director Steven Zaillian takes an unfilmable subject (chess), bases it on a book few read, names it after a guy nobody had seen in 20 years, and puts it all in the lap of an eight-year-old actor who never starred in a film before and would star in only one after. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" does all it can to stack the board against itself, yet succeeds quite well despite, and indeed, because of all that. Joshua Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc) is celebrating his seventh birthday in Washington Square Park when he catches sight of some rough-looking characters moving what look like his Lego figures on tables of black-and-white squares. Chess is a game few master, yet Josh learns it just from watching them. Soon he is amazing parents and wizened grandmasters alike with his skill at the game, but is Josh really a prodigy on the scale of Bobby Fischer, the New York youngster who went on to win the world championship - then disappear? "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is a fairly formulaic film in many ways. It presents us with stock situations like an adorable boy who only wants to be good; a father (Joe Mantegna) who is too concerned with winning; a mother (Joan Allen) afraid her son is being turned into a machine; and a streetwise black man (Laurence Fishburne) who sees things in the child before anyone else. There's even a villain who appears shrouded in darkness, and who glares at Josh so menacingly its easy to forget this dark figure isn't quite four feet tall. But the formula really works in this one, in part because it serves such a strange cause (how many other chess movies can you think of?) and mostly because of Pomeranc's unaffected work in the lead role. Pomeranc seems preternaturally aware of his fragility on camera and plays to it in ways that reflect not precociousness but depth. You just feel for the guy, exult with his triumphs and feel his disappointments so much you resent Mantegna when his character rides Josh about doing better. Pomeranc also does great ensemble work with the other characters, especially Ben Kingsley as Josh's instructor Bruce, a fellow who seems to have been somebody's idea of Josh a generation ago only for it to collapse on him. Bruce doesn't want Josh to show mercy, you sense because he blames his own softness for his post-child ruination. "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt," he tells Josh. "I'm not him," Josh replies. That's the whole movie right there. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" feels incomplete in parts. Maybe it's just zen-like in its comfort with koan-like plot holes. We never get a real chance to see Josh learning much with Vinnie, the Fishburne character, in a way that would better explain their later closeness. Mantagna's transformation into hard-driving parent (he has a funny but nasty scene with a teacher played by Laura Linney, one of many future talents on display here) isn't laid out convincingly. But thanks both to Zaillian's affecting script and superlative camera work by the incomparable Conrad Hall working close to his zenith, you sense many things lying just beneath the surface of your view, there to be pondered when the rush of the film dissipates. And what a rush! Josh learns that winning isn't everything, but he also comes to care enough to give it his best shot in a climax both thrilling and heartwarming, even if it plays a bit to conventions. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" suggests something redemptive and perhaps even romantic in a game it dares to compare to art. In the process, it winds up presenting us with art both in theory and in practice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Family movie disguised as chess movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmoujik
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're a chess player, you should know: I saw that there were some goofs regarding chess in this movie, but I didn't know that NONE OF THE CHESS RELATED SEQUENCES MADE SENSE. What's the point of making such a movie? How hard is it to get a chess adviser for the editing process. It doesn't have to be a GM. Any decent player would suffice. You could just go a block from the Washington sq. to a chess caf&eacute; and find someone who'd have time to help not to make this movie an embarrassment. Only good parts were documentary ones showing Bobby Fischer, and I would recommend to see "Bobby Fischer against the world" for a chess cinematic fix. Otherwise this family movie is pretty banal, and I wish, someone had written this review before I considered spending time watching this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought-provoking gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Troye Dchgl
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a parent, how do you strike a balance between supporting your children and pushing your children too hard? As a teacher, what is the "correct" way to teach your pupils? There is no certain answer. But the film has the ability of making you think while delivering an exciting plot. Searching for Bobby Fischer is truly an inspiration. It is a reflection for parents to rethink how they should raise their kids, and how to give them the right message to pursue their interests. The film also shows there is no single "correct" way of teaching. A child should learn from all aspects, from different people and via different methods. "Maybe it's better not to be the best. Then you can lose and it's OK." Josh gives us a peek of the pressure of all the constant winners - it is hard for an all-time winner to lose, and sometimes you would rather be "not the best" so you can actually lose without feeling too bad. The only advisable solution is probably to give yourself less pressure when it comes to competitions by loving the game rather than forcing yourself to win. After all, it is just a game in which you are supposed to seek interest, and you should be enjoying the moment. This is highly recommended for all ages. Beautifully written is the script. There is nothing to criticize on the acting. The background music throughout the movie is highly enjoyable and appropriate. The simplicity of the movie is also great. For kids, this is a great adventure about a unknown chess prodigy becoming a champion. For grown-ups, this is also a story that gives something to learn and something to think about. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the kind of movie that can stand the test of time. Although it was made almost 20 years ago, I don't feel a bit of antiquatedness at all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This goes beyond chess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cstotlar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a pianist and classical performer, I've seen a great number of young prodigies in the field of musical performance. The large majority of them never make it past adolescence. In many cases, some of them didn't get beyond the point of doing something quite well at a very early age and were dismissed when the age factor no longer applied. This said, the parents pushed so many of them mercilessly - and rather unashamedly. The kids wanted to please their parents and the parents wanted to please themselves. It's as simple and as tragic as that and it goes on everywhere, with sports near the top, for example. The film then came as no particular surprise. It could be a valuable wake-up call to overly ambitious parents who haven't noticed who their kids ARE rather than what they can do. In this respect the film was spot on and quite frank and sincere. It went on for too long. There were too many "re-wordings" throughout which made the effort seem pedantic at times. The actors, too often shown in semi-obscurity, did their parts beautifully and I would agree with another reviewer who found the wife's contribution essential and beautifully underplayed. The game of chess doesn't have much attraction for those who don't know the game and the director and writer kept this firmly in mind by speeding up the rounds and focusing on the facial expressions. The film could definitely be "tightened up" and pared down a bit. Curtis Stotlar
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice movie for all, but great for chess fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film itself is not as great as the story behind it. Frankly, the plot is the typical American sports movie with the good hearted champion that has both talent and decency and that works hard for his art. I guess it would have been worse if it wasn't based on the book written by Josh Waitzkin's father. Josh Waitzkin has a fascinating story that I recommend you read on. He was the highest rated chess player in the US since he was 8 years old, then his father wrote the book that this movie is based on, then all the sudden celebrity messed with his chess game. Instead of clinging to chess, Josh decides to stop playing, and takes up Ju-Jitsu. He does great at it as well. His book, The Art of Learning, describes the process. Josh Waitzkin is also the guy from the "Waitzkin Academy" tutorial in the ChessMaster XI chess game. But back to the film. At the time, Josh was the next Bobby Fischer, only nicer. Everybody loved a true American hero, especially in a game that was dominated by Russians. The Art of Learning was not out yet, so the people that made the movie saw no problem in portraying the boy as a chess prodigy that did not lose to anyone unless he chose to. In reality, the wonder of Josh Waitzkin is that he really was brilliant and even as a kid he realised that losing is the true teacher. Losing in a finals of a championship defined his life, as he saw the true value of humility and confidence. Having all that information in the background had me see the movie with completely different eyes and I rather liked it. I wish it was more technical, but then no one would watch it except a few Russians, so... Funny trivia: three chess players depicted in the movie were the real people: Kamran Shirazi, Joel Benjamin and Roman DzinDziChashvili, while a girl identified as "82nd girl", which means one of Josh's opponents in the game who ranked the 82nd, is Katya Waitzkin, Josh's real life sister. Bottom line: it has some valuable lessons in there, but hidden in the usual Hollywood bull. It is nice to watch and has a lot more meaning to chess players than people not playing. I liked it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Just for Chess Geeks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Benik
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when it first came out, and I was in my mid-twenties and just getting started in the world. I saw it then as a movie about chess, and what young chess prodigies go through in order to reach the top levels. I saw it again last night, eighteen years later. The movie is the same, but I am different. I am about the age of Josh Waitzkin's father, and I have a daughter who is the same age as Josh. And although my daughter is not a prodigy of chess or anything else, I can see a lot of her in Josh, and a lot of me in his father. This is actually not a film about chess; it is a film about raising children. We live in the Dallas suburbs, where there are a lot of families and a lot of activities for children. I see parents take their children to soccer games, gymnastics camps and acting classes, and I see the obsession in their eyes. They want to expose their kids to many different pursuits, but once they see a talent forming, they focus on only that pursuit, to the exclusion of all others. They sink their money, their time, and all of their child's energy into developing that talent, at the expense of all other interests. Maybe it is pressure to earn a scholarship. Maybe it is the availability of year-round seasons and elite leagues. Maybe it is the unbelievable salaries that top athletes are earning. But I think that the problem that this movie points out -- that pushing kids to be the best at something at any cost -- has gotten worse instead of better. This movie could just as easily been about gymnastics or golf or music as it is about chess. The issues raised are the same. I just hope that more parents can see this film, and recognize that if our goal is raise happy, balanced people, pushing our kids to become elite performers is not the way to get there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern Classic with life lessons, engaging history, great story telling.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-2829
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much more than a movie about chess, this movie deals with childhood geniuses, the difficult choices of parents in how far to push their "prodigy" and the challenge of finding balance in a life filled with difficult choices. I have watched this movie a few times now, and have gleaned different things from it depending on where I am in my own life. This time around had new meaning as I have a child very gifted with piano. I've had similar challenges to Josh Waitzkin's parents in trying to decide how much to push your children - and for what purposes. Most parents probably feel that pull, even without "geniuses" - finding balance in what kids CAN do, what they SHOULD do, and what they WANT to do. We want our children to be happy, but we also know that part of being happy is doing something they are good at and helping them find meaning. I'm also a fan of chess and so really enjoy the glimpses into the chess world this movie portrays. The brilliance of those who stand even above the best minds in their field is the stuff of legends. Bobby Fischer, Garry Kasparov, Anatoly Karpov, Emmanuel Lasker... every bit leaders in their elite worlds as the likes of say Michael Jordan, Mike Tyson, Tiger Woods. Always interesting to me. Great performances all around, from the young (and skinny) Laurence Fishburne to the always stately Ben Kingsley. From the interested and caring parents to the young Josh Waitzskin... even the "enemy" chess player are all well cast and enjoyable throughout the movie. A modern classic in my opinion, and great for the whole family (probably at least 7 or 8 years old is a good lower limit). I appreciate the lessons it teaches, the story of Josh and the truths we discover.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you know anything about chess, or even if you don't, chances are you've heard the name Bobby Fischer. He was the most renowned and most skilled chess master who ever lived. His level of expertise at the game of chess could be matched by no one but himself. He was a legend to that world, but only revered because of his ability at chess. Apart from that he was a detached and solitary individual who obviously had some sort of mental deficiency that kept him from connecting with the real world. Thus his world was all chess. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the story of Josh Waitzkin, another chess master who was discovered long after Bobby Fischer. Josh unexpectedly discovers that he has a unique gift in playing chess and so the pressure from all different people sets in for him to become the best. The title of the film is Searching for Bobby Fischer, but in the context of the film the title literally means searching for the next Bobby Fischer. These pressures and goals Josh must face send us through an interesting, yet very subdued story. Searching for Bobby Fischer is very slow, but appropriately slow. Not a ton actually happens in the film as it is much more character driven. There are a lot of different characters in the film that each drive different plot lines. The film takes a while to get going because of the different characters that have be introduced, and are introduced very slowly and drawn out. Because of this early character development, there's a lot of build up necessary before the first actual conflicts of the film arise. It is almost an hour into the film before we get to see these conflicts start to take shape and affect the storyline. You have to stick with this film to get the full effect of it, which is worth it in the end. I can also commend the story for being very focused but also broad. The stories obviously centers around chess, but as it goes along it becomes more about Josh's relationships with the various people in his life, more so than anything else. The main theme of the film eventually molds into character relationships, as each character seems to have a clear cut relation with the others in order to fully flesh them all out and make them interesting. The storyline works in such a way that it is easy for it to elicit emotional responses out of its audience, so because of this I felt a little less drawn in. I didn't feel much emotion throughout the film and most of the time I just had to take it for what it was. Speaking from a personal standpoint, it isn't the most fascinating kind of story for me, but it doesn't mean it wasn't a well made film. It is very high quality with all the necessary aspects to make it a notable film. The direction is very subdued and avoids anything flashy or grand, but it keeps the flow of the film nice and smooth. The dialouge also keeps with the silky smooth theme of the film, and it is delivered by some very fine actors. All the actors do a very nice job in their respective roles. The main character, Josh Waitzkin, is only seven years old and for a child actor does a decent job. He was very sophisticated for his age and didn't always feel like a kid, but maybe that was the intention of the film. He probably was a fairly detached boy, just like Bobby Fischer, and so he didn't seem like what we think of when we think seven year old boy. And yet the film also spent a lot of time focusing on Josh's balance between chess and growing up like a normal kid, so his attitude wasn't always fitting. Plus he seems like he is on depressants for the entire film. The rest of the cast is A-list and does a great job. Joe Mantegna as Josh's father does a great job as a character trying to balance out his life much in the same way Josh is balancing his. His father must balance his want for his son to be a great chess player, but he also wants his son to live a normal childhood without all of the extreme pressures of chess. Ben Kingsley and Laurence Fishburne both play mentors to Josh, but with very different personalities. Kingsley is an old retired chess master who is very by the book and rigid in his teaching. Fishburne is much more free and sees the game of chess as a much more surreal and introspective experience. The contrast between these two characters is very interesting to watch unfold. Searching for Bobby Fischer is a good film, not a great film, just a good film. It has all the necessary components that make good films. The direction is smart, the dialouge is crisp, and the acting is fantastic. From a personal standpoint this wasn't the most gripping or emotionally moving film for me, but for others I can definitely see how it would be. This film can be enjoyed a lot more than I enjoyed it because it is a good film and there are a lot of good things going for it. But as far as I'm concerned, it was one of those films that I watch, enjoy enough to feel like it was worth my two hours, but then I never watch it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Knight to C-8, Checkmate!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a true story the feature focuses upon a child chess prodigy, Josh Waitzkin. Oh, the lad does enjoy things like baseball, but as soon as he discovers his gift for chess, then it is a new beginning. We often see child masterminds in music and in art and in the sciences, including mathematics. For instance, didn't Mozart make his debut at age four? And what about Pascal, who wrote a treatise at age nine? Anyway, our seven year-old chess genius has a grasp of complicated moves that exceeds that of adults. Still, he is just a boy; he simply has not lived. In the film, we see clips of the great chess grandmaster, Bobby Fischer, who won the US Chess Championship at age 14. He could play (and win) many board games at once. He became official world champion in 1972 when he defeated Soviet champ Boris Spassky. After his victory, he appeared on a Bob Hope TV special. But after 1975 he became a recluse and practically disappeared from the planet. Fischer had controversial beliefs. For instance, he believed in a worldwide Jewish conspiracy, and favored the Palestinians over Israel. In any case, the film's title refers not to Bobby Fischer, but to a potential American successor, one who plays like him (like Josh). And hopefully not one who had lived such an abnormal life like Fischer. Josh Waitzkin, well-played by Max Pomeranc, a real chess player, was born with his gift, which he discovers at an early age. He enjoys going to Washington Park in NYC to play with the dregs and hustlers who hang out there. Note that one of the Russian players there once defeated Tal, who was world champ in 1960-61. The Washington Park folks play a fast game ("blitz"), use unorthodox moves, and intimate their opponents. Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne), a drug addict, is one of the hustlers in the park. He seems to like Josh. As he parents discover Josh's gift, they seem oblivious of what to do with it. For instance, is winning at chess the only thing in life? Eventually, Josh's sports-writer father Fred (Joe Mantegna, in a luminous performance), hires Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley) a brilliant chess-master and former national champion, to coach his son. Bruce's style, in contrast to Vinnie's, is to use the planned approach. But Bruce seems to be almost as difficult to deal with as Fischer. He says that Josh's personality is represented by the KING chess piece, and reminds Josh that "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt." Bruce wants to keep the boy away from Washington Park, which is a hindrance to his understanding of the finer points of chess even though Josh loves the place. When Bruce later tries to teach Josh the cutthroat style of chess, Josh's mother (Bonnie = Joan Allen), becomes chagrined and states, "He's decent!" (Translation = He does not hate his opponents.) When a patronizing teacher (Laura Linney) tries to belittle Josh's achievement  his string of victories  Fred indignantly proclaims, "He's better at this than I've ever been at anything in my life. He's better at this than you'll ever be at anything. My son has a gift. He has a gift, and when you acknowledge that, then maybe we will have something to talk about." There is a point where one may ask what happens when the need to win consumes all of the fun. In the course of the movie, we learn much about tournament chess, as Josh works his way to the top. We see what happens when he begins to lose interest and sustains a series of reverses before he regains his position. In the end it comes down to the two best players  Josh and Jonathan Poe  for the junior national championship. Who will win? The movie is based upon Fred Waitzkin's autobiographical book. Our feature does not focus on any one game or on individual piece moves, so that one does not need to know how to play chess to enjoy the film. Ben Kingsley, as usual, is great in his portrayal of Bruce Pandolfini, a real New York personality who teaches chess, writes columns, and has authored many books. He actually coached young Waitzkin for quite a long time. Apparently the real Pandolfini is milder and has a more easygoing style, unlike the movie's portrayal. But that's Hollywood. An error is the film was a reference to former world champion Casablanca; that grandmaster's real name was Jose Raul Capablanca (In 1921 Capablanca defeated Emanuel Lasker, who had held the world championship since 1894, when he bested Wilhelm Steinitz). Despite minor issues, the movie exudes both realism and fascination. Postscript: Josh Waitzkin became an International Master at age 16. He developed into the highest rated American chess player under age 18, and was national chess champion eight times. Waitzkin authored two books. He moved on into the martial arts field, and won championships. The youngest grandmaster in American history is now Fabiano Luigi Caruana, who was not quite 15 when he won in 2007.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close to flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robyn Nesbitt (nesfilmreviews)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Searching for Bobby Fischer" contains in its title a reminder of a time that was. Bobby Fischer was arguably the greatest chess player of all time. As a boy, he faced and defeated the greatest players of his time. In 1972, after a prelude of countless controversies, he won the world chess championship away from the Russians for the first time in years. Then he essentially disappeared and went off the deep end-- into a underworld of rented rooms, phantom sightings, and paranoid outbursts. "Searching for Bobby Fischer"-a film of remarkable sensitivity and insight, tells a story based on fact, about a "new" Bobby Fischer - a young boy named Josh Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc), who was born with a gift for chess--which he nurtured in the rough-and- tumble world of of chess hustlers in New York's Washington Square Park. His parents acknowledge his gift, but are concerned about how he can develop it without stunting the other areas of his life. After realizing what his son is capable of, Fred seeks out a chess player--a once highly regarded grand master named Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley), and hires him to tutor Josh. Bruce tries to teach his pupil a regimented, cerebral approach to the game, while Josh's mentor from the park, Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne) favors a fast paced and aggressive style used by hustlers to intimidate their opponents. Josh proves so adept at the game that Fred enters his son in a tournament. Bruce advises against this, believing that "winning and losing" has nothing to do with chess. Caught up in his son's gift and the thrill of competition, Fred pushes Josh to excel. Josh's weakness as a sportsman is his kindness, which Bonnie fears Fred will beat out of him in his efforts to make his son a winner. When he encounters another prodigy (Michael Nirenberg), who dispatches his opponents with cold-blooded efficiency. Josh has to decide for himself how important winning and losing is. The movie succeeds with the heart-warming, honest acting of the film's protagonist Max Pomeranc. Steven Zaillian, the director, made a conscious choice when he cast the film to find kids who actually could play chess. He wanted chess players first and foremost- - and who also could handle the demands of the script. His face is expressive, open - and yet strangely inscrutable when he plays chess. The criteria Zaillian demands of his protagonist ultimately defines whether this film works or not- -and Max delivers a truly natural performance. The audiences' enjoyment of this film pivots on his character-- and Pomeranc is wonderful. Zaillian's superb script attracted a fantasitc cast that includes: Joe Mantegna, Joan Allen, Ben Kingsley, and Laurence Fishburne. Supported in minor roes by David Paymer, William H. Macy, Tony Shalhoub, Dan Hedaya, Laura Linney, and Austin Pendleton. Of all those Renowned cinematographer Conrad Hall referred to the film in what he called "magical naturalism" - conveying a child's sense of imagination - while James Horner's music reflects that spirit with equal mastery. "Searching for Bobby Fischer" is an intensely fascinating movie capable of involving those who are not familiar about chess, as well as those who love it. Steven Zaillian effectively integrates the actual story and footage of Bobby Fischer throughout the film--running parallel to Josh's story, only enhancing the fascinating storyline. The focus of the film is less on the actual game than it is on the people, emotions, and pressures surrounding Josh. It is a tale of the human spirit and triumph. By the end of "Searching for Bobby Fischer", we have gained insight about the intensity and competitiveness nature of chess tournaments, and a great deal about human nature. The film's implications are many. Think of it as a very smart sports film that substitutes quiet intensity for physical action. There's no denying "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is one film in which every major element - writing, directing, casting, photography, music - is perfectly in tune, exploring the nature of competition with humor, intelligence, and depth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Winning's Not The Only Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bill Slocum (bill.slocum@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "You've got to go to the edge of defeat," one player tells another in the second half of "Searching For Bobby Fischer." That seemed to be the guiding strategy behind the movie as well. Writer-director Steven Zaillian takes an unfilmable subject (chess), bases it on a book few read, names it after a guy nobody had seen in 20 years, and puts it all in the lap of an eight-year-old actor who never starred in a film before and would star in only one after. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" does all it can to stack the board against itself, yet succeeds quite well despite, and indeed, because of all that. Joshua Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc) is celebrating his seventh birthday in Washington Square Park when he catches sight of some rough-looking characters moving what look like his Lego figures on tables of black-and-white squares. Chess is a game few master, yet Josh learns it just from watching them. Soon he is amazing parents and wizened grandmasters alike with his skill at the game, but is Josh really a prodigy on the scale of Bobby Fischer, the New York youngster who went on to win the world championship - then disappear? "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is a fairly formulaic film in many ways. It presents us with stock situations like an adorable boy who only wants to be good; a father (Joe Mantegna) who is too concerned with winning; a mother (Joan Allen) afraid her son is being turned into a machine; and a streetwise black man (Laurence Fishburne) who sees things in the child before anyone else. There's even a villain who appears shrouded in darkness, and who glares at Josh so menacingly its easy to forget this dark figure isn't quite four feet tall. But the formula really works in this one, in part because it serves such a strange cause (how many other chess movies can you think of?) and mostly because of Pomeranc's unaffected work in the lead role. Pomeranc seems preternaturally aware of his fragility on camera and plays to it in ways that reflect not precociousness but depth. You just feel for the guy, exult with his triumphs and feel his disappointments so much you resent Mantegna when his character rides Josh about doing better. Pomeranc also does great ensemble work with the other characters, especially Ben Kingsley as Josh's instructor Bruce, a fellow who seems to have been somebody's idea of Josh a generation ago only for it to collapse on him. Bruce doesn't want Josh to show mercy, you sense because he blames his own softness for his post-child ruination. "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt," he tells Josh. "I'm not him," Josh replies. That's the whole movie right there. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" feels incomplete in parts. Maybe it's just zen-like in its comfort with koan-like plot holes. We never get a real chance to see Josh learning much with Vinnie, the Fishburne character, in a way that would better explain their later closeness. Mantagna's transformation into hard-driving parent (he has a funny but nasty scene with a teacher played by Laura Linney, one of many future talents on display here) isn't laid out convincingly. But thanks both to Zaillian's affecting script and superlative camera work by the incomparable Conrad Hall working close to his zenith, you sense many things lying just beneath the surface of your view, there to be pondered when the rush of the film dissipates. And what a rush! Josh learns that winning isn't everything, but he also comes to care enough to give it his best shot in a climax both thrilling and heartwarming, even if it plays a bit to conventions. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" suggests something redemptive and perhaps even romantic in a game it dares to compare to art. In the process, it winds up presenting us with art both in theory and in practice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Family movie disguised as chess movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmoujik
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're a chess player, you should know: I saw that there were some goofs regarding chess in this movie, but I didn't know that NONE OF THE CHESS RELATED SEQUENCES MADE SENSE. What's the point of making such a movie? How hard is it to get a chess adviser for the editing process. It doesn't have to be a GM. Any decent player would suffice. You could just go a block from the Washington sq. to a chess caf&eacute; and find someone who'd have time to help not to make this movie an embarrassment. Only good parts were documentary ones showing Bobby Fischer, and I would recommend to see "Bobby Fischer against the world" for a chess cinematic fix. Otherwise this family movie is pretty banal, and I wish, someone had written this review before I considered spending time watching this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought-provoking gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Troye Dchgl
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a parent, how do you strike a balance between supporting your children and pushing your children too hard? As a teacher, what is the "correct" way to teach your pupils? There is no certain answer. But the film has the ability of making you think while delivering an exciting plot. Searching for Bobby Fischer is truly an inspiration. It is a reflection for parents to rethink how they should raise their kids, and how to give them the right message to pursue their interests. The film also shows there is no single "correct" way of teaching. A child should learn from all aspects, from different people and via different methods. "Maybe it's better not to be the best. Then you can lose and it's OK." Josh gives us a peek of the pressure of all the constant winners - it is hard for an all-time winner to lose, and sometimes you would rather be "not the best" so you can actually lose without feeling too bad. The only advisable solution is probably to give yourself less pressure when it comes to competitions by loving the game rather than forcing yourself to win. After all, it is just a game in which you are supposed to seek interest, and you should be enjoying the moment. This is highly recommended for all ages. Beautifully written is the script. There is nothing to criticize on the acting. The background music throughout the movie is highly enjoyable and appropriate. The simplicity of the movie is also great. For kids, this is a great adventure about a unknown chess prodigy becoming a champion. For grown-ups, this is also a story that gives something to learn and something to think about. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the kind of movie that can stand the test of time. Although it was made almost 20 years ago, I don't feel a bit of antiquatedness at all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This goes beyond chess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cstotlar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a pianist and classical performer, I've seen a great number of young prodigies in the field of musical performance. The large majority of them never make it past adolescence. In many cases, some of them didn't get beyond the point of doing something quite well at a very early age and were dismissed when the age factor no longer applied. This said, the parents pushed so many of them mercilessly - and rather unashamedly. The kids wanted to please their parents and the parents wanted to please themselves. It's as simple and as tragic as that and it goes on everywhere, with sports near the top, for example. The film then came as no particular surprise. It could be a valuable wake-up call to overly ambitious parents who haven't noticed who their kids ARE rather than what they can do. In this respect the film was spot on and quite frank and sincere. It went on for too long. There were too many "re-wordings" throughout which made the effort seem pedantic at times. The actors, too often shown in semi-obscurity, did their parts beautifully and I would agree with another reviewer who found the wife's contribution essential and beautifully underplayed. The game of chess doesn't have much attraction for those who don't know the game and the director and writer kept this firmly in mind by speeding up the rounds and focusing on the facial expressions. The film could definitely be "tightened up" and pared down a bit. Curtis Stotlar
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice movie for all, but great for chess fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film itself is not as great as the story behind it. Frankly, the plot is the typical American sports movie with the good hearted champion that has both talent and decency and that works hard for his art. I guess it would have been worse if it wasn't based on the book written by Josh Waitzkin's father. Josh Waitzkin has a fascinating story that I recommend you read on. He was the highest rated chess player in the US since he was 8 years old, then his father wrote the book that this movie is based on, then all the sudden celebrity messed with his chess game. Instead of clinging to chess, Josh decides to stop playing, and takes up Ju-Jitsu. He does great at it as well. His book, The Art of Learning, describes the process. Josh Waitzkin is also the guy from the "Waitzkin Academy" tutorial in the ChessMaster XI chess game. But back to the film. At the time, Josh was the next Bobby Fischer, only nicer. Everybody loved a true American hero, especially in a game that was dominated by Russians. The Art of Learning was not out yet, so the people that made the movie saw no problem in portraying the boy as a chess prodigy that did not lose to anyone unless he chose to. In reality, the wonder of Josh Waitzkin is that he really was brilliant and even as a kid he realised that losing is the true teacher. Losing in a finals of a championship defined his life, as he saw the true value of humility and confidence. Having all that information in the background had me see the movie with completely different eyes and I rather liked it. I wish it was more technical, but then no one would watch it except a few Russians, so... Funny trivia: three chess players depicted in the movie were the real people: Kamran Shirazi, Joel Benjamin and Roman DzinDziChashvili, while a girl identified as "82nd girl", which means one of Josh's opponents in the game who ranked the 82nd, is Katya Waitzkin, Josh's real life sister. Bottom line: it has some valuable lessons in there, but hidden in the usual Hollywood bull. It is nice to watch and has a lot more meaning to chess players than people not playing. I liked it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Just for Chess Geeks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Benik
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when it first came out, and I was in my mid-twenties and just getting started in the world. I saw it then as a movie about chess, and what young chess prodigies go through in order to reach the top levels. I saw it again last night, eighteen years later. The movie is the same, but I am different. I am about the age of Josh Waitzkin's father, and I have a daughter who is the same age as Josh. And although my daughter is not a prodigy of chess or anything else, I can see a lot of her in Josh, and a lot of me in his father. This is actually not a film about chess; it is a film about raising children. We live in the Dallas suburbs, where there are a lot of families and a lot of activities for children. I see parents take their children to soccer games, gymnastics camps and acting classes, and I see the obsession in their eyes. They want to expose their kids to many different pursuits, but once they see a talent forming, they focus on only that pursuit, to the exclusion of all others. They sink their money, their time, and all of their child's energy into developing that talent, at the expense of all other interests. Maybe it is pressure to earn a scholarship. Maybe it is the availability of year-round seasons and elite leagues. Maybe it is the unbelievable salaries that top athletes are earning. But I think that the problem that this movie points out -- that pushing kids to be the best at something at any cost -- has gotten worse instead of better. This movie could just as easily been about gymnastics or golf or music as it is about chess. The issues raised are the same. I just hope that more parents can see this film, and recognize that if our goal is raise happy, balanced people, pushing our kids to become elite performers is not the way to get there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern Classic with life lessons, engaging history, great story telling.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-2829
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much more than a movie about chess, this movie deals with childhood geniuses, the difficult choices of parents in how far to push their "prodigy" and the challenge of finding balance in a life filled with difficult choices. I have watched this movie a few times now, and have gleaned different things from it depending on where I am in my own life. This time around had new meaning as I have a child very gifted with piano. I've had similar challenges to Josh Waitzkin's parents in trying to decide how much to push your children - and for what purposes. Most parents probably feel that pull, even without "geniuses" - finding balance in what kids CAN do, what they SHOULD do, and what they WANT to do. We want our children to be happy, but we also know that part of being happy is doing something they are good at and helping them find meaning. I'm also a fan of chess and so really enjoy the glimpses into the chess world this movie portrays. The brilliance of those who stand even above the best minds in their field is the stuff of legends. Bobby Fischer, Garry Kasparov, Anatoly Karpov, Emmanuel Lasker... every bit leaders in their elite worlds as the likes of say Michael Jordan, Mike Tyson, Tiger Woods. Always interesting to me. Great performances all around, from the young (and skinny) Laurence Fishburne to the always stately Ben Kingsley. From the interested and caring parents to the young Josh Waitzskin... even the "enemy" chess player are all well cast and enjoyable throughout the movie. A modern classic in my opinion, and great for the whole family (probably at least 7 or 8 years old is a good lower limit). I appreciate the lessons it teaches, the story of Josh and the truths we discover.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you know anything about chess, or even if you don't, chances are you've heard the name Bobby Fischer. He was the most renowned and most skilled chess master who ever lived. His level of expertise at the game of chess could be matched by no one but himself. He was a legend to that world, but only revered because of his ability at chess. Apart from that he was a detached and solitary individual who obviously had some sort of mental deficiency that kept him from connecting with the real world. Thus his world was all chess. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the story of Josh Waitzkin, another chess master who was discovered long after Bobby Fischer. Josh unexpectedly discovers that he has a unique gift in playing chess and so the pressure from all different people sets in for him to become the best. The title of the film is Searching for Bobby Fischer, but in the context of the film the title literally means searching for the next Bobby Fischer. These pressures and goals Josh must face send us through an interesting, yet very subdued story. Searching for Bobby Fischer is very slow, but appropriately slow. Not a ton actually happens in the film as it is much more character driven. There are a lot of different characters in the film that each drive different plot lines. The film takes a while to get going because of the different characters that have be introduced, and are introduced very slowly and drawn out. Because of this early character development, there's a lot of build up necessary before the first actual conflicts of the film arise. It is almost an hour into the film before we get to see these conflicts start to take shape and affect the storyline. You have to stick with this film to get the full effect of it, which is worth it in the end. I can also commend the story for being very focused but also broad. The stories obviously centers around chess, but as it goes along it becomes more about Josh's relationships with the various people in his life, more so than anything else. The main theme of the film eventually molds into character relationships, as each character seems to have a clear cut relation with the others in order to fully flesh them all out and make them interesting. The storyline works in such a way that it is easy for it to elicit emotional responses out of its audience, so because of this I felt a little less drawn in. I didn't feel much emotion throughout the film and most of the time I just had to take it for what it was. Speaking from a personal standpoint, it isn't the most fascinating kind of story for me, but it doesn't mean it wasn't a well made film. It is very high quality with all the necessary aspects to make it a notable film. The direction is very subdued and avoids anything flashy or grand, but it keeps the flow of the film nice and smooth. The dialouge also keeps with the silky smooth theme of the film, and it is delivered by some very fine actors. All the actors do a very nice job in their respective roles. The main character, Josh Waitzkin, is only seven years old and for a child actor does a decent job. He was very sophisticated for his age and didn't always feel like a kid, but maybe that was the intention of the film. He probably was a fairly detached boy, just like Bobby Fischer, and so he didn't seem like what we think of when we think seven year old boy. And yet the film also spent a lot of time focusing on Josh's balance between chess and growing up like a normal kid, so his attitude wasn't always fitting. Plus he seems like he is on depressants for the entire film. The rest of the cast is A-list and does a great job. Joe Mantegna as Josh's father does a great job as a character trying to balance out his life much in the same way Josh is balancing his. His father must balance his want for his son to be a great chess player, but he also wants his son to live a normal childhood without all of the extreme pressures of chess. Ben Kingsley and Laurence Fishburne both play mentors to Josh, but with very different personalities. Kingsley is an old retired chess master who is very by the book and rigid in his teaching. Fishburne is much more free and sees the game of chess as a much more surreal and introspective experience. The contrast between these two characters is very interesting to watch unfold. Searching for Bobby Fischer is a good film, not a great film, just a good film. It has all the necessary components that make good films. The direction is smart, the dialouge is crisp, and the acting is fantastic. From a personal standpoint this wasn't the most gripping or emotionally moving film for me, but for others I can definitely see how it would be. This film can be enjoyed a lot more than I enjoyed it because it is a good film and there are a lot of good things going for it. But as far as I'm concerned, it was one of those films that I watch, enjoy enough to feel like it was worth my two hours, but then I never watch it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Knight to C-8, Checkmate!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a true story the feature focuses upon a child chess prodigy, Josh Waitzkin. Oh, the lad does enjoy things like baseball, but as soon as he discovers his gift for chess, then it is a new beginning. We often see child masterminds in music and in art and in the sciences, including mathematics. For instance, didn't Mozart make his debut at age four? And what about Pascal, who wrote a treatise at age nine? Anyway, our seven year-old chess genius has a grasp of complicated moves that exceeds that of adults. Still, he is just a boy; he simply has not lived. In the film, we see clips of the great chess grandmaster, Bobby Fischer, who won the US Chess Championship at age 14. He could play (and win) many board games at once. He became official world champion in 1972 when he defeated Soviet champ Boris Spassky. After his victory, he appeared on a Bob Hope TV special. But after 1975 he became a recluse and practically disappeared from the planet. Fischer had controversial beliefs. For instance, he believed in a worldwide Jewish conspiracy, and favored the Palestinians over Israel. In any case, the film's title refers not to Bobby Fischer, but to a potential American successor, one who plays like him (like Josh). And hopefully not one who had lived such an abnormal life like Fischer. Josh Waitzkin, well-played by Max Pomeranc, a real chess player, was born with his gift, which he discovers at an early age. He enjoys going to Washington Park in NYC to play with the dregs and hustlers who hang out there. Note that one of the Russian players there once defeated Tal, who was world champ in 1960-61. The Washington Park folks play a fast game ("blitz"), use unorthodox moves, and intimate their opponents. Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne), a drug addict, is one of the hustlers in the park. He seems to like Josh. As he parents discover Josh's gift, they seem oblivious of what to do with it. For instance, is winning at chess the only thing in life? Eventually, Josh's sports-writer father Fred (Joe Mantegna, in a luminous performance), hires Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley) a brilliant chess-master and former national champion, to coach his son. Bruce's style, in contrast to Vinnie's, is to use the planned approach. But Bruce seems to be almost as difficult to deal with as Fischer. He says that Josh's personality is represented by the KING chess piece, and reminds Josh that "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt." Bruce wants to keep the boy away from Washington Park, which is a hindrance to his understanding of the finer points of chess even though Josh loves the place. When Bruce later tries to teach Josh the cutthroat style of chess, Josh's mother (Bonnie = Joan Allen), becomes chagrined and states, "He's decent!" (Translation = He does not hate his opponents.) When a patronizing teacher (Laura Linney) tries to belittle Josh's achievement  his string of victories  Fred indignantly proclaims, "He's better at this than I've ever been at anything in my life. He's better at this than you'll ever be at anything. My son has a gift. He has a gift, and when you acknowledge that, then maybe we will have something to talk about." There is a point where one may ask what happens when the need to win consumes all of the fun. In the course of the movie, we learn much about tournament chess, as Josh works his way to the top. We see what happens when he begins to lose interest and sustains a series of reverses before he regains his position. In the end it comes down to the two best players  Josh and Jonathan Poe  for the junior national championship. Who will win? The movie is based upon Fred Waitzkin's autobiographical book. Our feature does not focus on any one game or on individual piece moves, so that one does not need to know how to play chess to enjoy the film. Ben Kingsley, as usual, is great in his portrayal of Bruce Pandolfini, a real New York personality who teaches chess, writes columns, and has authored many books. He actually coached young Waitzkin for quite a long time. Apparently the real Pandolfini is milder and has a more easygoing style, unlike the movie's portrayal. But that's Hollywood. An error is the film was a reference to former world champion Casablanca; that grandmaster's real name was Jose Raul Capablanca (In 1921 Capablanca defeated Emanuel Lasker, who had held the world championship since 1894, when he bested Wilhelm Steinitz). Despite minor issues, the movie exudes both realism and fascination. Postscript: Josh Waitzkin became an International Master at age 16. He developed into the highest rated American chess player under age 18, and was national chess champion eight times. Waitzkin authored two books. He moved on into the martial arts field, and won championships. The youngest grandmaster in American history is now Fabiano Luigi Caruana, who was not quite 15 when he won in 2007.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close to flawless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robyn Nesbitt (nesfilmreviews)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Searching for Bobby Fischer" contains in its title a reminder of a time that was. Bobby Fischer was arguably the greatest chess player of all time. As a boy, he faced and defeated the greatest players of his time. In 1972, after a prelude of countless controversies, he won the world chess championship away from the Russians for the first time in years. Then he essentially disappeared and went off the deep end-- into a underworld of rented rooms, phantom sightings, and paranoid outbursts. "Searching for Bobby Fischer"-a film of remarkable sensitivity and insight, tells a story based on fact, about a "new" Bobby Fischer - a young boy named Josh Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc), who was born with a gift for chess--which he nurtured in the rough-and- tumble world of of chess hustlers in New York's Washington Square Park. His parents acknowledge his gift, but are concerned about how he can develop it without stunting the other areas of his life. After realizing what his son is capable of, Fred seeks out a chess player--a once highly regarded grand master named Bruce Pandolfini (Ben Kingsley), and hires him to tutor Josh. Bruce tries to teach his pupil a regimented, cerebral approach to the game, while Josh's mentor from the park, Vinnie (Laurence Fishburne) favors a fast paced and aggressive style used by hustlers to intimidate their opponents. Josh proves so adept at the game that Fred enters his son in a tournament. Bruce advises against this, believing that "winning and losing" has nothing to do with chess. Caught up in his son's gift and the thrill of competition, Fred pushes Josh to excel. Josh's weakness as a sportsman is his kindness, which Bonnie fears Fred will beat out of him in his efforts to make his son a winner. When he encounters another prodigy (Michael Nirenberg), who dispatches his opponents with cold-blooded efficiency. Josh has to decide for himself how important winning and losing is. The movie succeeds with the heart-warming, honest acting of the film's protagonist Max Pomeranc. Steven Zaillian, the director, made a conscious choice when he cast the film to find kids who actually could play chess. He wanted chess players first and foremost- - and who also could handle the demands of the script. His face is expressive, open - and yet strangely inscrutable when he plays chess. The criteria Zaillian demands of his protagonist ultimately defines whether this film works or not- -and Max delivers a truly natural performance. The audiences' enjoyment of this film pivots on his character-- and Pomeranc is wonderful. Zaillian's superb script attracted a fantasitc cast that includes: Joe Mantegna, Joan Allen, Ben Kingsley, and Laurence Fishburne. Supported in minor roes by David Paymer, William H. Macy, Tony Shalhoub, Dan Hedaya, Laura Linney, and Austin Pendleton. Of all those Renowned cinematographer Conrad Hall referred to the film in what he called "magical naturalism" - conveying a child's sense of imagination - while James Horner's music reflects that spirit with equal mastery. "Searching for Bobby Fischer" is an intensely fascinating movie capable of involving those who are not familiar about chess, as well as those who love it. Steven Zaillian effectively integrates the actual story and footage of Bobby Fischer throughout the film--running parallel to Josh's story, only enhancing the fascinating storyline. The focus of the film is less on the actual game than it is on the people, emotions, and pressures surrounding Josh. It is a tale of the human spirit and triumph. By the end of "Searching for Bobby Fischer", we have gained insight about the intensity and competitiveness nature of chess tournaments, and a great deal about human nature. The film's implications are many. Think of it as a very smart sports film that substitutes quiet intensity for physical action. There's no denying "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is one film in which every major element - writing, directing, casting, photography, music - is perfectly in tune, exploring the nature of competition with humor, intelligence, and depth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Winning's Not The Only Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bill Slocum (bill.slocum@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "You've got to go to the edge of defeat," one player tells another in the second half of "Searching For Bobby Fischer." That seemed to be the guiding strategy behind the movie as well. Writer-director Steven Zaillian takes an unfilmable subject (chess), bases it on a book few read, names it after a guy nobody had seen in 20 years, and puts it all in the lap of an eight-year-old actor who never starred in a film before and would star in only one after. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" does all it can to stack the board against itself, yet succeeds quite well despite, and indeed, because of all that. Joshua Waitzkin (Max Pomeranc) is celebrating his seventh birthday in Washington Square Park when he catches sight of some rough-looking characters moving what look like his Lego figures on tables of black-and-white squares. Chess is a game few master, yet Josh learns it just from watching them. Soon he is amazing parents and wizened grandmasters alike with his skill at the game, but is Josh really a prodigy on the scale of Bobby Fischer, the New York youngster who went on to win the world championship - then disappear? "Searching For Bobby Fischer" is a fairly formulaic film in many ways. It presents us with stock situations like an adorable boy who only wants to be good; a father (Joe Mantegna) who is too concerned with winning; a mother (Joan Allen) afraid her son is being turned into a machine; and a streetwise black man (Laurence Fishburne) who sees things in the child before anyone else. There's even a villain who appears shrouded in darkness, and who glares at Josh so menacingly its easy to forget this dark figure isn't quite four feet tall. But the formula really works in this one, in part because it serves such a strange cause (how many other chess movies can you think of?) and mostly because of Pomeranc's unaffected work in the lead role. Pomeranc seems preternaturally aware of his fragility on camera and plays to it in ways that reflect not precociousness but depth. You just feel for the guy, exult with his triumphs and feel his disappointments so much you resent Mantegna when his character rides Josh about doing better. Pomeranc also does great ensemble work with the other characters, especially Ben Kingsley as Josh's instructor Bruce, a fellow who seems to have been somebody's idea of Josh a generation ago only for it to collapse on him. Bruce doesn't want Josh to show mercy, you sense because he blames his own softness for his post-child ruination. "Bobby Fischer held the world in contempt," he tells Josh. "I'm not him," Josh replies. That's the whole movie right there. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" feels incomplete in parts. Maybe it's just zen-like in its comfort with koan-like plot holes. We never get a real chance to see Josh learning much with Vinnie, the Fishburne character, in a way that would better explain their later closeness. Mantagna's transformation into hard-driving parent (he has a funny but nasty scene with a teacher played by Laura Linney, one of many future talents on display here) isn't laid out convincingly. But thanks both to Zaillian's affecting script and superlative camera work by the incomparable Conrad Hall working close to his zenith, you sense many things lying just beneath the surface of your view, there to be pondered when the rush of the film dissipates. And what a rush! Josh learns that winning isn't everything, but he also comes to care enough to give it his best shot in a climax both thrilling and heartwarming, even if it plays a bit to conventions. "Searching For Bobby Fischer" suggests something redemptive and perhaps even romantic in a game it dares to compare to art. In the process, it winds up presenting us with art both in theory and in practice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Family movie disguised as chess movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gmoujik
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're a chess player, you should know: I saw that there were some goofs regarding chess in this movie, but I didn't know that NONE OF THE CHESS RELATED SEQUENCES MADE SENSE. What's the point of making such a movie? How hard is it to get a chess adviser for the editing process. It doesn't have to be a GM. Any decent player would suffice. You could just go a block from the Washington sq. to a chess caf&eacute; and find someone who'd have time to help not to make this movie an embarrassment. Only good parts were documentary ones showing Bobby Fischer, and I would recommend to see "Bobby Fischer against the world" for a chess cinematic fix. Otherwise this family movie is pretty banal, and I wish, someone had written this review before I considered spending time watching this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A thought-provoking gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Troye Dchgl
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a parent, how do you strike a balance between supporting your children and pushing your children too hard? As a teacher, what is the "correct" way to teach your pupils? There is no certain answer. But the film has the ability of making you think while delivering an exciting plot. Searching for Bobby Fischer is truly an inspiration. It is a reflection for parents to rethink how they should raise their kids, and how to give them the right message to pursue their interests. The film also shows there is no single "correct" way of teaching. A child should learn from all aspects, from different people and via different methods. "Maybe it's better not to be the best. Then you can lose and it's OK." Josh gives us a peek of the pressure of all the constant winners - it is hard for an all-time winner to lose, and sometimes you would rather be "not the best" so you can actually lose without feeling too bad. The only advisable solution is probably to give yourself less pressure when it comes to competitions by loving the game rather than forcing yourself to win. After all, it is just a game in which you are supposed to seek interest, and you should be enjoying the moment. This is highly recommended for all ages. Beautifully written is the script. There is nothing to criticize on the acting. The background music throughout the movie is highly enjoyable and appropriate. The simplicity of the movie is also great. For kids, this is a great adventure about a unknown chess prodigy becoming a champion. For grown-ups, this is also a story that gives something to learn and something to think about. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the kind of movie that can stand the test of time. Although it was made almost 20 years ago, I don't feel a bit of antiquatedness at all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This goes beyond chess
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cstotlar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a pianist and classical performer, I've seen a great number of young prodigies in the field of musical performance. The large majority of them never make it past adolescence. In many cases, some of them didn't get beyond the point of doing something quite well at a very early age and were dismissed when the age factor no longer applied. This said, the parents pushed so many of them mercilessly - and rather unashamedly. The kids wanted to please their parents and the parents wanted to please themselves. It's as simple and as tragic as that and it goes on everywhere, with sports near the top, for example. The film then came as no particular surprise. It could be a valuable wake-up call to overly ambitious parents who haven't noticed who their kids ARE rather than what they can do. In this respect the film was spot on and quite frank and sincere. It went on for too long. There were too many "re-wordings" throughout which made the effort seem pedantic at times. The actors, too often shown in semi-obscurity, did their parts beautifully and I would agree with another reviewer who found the wife's contribution essential and beautifully underplayed. The game of chess doesn't have much attraction for those who don't know the game and the director and writer kept this firmly in mind by speeding up the rounds and focusing on the facial expressions. The film could definitely be "tightened up" and pared down a bit. Curtis Stotlar
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A nice movie for all, but great for chess fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film itself is not as great as the story behind it. Frankly, the plot is the typical American sports movie with the good hearted champion that has both talent and decency and that works hard for his art. I guess it would have been worse if it wasn't based on the book written by Josh Waitzkin's father. Josh Waitzkin has a fascinating story that I recommend you read on. He was the highest rated chess player in the US since he was 8 years old, then his father wrote the book that this movie is based on, then all the sudden celebrity messed with his chess game. Instead of clinging to chess, Josh decides to stop playing, and takes up Ju-Jitsu. He does great at it as well. His book, The Art of Learning, describes the process. Josh Waitzkin is also the guy from the "Waitzkin Academy" tutorial in the ChessMaster XI chess game. But back to the film. At the time, Josh was the next Bobby Fischer, only nicer. Everybody loved a true American hero, especially in a game that was dominated by Russians. The Art of Learning was not out yet, so the people that made the movie saw no problem in portraying the boy as a chess prodigy that did not lose to anyone unless he chose to. In reality, the wonder of Josh Waitzkin is that he really was brilliant and even as a kid he realised that losing is the true teacher. Losing in a finals of a championship defined his life, as he saw the true value of humility and confidence. Having all that information in the background had me see the movie with completely different eyes and I rather liked it. I wish it was more technical, but then no one would watch it except a few Russians, so... Funny trivia: three chess players depicted in the movie were the real people: Kamran Shirazi, Joel Benjamin and Roman DzinDziChashvili, while a girl identified as "82nd girl", which means one of Josh's opponents in the game who ranked the 82nd, is Katya Waitzkin, Josh's real life sister. Bottom line: it has some valuable lessons in there, but hidden in the usual Hollywood bull. It is nice to watch and has a lot more meaning to chess players than people not playing. I liked it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Just for Chess Geeks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joe Benik
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this movie when it first came out, and I was in my mid-twenties and just getting started in the world. I saw it then as a movie about chess, and what young chess prodigies go through in order to reach the top levels. I saw it again last night, eighteen years later. The movie is the same, but I am different. I am about the age of Josh Waitzkin's father, and I have a daughter who is the same age as Josh. And although my daughter is not a prodigy of chess or anything else, I can see a lot of her in Josh, and a lot of me in his father. This is actually not a film about chess; it is a film about raising children. We live in the Dallas suburbs, where there are a lot of families and a lot of activities for children. I see parents take their children to soccer games, gymnastics camps and acting classes, and I see the obsession in their eyes. They want to expose their kids to many different pursuits, but once they see a talent forming, they focus on only that pursuit, to the exclusion of all others. They sink their money, their time, and all of their child's energy into developing that talent, at the expense of all other interests. Maybe it is pressure to earn a scholarship. Maybe it is the availability of year-round seasons and elite leagues. Maybe it is the unbelievable salaries that top athletes are earning. But I think that the problem that this movie points out -- that pushing kids to be the best at something at any cost -- has gotten worse instead of better. This movie could just as easily been about gymnastics or golf or music as it is about chess. The issues raised are the same. I just hope that more parents can see this film, and recognize that if our goal is raise happy, balanced people, pushing our kids to become elite performers is not the way to get there.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Modern Classic with life lessons, engaging history, great story telling.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-2829
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Much more than a movie about chess, this movie deals with childhood geniuses, the difficult choices of parents in how far to push their "prodigy" and the challenge of finding balance in a life filled with difficult choices. I have watched this movie a few times now, and have gleaned different things from it depending on where I am in my own life. This time around had new meaning as I have a child very gifted with piano. I've had similar challenges to Josh Waitzkin's parents in trying to decide how much to push your children - and for what purposes. Most parents probably feel that pull, even without "geniuses" - finding balance in what kids CAN do, what they SHOULD do, and what they WANT to do. We want our children to be happy, but we also know that part of being happy is doing something they are good at and helping them find meaning. I'm also a fan of chess and so really enjoy the glimpses into the chess world this movie portrays. The brilliance of those who stand even above the best minds in their field is the stuff of legends. Bobby Fischer, Garry Kasparov, Anatoly Karpov, Emmanuel Lasker... every bit leaders in their elite worlds as the likes of say Michael Jordan, Mike Tyson, Tiger Woods. Always interesting to me. Great performances all around, from the young (and skinny) Laurence Fishburne to the always stately Ben Kingsley. From the interested and caring parents to the young Josh Waitzskin... even the "enemy" chess player are all well cast and enjoyable throughout the movie. A modern classic in my opinion, and great for the whole family (probably at least 7 or 8 years old is a good lower limit). I appreciate the lessons it teaches, the story of Josh and the truths we discover.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well made but not my cup of tea
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you know anything about chess, or even if you don't, chances are you've heard the name Bobby Fischer. He was the most renowned and most skilled chess master who ever lived. His level of expertise at the game of chess could be matched by no one but himself. He was a legend to that world, but only revered because of his ability at chess. Apart from that he was a detached and solitary individual who obviously had some sort of mental deficiency that kept him from connecting with the real world. Thus his world was all chess. Searching for Bobby Fischer is the story of Josh Waitzkin, another chess master who was discovered long after Bobby Fischer. Josh unexpectedly discovers that he has a unique gift in playing chess and so the pressure from all different people sets in for him to become the best. The title of the film is Searching for Bobby Fischer, but in the context of the film the title literally means searching for the next Bobby Fischer. These pressures and goals Josh must face send us through an interesting, yet very subdued story. Searching for Bobby Fischer is very slow, but appropriately slow. Not a ton actually happens in the film as it is much more character driven. There are a lot of different characters in the film that each drive different plot lines. The film takes a while to get going because of the different characters that have be introduced, and are introduced very slowly and drawn out. Because of this early character development, there's a lot of build up necessary before the first actual conflicts of the film arise. It is almost an hour into the film before we get to see these conflicts start to take shape and affect the storyline. You have to stick with this film to get the full effect of it, which is worth it in the end. I can also commend the story for being very focused but also broad. The stories obviously centers around chess, but as it goes along it becomes more about Josh's relationships with the various people in his life, more so than anything else. The main theme of the film eventually molds into character relationships, as each character seems to have a clear cut relation with the others in order to fully flesh them all out and make them interesting. The storyline works in such a way that it is easy for it to elicit emotional responses out of its audience, so because of this I felt a little less drawn in. I didn't feel much emotion throughout the film and most of the time I just had to take it for what it was. Speaking from a personal standpoint, it isn't the most fascinating kind of story for me, but it doesn't mean it wasn't a well made film. It is very high quality with all the necessary aspects to make it a notable film. The direction is very subdued and avoids anything flashy or grand, but it keeps the flow of the film nice and smooth. The dialouge also keeps with the silky smooth theme of the film, and it is delivered by some very fine actors. All the actors do a very nice job in their respective roles. The main character, Josh Waitzkin, is only seven years old and for a child actor does a decent job. He was very sophisticated for his age and didn't always feel like a kid, but maybe that was the intention of the film. He probably was a fairly detached boy, just like Bobby Fischer, and so he didn't seem like what we think of when we think seven year old boy. And yet the film also spent a lot of time focusing on Josh's balance between chess and growing up like a normal kid, so his attitude wasn't always fitting. Plus he seems like he is on depressants for the entire film. The rest of the cast is A-list and does a great job. Joe Mantegna as Josh's father does a great job as a character trying to balance out his life much in the same way Josh is balancing his. His father must balance his want for his son to be a great chess player, but he also wants his son to live a normal childhood without all of the extreme pressures of chess. Ben Kingsley and Laurence Fishburne both play mentors to Josh, but with very different personalities. Kingsley is an old retired chess master who is very by the book and rigid in his teaching. Fishburne is much more free and sees the game of chess as a much more surreal and introspective experience. The contrast between these two characters is very interesting to watch unfold. Searching for Bobby Fischer is a good film, not a great film, just a good film. It has all the necessary components that make good films. The direction is smart, the dialouge is crisp, and the acting is fantastic. From a personal standpoint this wasn't the most gripping or emotionally moving film for me, but for others I can definitely see how it would be. This film can be enjoyed a lot more than I enjoyed it because it is a good film and there are a lot of good things going for it. But as far as I'm concerned, it was one of those films that I watch, enjoy enough to feel like it was worth my two hours, but then I never watch it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
