<filme>
 <id>
  871
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120434
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Vegas Vacation
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  When Clark Griswold puts his mind to something, we soon realize he hasn't got one. Still, nothing stops him when the vacation bug hits. This time, he's chosen Las Vegas, the new family ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  When Clark Griswold puts his mind to something, we soon realize he hasn't got one. Still, nothing stops him when the vacation bug hits. This time, he's chosen Las Vegas, the new family entertainment capital of America! Chevy Chase returns as bubbly, bumbling Clark in Vegas Vacation, a jokers-are-wild laugh fest including two other stars from past Vacations. Beverly D'Angelo is back as wife Ellen, doting on the guy she calls "Sparky," and Randy Quaid again delights as grubby goof ball Cousin Eddie. Ethan Embry (That Thing You Do!) and screen-debuting Marisol Nichols are Griswold teens who love the round-the-clock nightlife - as long as they don't share it with Mom and Dad! From Seigfried and Roy's extravaganza to a Hoover Dam tour, from cruising to losing (Wallace Shawn as a shifty blackjack dealer) to amorous crooning (Wayne Newton falls for Ellen): watch Clark try to keep family and wallet together!
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   vacation
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hoover dam
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   remarriage
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   national lampoon series
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wedding
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Stephen Kessler
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Elisa Bell
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Bob Ducsay
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Chevy Chase
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Beverly D'Angelo
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Randy Quaid
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Griswalds go to Vegas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the forth and last movie about Griswalds. Well , at least until the new remake of "Vacation" doesn't show up. It doesn't have the National Lampoons title , but it is the sequel to previous three movies. It was directed Stephen Kessler. What is more important is that John Hughes (writer of all three movies) isn't the writer of this one. "Vegas vacation" was written by Elisa Bell and Bob Ducsay. It's hard to find a good third movie in the series , much less forth. It's also a risk to make a sequel to an 80's movie . Many of the sequels to 80's movies fails , because they aren't able to capture that specific 80's magic of the original ("Another 48 hours" , "Beverly Hills cop 3", "Blues brothers 2000" for example). Griswalds didn't really needed another sequel , since the third one was really good . So who needed it ? Chevy Chase . After the 1989 he wasn't able to make a successful movie and this was his last attempt to become a major star once more . In the end it's not a bad movie , but it lacks freshness . The writers actually did a lot of work to keep "Vegas vacation" in style of previous movies and for most part the movie resembles Hughes sense of humor. Unfortunately , there are too many moments of boredom when nothing happens and most of the jokes are mildly amusing . The funniest scenes are happening near the ending , when Clark and Eddie go to VERY cheap restaurant and unusual casino (where you can play Rock, paper, scissors ! ). There is also a nice tribute scene to the first movie with the chick in the car. On the other hand the scene at the Hoover Dam is rather unbelievable , even for Clark. The old cast is back and in a good shape  Chevy Chase , Beverly D'Angelo and Randy Quaid. The kids has been recast again . Ethan Embry plays Rusty and Marisol Nichols plays Audrey. I have to say they are my least favorite couple from the whole series. They give very flat performances. Anyway , it's still a quite decent goodbye for Griswalds. It was good to hear Beach boys "Good vibrations " and once again Lindsey Buckhingam "Holiday road" . And the scene with between Clark and the old lonely man shows why the audience liked Clark so much . He isn't too bright , but he's heart is in the right place. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't forget to visit the Dam gift shop....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its the same kind of plot as all the others, Clark decides to take the family to Vegas, and all starts of shenanigans start. Clark starts to lose all the money, Ellen gets chased by Wayne Newton, Rusty becomes a Player, and Audrey becomes a dancer. Cousin Eddie is along for the ride, and so are bad jokes and bad blue screen..... Even though its the poorest one from the franchise, its still likable, thanks to the chemistry between Chase and D'angelo. They just come off so natural that you really don't care if the jokes are rehashed, and Eddie is just in it to stop lethargy setting in. Its predictable, Clark is the only one who gets over his head, while the other three would probably have the time of their lives if they were just left alone. The script isn't the best, and the Dam tour takes you away front he fundamental elements of the story, but or a final Vacation movie, its not to bad, Chase is always a likable screen presence, and there are far worse ways to spend ninety minutes. Dumb silly fun, that you will forget about the minute you turn the TV off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funnier than the other films in the series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did we need this movie? No we did not. It's surprisingly enjoyable though. Not very good, but for my money the best 'Vacation' movie. There are a few inspired bits and pieces, like Chevy Chase and dim cousin Randy Quaid coming across a cut-price casino where the games include scissors paper stone, guess which hand, a coin toss, and guess a number between 1 and 10! Admittedly a lot of the jokes fall flat - Chase's character is an idiot but would he really be stupid enough to climb an electricity pylon about Hoover Dam? - and Wallace Shawn is wasted as an annoying card dealer. But despite its faults and ultimate redundancy it's kind of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a former hotel manager in Vegas, the movie is perfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    db-beurylaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I lived in Las Vegas for 25 years. This movie hits all of the points of a Las Vegas. That's the strength and point of all four of the Vacation movies all that stuff really happens. Except for maybe winning a whole lot of money, but you know that. The really awful buffet in some of the sleazier hotels, the way some dealers can clean you out with every hand, the obligatory trip to Hoover Dam. Heck, one of my friend's girlfriends was actually hit on and picked up by Wayne Newton. Yes you can cook meat on a rock on a hot day and every day in the Summer is a hot day. Rattle snakes radioactivity its all part of Las Vegas fun. This movie hits all of the highlights. Think of it as a travel log with attitude. Loved it. Cast is perfect. Chevy is the unflappable fool tourist who flops around as a fish out of water. Randy Quaid is the kind of guy who is right at home in Las Vegas and proud that his daughter is an "entertainer" But the person who makes it all work is Beverly who takes all the abuse and slyly sticks in her comments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good, But Long-Waited Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Randy Quaid, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols and Wayne Newton star in this 1997 comedy sequel. In this installment, Clark Griswold (Chase) takes his wife, Ellen (D'Angelo) and 2 kids, Rusty (Embry) and Audrey (Nichols) to Las Vegas, Nevada for a family trip. Clark runs into cousin Eddie (Quaid) while getting there and has bad luck. Newton plays himself who falls in love with Ellen and Clark starts getting himself addicted to gambling causing him to lose most of his money and his family starts going their separate ways. Soon, Clark tries to redeem himself and get his family back together. This is a pretty good, but long-waited sequel, Chevy is great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite of the vacation films, go ahead, laugh yourself silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clark Griswold (Chevy Chase) arrives at his home in Chicago, one day, in very high spirits. His wife, Ellen (Beverly D'Angelo) and two kids, Audrey (Marisol Nichols) and Rusty (Ethan Embry) are called to a family meeting. In short order, Clark announces that his new formula for food preservation has garnered a big bonus and he is taking them all to Las Vegas. No one is very excited but they have little choice but to go along. When they arrive in town, the Griswolds take a limo to their hotel, although poor Audrey gets stuck in the moonroof, thanks to her dad. Before long, cousin Eddie (Randy Quaid) shows up, for Ellen has called her cousin, Eddie's wife Catherine, to announce their visit. Eddie promptly watches Clark lose a whopping $300 bucks at the blackjack table, much to the joy of the sadistic dealer, Marty (Wallace Shawn). After the loss, Eddie invites everyone to his house north of Vegas, where the government has given him some lovely, parched, radioactive land. From there, its on to Hoover Dam and to a bunch of shows, including Sigfried & Roy and Wayne Newton. Newton, in fact, makes a play for Ellen in front of the audience, although Clark thinks its part of the act. While Ellen gets invited to have cocktails with Wayne, Clark goes on gambling and the kids, under age, get fake identifications so they can likewise play the tables (Rusty) and try out exotic dancing (Audrey). They even have an encounter with an old, old gambler (Sid Caesar). How will their great adventure end? This is the best of the vacation films, my opinion, even though all are enjoyable. The script is lively and inventive and so, so funny. The cast, too, is excellent, with the main folks reprising their long established roles, and Newton, Embry, Nichols, Shawn, and especially Caesar, adding greatly to the merriment. The scenery is the best of the strip, Eddie's abode notwithstanding, and the costumes and direction are topnotch, also. Do you, personally, need a vacation from the norm? VV is the cure for the anytime blues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big lights, big money, and big laughs like the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This installment of the comedy classic Vacation series is often regarded as "the worst in the series". That couldn't be further from the truth. This is my second favorite in the entire franchise next to the original film. Vegas Vacation was watched by me countless times in the late nineties when I was very young, and really didn't know what the characters were discussing, or even saying for that matter. Along with Fools Rush In, this was my favorite film in my childhood. I recently ran into the National Lampoon's Vacation Collection on Amazon for about $25. What the hell? I'll pay that. I had already watched the first two, and really wanted to dive into the third and rewatch this (keep in mind, at the time, it had been around nine years since I had seen the film). I recently ran into it on Comedy Central, and there was the question again; "what the hell?" The Griswold Family returns to the screen, this time taking a family vacation to Las Vegas. While it isn't much of a family-friendly place, Clark (Chase) and Rusty (Embry) are more than happy to head there and have a damn good time. They even stop at Cousin Eddie's house (Quaid) for more fun, but soon enough, they wind up taking him to Vegas unexpectedly. Let the crazy, nonstop, unrealistic, comedy antics begin. Clark gambles away their money, the wife Ellen (D'Angelo) falls in love with Wayne Newton, Rusty gets a fake ID and wins big, and Audrey (played by the stunning and gorgeous Marisol Nichols) loosens up to become a dancer. It's nothing special, but back in the day, to a five year old, it was colorful, vibrant, jumpy, loud, and off it's own medicine. I loved it. I saw love at first sight when I saw Marisol Nichols play Audrey. Then when I grew older, I questioned if continuity was even brought up when making this sequel. The children look nothing like they did in the first three films. Rusty was an average looking guy, but in this one his a very handsome, grown individual. Audrey has the biggest change of all. She was the homely child in the first three, but in this one she's got black hair and is amazingly gorgeous. Puberty did her well. But who cares? The jokes are somewhat fresh, the scenes are classic (my favorite being the dam boring tour), and the characters return to give it their all once more. Hard to believe that this would be the last time we see these characters in the flesh until thirteen years later when Chevy and Beverly would appear in the short Hotel Hell Vacation. I suspected something like National Lampoon's Australian Vacation, But it was still nice to see them back at it one more time. Vegas Vacation isn't perfect. You could almost think of it has a hopelessly lost spin off that doesn't take too many new routes, or even has appropriately placed characters. It doesn't even have the National Lampoon's name in the title. My only theory is that Warner Bros. (the company that distributed every other Vacation film) wanted to make another film in the franchise. They probably suggested the idea of Vegas with high hopes, National Lampoon maybe scrapped it, and WB went on to do it by themselves with no endorsement of National Lampoon. After all, they do own a part of the name, might as well milk it. No matter, Vegas Vacation is a film I'm proud to call one of my favorite comedies, and my second favorite in the Vacation franchise. Starring: Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols, and Randy Quaid. Directed by: Stephen Kessler.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    dud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this fourth installment in the vacation series is close to abysmal in my opinion.it's cheap gimmickry at it lowest.the first three in the series were all very good,pretty much at the same level of quality of jokes and story.this one was neither funny nor clever.the only good thing about the the whole travesty is Wallace Shawn who has a small role as a black jack dealer.his bit is quite funny.but that's it.otherwise it's sheer tedium.it's worth noting that the words "national lampoon" do not appear before the title,so maybe that says something right there.anyway,if i had known how bad this thing was,i would have booked myself self an appointment for a sinus scraping instead.it would have been more enjoyable.i'll give it 3/10 for Wallace Shawn
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets the number three spot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bjorn (ODDBear)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, Clark Griswold has so far botched a road trip, a European vacation and (most memorably) a Christmas vacation; so why does he continue to make his family go through hell on his endless quest for a fun vacation? That's easy; it's pretty enjoyable for us to watch :) "Vegas Vacation" sits comfortably as the third most enjoyable film in the series; surpassing "European Vacation" but not as enjoyable as "Vacation" or "Christmas Vacation". It's pretty far reaching at times but there are solid moments here; such as Clark damn near destroying a damn and getting crazy (as only Clark Griswold can) playing cards and losing everything. The Wayne Newton gag soon grows tiresome and everything concerning Audrey and Russ pretty much stinks but Randy Quaid delivers once again as obnoxious Cousin Eddie and Chase hasn't lost his touch as the world's most annoying (yet somehow oddly endearing) family dad.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I used to like it, but now I think it is silly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sirus_the_Virus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to really like Vegas Vacation. But I watched it again recently and, well, it wasn't that good. I still give it credit, but it's not that great. Vegas vacation is rated PG, and I can really see it. The film has it's funny moments but really doesn't come alive like the first and third film did. The film is corny, and there are many silly scenes. Ellen(Beverly D'Angelo) is irritating, and in this film she falls head over heels for Wayne Newton. If only I could find these high heels so then I could throw them at her. Vegas Vacation is sort of irritating. It's probably the weakest in the series. It's a silly, silly sequel. Vegas vacation:**/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Griswalds go to Vegas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the forth and last movie about Griswalds. Well , at least until the new remake of "Vacation" doesn't show up. It doesn't have the National Lampoons title , but it is the sequel to previous three movies. It was directed Stephen Kessler. What is more important is that John Hughes (writer of all three movies) isn't the writer of this one. "Vegas vacation" was written by Elisa Bell and Bob Ducsay. It's hard to find a good third movie in the series , much less forth. It's also a risk to make a sequel to an 80's movie . Many of the sequels to 80's movies fails , because they aren't able to capture that specific 80's magic of the original ("Another 48 hours" , "Beverly Hills cop 3", "Blues brothers 2000" for example). Griswalds didn't really needed another sequel , since the third one was really good . So who needed it ? Chevy Chase . After the 1989 he wasn't able to make a successful movie and this was his last attempt to become a major star once more . In the end it's not a bad movie , but it lacks freshness . The writers actually did a lot of work to keep "Vegas vacation" in style of previous movies and for most part the movie resembles Hughes sense of humor. Unfortunately , there are too many moments of boredom when nothing happens and most of the jokes are mildly amusing . The funniest scenes are happening near the ending , when Clark and Eddie go to VERY cheap restaurant and unusual casino (where you can play Rock, paper, scissors ! ). There is also a nice tribute scene to the first movie with the chick in the car. On the other hand the scene at the Hoover Dam is rather unbelievable , even for Clark. The old cast is back and in a good shape  Chevy Chase , Beverly D'Angelo and Randy Quaid. The kids has been recast again . Ethan Embry plays Rusty and Marisol Nichols plays Audrey. I have to say they are my least favorite couple from the whole series. They give very flat performances. Anyway , it's still a quite decent goodbye for Griswalds. It was good to hear Beach boys "Good vibrations " and once again Lindsey Buckhingam "Holiday road" . And the scene with between Clark and the old lonely man shows why the audience liked Clark so much . He isn't too bright , but he's heart is in the right place. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't forget to visit the Dam gift shop....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its the same kind of plot as all the others, Clark decides to take the family to Vegas, and all starts of shenanigans start. Clark starts to lose all the money, Ellen gets chased by Wayne Newton, Rusty becomes a Player, and Audrey becomes a dancer. Cousin Eddie is along for the ride, and so are bad jokes and bad blue screen..... Even though its the poorest one from the franchise, its still likable, thanks to the chemistry between Chase and D'angelo. They just come off so natural that you really don't care if the jokes are rehashed, and Eddie is just in it to stop lethargy setting in. Its predictable, Clark is the only one who gets over his head, while the other three would probably have the time of their lives if they were just left alone. The script isn't the best, and the Dam tour takes you away front he fundamental elements of the story, but or a final Vacation movie, its not to bad, Chase is always a likable screen presence, and there are far worse ways to spend ninety minutes. Dumb silly fun, that you will forget about the minute you turn the TV off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funnier than the other films in the series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did we need this movie? No we did not. It's surprisingly enjoyable though. Not very good, but for my money the best 'Vacation' movie. There are a few inspired bits and pieces, like Chevy Chase and dim cousin Randy Quaid coming across a cut-price casino where the games include scissors paper stone, guess which hand, a coin toss, and guess a number between 1 and 10! Admittedly a lot of the jokes fall flat - Chase's character is an idiot but would he really be stupid enough to climb an electricity pylon about Hoover Dam? - and Wallace Shawn is wasted as an annoying card dealer. But despite its faults and ultimate redundancy it's kind of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a former hotel manager in Vegas, the movie is perfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    db-beurylaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I lived in Las Vegas for 25 years. This movie hits all of the points of a Las Vegas. That's the strength and point of all four of the Vacation movies all that stuff really happens. Except for maybe winning a whole lot of money, but you know that. The really awful buffet in some of the sleazier hotels, the way some dealers can clean you out with every hand, the obligatory trip to Hoover Dam. Heck, one of my friend's girlfriends was actually hit on and picked up by Wayne Newton. Yes you can cook meat on a rock on a hot day and every day in the Summer is a hot day. Rattle snakes radioactivity its all part of Las Vegas fun. This movie hits all of the highlights. Think of it as a travel log with attitude. Loved it. Cast is perfect. Chevy is the unflappable fool tourist who flops around as a fish out of water. Randy Quaid is the kind of guy who is right at home in Las Vegas and proud that his daughter is an "entertainer" But the person who makes it all work is Beverly who takes all the abuse and slyly sticks in her comments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good, But Long-Waited Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Randy Quaid, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols and Wayne Newton star in this 1997 comedy sequel. In this installment, Clark Griswold (Chase) takes his wife, Ellen (D'Angelo) and 2 kids, Rusty (Embry) and Audrey (Nichols) to Las Vegas, Nevada for a family trip. Clark runs into cousin Eddie (Quaid) while getting there and has bad luck. Newton plays himself who falls in love with Ellen and Clark starts getting himself addicted to gambling causing him to lose most of his money and his family starts going their separate ways. Soon, Clark tries to redeem himself and get his family back together. This is a pretty good, but long-waited sequel, Chevy is great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite of the vacation films, go ahead, laugh yourself silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clark Griswold (Chevy Chase) arrives at his home in Chicago, one day, in very high spirits. His wife, Ellen (Beverly D'Angelo) and two kids, Audrey (Marisol Nichols) and Rusty (Ethan Embry) are called to a family meeting. In short order, Clark announces that his new formula for food preservation has garnered a big bonus and he is taking them all to Las Vegas. No one is very excited but they have little choice but to go along. When they arrive in town, the Griswolds take a limo to their hotel, although poor Audrey gets stuck in the moonroof, thanks to her dad. Before long, cousin Eddie (Randy Quaid) shows up, for Ellen has called her cousin, Eddie's wife Catherine, to announce their visit. Eddie promptly watches Clark lose a whopping $300 bucks at the blackjack table, much to the joy of the sadistic dealer, Marty (Wallace Shawn). After the loss, Eddie invites everyone to his house north of Vegas, where the government has given him some lovely, parched, radioactive land. From there, its on to Hoover Dam and to a bunch of shows, including Sigfried & Roy and Wayne Newton. Newton, in fact, makes a play for Ellen in front of the audience, although Clark thinks its part of the act. While Ellen gets invited to have cocktails with Wayne, Clark goes on gambling and the kids, under age, get fake identifications so they can likewise play the tables (Rusty) and try out exotic dancing (Audrey). They even have an encounter with an old, old gambler (Sid Caesar). How will their great adventure end? This is the best of the vacation films, my opinion, even though all are enjoyable. The script is lively and inventive and so, so funny. The cast, too, is excellent, with the main folks reprising their long established roles, and Newton, Embry, Nichols, Shawn, and especially Caesar, adding greatly to the merriment. The scenery is the best of the strip, Eddie's abode notwithstanding, and the costumes and direction are topnotch, also. Do you, personally, need a vacation from the norm? VV is the cure for the anytime blues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big lights, big money, and big laughs like the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This installment of the comedy classic Vacation series is often regarded as "the worst in the series". That couldn't be further from the truth. This is my second favorite in the entire franchise next to the original film. Vegas Vacation was watched by me countless times in the late nineties when I was very young, and really didn't know what the characters were discussing, or even saying for that matter. Along with Fools Rush In, this was my favorite film in my childhood. I recently ran into the National Lampoon's Vacation Collection on Amazon for about $25. What the hell? I'll pay that. I had already watched the first two, and really wanted to dive into the third and rewatch this (keep in mind, at the time, it had been around nine years since I had seen the film). I recently ran into it on Comedy Central, and there was the question again; "what the hell?" The Griswold Family returns to the screen, this time taking a family vacation to Las Vegas. While it isn't much of a family-friendly place, Clark (Chase) and Rusty (Embry) are more than happy to head there and have a damn good time. They even stop at Cousin Eddie's house (Quaid) for more fun, but soon enough, they wind up taking him to Vegas unexpectedly. Let the crazy, nonstop, unrealistic, comedy antics begin. Clark gambles away their money, the wife Ellen (D'Angelo) falls in love with Wayne Newton, Rusty gets a fake ID and wins big, and Audrey (played by the stunning and gorgeous Marisol Nichols) loosens up to become a dancer. It's nothing special, but back in the day, to a five year old, it was colorful, vibrant, jumpy, loud, and off it's own medicine. I loved it. I saw love at first sight when I saw Marisol Nichols play Audrey. Then when I grew older, I questioned if continuity was even brought up when making this sequel. The children look nothing like they did in the first three films. Rusty was an average looking guy, but in this one his a very handsome, grown individual. Audrey has the biggest change of all. She was the homely child in the first three, but in this one she's got black hair and is amazingly gorgeous. Puberty did her well. But who cares? The jokes are somewhat fresh, the scenes are classic (my favorite being the dam boring tour), and the characters return to give it their all once more. Hard to believe that this would be the last time we see these characters in the flesh until thirteen years later when Chevy and Beverly would appear in the short Hotel Hell Vacation. I suspected something like National Lampoon's Australian Vacation, But it was still nice to see them back at it one more time. Vegas Vacation isn't perfect. You could almost think of it has a hopelessly lost spin off that doesn't take too many new routes, or even has appropriately placed characters. It doesn't even have the National Lampoon's name in the title. My only theory is that Warner Bros. (the company that distributed every other Vacation film) wanted to make another film in the franchise. They probably suggested the idea of Vegas with high hopes, National Lampoon maybe scrapped it, and WB went on to do it by themselves with no endorsement of National Lampoon. After all, they do own a part of the name, might as well milk it. No matter, Vegas Vacation is a film I'm proud to call one of my favorite comedies, and my second favorite in the Vacation franchise. Starring: Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols, and Randy Quaid. Directed by: Stephen Kessler.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    dud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this fourth installment in the vacation series is close to abysmal in my opinion.it's cheap gimmickry at it lowest.the first three in the series were all very good,pretty much at the same level of quality of jokes and story.this one was neither funny nor clever.the only good thing about the the whole travesty is Wallace Shawn who has a small role as a black jack dealer.his bit is quite funny.but that's it.otherwise it's sheer tedium.it's worth noting that the words "national lampoon" do not appear before the title,so maybe that says something right there.anyway,if i had known how bad this thing was,i would have booked myself self an appointment for a sinus scraping instead.it would have been more enjoyable.i'll give it 3/10 for Wallace Shawn
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets the number three spot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bjorn (ODDBear)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, Clark Griswold has so far botched a road trip, a European vacation and (most memorably) a Christmas vacation; so why does he continue to make his family go through hell on his endless quest for a fun vacation? That's easy; it's pretty enjoyable for us to watch :) "Vegas Vacation" sits comfortably as the third most enjoyable film in the series; surpassing "European Vacation" but not as enjoyable as "Vacation" or "Christmas Vacation". It's pretty far reaching at times but there are solid moments here; such as Clark damn near destroying a damn and getting crazy (as only Clark Griswold can) playing cards and losing everything. The Wayne Newton gag soon grows tiresome and everything concerning Audrey and Russ pretty much stinks but Randy Quaid delivers once again as obnoxious Cousin Eddie and Chase hasn't lost his touch as the world's most annoying (yet somehow oddly endearing) family dad.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I used to like it, but now I think it is silly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sirus_the_Virus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to really like Vegas Vacation. But I watched it again recently and, well, it wasn't that good. I still give it credit, but it's not that great. Vegas vacation is rated PG, and I can really see it. The film has it's funny moments but really doesn't come alive like the first and third film did. The film is corny, and there are many silly scenes. Ellen(Beverly D'Angelo) is irritating, and in this film she falls head over heels for Wayne Newton. If only I could find these high heels so then I could throw them at her. Vegas Vacation is sort of irritating. It's probably the weakest in the series. It's a silly, silly sequel. Vegas vacation:**/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Griswalds go to Vegas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the forth and last movie about Griswalds. Well , at least until the new remake of "Vacation" doesn't show up. It doesn't have the National Lampoons title , but it is the sequel to previous three movies. It was directed Stephen Kessler. What is more important is that John Hughes (writer of all three movies) isn't the writer of this one. "Vegas vacation" was written by Elisa Bell and Bob Ducsay. It's hard to find a good third movie in the series , much less forth. It's also a risk to make a sequel to an 80's movie . Many of the sequels to 80's movies fails , because they aren't able to capture that specific 80's magic of the original ("Another 48 hours" , "Beverly Hills cop 3", "Blues brothers 2000" for example). Griswalds didn't really needed another sequel , since the third one was really good . So who needed it ? Chevy Chase . After the 1989 he wasn't able to make a successful movie and this was his last attempt to become a major star once more . In the end it's not a bad movie , but it lacks freshness . The writers actually did a lot of work to keep "Vegas vacation" in style of previous movies and for most part the movie resembles Hughes sense of humor. Unfortunately , there are too many moments of boredom when nothing happens and most of the jokes are mildly amusing . The funniest scenes are happening near the ending , when Clark and Eddie go to VERY cheap restaurant and unusual casino (where you can play Rock, paper, scissors ! ). There is also a nice tribute scene to the first movie with the chick in the car. On the other hand the scene at the Hoover Dam is rather unbelievable , even for Clark. The old cast is back and in a good shape  Chevy Chase , Beverly D'Angelo and Randy Quaid. The kids has been recast again . Ethan Embry plays Rusty and Marisol Nichols plays Audrey. I have to say they are my least favorite couple from the whole series. They give very flat performances. Anyway , it's still a quite decent goodbye for Griswalds. It was good to hear Beach boys "Good vibrations " and once again Lindsey Buckhingam "Holiday road" . And the scene with between Clark and the old lonely man shows why the audience liked Clark so much . He isn't too bright , but he's heart is in the right place. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't forget to visit the Dam gift shop....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its the same kind of plot as all the others, Clark decides to take the family to Vegas, and all starts of shenanigans start. Clark starts to lose all the money, Ellen gets chased by Wayne Newton, Rusty becomes a Player, and Audrey becomes a dancer. Cousin Eddie is along for the ride, and so are bad jokes and bad blue screen..... Even though its the poorest one from the franchise, its still likable, thanks to the chemistry between Chase and D'angelo. They just come off so natural that you really don't care if the jokes are rehashed, and Eddie is just in it to stop lethargy setting in. Its predictable, Clark is the only one who gets over his head, while the other three would probably have the time of their lives if they were just left alone. The script isn't the best, and the Dam tour takes you away front he fundamental elements of the story, but or a final Vacation movie, its not to bad, Chase is always a likable screen presence, and there are far worse ways to spend ninety minutes. Dumb silly fun, that you will forget about the minute you turn the TV off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funnier than the other films in the series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did we need this movie? No we did not. It's surprisingly enjoyable though. Not very good, but for my money the best 'Vacation' movie. There are a few inspired bits and pieces, like Chevy Chase and dim cousin Randy Quaid coming across a cut-price casino where the games include scissors paper stone, guess which hand, a coin toss, and guess a number between 1 and 10! Admittedly a lot of the jokes fall flat - Chase's character is an idiot but would he really be stupid enough to climb an electricity pylon about Hoover Dam? - and Wallace Shawn is wasted as an annoying card dealer. But despite its faults and ultimate redundancy it's kind of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a former hotel manager in Vegas, the movie is perfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    db-beurylaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I lived in Las Vegas for 25 years. This movie hits all of the points of a Las Vegas. That's the strength and point of all four of the Vacation movies all that stuff really happens. Except for maybe winning a whole lot of money, but you know that. The really awful buffet in some of the sleazier hotels, the way some dealers can clean you out with every hand, the obligatory trip to Hoover Dam. Heck, one of my friend's girlfriends was actually hit on and picked up by Wayne Newton. Yes you can cook meat on a rock on a hot day and every day in the Summer is a hot day. Rattle snakes radioactivity its all part of Las Vegas fun. This movie hits all of the highlights. Think of it as a travel log with attitude. Loved it. Cast is perfect. Chevy is the unflappable fool tourist who flops around as a fish out of water. Randy Quaid is the kind of guy who is right at home in Las Vegas and proud that his daughter is an "entertainer" But the person who makes it all work is Beverly who takes all the abuse and slyly sticks in her comments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good, But Long-Waited Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Randy Quaid, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols and Wayne Newton star in this 1997 comedy sequel. In this installment, Clark Griswold (Chase) takes his wife, Ellen (D'Angelo) and 2 kids, Rusty (Embry) and Audrey (Nichols) to Las Vegas, Nevada for a family trip. Clark runs into cousin Eddie (Quaid) while getting there and has bad luck. Newton plays himself who falls in love with Ellen and Clark starts getting himself addicted to gambling causing him to lose most of his money and his family starts going their separate ways. Soon, Clark tries to redeem himself and get his family back together. This is a pretty good, but long-waited sequel, Chevy is great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite of the vacation films, go ahead, laugh yourself silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clark Griswold (Chevy Chase) arrives at his home in Chicago, one day, in very high spirits. His wife, Ellen (Beverly D'Angelo) and two kids, Audrey (Marisol Nichols) and Rusty (Ethan Embry) are called to a family meeting. In short order, Clark announces that his new formula for food preservation has garnered a big bonus and he is taking them all to Las Vegas. No one is very excited but they have little choice but to go along. When they arrive in town, the Griswolds take a limo to their hotel, although poor Audrey gets stuck in the moonroof, thanks to her dad. Before long, cousin Eddie (Randy Quaid) shows up, for Ellen has called her cousin, Eddie's wife Catherine, to announce their visit. Eddie promptly watches Clark lose a whopping $300 bucks at the blackjack table, much to the joy of the sadistic dealer, Marty (Wallace Shawn). After the loss, Eddie invites everyone to his house north of Vegas, where the government has given him some lovely, parched, radioactive land. From there, its on to Hoover Dam and to a bunch of shows, including Sigfried & Roy and Wayne Newton. Newton, in fact, makes a play for Ellen in front of the audience, although Clark thinks its part of the act. While Ellen gets invited to have cocktails with Wayne, Clark goes on gambling and the kids, under age, get fake identifications so they can likewise play the tables (Rusty) and try out exotic dancing (Audrey). They even have an encounter with an old, old gambler (Sid Caesar). How will their great adventure end? This is the best of the vacation films, my opinion, even though all are enjoyable. The script is lively and inventive and so, so funny. The cast, too, is excellent, with the main folks reprising their long established roles, and Newton, Embry, Nichols, Shawn, and especially Caesar, adding greatly to the merriment. The scenery is the best of the strip, Eddie's abode notwithstanding, and the costumes and direction are topnotch, also. Do you, personally, need a vacation from the norm? VV is the cure for the anytime blues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big lights, big money, and big laughs like the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This installment of the comedy classic Vacation series is often regarded as "the worst in the series". That couldn't be further from the truth. This is my second favorite in the entire franchise next to the original film. Vegas Vacation was watched by me countless times in the late nineties when I was very young, and really didn't know what the characters were discussing, or even saying for that matter. Along with Fools Rush In, this was my favorite film in my childhood. I recently ran into the National Lampoon's Vacation Collection on Amazon for about $25. What the hell? I'll pay that. I had already watched the first two, and really wanted to dive into the third and rewatch this (keep in mind, at the time, it had been around nine years since I had seen the film). I recently ran into it on Comedy Central, and there was the question again; "what the hell?" The Griswold Family returns to the screen, this time taking a family vacation to Las Vegas. While it isn't much of a family-friendly place, Clark (Chase) and Rusty (Embry) are more than happy to head there and have a damn good time. They even stop at Cousin Eddie's house (Quaid) for more fun, but soon enough, they wind up taking him to Vegas unexpectedly. Let the crazy, nonstop, unrealistic, comedy antics begin. Clark gambles away their money, the wife Ellen (D'Angelo) falls in love with Wayne Newton, Rusty gets a fake ID and wins big, and Audrey (played by the stunning and gorgeous Marisol Nichols) loosens up to become a dancer. It's nothing special, but back in the day, to a five year old, it was colorful, vibrant, jumpy, loud, and off it's own medicine. I loved it. I saw love at first sight when I saw Marisol Nichols play Audrey. Then when I grew older, I questioned if continuity was even brought up when making this sequel. The children look nothing like they did in the first three films. Rusty was an average looking guy, but in this one his a very handsome, grown individual. Audrey has the biggest change of all. She was the homely child in the first three, but in this one she's got black hair and is amazingly gorgeous. Puberty did her well. But who cares? The jokes are somewhat fresh, the scenes are classic (my favorite being the dam boring tour), and the characters return to give it their all once more. Hard to believe that this would be the last time we see these characters in the flesh until thirteen years later when Chevy and Beverly would appear in the short Hotel Hell Vacation. I suspected something like National Lampoon's Australian Vacation, But it was still nice to see them back at it one more time. Vegas Vacation isn't perfect. You could almost think of it has a hopelessly lost spin off that doesn't take too many new routes, or even has appropriately placed characters. It doesn't even have the National Lampoon's name in the title. My only theory is that Warner Bros. (the company that distributed every other Vacation film) wanted to make another film in the franchise. They probably suggested the idea of Vegas with high hopes, National Lampoon maybe scrapped it, and WB went on to do it by themselves with no endorsement of National Lampoon. After all, they do own a part of the name, might as well milk it. No matter, Vegas Vacation is a film I'm proud to call one of my favorite comedies, and my second favorite in the Vacation franchise. Starring: Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols, and Randy Quaid. Directed by: Stephen Kessler.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    dud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this fourth installment in the vacation series is close to abysmal in my opinion.it's cheap gimmickry at it lowest.the first three in the series were all very good,pretty much at the same level of quality of jokes and story.this one was neither funny nor clever.the only good thing about the the whole travesty is Wallace Shawn who has a small role as a black jack dealer.his bit is quite funny.but that's it.otherwise it's sheer tedium.it's worth noting that the words "national lampoon" do not appear before the title,so maybe that says something right there.anyway,if i had known how bad this thing was,i would have booked myself self an appointment for a sinus scraping instead.it would have been more enjoyable.i'll give it 3/10 for Wallace Shawn
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets the number three spot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bjorn (ODDBear)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, Clark Griswold has so far botched a road trip, a European vacation and (most memorably) a Christmas vacation; so why does he continue to make his family go through hell on his endless quest for a fun vacation? That's easy; it's pretty enjoyable for us to watch :) "Vegas Vacation" sits comfortably as the third most enjoyable film in the series; surpassing "European Vacation" but not as enjoyable as "Vacation" or "Christmas Vacation". It's pretty far reaching at times but there are solid moments here; such as Clark damn near destroying a damn and getting crazy (as only Clark Griswold can) playing cards and losing everything. The Wayne Newton gag soon grows tiresome and everything concerning Audrey and Russ pretty much stinks but Randy Quaid delivers once again as obnoxious Cousin Eddie and Chase hasn't lost his touch as the world's most annoying (yet somehow oddly endearing) family dad.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I used to like it, but now I think it is silly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sirus_the_Virus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to really like Vegas Vacation. But I watched it again recently and, well, it wasn't that good. I still give it credit, but it's not that great. Vegas vacation is rated PG, and I can really see it. The film has it's funny moments but really doesn't come alive like the first and third film did. The film is corny, and there are many silly scenes. Ellen(Beverly D'Angelo) is irritating, and in this film she falls head over heels for Wayne Newton. If only I could find these high heels so then I could throw them at her. Vegas Vacation is sort of irritating. It's probably the weakest in the series. It's a silly, silly sequel. Vegas vacation:**/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Griswalds go to Vegas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the forth and last movie about Griswalds. Well , at least until the new remake of "Vacation" doesn't show up. It doesn't have the National Lampoons title , but it is the sequel to previous three movies. It was directed Stephen Kessler. What is more important is that John Hughes (writer of all three movies) isn't the writer of this one. "Vegas vacation" was written by Elisa Bell and Bob Ducsay. It's hard to find a good third movie in the series , much less forth. It's also a risk to make a sequel to an 80's movie . Many of the sequels to 80's movies fails , because they aren't able to capture that specific 80's magic of the original ("Another 48 hours" , "Beverly Hills cop 3", "Blues brothers 2000" for example). Griswalds didn't really needed another sequel , since the third one was really good . So who needed it ? Chevy Chase . After the 1989 he wasn't able to make a successful movie and this was his last attempt to become a major star once more . In the end it's not a bad movie , but it lacks freshness . The writers actually did a lot of work to keep "Vegas vacation" in style of previous movies and for most part the movie resembles Hughes sense of humor. Unfortunately , there are too many moments of boredom when nothing happens and most of the jokes are mildly amusing . The funniest scenes are happening near the ending , when Clark and Eddie go to VERY cheap restaurant and unusual casino (where you can play Rock, paper, scissors ! ). There is also a nice tribute scene to the first movie with the chick in the car. On the other hand the scene at the Hoover Dam is rather unbelievable , even for Clark. The old cast is back and in a good shape  Chevy Chase , Beverly D'Angelo and Randy Quaid. The kids has been recast again . Ethan Embry plays Rusty and Marisol Nichols plays Audrey. I have to say they are my least favorite couple from the whole series. They give very flat performances. Anyway , it's still a quite decent goodbye for Griswalds. It was good to hear Beach boys "Good vibrations " and once again Lindsey Buckhingam "Holiday road" . And the scene with between Clark and the old lonely man shows why the audience liked Clark so much . He isn't too bright , but he's heart is in the right place. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't forget to visit the Dam gift shop....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its the same kind of plot as all the others, Clark decides to take the family to Vegas, and all starts of shenanigans start. Clark starts to lose all the money, Ellen gets chased by Wayne Newton, Rusty becomes a Player, and Audrey becomes a dancer. Cousin Eddie is along for the ride, and so are bad jokes and bad blue screen..... Even though its the poorest one from the franchise, its still likable, thanks to the chemistry between Chase and D'angelo. They just come off so natural that you really don't care if the jokes are rehashed, and Eddie is just in it to stop lethargy setting in. Its predictable, Clark is the only one who gets over his head, while the other three would probably have the time of their lives if they were just left alone. The script isn't the best, and the Dam tour takes you away front he fundamental elements of the story, but or a final Vacation movie, its not to bad, Chase is always a likable screen presence, and there are far worse ways to spend ninety minutes. Dumb silly fun, that you will forget about the minute you turn the TV off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funnier than the other films in the series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did we need this movie? No we did not. It's surprisingly enjoyable though. Not very good, but for my money the best 'Vacation' movie. There are a few inspired bits and pieces, like Chevy Chase and dim cousin Randy Quaid coming across a cut-price casino where the games include scissors paper stone, guess which hand, a coin toss, and guess a number between 1 and 10! Admittedly a lot of the jokes fall flat - Chase's character is an idiot but would he really be stupid enough to climb an electricity pylon about Hoover Dam? - and Wallace Shawn is wasted as an annoying card dealer. But despite its faults and ultimate redundancy it's kind of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a former hotel manager in Vegas, the movie is perfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    db-beurylaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I lived in Las Vegas for 25 years. This movie hits all of the points of a Las Vegas. That's the strength and point of all four of the Vacation movies all that stuff really happens. Except for maybe winning a whole lot of money, but you know that. The really awful buffet in some of the sleazier hotels, the way some dealers can clean you out with every hand, the obligatory trip to Hoover Dam. Heck, one of my friend's girlfriends was actually hit on and picked up by Wayne Newton. Yes you can cook meat on a rock on a hot day and every day in the Summer is a hot day. Rattle snakes radioactivity its all part of Las Vegas fun. This movie hits all of the highlights. Think of it as a travel log with attitude. Loved it. Cast is perfect. Chevy is the unflappable fool tourist who flops around as a fish out of water. Randy Quaid is the kind of guy who is right at home in Las Vegas and proud that his daughter is an "entertainer" But the person who makes it all work is Beverly who takes all the abuse and slyly sticks in her comments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good, But Long-Waited Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Randy Quaid, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols and Wayne Newton star in this 1997 comedy sequel. In this installment, Clark Griswold (Chase) takes his wife, Ellen (D'Angelo) and 2 kids, Rusty (Embry) and Audrey (Nichols) to Las Vegas, Nevada for a family trip. Clark runs into cousin Eddie (Quaid) while getting there and has bad luck. Newton plays himself who falls in love with Ellen and Clark starts getting himself addicted to gambling causing him to lose most of his money and his family starts going their separate ways. Soon, Clark tries to redeem himself and get his family back together. This is a pretty good, but long-waited sequel, Chevy is great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite of the vacation films, go ahead, laugh yourself silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clark Griswold (Chevy Chase) arrives at his home in Chicago, one day, in very high spirits. His wife, Ellen (Beverly D'Angelo) and two kids, Audrey (Marisol Nichols) and Rusty (Ethan Embry) are called to a family meeting. In short order, Clark announces that his new formula for food preservation has garnered a big bonus and he is taking them all to Las Vegas. No one is very excited but they have little choice but to go along. When they arrive in town, the Griswolds take a limo to their hotel, although poor Audrey gets stuck in the moonroof, thanks to her dad. Before long, cousin Eddie (Randy Quaid) shows up, for Ellen has called her cousin, Eddie's wife Catherine, to announce their visit. Eddie promptly watches Clark lose a whopping $300 bucks at the blackjack table, much to the joy of the sadistic dealer, Marty (Wallace Shawn). After the loss, Eddie invites everyone to his house north of Vegas, where the government has given him some lovely, parched, radioactive land. From there, its on to Hoover Dam and to a bunch of shows, including Sigfried & Roy and Wayne Newton. Newton, in fact, makes a play for Ellen in front of the audience, although Clark thinks its part of the act. While Ellen gets invited to have cocktails with Wayne, Clark goes on gambling and the kids, under age, get fake identifications so they can likewise play the tables (Rusty) and try out exotic dancing (Audrey). They even have an encounter with an old, old gambler (Sid Caesar). How will their great adventure end? This is the best of the vacation films, my opinion, even though all are enjoyable. The script is lively and inventive and so, so funny. The cast, too, is excellent, with the main folks reprising their long established roles, and Newton, Embry, Nichols, Shawn, and especially Caesar, adding greatly to the merriment. The scenery is the best of the strip, Eddie's abode notwithstanding, and the costumes and direction are topnotch, also. Do you, personally, need a vacation from the norm? VV is the cure for the anytime blues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big lights, big money, and big laughs like the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This installment of the comedy classic Vacation series is often regarded as "the worst in the series". That couldn't be further from the truth. This is my second favorite in the entire franchise next to the original film. Vegas Vacation was watched by me countless times in the late nineties when I was very young, and really didn't know what the characters were discussing, or even saying for that matter. Along with Fools Rush In, this was my favorite film in my childhood. I recently ran into the National Lampoon's Vacation Collection on Amazon for about $25. What the hell? I'll pay that. I had already watched the first two, and really wanted to dive into the third and rewatch this (keep in mind, at the time, it had been around nine years since I had seen the film). I recently ran into it on Comedy Central, and there was the question again; "what the hell?" The Griswold Family returns to the screen, this time taking a family vacation to Las Vegas. While it isn't much of a family-friendly place, Clark (Chase) and Rusty (Embry) are more than happy to head there and have a damn good time. They even stop at Cousin Eddie's house (Quaid) for more fun, but soon enough, they wind up taking him to Vegas unexpectedly. Let the crazy, nonstop, unrealistic, comedy antics begin. Clark gambles away their money, the wife Ellen (D'Angelo) falls in love with Wayne Newton, Rusty gets a fake ID and wins big, and Audrey (played by the stunning and gorgeous Marisol Nichols) loosens up to become a dancer. It's nothing special, but back in the day, to a five year old, it was colorful, vibrant, jumpy, loud, and off it's own medicine. I loved it. I saw love at first sight when I saw Marisol Nichols play Audrey. Then when I grew older, I questioned if continuity was even brought up when making this sequel. The children look nothing like they did in the first three films. Rusty was an average looking guy, but in this one his a very handsome, grown individual. Audrey has the biggest change of all. She was the homely child in the first three, but in this one she's got black hair and is amazingly gorgeous. Puberty did her well. But who cares? The jokes are somewhat fresh, the scenes are classic (my favorite being the dam boring tour), and the characters return to give it their all once more. Hard to believe that this would be the last time we see these characters in the flesh until thirteen years later when Chevy and Beverly would appear in the short Hotel Hell Vacation. I suspected something like National Lampoon's Australian Vacation, But it was still nice to see them back at it one more time. Vegas Vacation isn't perfect. You could almost think of it has a hopelessly lost spin off that doesn't take too many new routes, or even has appropriately placed characters. It doesn't even have the National Lampoon's name in the title. My only theory is that Warner Bros. (the company that distributed every other Vacation film) wanted to make another film in the franchise. They probably suggested the idea of Vegas with high hopes, National Lampoon maybe scrapped it, and WB went on to do it by themselves with no endorsement of National Lampoon. After all, they do own a part of the name, might as well milk it. No matter, Vegas Vacation is a film I'm proud to call one of my favorite comedies, and my second favorite in the Vacation franchise. Starring: Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols, and Randy Quaid. Directed by: Stephen Kessler.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    dud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this fourth installment in the vacation series is close to abysmal in my opinion.it's cheap gimmickry at it lowest.the first three in the series were all very good,pretty much at the same level of quality of jokes and story.this one was neither funny nor clever.the only good thing about the the whole travesty is Wallace Shawn who has a small role as a black jack dealer.his bit is quite funny.but that's it.otherwise it's sheer tedium.it's worth noting that the words "national lampoon" do not appear before the title,so maybe that says something right there.anyway,if i had known how bad this thing was,i would have booked myself self an appointment for a sinus scraping instead.it would have been more enjoyable.i'll give it 3/10 for Wallace Shawn
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets the number three spot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bjorn (ODDBear)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, Clark Griswold has so far botched a road trip, a European vacation and (most memorably) a Christmas vacation; so why does he continue to make his family go through hell on his endless quest for a fun vacation? That's easy; it's pretty enjoyable for us to watch :) "Vegas Vacation" sits comfortably as the third most enjoyable film in the series; surpassing "European Vacation" but not as enjoyable as "Vacation" or "Christmas Vacation". It's pretty far reaching at times but there are solid moments here; such as Clark damn near destroying a damn and getting crazy (as only Clark Griswold can) playing cards and losing everything. The Wayne Newton gag soon grows tiresome and everything concerning Audrey and Russ pretty much stinks but Randy Quaid delivers once again as obnoxious Cousin Eddie and Chase hasn't lost his touch as the world's most annoying (yet somehow oddly endearing) family dad.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I used to like it, but now I think it is silly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sirus_the_Virus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to really like Vegas Vacation. But I watched it again recently and, well, it wasn't that good. I still give it credit, but it's not that great. Vegas vacation is rated PG, and I can really see it. The film has it's funny moments but really doesn't come alive like the first and third film did. The film is corny, and there are many silly scenes. Ellen(Beverly D'Angelo) is irritating, and in this film she falls head over heels for Wayne Newton. If only I could find these high heels so then I could throw them at her. Vegas Vacation is sort of irritating. It's probably the weakest in the series. It's a silly, silly sequel. Vegas vacation:**/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Griswalds go to Vegas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the forth and last movie about Griswalds. Well , at least until the new remake of "Vacation" doesn't show up. It doesn't have the National Lampoons title , but it is the sequel to previous three movies. It was directed Stephen Kessler. What is more important is that John Hughes (writer of all three movies) isn't the writer of this one. "Vegas vacation" was written by Elisa Bell and Bob Ducsay. It's hard to find a good third movie in the series , much less forth. It's also a risk to make a sequel to an 80's movie . Many of the sequels to 80's movies fails , because they aren't able to capture that specific 80's magic of the original ("Another 48 hours" , "Beverly Hills cop 3", "Blues brothers 2000" for example). Griswalds didn't really needed another sequel , since the third one was really good . So who needed it ? Chevy Chase . After the 1989 he wasn't able to make a successful movie and this was his last attempt to become a major star once more . In the end it's not a bad movie , but it lacks freshness . The writers actually did a lot of work to keep "Vegas vacation" in style of previous movies and for most part the movie resembles Hughes sense of humor. Unfortunately , there are too many moments of boredom when nothing happens and most of the jokes are mildly amusing . The funniest scenes are happening near the ending , when Clark and Eddie go to VERY cheap restaurant and unusual casino (where you can play Rock, paper, scissors ! ). There is also a nice tribute scene to the first movie with the chick in the car. On the other hand the scene at the Hoover Dam is rather unbelievable , even for Clark. The old cast is back and in a good shape  Chevy Chase , Beverly D'Angelo and Randy Quaid. The kids has been recast again . Ethan Embry plays Rusty and Marisol Nichols plays Audrey. I have to say they are my least favorite couple from the whole series. They give very flat performances. Anyway , it's still a quite decent goodbye for Griswalds. It was good to hear Beach boys "Good vibrations " and once again Lindsey Buckhingam "Holiday road" . And the scene with between Clark and the old lonely man shows why the audience liked Clark so much . He isn't too bright , but he's heart is in the right place. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't forget to visit the Dam gift shop....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its the same kind of plot as all the others, Clark decides to take the family to Vegas, and all starts of shenanigans start. Clark starts to lose all the money, Ellen gets chased by Wayne Newton, Rusty becomes a Player, and Audrey becomes a dancer. Cousin Eddie is along for the ride, and so are bad jokes and bad blue screen..... Even though its the poorest one from the franchise, its still likable, thanks to the chemistry between Chase and D'angelo. They just come off so natural that you really don't care if the jokes are rehashed, and Eddie is just in it to stop lethargy setting in. Its predictable, Clark is the only one who gets over his head, while the other three would probably have the time of their lives if they were just left alone. The script isn't the best, and the Dam tour takes you away front he fundamental elements of the story, but or a final Vacation movie, its not to bad, Chase is always a likable screen presence, and there are far worse ways to spend ninety minutes. Dumb silly fun, that you will forget about the minute you turn the TV off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funnier than the other films in the series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did we need this movie? No we did not. It's surprisingly enjoyable though. Not very good, but for my money the best 'Vacation' movie. There are a few inspired bits and pieces, like Chevy Chase and dim cousin Randy Quaid coming across a cut-price casino where the games include scissors paper stone, guess which hand, a coin toss, and guess a number between 1 and 10! Admittedly a lot of the jokes fall flat - Chase's character is an idiot but would he really be stupid enough to climb an electricity pylon about Hoover Dam? - and Wallace Shawn is wasted as an annoying card dealer. But despite its faults and ultimate redundancy it's kind of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a former hotel manager in Vegas, the movie is perfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    db-beurylaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I lived in Las Vegas for 25 years. This movie hits all of the points of a Las Vegas. That's the strength and point of all four of the Vacation movies all that stuff really happens. Except for maybe winning a whole lot of money, but you know that. The really awful buffet in some of the sleazier hotels, the way some dealers can clean you out with every hand, the obligatory trip to Hoover Dam. Heck, one of my friend's girlfriends was actually hit on and picked up by Wayne Newton. Yes you can cook meat on a rock on a hot day and every day in the Summer is a hot day. Rattle snakes radioactivity its all part of Las Vegas fun. This movie hits all of the highlights. Think of it as a travel log with attitude. Loved it. Cast is perfect. Chevy is the unflappable fool tourist who flops around as a fish out of water. Randy Quaid is the kind of guy who is right at home in Las Vegas and proud that his daughter is an "entertainer" But the person who makes it all work is Beverly who takes all the abuse and slyly sticks in her comments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good, But Long-Waited Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Randy Quaid, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols and Wayne Newton star in this 1997 comedy sequel. In this installment, Clark Griswold (Chase) takes his wife, Ellen (D'Angelo) and 2 kids, Rusty (Embry) and Audrey (Nichols) to Las Vegas, Nevada for a family trip. Clark runs into cousin Eddie (Quaid) while getting there and has bad luck. Newton plays himself who falls in love with Ellen and Clark starts getting himself addicted to gambling causing him to lose most of his money and his family starts going their separate ways. Soon, Clark tries to redeem himself and get his family back together. This is a pretty good, but long-waited sequel, Chevy is great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite of the vacation films, go ahead, laugh yourself silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clark Griswold (Chevy Chase) arrives at his home in Chicago, one day, in very high spirits. His wife, Ellen (Beverly D'Angelo) and two kids, Audrey (Marisol Nichols) and Rusty (Ethan Embry) are called to a family meeting. In short order, Clark announces that his new formula for food preservation has garnered a big bonus and he is taking them all to Las Vegas. No one is very excited but they have little choice but to go along. When they arrive in town, the Griswolds take a limo to their hotel, although poor Audrey gets stuck in the moonroof, thanks to her dad. Before long, cousin Eddie (Randy Quaid) shows up, for Ellen has called her cousin, Eddie's wife Catherine, to announce their visit. Eddie promptly watches Clark lose a whopping $300 bucks at the blackjack table, much to the joy of the sadistic dealer, Marty (Wallace Shawn). After the loss, Eddie invites everyone to his house north of Vegas, where the government has given him some lovely, parched, radioactive land. From there, its on to Hoover Dam and to a bunch of shows, including Sigfried & Roy and Wayne Newton. Newton, in fact, makes a play for Ellen in front of the audience, although Clark thinks its part of the act. While Ellen gets invited to have cocktails with Wayne, Clark goes on gambling and the kids, under age, get fake identifications so they can likewise play the tables (Rusty) and try out exotic dancing (Audrey). They even have an encounter with an old, old gambler (Sid Caesar). How will their great adventure end? This is the best of the vacation films, my opinion, even though all are enjoyable. The script is lively and inventive and so, so funny. The cast, too, is excellent, with the main folks reprising their long established roles, and Newton, Embry, Nichols, Shawn, and especially Caesar, adding greatly to the merriment. The scenery is the best of the strip, Eddie's abode notwithstanding, and the costumes and direction are topnotch, also. Do you, personally, need a vacation from the norm? VV is the cure for the anytime blues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big lights, big money, and big laughs like the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This installment of the comedy classic Vacation series is often regarded as "the worst in the series". That couldn't be further from the truth. This is my second favorite in the entire franchise next to the original film. Vegas Vacation was watched by me countless times in the late nineties when I was very young, and really didn't know what the characters were discussing, or even saying for that matter. Along with Fools Rush In, this was my favorite film in my childhood. I recently ran into the National Lampoon's Vacation Collection on Amazon for about $25. What the hell? I'll pay that. I had already watched the first two, and really wanted to dive into the third and rewatch this (keep in mind, at the time, it had been around nine years since I had seen the film). I recently ran into it on Comedy Central, and there was the question again; "what the hell?" The Griswold Family returns to the screen, this time taking a family vacation to Las Vegas. While it isn't much of a family-friendly place, Clark (Chase) and Rusty (Embry) are more than happy to head there and have a damn good time. They even stop at Cousin Eddie's house (Quaid) for more fun, but soon enough, they wind up taking him to Vegas unexpectedly. Let the crazy, nonstop, unrealistic, comedy antics begin. Clark gambles away their money, the wife Ellen (D'Angelo) falls in love with Wayne Newton, Rusty gets a fake ID and wins big, and Audrey (played by the stunning and gorgeous Marisol Nichols) loosens up to become a dancer. It's nothing special, but back in the day, to a five year old, it was colorful, vibrant, jumpy, loud, and off it's own medicine. I loved it. I saw love at first sight when I saw Marisol Nichols play Audrey. Then when I grew older, I questioned if continuity was even brought up when making this sequel. The children look nothing like they did in the first three films. Rusty was an average looking guy, but in this one his a very handsome, grown individual. Audrey has the biggest change of all. She was the homely child in the first three, but in this one she's got black hair and is amazingly gorgeous. Puberty did her well. But who cares? The jokes are somewhat fresh, the scenes are classic (my favorite being the dam boring tour), and the characters return to give it their all once more. Hard to believe that this would be the last time we see these characters in the flesh until thirteen years later when Chevy and Beverly would appear in the short Hotel Hell Vacation. I suspected something like National Lampoon's Australian Vacation, But it was still nice to see them back at it one more time. Vegas Vacation isn't perfect. You could almost think of it has a hopelessly lost spin off that doesn't take too many new routes, or even has appropriately placed characters. It doesn't even have the National Lampoon's name in the title. My only theory is that Warner Bros. (the company that distributed every other Vacation film) wanted to make another film in the franchise. They probably suggested the idea of Vegas with high hopes, National Lampoon maybe scrapped it, and WB went on to do it by themselves with no endorsement of National Lampoon. After all, they do own a part of the name, might as well milk it. No matter, Vegas Vacation is a film I'm proud to call one of my favorite comedies, and my second favorite in the Vacation franchise. Starring: Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols, and Randy Quaid. Directed by: Stephen Kessler.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    dud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this fourth installment in the vacation series is close to abysmal in my opinion.it's cheap gimmickry at it lowest.the first three in the series were all very good,pretty much at the same level of quality of jokes and story.this one was neither funny nor clever.the only good thing about the the whole travesty is Wallace Shawn who has a small role as a black jack dealer.his bit is quite funny.but that's it.otherwise it's sheer tedium.it's worth noting that the words "national lampoon" do not appear before the title,so maybe that says something right there.anyway,if i had known how bad this thing was,i would have booked myself self an appointment for a sinus scraping instead.it would have been more enjoyable.i'll give it 3/10 for Wallace Shawn
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets the number three spot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bjorn (ODDBear)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, Clark Griswold has so far botched a road trip, a European vacation and (most memorably) a Christmas vacation; so why does he continue to make his family go through hell on his endless quest for a fun vacation? That's easy; it's pretty enjoyable for us to watch :) "Vegas Vacation" sits comfortably as the third most enjoyable film in the series; surpassing "European Vacation" but not as enjoyable as "Vacation" or "Christmas Vacation". It's pretty far reaching at times but there are solid moments here; such as Clark damn near destroying a damn and getting crazy (as only Clark Griswold can) playing cards and losing everything. The Wayne Newton gag soon grows tiresome and everything concerning Audrey and Russ pretty much stinks but Randy Quaid delivers once again as obnoxious Cousin Eddie and Chase hasn't lost his touch as the world's most annoying (yet somehow oddly endearing) family dad.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I used to like it, but now I think it is silly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sirus_the_Virus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to really like Vegas Vacation. But I watched it again recently and, well, it wasn't that good. I still give it credit, but it's not that great. Vegas vacation is rated PG, and I can really see it. The film has it's funny moments but really doesn't come alive like the first and third film did. The film is corny, and there are many silly scenes. Ellen(Beverly D'Angelo) is irritating, and in this film she falls head over heels for Wayne Newton. If only I could find these high heels so then I could throw them at her. Vegas Vacation is sort of irritating. It's probably the weakest in the series. It's a silly, silly sequel. Vegas vacation:**/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Griswalds go to Vegas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the forth and last movie about Griswalds. Well , at least until the new remake of "Vacation" doesn't show up. It doesn't have the National Lampoons title , but it is the sequel to previous three movies. It was directed Stephen Kessler. What is more important is that John Hughes (writer of all three movies) isn't the writer of this one. "Vegas vacation" was written by Elisa Bell and Bob Ducsay. It's hard to find a good third movie in the series , much less forth. It's also a risk to make a sequel to an 80's movie . Many of the sequels to 80's movies fails , because they aren't able to capture that specific 80's magic of the original ("Another 48 hours" , "Beverly Hills cop 3", "Blues brothers 2000" for example). Griswalds didn't really needed another sequel , since the third one was really good . So who needed it ? Chevy Chase . After the 1989 he wasn't able to make a successful movie and this was his last attempt to become a major star once more . In the end it's not a bad movie , but it lacks freshness . The writers actually did a lot of work to keep "Vegas vacation" in style of previous movies and for most part the movie resembles Hughes sense of humor. Unfortunately , there are too many moments of boredom when nothing happens and most of the jokes are mildly amusing . The funniest scenes are happening near the ending , when Clark and Eddie go to VERY cheap restaurant and unusual casino (where you can play Rock, paper, scissors ! ). There is also a nice tribute scene to the first movie with the chick in the car. On the other hand the scene at the Hoover Dam is rather unbelievable , even for Clark. The old cast is back and in a good shape  Chevy Chase , Beverly D'Angelo and Randy Quaid. The kids has been recast again . Ethan Embry plays Rusty and Marisol Nichols plays Audrey. I have to say they are my least favorite couple from the whole series. They give very flat performances. Anyway , it's still a quite decent goodbye for Griswalds. It was good to hear Beach boys "Good vibrations " and once again Lindsey Buckhingam "Holiday road" . And the scene with between Clark and the old lonely man shows why the audience liked Clark so much . He isn't too bright , but he's heart is in the right place. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't forget to visit the Dam gift shop....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its the same kind of plot as all the others, Clark decides to take the family to Vegas, and all starts of shenanigans start. Clark starts to lose all the money, Ellen gets chased by Wayne Newton, Rusty becomes a Player, and Audrey becomes a dancer. Cousin Eddie is along for the ride, and so are bad jokes and bad blue screen..... Even though its the poorest one from the franchise, its still likable, thanks to the chemistry between Chase and D'angelo. They just come off so natural that you really don't care if the jokes are rehashed, and Eddie is just in it to stop lethargy setting in. Its predictable, Clark is the only one who gets over his head, while the other three would probably have the time of their lives if they were just left alone. The script isn't the best, and the Dam tour takes you away front he fundamental elements of the story, but or a final Vacation movie, its not to bad, Chase is always a likable screen presence, and there are far worse ways to spend ninety minutes. Dumb silly fun, that you will forget about the minute you turn the TV off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funnier than the other films in the series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did we need this movie? No we did not. It's surprisingly enjoyable though. Not very good, but for my money the best 'Vacation' movie. There are a few inspired bits and pieces, like Chevy Chase and dim cousin Randy Quaid coming across a cut-price casino where the games include scissors paper stone, guess which hand, a coin toss, and guess a number between 1 and 10! Admittedly a lot of the jokes fall flat - Chase's character is an idiot but would he really be stupid enough to climb an electricity pylon about Hoover Dam? - and Wallace Shawn is wasted as an annoying card dealer. But despite its faults and ultimate redundancy it's kind of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a former hotel manager in Vegas, the movie is perfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    db-beurylaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I lived in Las Vegas for 25 years. This movie hits all of the points of a Las Vegas. That's the strength and point of all four of the Vacation movies all that stuff really happens. Except for maybe winning a whole lot of money, but you know that. The really awful buffet in some of the sleazier hotels, the way some dealers can clean you out with every hand, the obligatory trip to Hoover Dam. Heck, one of my friend's girlfriends was actually hit on and picked up by Wayne Newton. Yes you can cook meat on a rock on a hot day and every day in the Summer is a hot day. Rattle snakes radioactivity its all part of Las Vegas fun. This movie hits all of the highlights. Think of it as a travel log with attitude. Loved it. Cast is perfect. Chevy is the unflappable fool tourist who flops around as a fish out of water. Randy Quaid is the kind of guy who is right at home in Las Vegas and proud that his daughter is an "entertainer" But the person who makes it all work is Beverly who takes all the abuse and slyly sticks in her comments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good, But Long-Waited Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Randy Quaid, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols and Wayne Newton star in this 1997 comedy sequel. In this installment, Clark Griswold (Chase) takes his wife, Ellen (D'Angelo) and 2 kids, Rusty (Embry) and Audrey (Nichols) to Las Vegas, Nevada for a family trip. Clark runs into cousin Eddie (Quaid) while getting there and has bad luck. Newton plays himself who falls in love with Ellen and Clark starts getting himself addicted to gambling causing him to lose most of his money and his family starts going their separate ways. Soon, Clark tries to redeem himself and get his family back together. This is a pretty good, but long-waited sequel, Chevy is great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite of the vacation films, go ahead, laugh yourself silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clark Griswold (Chevy Chase) arrives at his home in Chicago, one day, in very high spirits. His wife, Ellen (Beverly D'Angelo) and two kids, Audrey (Marisol Nichols) and Rusty (Ethan Embry) are called to a family meeting. In short order, Clark announces that his new formula for food preservation has garnered a big bonus and he is taking them all to Las Vegas. No one is very excited but they have little choice but to go along. When they arrive in town, the Griswolds take a limo to their hotel, although poor Audrey gets stuck in the moonroof, thanks to her dad. Before long, cousin Eddie (Randy Quaid) shows up, for Ellen has called her cousin, Eddie's wife Catherine, to announce their visit. Eddie promptly watches Clark lose a whopping $300 bucks at the blackjack table, much to the joy of the sadistic dealer, Marty (Wallace Shawn). After the loss, Eddie invites everyone to his house north of Vegas, where the government has given him some lovely, parched, radioactive land. From there, its on to Hoover Dam and to a bunch of shows, including Sigfried & Roy and Wayne Newton. Newton, in fact, makes a play for Ellen in front of the audience, although Clark thinks its part of the act. While Ellen gets invited to have cocktails with Wayne, Clark goes on gambling and the kids, under age, get fake identifications so they can likewise play the tables (Rusty) and try out exotic dancing (Audrey). They even have an encounter with an old, old gambler (Sid Caesar). How will their great adventure end? This is the best of the vacation films, my opinion, even though all are enjoyable. The script is lively and inventive and so, so funny. The cast, too, is excellent, with the main folks reprising their long established roles, and Newton, Embry, Nichols, Shawn, and especially Caesar, adding greatly to the merriment. The scenery is the best of the strip, Eddie's abode notwithstanding, and the costumes and direction are topnotch, also. Do you, personally, need a vacation from the norm? VV is the cure for the anytime blues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big lights, big money, and big laughs like the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This installment of the comedy classic Vacation series is often regarded as "the worst in the series". That couldn't be further from the truth. This is my second favorite in the entire franchise next to the original film. Vegas Vacation was watched by me countless times in the late nineties when I was very young, and really didn't know what the characters were discussing, or even saying for that matter. Along with Fools Rush In, this was my favorite film in my childhood. I recently ran into the National Lampoon's Vacation Collection on Amazon for about $25. What the hell? I'll pay that. I had already watched the first two, and really wanted to dive into the third and rewatch this (keep in mind, at the time, it had been around nine years since I had seen the film). I recently ran into it on Comedy Central, and there was the question again; "what the hell?" The Griswold Family returns to the screen, this time taking a family vacation to Las Vegas. While it isn't much of a family-friendly place, Clark (Chase) and Rusty (Embry) are more than happy to head there and have a damn good time. They even stop at Cousin Eddie's house (Quaid) for more fun, but soon enough, they wind up taking him to Vegas unexpectedly. Let the crazy, nonstop, unrealistic, comedy antics begin. Clark gambles away their money, the wife Ellen (D'Angelo) falls in love with Wayne Newton, Rusty gets a fake ID and wins big, and Audrey (played by the stunning and gorgeous Marisol Nichols) loosens up to become a dancer. It's nothing special, but back in the day, to a five year old, it was colorful, vibrant, jumpy, loud, and off it's own medicine. I loved it. I saw love at first sight when I saw Marisol Nichols play Audrey. Then when I grew older, I questioned if continuity was even brought up when making this sequel. The children look nothing like they did in the first three films. Rusty was an average looking guy, but in this one his a very handsome, grown individual. Audrey has the biggest change of all. She was the homely child in the first three, but in this one she's got black hair and is amazingly gorgeous. Puberty did her well. But who cares? The jokes are somewhat fresh, the scenes are classic (my favorite being the dam boring tour), and the characters return to give it their all once more. Hard to believe that this would be the last time we see these characters in the flesh until thirteen years later when Chevy and Beverly would appear in the short Hotel Hell Vacation. I suspected something like National Lampoon's Australian Vacation, But it was still nice to see them back at it one more time. Vegas Vacation isn't perfect. You could almost think of it has a hopelessly lost spin off that doesn't take too many new routes, or even has appropriately placed characters. It doesn't even have the National Lampoon's name in the title. My only theory is that Warner Bros. (the company that distributed every other Vacation film) wanted to make another film in the franchise. They probably suggested the idea of Vegas with high hopes, National Lampoon maybe scrapped it, and WB went on to do it by themselves with no endorsement of National Lampoon. After all, they do own a part of the name, might as well milk it. No matter, Vegas Vacation is a film I'm proud to call one of my favorite comedies, and my second favorite in the Vacation franchise. Starring: Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols, and Randy Quaid. Directed by: Stephen Kessler.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    dud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this fourth installment in the vacation series is close to abysmal in my opinion.it's cheap gimmickry at it lowest.the first three in the series were all very good,pretty much at the same level of quality of jokes and story.this one was neither funny nor clever.the only good thing about the the whole travesty is Wallace Shawn who has a small role as a black jack dealer.his bit is quite funny.but that's it.otherwise it's sheer tedium.it's worth noting that the words "national lampoon" do not appear before the title,so maybe that says something right there.anyway,if i had known how bad this thing was,i would have booked myself self an appointment for a sinus scraping instead.it would have been more enjoyable.i'll give it 3/10 for Wallace Shawn
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets the number three spot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bjorn (ODDBear)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, Clark Griswold has so far botched a road trip, a European vacation and (most memorably) a Christmas vacation; so why does he continue to make his family go through hell on his endless quest for a fun vacation? That's easy; it's pretty enjoyable for us to watch :) "Vegas Vacation" sits comfortably as the third most enjoyable film in the series; surpassing "European Vacation" but not as enjoyable as "Vacation" or "Christmas Vacation". It's pretty far reaching at times but there are solid moments here; such as Clark damn near destroying a damn and getting crazy (as only Clark Griswold can) playing cards and losing everything. The Wayne Newton gag soon grows tiresome and everything concerning Audrey and Russ pretty much stinks but Randy Quaid delivers once again as obnoxious Cousin Eddie and Chase hasn't lost his touch as the world's most annoying (yet somehow oddly endearing) family dad.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I used to like it, but now I think it is silly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sirus_the_Virus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to really like Vegas Vacation. But I watched it again recently and, well, it wasn't that good. I still give it credit, but it's not that great. Vegas vacation is rated PG, and I can really see it. The film has it's funny moments but really doesn't come alive like the first and third film did. The film is corny, and there are many silly scenes. Ellen(Beverly D'Angelo) is irritating, and in this film she falls head over heels for Wayne Newton. If only I could find these high heels so then I could throw them at her. Vegas Vacation is sort of irritating. It's probably the weakest in the series. It's a silly, silly sequel. Vegas vacation:**/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Griswalds go to Vegas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the forth and last movie about Griswalds. Well , at least until the new remake of "Vacation" doesn't show up. It doesn't have the National Lampoons title , but it is the sequel to previous three movies. It was directed Stephen Kessler. What is more important is that John Hughes (writer of all three movies) isn't the writer of this one. "Vegas vacation" was written by Elisa Bell and Bob Ducsay. It's hard to find a good third movie in the series , much less forth. It's also a risk to make a sequel to an 80's movie . Many of the sequels to 80's movies fails , because they aren't able to capture that specific 80's magic of the original ("Another 48 hours" , "Beverly Hills cop 3", "Blues brothers 2000" for example). Griswalds didn't really needed another sequel , since the third one was really good . So who needed it ? Chevy Chase . After the 1989 he wasn't able to make a successful movie and this was his last attempt to become a major star once more . In the end it's not a bad movie , but it lacks freshness . The writers actually did a lot of work to keep "Vegas vacation" in style of previous movies and for most part the movie resembles Hughes sense of humor. Unfortunately , there are too many moments of boredom when nothing happens and most of the jokes are mildly amusing . The funniest scenes are happening near the ending , when Clark and Eddie go to VERY cheap restaurant and unusual casino (where you can play Rock, paper, scissors ! ). There is also a nice tribute scene to the first movie with the chick in the car. On the other hand the scene at the Hoover Dam is rather unbelievable , even for Clark. The old cast is back and in a good shape  Chevy Chase , Beverly D'Angelo and Randy Quaid. The kids has been recast again . Ethan Embry plays Rusty and Marisol Nichols plays Audrey. I have to say they are my least favorite couple from the whole series. They give very flat performances. Anyway , it's still a quite decent goodbye for Griswalds. It was good to hear Beach boys "Good vibrations " and once again Lindsey Buckhingam "Holiday road" . And the scene with between Clark and the old lonely man shows why the audience liked Clark so much . He isn't too bright , but he's heart is in the right place. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't forget to visit the Dam gift shop....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its the same kind of plot as all the others, Clark decides to take the family to Vegas, and all starts of shenanigans start. Clark starts to lose all the money, Ellen gets chased by Wayne Newton, Rusty becomes a Player, and Audrey becomes a dancer. Cousin Eddie is along for the ride, and so are bad jokes and bad blue screen..... Even though its the poorest one from the franchise, its still likable, thanks to the chemistry between Chase and D'angelo. They just come off so natural that you really don't care if the jokes are rehashed, and Eddie is just in it to stop lethargy setting in. Its predictable, Clark is the only one who gets over his head, while the other three would probably have the time of their lives if they were just left alone. The script isn't the best, and the Dam tour takes you away front he fundamental elements of the story, but or a final Vacation movie, its not to bad, Chase is always a likable screen presence, and there are far worse ways to spend ninety minutes. Dumb silly fun, that you will forget about the minute you turn the TV off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funnier than the other films in the series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did we need this movie? No we did not. It's surprisingly enjoyable though. Not very good, but for my money the best 'Vacation' movie. There are a few inspired bits and pieces, like Chevy Chase and dim cousin Randy Quaid coming across a cut-price casino where the games include scissors paper stone, guess which hand, a coin toss, and guess a number between 1 and 10! Admittedly a lot of the jokes fall flat - Chase's character is an idiot but would he really be stupid enough to climb an electricity pylon about Hoover Dam? - and Wallace Shawn is wasted as an annoying card dealer. But despite its faults and ultimate redundancy it's kind of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a former hotel manager in Vegas, the movie is perfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    db-beurylaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I lived in Las Vegas for 25 years. This movie hits all of the points of a Las Vegas. That's the strength and point of all four of the Vacation movies all that stuff really happens. Except for maybe winning a whole lot of money, but you know that. The really awful buffet in some of the sleazier hotels, the way some dealers can clean you out with every hand, the obligatory trip to Hoover Dam. Heck, one of my friend's girlfriends was actually hit on and picked up by Wayne Newton. Yes you can cook meat on a rock on a hot day and every day in the Summer is a hot day. Rattle snakes radioactivity its all part of Las Vegas fun. This movie hits all of the highlights. Think of it as a travel log with attitude. Loved it. Cast is perfect. Chevy is the unflappable fool tourist who flops around as a fish out of water. Randy Quaid is the kind of guy who is right at home in Las Vegas and proud that his daughter is an "entertainer" But the person who makes it all work is Beverly who takes all the abuse and slyly sticks in her comments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good, But Long-Waited Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Randy Quaid, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols and Wayne Newton star in this 1997 comedy sequel. In this installment, Clark Griswold (Chase) takes his wife, Ellen (D'Angelo) and 2 kids, Rusty (Embry) and Audrey (Nichols) to Las Vegas, Nevada for a family trip. Clark runs into cousin Eddie (Quaid) while getting there and has bad luck. Newton plays himself who falls in love with Ellen and Clark starts getting himself addicted to gambling causing him to lose most of his money and his family starts going their separate ways. Soon, Clark tries to redeem himself and get his family back together. This is a pretty good, but long-waited sequel, Chevy is great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite of the vacation films, go ahead, laugh yourself silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clark Griswold (Chevy Chase) arrives at his home in Chicago, one day, in very high spirits. His wife, Ellen (Beverly D'Angelo) and two kids, Audrey (Marisol Nichols) and Rusty (Ethan Embry) are called to a family meeting. In short order, Clark announces that his new formula for food preservation has garnered a big bonus and he is taking them all to Las Vegas. No one is very excited but they have little choice but to go along. When they arrive in town, the Griswolds take a limo to their hotel, although poor Audrey gets stuck in the moonroof, thanks to her dad. Before long, cousin Eddie (Randy Quaid) shows up, for Ellen has called her cousin, Eddie's wife Catherine, to announce their visit. Eddie promptly watches Clark lose a whopping $300 bucks at the blackjack table, much to the joy of the sadistic dealer, Marty (Wallace Shawn). After the loss, Eddie invites everyone to his house north of Vegas, where the government has given him some lovely, parched, radioactive land. From there, its on to Hoover Dam and to a bunch of shows, including Sigfried & Roy and Wayne Newton. Newton, in fact, makes a play for Ellen in front of the audience, although Clark thinks its part of the act. While Ellen gets invited to have cocktails with Wayne, Clark goes on gambling and the kids, under age, get fake identifications so they can likewise play the tables (Rusty) and try out exotic dancing (Audrey). They even have an encounter with an old, old gambler (Sid Caesar). How will their great adventure end? This is the best of the vacation films, my opinion, even though all are enjoyable. The script is lively and inventive and so, so funny. The cast, too, is excellent, with the main folks reprising their long established roles, and Newton, Embry, Nichols, Shawn, and especially Caesar, adding greatly to the merriment. The scenery is the best of the strip, Eddie's abode notwithstanding, and the costumes and direction are topnotch, also. Do you, personally, need a vacation from the norm? VV is the cure for the anytime blues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big lights, big money, and big laughs like the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This installment of the comedy classic Vacation series is often regarded as "the worst in the series". That couldn't be further from the truth. This is my second favorite in the entire franchise next to the original film. Vegas Vacation was watched by me countless times in the late nineties when I was very young, and really didn't know what the characters were discussing, or even saying for that matter. Along with Fools Rush In, this was my favorite film in my childhood. I recently ran into the National Lampoon's Vacation Collection on Amazon for about $25. What the hell? I'll pay that. I had already watched the first two, and really wanted to dive into the third and rewatch this (keep in mind, at the time, it had been around nine years since I had seen the film). I recently ran into it on Comedy Central, and there was the question again; "what the hell?" The Griswold Family returns to the screen, this time taking a family vacation to Las Vegas. While it isn't much of a family-friendly place, Clark (Chase) and Rusty (Embry) are more than happy to head there and have a damn good time. They even stop at Cousin Eddie's house (Quaid) for more fun, but soon enough, they wind up taking him to Vegas unexpectedly. Let the crazy, nonstop, unrealistic, comedy antics begin. Clark gambles away their money, the wife Ellen (D'Angelo) falls in love with Wayne Newton, Rusty gets a fake ID and wins big, and Audrey (played by the stunning and gorgeous Marisol Nichols) loosens up to become a dancer. It's nothing special, but back in the day, to a five year old, it was colorful, vibrant, jumpy, loud, and off it's own medicine. I loved it. I saw love at first sight when I saw Marisol Nichols play Audrey. Then when I grew older, I questioned if continuity was even brought up when making this sequel. The children look nothing like they did in the first three films. Rusty was an average looking guy, but in this one his a very handsome, grown individual. Audrey has the biggest change of all. She was the homely child in the first three, but in this one she's got black hair and is amazingly gorgeous. Puberty did her well. But who cares? The jokes are somewhat fresh, the scenes are classic (my favorite being the dam boring tour), and the characters return to give it their all once more. Hard to believe that this would be the last time we see these characters in the flesh until thirteen years later when Chevy and Beverly would appear in the short Hotel Hell Vacation. I suspected something like National Lampoon's Australian Vacation, But it was still nice to see them back at it one more time. Vegas Vacation isn't perfect. You could almost think of it has a hopelessly lost spin off that doesn't take too many new routes, or even has appropriately placed characters. It doesn't even have the National Lampoon's name in the title. My only theory is that Warner Bros. (the company that distributed every other Vacation film) wanted to make another film in the franchise. They probably suggested the idea of Vegas with high hopes, National Lampoon maybe scrapped it, and WB went on to do it by themselves with no endorsement of National Lampoon. After all, they do own a part of the name, might as well milk it. No matter, Vegas Vacation is a film I'm proud to call one of my favorite comedies, and my second favorite in the Vacation franchise. Starring: Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols, and Randy Quaid. Directed by: Stephen Kessler.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    dud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this fourth installment in the vacation series is close to abysmal in my opinion.it's cheap gimmickry at it lowest.the first three in the series were all very good,pretty much at the same level of quality of jokes and story.this one was neither funny nor clever.the only good thing about the the whole travesty is Wallace Shawn who has a small role as a black jack dealer.his bit is quite funny.but that's it.otherwise it's sheer tedium.it's worth noting that the words "national lampoon" do not appear before the title,so maybe that says something right there.anyway,if i had known how bad this thing was,i would have booked myself self an appointment for a sinus scraping instead.it would have been more enjoyable.i'll give it 3/10 for Wallace Shawn
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets the number three spot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bjorn (ODDBear)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, Clark Griswold has so far botched a road trip, a European vacation and (most memorably) a Christmas vacation; so why does he continue to make his family go through hell on his endless quest for a fun vacation? That's easy; it's pretty enjoyable for us to watch :) "Vegas Vacation" sits comfortably as the third most enjoyable film in the series; surpassing "European Vacation" but not as enjoyable as "Vacation" or "Christmas Vacation". It's pretty far reaching at times but there are solid moments here; such as Clark damn near destroying a damn and getting crazy (as only Clark Griswold can) playing cards and losing everything. The Wayne Newton gag soon grows tiresome and everything concerning Audrey and Russ pretty much stinks but Randy Quaid delivers once again as obnoxious Cousin Eddie and Chase hasn't lost his touch as the world's most annoying (yet somehow oddly endearing) family dad.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I used to like it, but now I think it is silly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sirus_the_Virus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to really like Vegas Vacation. But I watched it again recently and, well, it wasn't that good. I still give it credit, but it's not that great. Vegas vacation is rated PG, and I can really see it. The film has it's funny moments but really doesn't come alive like the first and third film did. The film is corny, and there are many silly scenes. Ellen(Beverly D'Angelo) is irritating, and in this film she falls head over heels for Wayne Newton. If only I could find these high heels so then I could throw them at her. Vegas Vacation is sort of irritating. It's probably the weakest in the series. It's a silly, silly sequel. Vegas vacation:**/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Griswalds go to Vegas
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the forth and last movie about Griswalds. Well , at least until the new remake of "Vacation" doesn't show up. It doesn't have the National Lampoons title , but it is the sequel to previous three movies. It was directed Stephen Kessler. What is more important is that John Hughes (writer of all three movies) isn't the writer of this one. "Vegas vacation" was written by Elisa Bell and Bob Ducsay. It's hard to find a good third movie in the series , much less forth. It's also a risk to make a sequel to an 80's movie . Many of the sequels to 80's movies fails , because they aren't able to capture that specific 80's magic of the original ("Another 48 hours" , "Beverly Hills cop 3", "Blues brothers 2000" for example). Griswalds didn't really needed another sequel , since the third one was really good . So who needed it ? Chevy Chase . After the 1989 he wasn't able to make a successful movie and this was his last attempt to become a major star once more . In the end it's not a bad movie , but it lacks freshness . The writers actually did a lot of work to keep "Vegas vacation" in style of previous movies and for most part the movie resembles Hughes sense of humor. Unfortunately , there are too many moments of boredom when nothing happens and most of the jokes are mildly amusing . The funniest scenes are happening near the ending , when Clark and Eddie go to VERY cheap restaurant and unusual casino (where you can play Rock, paper, scissors ! ). There is also a nice tribute scene to the first movie with the chick in the car. On the other hand the scene at the Hoover Dam is rather unbelievable , even for Clark. The old cast is back and in a good shape  Chevy Chase , Beverly D'Angelo and Randy Quaid. The kids has been recast again . Ethan Embry plays Rusty and Marisol Nichols plays Audrey. I have to say they are my least favorite couple from the whole series. They give very flat performances. Anyway , it's still a quite decent goodbye for Griswalds. It was good to hear Beach boys "Good vibrations " and once again Lindsey Buckhingam "Holiday road" . And the scene with between Clark and the old lonely man shows why the audience liked Clark so much . He isn't too bright , but he's heart is in the right place. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't forget to visit the Dam gift shop....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its the same kind of plot as all the others, Clark decides to take the family to Vegas, and all starts of shenanigans start. Clark starts to lose all the money, Ellen gets chased by Wayne Newton, Rusty becomes a Player, and Audrey becomes a dancer. Cousin Eddie is along for the ride, and so are bad jokes and bad blue screen..... Even though its the poorest one from the franchise, its still likable, thanks to the chemistry between Chase and D'angelo. They just come off so natural that you really don't care if the jokes are rehashed, and Eddie is just in it to stop lethargy setting in. Its predictable, Clark is the only one who gets over his head, while the other three would probably have the time of their lives if they were just left alone. The script isn't the best, and the Dam tour takes you away front he fundamental elements of the story, but or a final Vacation movie, its not to bad, Chase is always a likable screen presence, and there are far worse ways to spend ninety minutes. Dumb silly fun, that you will forget about the minute you turn the TV off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funnier than the other films in the series
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did we need this movie? No we did not. It's surprisingly enjoyable though. Not very good, but for my money the best 'Vacation' movie. There are a few inspired bits and pieces, like Chevy Chase and dim cousin Randy Quaid coming across a cut-price casino where the games include scissors paper stone, guess which hand, a coin toss, and guess a number between 1 and 10! Admittedly a lot of the jokes fall flat - Chase's character is an idiot but would he really be stupid enough to climb an electricity pylon about Hoover Dam? - and Wallace Shawn is wasted as an annoying card dealer. But despite its faults and ultimate redundancy it's kind of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As a former hotel manager in Vegas, the movie is perfect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    db-beurylaw
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I lived in Las Vegas for 25 years. This movie hits all of the points of a Las Vegas. That's the strength and point of all four of the Vacation movies all that stuff really happens. Except for maybe winning a whole lot of money, but you know that. The really awful buffet in some of the sleazier hotels, the way some dealers can clean you out with every hand, the obligatory trip to Hoover Dam. Heck, one of my friend's girlfriends was actually hit on and picked up by Wayne Newton. Yes you can cook meat on a rock on a hot day and every day in the Summer is a hot day. Rattle snakes radioactivity its all part of Las Vegas fun. This movie hits all of the highlights. Think of it as a travel log with attitude. Loved it. Cast is perfect. Chevy is the unflappable fool tourist who flops around as a fish out of water. Randy Quaid is the kind of guy who is right at home in Las Vegas and proud that his daughter is an "entertainer" But the person who makes it all work is Beverly who takes all the abuse and slyly sticks in her comments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good, But Long-Waited Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Randy Quaid, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols and Wayne Newton star in this 1997 comedy sequel. In this installment, Clark Griswold (Chase) takes his wife, Ellen (D'Angelo) and 2 kids, Rusty (Embry) and Audrey (Nichols) to Las Vegas, Nevada for a family trip. Clark runs into cousin Eddie (Quaid) while getting there and has bad luck. Newton plays himself who falls in love with Ellen and Clark starts getting himself addicted to gambling causing him to lose most of his money and his family starts going their separate ways. Soon, Clark tries to redeem himself and get his family back together. This is a pretty good, but long-waited sequel, Chevy is great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite of the vacation films, go ahead, laugh yourself silly
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Clark Griswold (Chevy Chase) arrives at his home in Chicago, one day, in very high spirits. His wife, Ellen (Beverly D'Angelo) and two kids, Audrey (Marisol Nichols) and Rusty (Ethan Embry) are called to a family meeting. In short order, Clark announces that his new formula for food preservation has garnered a big bonus and he is taking them all to Las Vegas. No one is very excited but they have little choice but to go along. When they arrive in town, the Griswolds take a limo to their hotel, although poor Audrey gets stuck in the moonroof, thanks to her dad. Before long, cousin Eddie (Randy Quaid) shows up, for Ellen has called her cousin, Eddie's wife Catherine, to announce their visit. Eddie promptly watches Clark lose a whopping $300 bucks at the blackjack table, much to the joy of the sadistic dealer, Marty (Wallace Shawn). After the loss, Eddie invites everyone to his house north of Vegas, where the government has given him some lovely, parched, radioactive land. From there, its on to Hoover Dam and to a bunch of shows, including Sigfried & Roy and Wayne Newton. Newton, in fact, makes a play for Ellen in front of the audience, although Clark thinks its part of the act. While Ellen gets invited to have cocktails with Wayne, Clark goes on gambling and the kids, under age, get fake identifications so they can likewise play the tables (Rusty) and try out exotic dancing (Audrey). They even have an encounter with an old, old gambler (Sid Caesar). How will their great adventure end? This is the best of the vacation films, my opinion, even though all are enjoyable. The script is lively and inventive and so, so funny. The cast, too, is excellent, with the main folks reprising their long established roles, and Newton, Embry, Nichols, Shawn, and especially Caesar, adding greatly to the merriment. The scenery is the best of the strip, Eddie's abode notwithstanding, and the costumes and direction are topnotch, also. Do you, personally, need a vacation from the norm? VV is the cure for the anytime blues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big lights, big money, and big laughs like the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This installment of the comedy classic Vacation series is often regarded as "the worst in the series". That couldn't be further from the truth. This is my second favorite in the entire franchise next to the original film. Vegas Vacation was watched by me countless times in the late nineties when I was very young, and really didn't know what the characters were discussing, or even saying for that matter. Along with Fools Rush In, this was my favorite film in my childhood. I recently ran into the National Lampoon's Vacation Collection on Amazon for about $25. What the hell? I'll pay that. I had already watched the first two, and really wanted to dive into the third and rewatch this (keep in mind, at the time, it had been around nine years since I had seen the film). I recently ran into it on Comedy Central, and there was the question again; "what the hell?" The Griswold Family returns to the screen, this time taking a family vacation to Las Vegas. While it isn't much of a family-friendly place, Clark (Chase) and Rusty (Embry) are more than happy to head there and have a damn good time. They even stop at Cousin Eddie's house (Quaid) for more fun, but soon enough, they wind up taking him to Vegas unexpectedly. Let the crazy, nonstop, unrealistic, comedy antics begin. Clark gambles away their money, the wife Ellen (D'Angelo) falls in love with Wayne Newton, Rusty gets a fake ID and wins big, and Audrey (played by the stunning and gorgeous Marisol Nichols) loosens up to become a dancer. It's nothing special, but back in the day, to a five year old, it was colorful, vibrant, jumpy, loud, and off it's own medicine. I loved it. I saw love at first sight when I saw Marisol Nichols play Audrey. Then when I grew older, I questioned if continuity was even brought up when making this sequel. The children look nothing like they did in the first three films. Rusty was an average looking guy, but in this one his a very handsome, grown individual. Audrey has the biggest change of all. She was the homely child in the first three, but in this one she's got black hair and is amazingly gorgeous. Puberty did her well. But who cares? The jokes are somewhat fresh, the scenes are classic (my favorite being the dam boring tour), and the characters return to give it their all once more. Hard to believe that this would be the last time we see these characters in the flesh until thirteen years later when Chevy and Beverly would appear in the short Hotel Hell Vacation. I suspected something like National Lampoon's Australian Vacation, But it was still nice to see them back at it one more time. Vegas Vacation isn't perfect. You could almost think of it has a hopelessly lost spin off that doesn't take too many new routes, or even has appropriately placed characters. It doesn't even have the National Lampoon's name in the title. My only theory is that Warner Bros. (the company that distributed every other Vacation film) wanted to make another film in the franchise. They probably suggested the idea of Vegas with high hopes, National Lampoon maybe scrapped it, and WB went on to do it by themselves with no endorsement of National Lampoon. After all, they do own a part of the name, might as well milk it. No matter, Vegas Vacation is a film I'm proud to call one of my favorite comedies, and my second favorite in the Vacation franchise. Starring: Chevy Chase, Beverly D'Angelo, Ethan Embry, Marisol Nichols, and Randy Quaid. Directed by: Stephen Kessler.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    dud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    disdressed12
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this fourth installment in the vacation series is close to abysmal in my opinion.it's cheap gimmickry at it lowest.the first three in the series were all very good,pretty much at the same level of quality of jokes and story.this one was neither funny nor clever.the only good thing about the the whole travesty is Wallace Shawn who has a small role as a black jack dealer.his bit is quite funny.but that's it.otherwise it's sheer tedium.it's worth noting that the words "national lampoon" do not appear before the title,so maybe that says something right there.anyway,if i had known how bad this thing was,i would have booked myself self an appointment for a sinus scraping instead.it would have been more enjoyable.i'll give it 3/10 for Wallace Shawn
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gets the number three spot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bjorn (ODDBear)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, Clark Griswold has so far botched a road trip, a European vacation and (most memorably) a Christmas vacation; so why does he continue to make his family go through hell on his endless quest for a fun vacation? That's easy; it's pretty enjoyable for us to watch :) "Vegas Vacation" sits comfortably as the third most enjoyable film in the series; surpassing "European Vacation" but not as enjoyable as "Vacation" or "Christmas Vacation". It's pretty far reaching at times but there are solid moments here; such as Clark damn near destroying a damn and getting crazy (as only Clark Griswold can) playing cards and losing everything. The Wayne Newton gag soon grows tiresome and everything concerning Audrey and Russ pretty much stinks but Randy Quaid delivers once again as obnoxious Cousin Eddie and Chase hasn't lost his touch as the world's most annoying (yet somehow oddly endearing) family dad.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I used to like it, but now I think it is silly.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sirus_the_Virus
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to really like Vegas Vacation. But I watched it again recently and, well, it wasn't that good. I still give it credit, but it's not that great. Vegas vacation is rated PG, and I can really see it. The film has it's funny moments but really doesn't come alive like the first and third film did. The film is corny, and there are many silly scenes. Ellen(Beverly D'Angelo) is irritating, and in this film she falls head over heels for Wayne Newton. If only I could find these high heels so then I could throw them at her. Vegas Vacation is sort of irritating. It's probably the weakest in the series. It's a silly, silly sequel. Vegas vacation:**/****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
