<filme>
 <id>
  879
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119874
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Pacificador
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A US Army colonel and a civilian woman supervising him must track down stolen Russian nuclear weapons before they're used by terrorists.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Two trains crash somewhere in Russia, one carrying a nuclear payload. A nuclear explosion follows the crash and the world is on alert... However, White House nuclear expert Dr. Julia Kelly doesn't think it was an accident... Special Operations Intelligence Officer Colonel Thomas Devoe doesn't think so either... Together they must unravel a conspiracy that goes from Europe to New York, to stop a terrorist who has no demands...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   nuclear explosion
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   train crash
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   russia
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nuclear weapons
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   train
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Mimi Leder
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Leslie Cockburn
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Andrew Cockburn
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   George Clooney
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Nicole Kidman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Marcel Iures
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Peacetakers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never actually seen an episode of ER. I actually took to the movies to appreciate George Clooney, and have since 1997's The Peacemaker. While this movie didn't get a lot of hype or admiration, I truly had a good time. Loved the wit and snappiness of Clooney's dialogue, the action, suspense and drive of the characters. While it's not perfect and has that annoying "An Improbable Jump Through Solid Glass to Escape" scene that I always doubt and some omitted scenes that would've been awesome to see  i.e. two trains colliding, it was an enormously fun ride that, surprisingly, still holds up today, 16 years later. The plot is the norm: with a extensive plan, terrorists seize a nuclear bomb and it's up to two unlikely government heroes to work together, on a global scale, to find out: where they're headed, what they're up to and why. What stands this above the rest, was a fresh and young Clooney doing his soon-to-be normal, but great, schtick. I happen to be a fan of his cocky, but smart, ambitious but laid back appeal. So, I always give him a pass. And this movie contains one of my ALL TIME favorite movie scenes: (mild spoiler) Clooney's dear friend just gets killed and after an exciting car chase leaving one terrorist barely alive, Clooney says nothing in the downpour of water, walks up to him and shoots him point blank. As much as I like snappy comeback and final last crass words, this scene completely shocked and pleased me, because this is how it should've been done in real life and in the movies. Other than that one scene, it's exciting, interesting, has a great pace and a fun puzzle to put together while watching. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    George Clooney + Nicole Kidman together equal James Bond and spare NY from nuclear destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every so often, this picture had some realism to it. Mostly it was a hectic and overlong, nervous and excited movie. A Russian has hijacked 10 nuclear warheads that he's transporting for sale, with one going to a Serb-Croat-Muslim who intends to detonate it at the UN building. Kidman is the Executive Branch operative and Clooney is the military operative. The story takes on James Bond proportions as they seek out what's going on and then attempt to stop it. There are 2 or 3 climaxes that extend the story's length. After awhile, I was fast-forwarding through the predictable chase scene in NY City. There is quite an elaborate car chase scene in Serbia (I think) in which Clooney uses the car to destroy three cars in pursuit. This scene works well. Clooney handles his part nicely. He never fails to know what to do and acts very quickly. Kidman keeps up with him. The movie glorifies the U.S. technical prowess. The depictions are unreal and fantastic, if not ridiculous. It makes for propaganda. Nuclear warheads on American soil in terrorist hands are the ultimate U.S. nightmare, and so that's what the movie shows. In a moment of realism, we learn that the terrorist is attacking NY out of retaliation for US and NATO interference in the old Yugoslavia and the deaths of his family. It's called blowback. The other U.S. bugaboo is Iran (horror! horror!) and so another plot element is warheads headed for Iran. It's all strictly comic book level and by the numbers action, a popcorn feature. Nothing deep here except sell tickets and pay the upkeep of the producers, staff and movie makers. With Dreamworks making it, I didn't expect much, and nothing much happened. Why were the James Bond movies more satisfying?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nicole Kidman Was Looking Sexy But Then Again Russians Are Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    M MALIK
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nicole kid-man was so sexy but clooney was looking gay & a wannabe tough guy. Russians are portrayed as bad guys again in this who wants to launch a nuclear attack on USA but why because the main bad guy got betrayed & wanted revenge . i really don't care for stuff like this anymore because the only movie i lover of bombs is broken arrow of john travolta. the climax of the movie is bad & rushed & you'll see why i love movies but this ant-Russian & all that stuff is gone too far.after 9-11 a lot of films came out with more concepts like the plus point was that they have Afghanistan & Pakistan & terrorist groups stories & osama you know what i am saying. i cant understand clooney this guy acts the same in every film & his hairstyle also never change. my rating of the peacemaker is 2/10 watch only for Nicole kid-man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better movie starring George Clooney and Nichole Kidman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie would have been just as good if it was a plot for a James Bond movie. US military and civilian are tasked to find a stolen nuclear bomb. Cliff hanger of course is its detonation time, and how the two will find the bomb. I seriously think that this is one of the best role George Clooney played. He looks so real as the military officer. His chemistry with Nichole Kidman is really good too. The movie is hard to rate in that it's really well put together, but acting is bit weak, and this takes away from the tension. There's not enough character in George Clooney's role to make him interesting. Like many others who likes this movie, I like it for the story, and the quality of the production. It's an intriguing story, and is worth a watch for its story alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tired clich&eacute; of a movie which at least has a good opening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toll-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1997, although very much relevant in today's world, The Peacemaker stars George Clooney and Nicole Kidman in this action thriller revolving around potential terrorist attacks in New York. The film takes us to a variety of countries as our two leads hunt down the men responsible for selling nuclear warheads to those hell bent on causing pain and disruption to a country they feel is responsible for destroying their families lives. The Peacemaker opens with a brilliant opening sequence where a corrupt Russian General steals nine nuclear war heads from a train transporting them across the country. In an attempt to cover up their actions they set off one of the bombs in the process, killing up to 15,000 people. The cover up however is not successful and Lt Tom Devoe (Clooney) sees straight through the smoke screen, and upon briefing the acting adviser Dr Julia Kelly (Kidman) the two dart off across the World on the trail of the missing warheads, both using very opposite techniques to find their answers. From Vienna to Eastern Europe to New York City, Clooney and Kidman do all they can to prevent one of the biggest disasters to occur in western civilisation. For starters there is nothing particularly original about this film. The premise is a slight variation on something we have seen so many times before. The problem with this is in the writing where included throughout are several clich&eacute;d moment that we have seen in many films of the same era. For example we have the typical cursing every time something bad is said or a gun is fired, we have the typical screaming sidekick teamed up with the unfazed hard man (Kidman and Clooney), and as well we have the run 'with only ten seconds to spare' and jump as the bomb explodes in the background, as a matter of fact we have that twice. It is a slight shame really considering the opening sequence is very well done, but the pacing there on in just drags until the next set piece which is then followed again by slow pacing before the next set piece. This can only be a fault in the writing where we are literally given all the stereotypes of this type of film in one two hour block. The best part about the writing is the B story involving a diplomat who has an agenda for his deadly act. The story is dripped in slowly at the beginning and then brought to the forefront for the final act. It is the best part about the story as it is something slightly different than your typical Russian baddie plot; however it isn't particularly the norm that a B story actually completely overtakes the main plot of a film for the final thirty minutes of it. It makes the opening ninety minutes feel a little clunky and shows how weak the main plot actually is. Some of these issues could be down to the direction, which although not entirely bad does seem a little flat. Mimi Leder does manage to get a decent performance from Clooney but Kidman doesn't seem out of her comfort zone. The opening sequence is very well directed, and the music really adds to the drama, but the other action sequences seem pretty lifeless, especially the chase scene through the streets of Vienna. Also something that was heavily noticed whilst watching was the amount of time taken to chase this man throughout New York without the bomb going off when he had put a time limit on the bomb for a much shorter amount of time. Put it this way an entire third act which is about twenty minutes of screen time told us it was only about seven minutes in their world. It was definitely not plausible and there is a way they could have got over this. The film isn't entirely bad but there is enough wrong with it to make it not particularly good. The tired clich&eacute;s really take over after such a promising start to proceedings. The film could have, and probably should have, been better but the lifeless way in which the story was told, and the dull action sequences, really hindered the possibilities the film could have had. The music was one of the standout points, composed by Hans Zimmer, and from knowing his work in this day and age it is very obviously his work and the soundtrack booms over every tiny piece of action, unfortunately the action fails to live up to the score. I can't particularly say I was disappointed with this film as the opening scene was definitely one I was pleased to have seen, the thing is I could have happily turned it off after the opening twenty minutes and have ended up seeing a much better film. 2 / 5 For more reviews: www.tolli-movieworld.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Persistently Relevant and Riveting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker has both the sophistication, intelligence, and the suspense of its contemporary action thrillers as Spy Game (2001) and Enemy of the State (1998). The balance in the characters both male and female, the good and the bad guys makes for this mainstream action movie raises the bar on its other contemporary movies. The script is both cerebral and action packed, well edited, and nicely paced. Perhaps the renewed geopolitical tension in the world today with nuclear Iran and North Korea as well as the spread of terrorism keeps this movie relevant for today's audiences. Overall, this is a nice fusion of drama, action, technology, and political message of sorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the subplots derailed the film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattrochman
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker was a good and watchable film. The opening was solid and the structure of the story seemed interesting. Unlike other films of this genre, some intelligent and investigative plot lines unfolded. But ultimately the film should have steered clear of the plot line involving the Yugoslav character. Chasing the weapons, solid action, but running along side a rather silly plot about a man who seeks to avenge the deaths of his wife and daughter, and the war at the heart of it all, by detonating a nuclear bomb in the UN in New York. It became sentimental, far-fetched and sent the plot off course. I can only describe it as destabilising the main plot and I think that this is why a lot of people thought it was 'ok' but not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A humble masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mihnerts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, the 5.9 average doesn't do justice to this movie. The truth is that 'The Peacemaker' is a masterpiece and the reason is simple: it's captivating, thrilling and engages the human mind without relying on cgi effects but on masterfully directed subtle action scenes. I do not want to analyze it more because if I do I will miss the point. I will only say this: in many reviews we can read that it's a decent film and has nothing new to offer to the genre... In reality this is the exceptional thing about this film: it takes common place material, used again and again, and transforms them to something brilliant. This is one definition for the word masterpiece on cinema! I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I miss the cold war......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two trains crash somewhere in Russia, one carrying a nuclear payload. A nuclear explosion follows the crash and the world is on alert... However, White House nuclear expert Dr. Julia Kelly doesn't think it was an accident. Special Operations Intelligence Officer Colonel Thomas Devoe doesn't think so either. Together they must unravel a conspiracy that goes from Europe to New York, to stop a terrorist who has no demands... before Out of Sight made Clooney officially the coolest man on the planet, he was the one from ER who seemed desperate to be a huge movie star. A few of his movies, including this one, were so high profile, but so poorly received and average at the box office. It's because they seem so unique with the synopsis, but the execution is so average. Here Clooney has a bit of a swagger wearing white trousers and smirking at Kidman, who justs gets in a fluster every now and again. Sounds like the perfect recipe for a romantic comedy. But this is about Nuclear Weapons going missing. And the film drags in places. One of dreamworks first releases, it does have its moments. The car chase is quite good, and a siege on a bridge is visually impressive, as is the claustrophobic feel of the final act. But for a film that is over two hours long, these really seem few and far between, when the rest of the time we are treated to heated debate. The two stars are good, and you can tell Clooney will be big, It's a good job he met Soderbergh though. Heaven knows what would have happened to his career otherwise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than I thought it might be . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was particularly interested in this film because I was curious how Hollywood would treat this type of scenario, and of course, anything with Nicole Kidman in it has to be at least somewhat entertaining. I actually worked for DOE, in the national labs at Berkeley and also Los Alomos, a number of years ago, and a consequence of such have become quite familiar with nuclear ordnance in its myriad forms, including the so-called "suitcase nukes" that both the former Soviet Union & the USA have developed. Make no mistake, these types of miniaturized nuclear devices do exist, including from decommissioned MRV ballistic missiles and the like. The concept of nuclear warheads, slipping into the wrong hands does very much exist, although in current times this may more likely come from Pakistan, or any variety of "rogue" states who could acquire such through third party brokers. As a side note, any of these types of nuclear devices do require periodic "refurbishing", the details of which I won't elaborate on, but after a certain length of time, the capacity for thermo-nuclear detonation does diminish. Having said all that, does the film realistically portray any of this actually translating into a potential situation? Well . . . not exactly, but I think it's interesting that at least the concept was presented in a not overly ridiculous fashion. Sadly, with tremendous irony, I noted the twin trade towers in several of the background scenes. How odd it is that history often unfolds in the least expected ways. It was, after all, not a miniaturized nuke that was the greatest act of terrorism and evil ever perpetrated on US citizens, but rather planes filled with people . . . and boxcutters as the weaponry of terror. Was the film entertaining? Yes. Could it have been done better? Not sure if I have a qualified answer, but it certainly could have been done much worse. A bit dated? Perhaps . . . but I still think it's worth the time to watch, and contemplate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Peacetakers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never actually seen an episode of ER. I actually took to the movies to appreciate George Clooney, and have since 1997's The Peacemaker. While this movie didn't get a lot of hype or admiration, I truly had a good time. Loved the wit and snappiness of Clooney's dialogue, the action, suspense and drive of the characters. While it's not perfect and has that annoying "An Improbable Jump Through Solid Glass to Escape" scene that I always doubt and some omitted scenes that would've been awesome to see  i.e. two trains colliding, it was an enormously fun ride that, surprisingly, still holds up today, 16 years later. The plot is the norm: with a extensive plan, terrorists seize a nuclear bomb and it's up to two unlikely government heroes to work together, on a global scale, to find out: where they're headed, what they're up to and why. What stands this above the rest, was a fresh and young Clooney doing his soon-to-be normal, but great, schtick. I happen to be a fan of his cocky, but smart, ambitious but laid back appeal. So, I always give him a pass. And this movie contains one of my ALL TIME favorite movie scenes: (mild spoiler) Clooney's dear friend just gets killed and after an exciting car chase leaving one terrorist barely alive, Clooney says nothing in the downpour of water, walks up to him and shoots him point blank. As much as I like snappy comeback and final last crass words, this scene completely shocked and pleased me, because this is how it should've been done in real life and in the movies. Other than that one scene, it's exciting, interesting, has a great pace and a fun puzzle to put together while watching. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    George Clooney + Nicole Kidman together equal James Bond and spare NY from nuclear destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every so often, this picture had some realism to it. Mostly it was a hectic and overlong, nervous and excited movie. A Russian has hijacked 10 nuclear warheads that he's transporting for sale, with one going to a Serb-Croat-Muslim who intends to detonate it at the UN building. Kidman is the Executive Branch operative and Clooney is the military operative. The story takes on James Bond proportions as they seek out what's going on and then attempt to stop it. There are 2 or 3 climaxes that extend the story's length. After awhile, I was fast-forwarding through the predictable chase scene in NY City. There is quite an elaborate car chase scene in Serbia (I think) in which Clooney uses the car to destroy three cars in pursuit. This scene works well. Clooney handles his part nicely. He never fails to know what to do and acts very quickly. Kidman keeps up with him. The movie glorifies the U.S. technical prowess. The depictions are unreal and fantastic, if not ridiculous. It makes for propaganda. Nuclear warheads on American soil in terrorist hands are the ultimate U.S. nightmare, and so that's what the movie shows. In a moment of realism, we learn that the terrorist is attacking NY out of retaliation for US and NATO interference in the old Yugoslavia and the deaths of his family. It's called blowback. The other U.S. bugaboo is Iran (horror! horror!) and so another plot element is warheads headed for Iran. It's all strictly comic book level and by the numbers action, a popcorn feature. Nothing deep here except sell tickets and pay the upkeep of the producers, staff and movie makers. With Dreamworks making it, I didn't expect much, and nothing much happened. Why were the James Bond movies more satisfying?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nicole Kidman Was Looking Sexy But Then Again Russians Are Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    M MALIK
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nicole kid-man was so sexy but clooney was looking gay & a wannabe tough guy. Russians are portrayed as bad guys again in this who wants to launch a nuclear attack on USA but why because the main bad guy got betrayed & wanted revenge . i really don't care for stuff like this anymore because the only movie i lover of bombs is broken arrow of john travolta. the climax of the movie is bad & rushed & you'll see why i love movies but this ant-Russian & all that stuff is gone too far.after 9-11 a lot of films came out with more concepts like the plus point was that they have Afghanistan & Pakistan & terrorist groups stories & osama you know what i am saying. i cant understand clooney this guy acts the same in every film & his hairstyle also never change. my rating of the peacemaker is 2/10 watch only for Nicole kid-man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better movie starring George Clooney and Nichole Kidman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie would have been just as good if it was a plot for a James Bond movie. US military and civilian are tasked to find a stolen nuclear bomb. Cliff hanger of course is its detonation time, and how the two will find the bomb. I seriously think that this is one of the best role George Clooney played. He looks so real as the military officer. His chemistry with Nichole Kidman is really good too. The movie is hard to rate in that it's really well put together, but acting is bit weak, and this takes away from the tension. There's not enough character in George Clooney's role to make him interesting. Like many others who likes this movie, I like it for the story, and the quality of the production. It's an intriguing story, and is worth a watch for its story alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tired clich&eacute; of a movie which at least has a good opening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toll-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1997, although very much relevant in today's world, The Peacemaker stars George Clooney and Nicole Kidman in this action thriller revolving around potential terrorist attacks in New York. The film takes us to a variety of countries as our two leads hunt down the men responsible for selling nuclear warheads to those hell bent on causing pain and disruption to a country they feel is responsible for destroying their families lives. The Peacemaker opens with a brilliant opening sequence where a corrupt Russian General steals nine nuclear war heads from a train transporting them across the country. In an attempt to cover up their actions they set off one of the bombs in the process, killing up to 15,000 people. The cover up however is not successful and Lt Tom Devoe (Clooney) sees straight through the smoke screen, and upon briefing the acting adviser Dr Julia Kelly (Kidman) the two dart off across the World on the trail of the missing warheads, both using very opposite techniques to find their answers. From Vienna to Eastern Europe to New York City, Clooney and Kidman do all they can to prevent one of the biggest disasters to occur in western civilisation. For starters there is nothing particularly original about this film. The premise is a slight variation on something we have seen so many times before. The problem with this is in the writing where included throughout are several clich&eacute;d moment that we have seen in many films of the same era. For example we have the typical cursing every time something bad is said or a gun is fired, we have the typical screaming sidekick teamed up with the unfazed hard man (Kidman and Clooney), and as well we have the run 'with only ten seconds to spare' and jump as the bomb explodes in the background, as a matter of fact we have that twice. It is a slight shame really considering the opening sequence is very well done, but the pacing there on in just drags until the next set piece which is then followed again by slow pacing before the next set piece. This can only be a fault in the writing where we are literally given all the stereotypes of this type of film in one two hour block. The best part about the writing is the B story involving a diplomat who has an agenda for his deadly act. The story is dripped in slowly at the beginning and then brought to the forefront for the final act. It is the best part about the story as it is something slightly different than your typical Russian baddie plot; however it isn't particularly the norm that a B story actually completely overtakes the main plot of a film for the final thirty minutes of it. It makes the opening ninety minutes feel a little clunky and shows how weak the main plot actually is. Some of these issues could be down to the direction, which although not entirely bad does seem a little flat. Mimi Leder does manage to get a decent performance from Clooney but Kidman doesn't seem out of her comfort zone. The opening sequence is very well directed, and the music really adds to the drama, but the other action sequences seem pretty lifeless, especially the chase scene through the streets of Vienna. Also something that was heavily noticed whilst watching was the amount of time taken to chase this man throughout New York without the bomb going off when he had put a time limit on the bomb for a much shorter amount of time. Put it this way an entire third act which is about twenty minutes of screen time told us it was only about seven minutes in their world. It was definitely not plausible and there is a way they could have got over this. The film isn't entirely bad but there is enough wrong with it to make it not particularly good. The tired clich&eacute;s really take over after such a promising start to proceedings. The film could have, and probably should have, been better but the lifeless way in which the story was told, and the dull action sequences, really hindered the possibilities the film could have had. The music was one of the standout points, composed by Hans Zimmer, and from knowing his work in this day and age it is very obviously his work and the soundtrack booms over every tiny piece of action, unfortunately the action fails to live up to the score. I can't particularly say I was disappointed with this film as the opening scene was definitely one I was pleased to have seen, the thing is I could have happily turned it off after the opening twenty minutes and have ended up seeing a much better film. 2 / 5 For more reviews: www.tolli-movieworld.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Persistently Relevant and Riveting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker has both the sophistication, intelligence, and the suspense of its contemporary action thrillers as Spy Game (2001) and Enemy of the State (1998). The balance in the characters both male and female, the good and the bad guys makes for this mainstream action movie raises the bar on its other contemporary movies. The script is both cerebral and action packed, well edited, and nicely paced. Perhaps the renewed geopolitical tension in the world today with nuclear Iran and North Korea as well as the spread of terrorism keeps this movie relevant for today's audiences. Overall, this is a nice fusion of drama, action, technology, and political message of sorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the subplots derailed the film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattrochman
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker was a good and watchable film. The opening was solid and the structure of the story seemed interesting. Unlike other films of this genre, some intelligent and investigative plot lines unfolded. But ultimately the film should have steered clear of the plot line involving the Yugoslav character. Chasing the weapons, solid action, but running along side a rather silly plot about a man who seeks to avenge the deaths of his wife and daughter, and the war at the heart of it all, by detonating a nuclear bomb in the UN in New York. It became sentimental, far-fetched and sent the plot off course. I can only describe it as destabilising the main plot and I think that this is why a lot of people thought it was 'ok' but not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A humble masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mihnerts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, the 5.9 average doesn't do justice to this movie. The truth is that 'The Peacemaker' is a masterpiece and the reason is simple: it's captivating, thrilling and engages the human mind without relying on cgi effects but on masterfully directed subtle action scenes. I do not want to analyze it more because if I do I will miss the point. I will only say this: in many reviews we can read that it's a decent film and has nothing new to offer to the genre... In reality this is the exceptional thing about this film: it takes common place material, used again and again, and transforms them to something brilliant. This is one definition for the word masterpiece on cinema! I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I miss the cold war......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two trains crash somewhere in Russia, one carrying a nuclear payload. A nuclear explosion follows the crash and the world is on alert... However, White House nuclear expert Dr. Julia Kelly doesn't think it was an accident. Special Operations Intelligence Officer Colonel Thomas Devoe doesn't think so either. Together they must unravel a conspiracy that goes from Europe to New York, to stop a terrorist who has no demands... before Out of Sight made Clooney officially the coolest man on the planet, he was the one from ER who seemed desperate to be a huge movie star. A few of his movies, including this one, were so high profile, but so poorly received and average at the box office. It's because they seem so unique with the synopsis, but the execution is so average. Here Clooney has a bit of a swagger wearing white trousers and smirking at Kidman, who justs gets in a fluster every now and again. Sounds like the perfect recipe for a romantic comedy. But this is about Nuclear Weapons going missing. And the film drags in places. One of dreamworks first releases, it does have its moments. The car chase is quite good, and a siege on a bridge is visually impressive, as is the claustrophobic feel of the final act. But for a film that is over two hours long, these really seem few and far between, when the rest of the time we are treated to heated debate. The two stars are good, and you can tell Clooney will be big, It's a good job he met Soderbergh though. Heaven knows what would have happened to his career otherwise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than I thought it might be . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was particularly interested in this film because I was curious how Hollywood would treat this type of scenario, and of course, anything with Nicole Kidman in it has to be at least somewhat entertaining. I actually worked for DOE, in the national labs at Berkeley and also Los Alomos, a number of years ago, and a consequence of such have become quite familiar with nuclear ordnance in its myriad forms, including the so-called "suitcase nukes" that both the former Soviet Union & the USA have developed. Make no mistake, these types of miniaturized nuclear devices do exist, including from decommissioned MRV ballistic missiles and the like. The concept of nuclear warheads, slipping into the wrong hands does very much exist, although in current times this may more likely come from Pakistan, or any variety of "rogue" states who could acquire such through third party brokers. As a side note, any of these types of nuclear devices do require periodic "refurbishing", the details of which I won't elaborate on, but after a certain length of time, the capacity for thermo-nuclear detonation does diminish. Having said all that, does the film realistically portray any of this actually translating into a potential situation? Well . . . not exactly, but I think it's interesting that at least the concept was presented in a not overly ridiculous fashion. Sadly, with tremendous irony, I noted the twin trade towers in several of the background scenes. How odd it is that history often unfolds in the least expected ways. It was, after all, not a miniaturized nuke that was the greatest act of terrorism and evil ever perpetrated on US citizens, but rather planes filled with people . . . and boxcutters as the weaponry of terror. Was the film entertaining? Yes. Could it have been done better? Not sure if I have a qualified answer, but it certainly could have been done much worse. A bit dated? Perhaps . . . but I still think it's worth the time to watch, and contemplate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Peacetakers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never actually seen an episode of ER. I actually took to the movies to appreciate George Clooney, and have since 1997's The Peacemaker. While this movie didn't get a lot of hype or admiration, I truly had a good time. Loved the wit and snappiness of Clooney's dialogue, the action, suspense and drive of the characters. While it's not perfect and has that annoying "An Improbable Jump Through Solid Glass to Escape" scene that I always doubt and some omitted scenes that would've been awesome to see  i.e. two trains colliding, it was an enormously fun ride that, surprisingly, still holds up today, 16 years later. The plot is the norm: with a extensive plan, terrorists seize a nuclear bomb and it's up to two unlikely government heroes to work together, on a global scale, to find out: where they're headed, what they're up to and why. What stands this above the rest, was a fresh and young Clooney doing his soon-to-be normal, but great, schtick. I happen to be a fan of his cocky, but smart, ambitious but laid back appeal. So, I always give him a pass. And this movie contains one of my ALL TIME favorite movie scenes: (mild spoiler) Clooney's dear friend just gets killed and after an exciting car chase leaving one terrorist barely alive, Clooney says nothing in the downpour of water, walks up to him and shoots him point blank. As much as I like snappy comeback and final last crass words, this scene completely shocked and pleased me, because this is how it should've been done in real life and in the movies. Other than that one scene, it's exciting, interesting, has a great pace and a fun puzzle to put together while watching. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    George Clooney + Nicole Kidman together equal James Bond and spare NY from nuclear destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every so often, this picture had some realism to it. Mostly it was a hectic and overlong, nervous and excited movie. A Russian has hijacked 10 nuclear warheads that he's transporting for sale, with one going to a Serb-Croat-Muslim who intends to detonate it at the UN building. Kidman is the Executive Branch operative and Clooney is the military operative. The story takes on James Bond proportions as they seek out what's going on and then attempt to stop it. There are 2 or 3 climaxes that extend the story's length. After awhile, I was fast-forwarding through the predictable chase scene in NY City. There is quite an elaborate car chase scene in Serbia (I think) in which Clooney uses the car to destroy three cars in pursuit. This scene works well. Clooney handles his part nicely. He never fails to know what to do and acts very quickly. Kidman keeps up with him. The movie glorifies the U.S. technical prowess. The depictions are unreal and fantastic, if not ridiculous. It makes for propaganda. Nuclear warheads on American soil in terrorist hands are the ultimate U.S. nightmare, and so that's what the movie shows. In a moment of realism, we learn that the terrorist is attacking NY out of retaliation for US and NATO interference in the old Yugoslavia and the deaths of his family. It's called blowback. The other U.S. bugaboo is Iran (horror! horror!) and so another plot element is warheads headed for Iran. It's all strictly comic book level and by the numbers action, a popcorn feature. Nothing deep here except sell tickets and pay the upkeep of the producers, staff and movie makers. With Dreamworks making it, I didn't expect much, and nothing much happened. Why were the James Bond movies more satisfying?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nicole Kidman Was Looking Sexy But Then Again Russians Are Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    M MALIK
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nicole kid-man was so sexy but clooney was looking gay & a wannabe tough guy. Russians are portrayed as bad guys again in this who wants to launch a nuclear attack on USA but why because the main bad guy got betrayed & wanted revenge . i really don't care for stuff like this anymore because the only movie i lover of bombs is broken arrow of john travolta. the climax of the movie is bad & rushed & you'll see why i love movies but this ant-Russian & all that stuff is gone too far.after 9-11 a lot of films came out with more concepts like the plus point was that they have Afghanistan & Pakistan & terrorist groups stories & osama you know what i am saying. i cant understand clooney this guy acts the same in every film & his hairstyle also never change. my rating of the peacemaker is 2/10 watch only for Nicole kid-man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better movie starring George Clooney and Nichole Kidman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie would have been just as good if it was a plot for a James Bond movie. US military and civilian are tasked to find a stolen nuclear bomb. Cliff hanger of course is its detonation time, and how the two will find the bomb. I seriously think that this is one of the best role George Clooney played. He looks so real as the military officer. His chemistry with Nichole Kidman is really good too. The movie is hard to rate in that it's really well put together, but acting is bit weak, and this takes away from the tension. There's not enough character in George Clooney's role to make him interesting. Like many others who likes this movie, I like it for the story, and the quality of the production. It's an intriguing story, and is worth a watch for its story alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tired clich&eacute; of a movie which at least has a good opening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toll-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1997, although very much relevant in today's world, The Peacemaker stars George Clooney and Nicole Kidman in this action thriller revolving around potential terrorist attacks in New York. The film takes us to a variety of countries as our two leads hunt down the men responsible for selling nuclear warheads to those hell bent on causing pain and disruption to a country they feel is responsible for destroying their families lives. The Peacemaker opens with a brilliant opening sequence where a corrupt Russian General steals nine nuclear war heads from a train transporting them across the country. In an attempt to cover up their actions they set off one of the bombs in the process, killing up to 15,000 people. The cover up however is not successful and Lt Tom Devoe (Clooney) sees straight through the smoke screen, and upon briefing the acting adviser Dr Julia Kelly (Kidman) the two dart off across the World on the trail of the missing warheads, both using very opposite techniques to find their answers. From Vienna to Eastern Europe to New York City, Clooney and Kidman do all they can to prevent one of the biggest disasters to occur in western civilisation. For starters there is nothing particularly original about this film. The premise is a slight variation on something we have seen so many times before. The problem with this is in the writing where included throughout are several clich&eacute;d moment that we have seen in many films of the same era. For example we have the typical cursing every time something bad is said or a gun is fired, we have the typical screaming sidekick teamed up with the unfazed hard man (Kidman and Clooney), and as well we have the run 'with only ten seconds to spare' and jump as the bomb explodes in the background, as a matter of fact we have that twice. It is a slight shame really considering the opening sequence is very well done, but the pacing there on in just drags until the next set piece which is then followed again by slow pacing before the next set piece. This can only be a fault in the writing where we are literally given all the stereotypes of this type of film in one two hour block. The best part about the writing is the B story involving a diplomat who has an agenda for his deadly act. The story is dripped in slowly at the beginning and then brought to the forefront for the final act. It is the best part about the story as it is something slightly different than your typical Russian baddie plot; however it isn't particularly the norm that a B story actually completely overtakes the main plot of a film for the final thirty minutes of it. It makes the opening ninety minutes feel a little clunky and shows how weak the main plot actually is. Some of these issues could be down to the direction, which although not entirely bad does seem a little flat. Mimi Leder does manage to get a decent performance from Clooney but Kidman doesn't seem out of her comfort zone. The opening sequence is very well directed, and the music really adds to the drama, but the other action sequences seem pretty lifeless, especially the chase scene through the streets of Vienna. Also something that was heavily noticed whilst watching was the amount of time taken to chase this man throughout New York without the bomb going off when he had put a time limit on the bomb for a much shorter amount of time. Put it this way an entire third act which is about twenty minutes of screen time told us it was only about seven minutes in their world. It was definitely not plausible and there is a way they could have got over this. The film isn't entirely bad but there is enough wrong with it to make it not particularly good. The tired clich&eacute;s really take over after such a promising start to proceedings. The film could have, and probably should have, been better but the lifeless way in which the story was told, and the dull action sequences, really hindered the possibilities the film could have had. The music was one of the standout points, composed by Hans Zimmer, and from knowing his work in this day and age it is very obviously his work and the soundtrack booms over every tiny piece of action, unfortunately the action fails to live up to the score. I can't particularly say I was disappointed with this film as the opening scene was definitely one I was pleased to have seen, the thing is I could have happily turned it off after the opening twenty minutes and have ended up seeing a much better film. 2 / 5 For more reviews: www.tolli-movieworld.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Persistently Relevant and Riveting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker has both the sophistication, intelligence, and the suspense of its contemporary action thrillers as Spy Game (2001) and Enemy of the State (1998). The balance in the characters both male and female, the good and the bad guys makes for this mainstream action movie raises the bar on its other contemporary movies. The script is both cerebral and action packed, well edited, and nicely paced. Perhaps the renewed geopolitical tension in the world today with nuclear Iran and North Korea as well as the spread of terrorism keeps this movie relevant for today's audiences. Overall, this is a nice fusion of drama, action, technology, and political message of sorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the subplots derailed the film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattrochman
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker was a good and watchable film. The opening was solid and the structure of the story seemed interesting. Unlike other films of this genre, some intelligent and investigative plot lines unfolded. But ultimately the film should have steered clear of the plot line involving the Yugoslav character. Chasing the weapons, solid action, but running along side a rather silly plot about a man who seeks to avenge the deaths of his wife and daughter, and the war at the heart of it all, by detonating a nuclear bomb in the UN in New York. It became sentimental, far-fetched and sent the plot off course. I can only describe it as destabilising the main plot and I think that this is why a lot of people thought it was 'ok' but not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A humble masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mihnerts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, the 5.9 average doesn't do justice to this movie. The truth is that 'The Peacemaker' is a masterpiece and the reason is simple: it's captivating, thrilling and engages the human mind without relying on cgi effects but on masterfully directed subtle action scenes. I do not want to analyze it more because if I do I will miss the point. I will only say this: in many reviews we can read that it's a decent film and has nothing new to offer to the genre... In reality this is the exceptional thing about this film: it takes common place material, used again and again, and transforms them to something brilliant. This is one definition for the word masterpiece on cinema! I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I miss the cold war......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two trains crash somewhere in Russia, one carrying a nuclear payload. A nuclear explosion follows the crash and the world is on alert... However, White House nuclear expert Dr. Julia Kelly doesn't think it was an accident. Special Operations Intelligence Officer Colonel Thomas Devoe doesn't think so either. Together they must unravel a conspiracy that goes from Europe to New York, to stop a terrorist who has no demands... before Out of Sight made Clooney officially the coolest man on the planet, he was the one from ER who seemed desperate to be a huge movie star. A few of his movies, including this one, were so high profile, but so poorly received and average at the box office. It's because they seem so unique with the synopsis, but the execution is so average. Here Clooney has a bit of a swagger wearing white trousers and smirking at Kidman, who justs gets in a fluster every now and again. Sounds like the perfect recipe for a romantic comedy. But this is about Nuclear Weapons going missing. And the film drags in places. One of dreamworks first releases, it does have its moments. The car chase is quite good, and a siege on a bridge is visually impressive, as is the claustrophobic feel of the final act. But for a film that is over two hours long, these really seem few and far between, when the rest of the time we are treated to heated debate. The two stars are good, and you can tell Clooney will be big, It's a good job he met Soderbergh though. Heaven knows what would have happened to his career otherwise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than I thought it might be . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was particularly interested in this film because I was curious how Hollywood would treat this type of scenario, and of course, anything with Nicole Kidman in it has to be at least somewhat entertaining. I actually worked for DOE, in the national labs at Berkeley and also Los Alomos, a number of years ago, and a consequence of such have become quite familiar with nuclear ordnance in its myriad forms, including the so-called "suitcase nukes" that both the former Soviet Union & the USA have developed. Make no mistake, these types of miniaturized nuclear devices do exist, including from decommissioned MRV ballistic missiles and the like. The concept of nuclear warheads, slipping into the wrong hands does very much exist, although in current times this may more likely come from Pakistan, or any variety of "rogue" states who could acquire such through third party brokers. As a side note, any of these types of nuclear devices do require periodic "refurbishing", the details of which I won't elaborate on, but after a certain length of time, the capacity for thermo-nuclear detonation does diminish. Having said all that, does the film realistically portray any of this actually translating into a potential situation? Well . . . not exactly, but I think it's interesting that at least the concept was presented in a not overly ridiculous fashion. Sadly, with tremendous irony, I noted the twin trade towers in several of the background scenes. How odd it is that history often unfolds in the least expected ways. It was, after all, not a miniaturized nuke that was the greatest act of terrorism and evil ever perpetrated on US citizens, but rather planes filled with people . . . and boxcutters as the weaponry of terror. Was the film entertaining? Yes. Could it have been done better? Not sure if I have a qualified answer, but it certainly could have been done much worse. A bit dated? Perhaps . . . but I still think it's worth the time to watch, and contemplate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Peacetakers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never actually seen an episode of ER. I actually took to the movies to appreciate George Clooney, and have since 1997's The Peacemaker. While this movie didn't get a lot of hype or admiration, I truly had a good time. Loved the wit and snappiness of Clooney's dialogue, the action, suspense and drive of the characters. While it's not perfect and has that annoying "An Improbable Jump Through Solid Glass to Escape" scene that I always doubt and some omitted scenes that would've been awesome to see  i.e. two trains colliding, it was an enormously fun ride that, surprisingly, still holds up today, 16 years later. The plot is the norm: with a extensive plan, terrorists seize a nuclear bomb and it's up to two unlikely government heroes to work together, on a global scale, to find out: where they're headed, what they're up to and why. What stands this above the rest, was a fresh and young Clooney doing his soon-to-be normal, but great, schtick. I happen to be a fan of his cocky, but smart, ambitious but laid back appeal. So, I always give him a pass. And this movie contains one of my ALL TIME favorite movie scenes: (mild spoiler) Clooney's dear friend just gets killed and after an exciting car chase leaving one terrorist barely alive, Clooney says nothing in the downpour of water, walks up to him and shoots him point blank. As much as I like snappy comeback and final last crass words, this scene completely shocked and pleased me, because this is how it should've been done in real life and in the movies. Other than that one scene, it's exciting, interesting, has a great pace and a fun puzzle to put together while watching. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    George Clooney + Nicole Kidman together equal James Bond and spare NY from nuclear destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every so often, this picture had some realism to it. Mostly it was a hectic and overlong, nervous and excited movie. A Russian has hijacked 10 nuclear warheads that he's transporting for sale, with one going to a Serb-Croat-Muslim who intends to detonate it at the UN building. Kidman is the Executive Branch operative and Clooney is the military operative. The story takes on James Bond proportions as they seek out what's going on and then attempt to stop it. There are 2 or 3 climaxes that extend the story's length. After awhile, I was fast-forwarding through the predictable chase scene in NY City. There is quite an elaborate car chase scene in Serbia (I think) in which Clooney uses the car to destroy three cars in pursuit. This scene works well. Clooney handles his part nicely. He never fails to know what to do and acts very quickly. Kidman keeps up with him. The movie glorifies the U.S. technical prowess. The depictions are unreal and fantastic, if not ridiculous. It makes for propaganda. Nuclear warheads on American soil in terrorist hands are the ultimate U.S. nightmare, and so that's what the movie shows. In a moment of realism, we learn that the terrorist is attacking NY out of retaliation for US and NATO interference in the old Yugoslavia and the deaths of his family. It's called blowback. The other U.S. bugaboo is Iran (horror! horror!) and so another plot element is warheads headed for Iran. It's all strictly comic book level and by the numbers action, a popcorn feature. Nothing deep here except sell tickets and pay the upkeep of the producers, staff and movie makers. With Dreamworks making it, I didn't expect much, and nothing much happened. Why were the James Bond movies more satisfying?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nicole Kidman Was Looking Sexy But Then Again Russians Are Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    M MALIK
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nicole kid-man was so sexy but clooney was looking gay & a wannabe tough guy. Russians are portrayed as bad guys again in this who wants to launch a nuclear attack on USA but why because the main bad guy got betrayed & wanted revenge . i really don't care for stuff like this anymore because the only movie i lover of bombs is broken arrow of john travolta. the climax of the movie is bad & rushed & you'll see why i love movies but this ant-Russian & all that stuff is gone too far.after 9-11 a lot of films came out with more concepts like the plus point was that they have Afghanistan & Pakistan & terrorist groups stories & osama you know what i am saying. i cant understand clooney this guy acts the same in every film & his hairstyle also never change. my rating of the peacemaker is 2/10 watch only for Nicole kid-man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better movie starring George Clooney and Nichole Kidman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie would have been just as good if it was a plot for a James Bond movie. US military and civilian are tasked to find a stolen nuclear bomb. Cliff hanger of course is its detonation time, and how the two will find the bomb. I seriously think that this is one of the best role George Clooney played. He looks so real as the military officer. His chemistry with Nichole Kidman is really good too. The movie is hard to rate in that it's really well put together, but acting is bit weak, and this takes away from the tension. There's not enough character in George Clooney's role to make him interesting. Like many others who likes this movie, I like it for the story, and the quality of the production. It's an intriguing story, and is worth a watch for its story alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tired clich&eacute; of a movie which at least has a good opening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toll-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1997, although very much relevant in today's world, The Peacemaker stars George Clooney and Nicole Kidman in this action thriller revolving around potential terrorist attacks in New York. The film takes us to a variety of countries as our two leads hunt down the men responsible for selling nuclear warheads to those hell bent on causing pain and disruption to a country they feel is responsible for destroying their families lives. The Peacemaker opens with a brilliant opening sequence where a corrupt Russian General steals nine nuclear war heads from a train transporting them across the country. In an attempt to cover up their actions they set off one of the bombs in the process, killing up to 15,000 people. The cover up however is not successful and Lt Tom Devoe (Clooney) sees straight through the smoke screen, and upon briefing the acting adviser Dr Julia Kelly (Kidman) the two dart off across the World on the trail of the missing warheads, both using very opposite techniques to find their answers. From Vienna to Eastern Europe to New York City, Clooney and Kidman do all they can to prevent one of the biggest disasters to occur in western civilisation. For starters there is nothing particularly original about this film. The premise is a slight variation on something we have seen so many times before. The problem with this is in the writing where included throughout are several clich&eacute;d moment that we have seen in many films of the same era. For example we have the typical cursing every time something bad is said or a gun is fired, we have the typical screaming sidekick teamed up with the unfazed hard man (Kidman and Clooney), and as well we have the run 'with only ten seconds to spare' and jump as the bomb explodes in the background, as a matter of fact we have that twice. It is a slight shame really considering the opening sequence is very well done, but the pacing there on in just drags until the next set piece which is then followed again by slow pacing before the next set piece. This can only be a fault in the writing where we are literally given all the stereotypes of this type of film in one two hour block. The best part about the writing is the B story involving a diplomat who has an agenda for his deadly act. The story is dripped in slowly at the beginning and then brought to the forefront for the final act. It is the best part about the story as it is something slightly different than your typical Russian baddie plot; however it isn't particularly the norm that a B story actually completely overtakes the main plot of a film for the final thirty minutes of it. It makes the opening ninety minutes feel a little clunky and shows how weak the main plot actually is. Some of these issues could be down to the direction, which although not entirely bad does seem a little flat. Mimi Leder does manage to get a decent performance from Clooney but Kidman doesn't seem out of her comfort zone. The opening sequence is very well directed, and the music really adds to the drama, but the other action sequences seem pretty lifeless, especially the chase scene through the streets of Vienna. Also something that was heavily noticed whilst watching was the amount of time taken to chase this man throughout New York without the bomb going off when he had put a time limit on the bomb for a much shorter amount of time. Put it this way an entire third act which is about twenty minutes of screen time told us it was only about seven minutes in their world. It was definitely not plausible and there is a way they could have got over this. The film isn't entirely bad but there is enough wrong with it to make it not particularly good. The tired clich&eacute;s really take over after such a promising start to proceedings. The film could have, and probably should have, been better but the lifeless way in which the story was told, and the dull action sequences, really hindered the possibilities the film could have had. The music was one of the standout points, composed by Hans Zimmer, and from knowing his work in this day and age it is very obviously his work and the soundtrack booms over every tiny piece of action, unfortunately the action fails to live up to the score. I can't particularly say I was disappointed with this film as the opening scene was definitely one I was pleased to have seen, the thing is I could have happily turned it off after the opening twenty minutes and have ended up seeing a much better film. 2 / 5 For more reviews: www.tolli-movieworld.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Persistently Relevant and Riveting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker has both the sophistication, intelligence, and the suspense of its contemporary action thrillers as Spy Game (2001) and Enemy of the State (1998). The balance in the characters both male and female, the good and the bad guys makes for this mainstream action movie raises the bar on its other contemporary movies. The script is both cerebral and action packed, well edited, and nicely paced. Perhaps the renewed geopolitical tension in the world today with nuclear Iran and North Korea as well as the spread of terrorism keeps this movie relevant for today's audiences. Overall, this is a nice fusion of drama, action, technology, and political message of sorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the subplots derailed the film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattrochman
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker was a good and watchable film. The opening was solid and the structure of the story seemed interesting. Unlike other films of this genre, some intelligent and investigative plot lines unfolded. But ultimately the film should have steered clear of the plot line involving the Yugoslav character. Chasing the weapons, solid action, but running along side a rather silly plot about a man who seeks to avenge the deaths of his wife and daughter, and the war at the heart of it all, by detonating a nuclear bomb in the UN in New York. It became sentimental, far-fetched and sent the plot off course. I can only describe it as destabilising the main plot and I think that this is why a lot of people thought it was 'ok' but not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A humble masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mihnerts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, the 5.9 average doesn't do justice to this movie. The truth is that 'The Peacemaker' is a masterpiece and the reason is simple: it's captivating, thrilling and engages the human mind without relying on cgi effects but on masterfully directed subtle action scenes. I do not want to analyze it more because if I do I will miss the point. I will only say this: in many reviews we can read that it's a decent film and has nothing new to offer to the genre... In reality this is the exceptional thing about this film: it takes common place material, used again and again, and transforms them to something brilliant. This is one definition for the word masterpiece on cinema! I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I miss the cold war......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two trains crash somewhere in Russia, one carrying a nuclear payload. A nuclear explosion follows the crash and the world is on alert... However, White House nuclear expert Dr. Julia Kelly doesn't think it was an accident. Special Operations Intelligence Officer Colonel Thomas Devoe doesn't think so either. Together they must unravel a conspiracy that goes from Europe to New York, to stop a terrorist who has no demands... before Out of Sight made Clooney officially the coolest man on the planet, he was the one from ER who seemed desperate to be a huge movie star. A few of his movies, including this one, were so high profile, but so poorly received and average at the box office. It's because they seem so unique with the synopsis, but the execution is so average. Here Clooney has a bit of a swagger wearing white trousers and smirking at Kidman, who justs gets in a fluster every now and again. Sounds like the perfect recipe for a romantic comedy. But this is about Nuclear Weapons going missing. And the film drags in places. One of dreamworks first releases, it does have its moments. The car chase is quite good, and a siege on a bridge is visually impressive, as is the claustrophobic feel of the final act. But for a film that is over two hours long, these really seem few and far between, when the rest of the time we are treated to heated debate. The two stars are good, and you can tell Clooney will be big, It's a good job he met Soderbergh though. Heaven knows what would have happened to his career otherwise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than I thought it might be . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was particularly interested in this film because I was curious how Hollywood would treat this type of scenario, and of course, anything with Nicole Kidman in it has to be at least somewhat entertaining. I actually worked for DOE, in the national labs at Berkeley and also Los Alomos, a number of years ago, and a consequence of such have become quite familiar with nuclear ordnance in its myriad forms, including the so-called "suitcase nukes" that both the former Soviet Union & the USA have developed. Make no mistake, these types of miniaturized nuclear devices do exist, including from decommissioned MRV ballistic missiles and the like. The concept of nuclear warheads, slipping into the wrong hands does very much exist, although in current times this may more likely come from Pakistan, or any variety of "rogue" states who could acquire such through third party brokers. As a side note, any of these types of nuclear devices do require periodic "refurbishing", the details of which I won't elaborate on, but after a certain length of time, the capacity for thermo-nuclear detonation does diminish. Having said all that, does the film realistically portray any of this actually translating into a potential situation? Well . . . not exactly, but I think it's interesting that at least the concept was presented in a not overly ridiculous fashion. Sadly, with tremendous irony, I noted the twin trade towers in several of the background scenes. How odd it is that history often unfolds in the least expected ways. It was, after all, not a miniaturized nuke that was the greatest act of terrorism and evil ever perpetrated on US citizens, but rather planes filled with people . . . and boxcutters as the weaponry of terror. Was the film entertaining? Yes. Could it have been done better? Not sure if I have a qualified answer, but it certainly could have been done much worse. A bit dated? Perhaps . . . but I still think it's worth the time to watch, and contemplate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Peacetakers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never actually seen an episode of ER. I actually took to the movies to appreciate George Clooney, and have since 1997's The Peacemaker. While this movie didn't get a lot of hype or admiration, I truly had a good time. Loved the wit and snappiness of Clooney's dialogue, the action, suspense and drive of the characters. While it's not perfect and has that annoying "An Improbable Jump Through Solid Glass to Escape" scene that I always doubt and some omitted scenes that would've been awesome to see  i.e. two trains colliding, it was an enormously fun ride that, surprisingly, still holds up today, 16 years later. The plot is the norm: with a extensive plan, terrorists seize a nuclear bomb and it's up to two unlikely government heroes to work together, on a global scale, to find out: where they're headed, what they're up to and why. What stands this above the rest, was a fresh and young Clooney doing his soon-to-be normal, but great, schtick. I happen to be a fan of his cocky, but smart, ambitious but laid back appeal. So, I always give him a pass. And this movie contains one of my ALL TIME favorite movie scenes: (mild spoiler) Clooney's dear friend just gets killed and after an exciting car chase leaving one terrorist barely alive, Clooney says nothing in the downpour of water, walks up to him and shoots him point blank. As much as I like snappy comeback and final last crass words, this scene completely shocked and pleased me, because this is how it should've been done in real life and in the movies. Other than that one scene, it's exciting, interesting, has a great pace and a fun puzzle to put together while watching. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    George Clooney + Nicole Kidman together equal James Bond and spare NY from nuclear destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every so often, this picture had some realism to it. Mostly it was a hectic and overlong, nervous and excited movie. A Russian has hijacked 10 nuclear warheads that he's transporting for sale, with one going to a Serb-Croat-Muslim who intends to detonate it at the UN building. Kidman is the Executive Branch operative and Clooney is the military operative. The story takes on James Bond proportions as they seek out what's going on and then attempt to stop it. There are 2 or 3 climaxes that extend the story's length. After awhile, I was fast-forwarding through the predictable chase scene in NY City. There is quite an elaborate car chase scene in Serbia (I think) in which Clooney uses the car to destroy three cars in pursuit. This scene works well. Clooney handles his part nicely. He never fails to know what to do and acts very quickly. Kidman keeps up with him. The movie glorifies the U.S. technical prowess. The depictions are unreal and fantastic, if not ridiculous. It makes for propaganda. Nuclear warheads on American soil in terrorist hands are the ultimate U.S. nightmare, and so that's what the movie shows. In a moment of realism, we learn that the terrorist is attacking NY out of retaliation for US and NATO interference in the old Yugoslavia and the deaths of his family. It's called blowback. The other U.S. bugaboo is Iran (horror! horror!) and so another plot element is warheads headed for Iran. It's all strictly comic book level and by the numbers action, a popcorn feature. Nothing deep here except sell tickets and pay the upkeep of the producers, staff and movie makers. With Dreamworks making it, I didn't expect much, and nothing much happened. Why were the James Bond movies more satisfying?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nicole Kidman Was Looking Sexy But Then Again Russians Are Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    M MALIK
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nicole kid-man was so sexy but clooney was looking gay & a wannabe tough guy. Russians are portrayed as bad guys again in this who wants to launch a nuclear attack on USA but why because the main bad guy got betrayed & wanted revenge . i really don't care for stuff like this anymore because the only movie i lover of bombs is broken arrow of john travolta. the climax of the movie is bad & rushed & you'll see why i love movies but this ant-Russian & all that stuff is gone too far.after 9-11 a lot of films came out with more concepts like the plus point was that they have Afghanistan & Pakistan & terrorist groups stories & osama you know what i am saying. i cant understand clooney this guy acts the same in every film & his hairstyle also never change. my rating of the peacemaker is 2/10 watch only for Nicole kid-man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better movie starring George Clooney and Nichole Kidman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie would have been just as good if it was a plot for a James Bond movie. US military and civilian are tasked to find a stolen nuclear bomb. Cliff hanger of course is its detonation time, and how the two will find the bomb. I seriously think that this is one of the best role George Clooney played. He looks so real as the military officer. His chemistry with Nichole Kidman is really good too. The movie is hard to rate in that it's really well put together, but acting is bit weak, and this takes away from the tension. There's not enough character in George Clooney's role to make him interesting. Like many others who likes this movie, I like it for the story, and the quality of the production. It's an intriguing story, and is worth a watch for its story alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tired clich&eacute; of a movie which at least has a good opening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toll-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1997, although very much relevant in today's world, The Peacemaker stars George Clooney and Nicole Kidman in this action thriller revolving around potential terrorist attacks in New York. The film takes us to a variety of countries as our two leads hunt down the men responsible for selling nuclear warheads to those hell bent on causing pain and disruption to a country they feel is responsible for destroying their families lives. The Peacemaker opens with a brilliant opening sequence where a corrupt Russian General steals nine nuclear war heads from a train transporting them across the country. In an attempt to cover up their actions they set off one of the bombs in the process, killing up to 15,000 people. The cover up however is not successful and Lt Tom Devoe (Clooney) sees straight through the smoke screen, and upon briefing the acting adviser Dr Julia Kelly (Kidman) the two dart off across the World on the trail of the missing warheads, both using very opposite techniques to find their answers. From Vienna to Eastern Europe to New York City, Clooney and Kidman do all they can to prevent one of the biggest disasters to occur in western civilisation. For starters there is nothing particularly original about this film. The premise is a slight variation on something we have seen so many times before. The problem with this is in the writing where included throughout are several clich&eacute;d moment that we have seen in many films of the same era. For example we have the typical cursing every time something bad is said or a gun is fired, we have the typical screaming sidekick teamed up with the unfazed hard man (Kidman and Clooney), and as well we have the run 'with only ten seconds to spare' and jump as the bomb explodes in the background, as a matter of fact we have that twice. It is a slight shame really considering the opening sequence is very well done, but the pacing there on in just drags until the next set piece which is then followed again by slow pacing before the next set piece. This can only be a fault in the writing where we are literally given all the stereotypes of this type of film in one two hour block. The best part about the writing is the B story involving a diplomat who has an agenda for his deadly act. The story is dripped in slowly at the beginning and then brought to the forefront for the final act. It is the best part about the story as it is something slightly different than your typical Russian baddie plot; however it isn't particularly the norm that a B story actually completely overtakes the main plot of a film for the final thirty minutes of it. It makes the opening ninety minutes feel a little clunky and shows how weak the main plot actually is. Some of these issues could be down to the direction, which although not entirely bad does seem a little flat. Mimi Leder does manage to get a decent performance from Clooney but Kidman doesn't seem out of her comfort zone. The opening sequence is very well directed, and the music really adds to the drama, but the other action sequences seem pretty lifeless, especially the chase scene through the streets of Vienna. Also something that was heavily noticed whilst watching was the amount of time taken to chase this man throughout New York without the bomb going off when he had put a time limit on the bomb for a much shorter amount of time. Put it this way an entire third act which is about twenty minutes of screen time told us it was only about seven minutes in their world. It was definitely not plausible and there is a way they could have got over this. The film isn't entirely bad but there is enough wrong with it to make it not particularly good. The tired clich&eacute;s really take over after such a promising start to proceedings. The film could have, and probably should have, been better but the lifeless way in which the story was told, and the dull action sequences, really hindered the possibilities the film could have had. The music was one of the standout points, composed by Hans Zimmer, and from knowing his work in this day and age it is very obviously his work and the soundtrack booms over every tiny piece of action, unfortunately the action fails to live up to the score. I can't particularly say I was disappointed with this film as the opening scene was definitely one I was pleased to have seen, the thing is I could have happily turned it off after the opening twenty minutes and have ended up seeing a much better film. 2 / 5 For more reviews: www.tolli-movieworld.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Persistently Relevant and Riveting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker has both the sophistication, intelligence, and the suspense of its contemporary action thrillers as Spy Game (2001) and Enemy of the State (1998). The balance in the characters both male and female, the good and the bad guys makes for this mainstream action movie raises the bar on its other contemporary movies. The script is both cerebral and action packed, well edited, and nicely paced. Perhaps the renewed geopolitical tension in the world today with nuclear Iran and North Korea as well as the spread of terrorism keeps this movie relevant for today's audiences. Overall, this is a nice fusion of drama, action, technology, and political message of sorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the subplots derailed the film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattrochman
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker was a good and watchable film. The opening was solid and the structure of the story seemed interesting. Unlike other films of this genre, some intelligent and investigative plot lines unfolded. But ultimately the film should have steered clear of the plot line involving the Yugoslav character. Chasing the weapons, solid action, but running along side a rather silly plot about a man who seeks to avenge the deaths of his wife and daughter, and the war at the heart of it all, by detonating a nuclear bomb in the UN in New York. It became sentimental, far-fetched and sent the plot off course. I can only describe it as destabilising the main plot and I think that this is why a lot of people thought it was 'ok' but not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A humble masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mihnerts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, the 5.9 average doesn't do justice to this movie. The truth is that 'The Peacemaker' is a masterpiece and the reason is simple: it's captivating, thrilling and engages the human mind without relying on cgi effects but on masterfully directed subtle action scenes. I do not want to analyze it more because if I do I will miss the point. I will only say this: in many reviews we can read that it's a decent film and has nothing new to offer to the genre... In reality this is the exceptional thing about this film: it takes common place material, used again and again, and transforms them to something brilliant. This is one definition for the word masterpiece on cinema! I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I miss the cold war......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two trains crash somewhere in Russia, one carrying a nuclear payload. A nuclear explosion follows the crash and the world is on alert... However, White House nuclear expert Dr. Julia Kelly doesn't think it was an accident. Special Operations Intelligence Officer Colonel Thomas Devoe doesn't think so either. Together they must unravel a conspiracy that goes from Europe to New York, to stop a terrorist who has no demands... before Out of Sight made Clooney officially the coolest man on the planet, he was the one from ER who seemed desperate to be a huge movie star. A few of his movies, including this one, were so high profile, but so poorly received and average at the box office. It's because they seem so unique with the synopsis, but the execution is so average. Here Clooney has a bit of a swagger wearing white trousers and smirking at Kidman, who justs gets in a fluster every now and again. Sounds like the perfect recipe for a romantic comedy. But this is about Nuclear Weapons going missing. And the film drags in places. One of dreamworks first releases, it does have its moments. The car chase is quite good, and a siege on a bridge is visually impressive, as is the claustrophobic feel of the final act. But for a film that is over two hours long, these really seem few and far between, when the rest of the time we are treated to heated debate. The two stars are good, and you can tell Clooney will be big, It's a good job he met Soderbergh though. Heaven knows what would have happened to his career otherwise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than I thought it might be . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was particularly interested in this film because I was curious how Hollywood would treat this type of scenario, and of course, anything with Nicole Kidman in it has to be at least somewhat entertaining. I actually worked for DOE, in the national labs at Berkeley and also Los Alomos, a number of years ago, and a consequence of such have become quite familiar with nuclear ordnance in its myriad forms, including the so-called "suitcase nukes" that both the former Soviet Union & the USA have developed. Make no mistake, these types of miniaturized nuclear devices do exist, including from decommissioned MRV ballistic missiles and the like. The concept of nuclear warheads, slipping into the wrong hands does very much exist, although in current times this may more likely come from Pakistan, or any variety of "rogue" states who could acquire such through third party brokers. As a side note, any of these types of nuclear devices do require periodic "refurbishing", the details of which I won't elaborate on, but after a certain length of time, the capacity for thermo-nuclear detonation does diminish. Having said all that, does the film realistically portray any of this actually translating into a potential situation? Well . . . not exactly, but I think it's interesting that at least the concept was presented in a not overly ridiculous fashion. Sadly, with tremendous irony, I noted the twin trade towers in several of the background scenes. How odd it is that history often unfolds in the least expected ways. It was, after all, not a miniaturized nuke that was the greatest act of terrorism and evil ever perpetrated on US citizens, but rather planes filled with people . . . and boxcutters as the weaponry of terror. Was the film entertaining? Yes. Could it have been done better? Not sure if I have a qualified answer, but it certainly could have been done much worse. A bit dated? Perhaps . . . but I still think it's worth the time to watch, and contemplate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Peacetakers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never actually seen an episode of ER. I actually took to the movies to appreciate George Clooney, and have since 1997's The Peacemaker. While this movie didn't get a lot of hype or admiration, I truly had a good time. Loved the wit and snappiness of Clooney's dialogue, the action, suspense and drive of the characters. While it's not perfect and has that annoying "An Improbable Jump Through Solid Glass to Escape" scene that I always doubt and some omitted scenes that would've been awesome to see  i.e. two trains colliding, it was an enormously fun ride that, surprisingly, still holds up today, 16 years later. The plot is the norm: with a extensive plan, terrorists seize a nuclear bomb and it's up to two unlikely government heroes to work together, on a global scale, to find out: where they're headed, what they're up to and why. What stands this above the rest, was a fresh and young Clooney doing his soon-to-be normal, but great, schtick. I happen to be a fan of his cocky, but smart, ambitious but laid back appeal. So, I always give him a pass. And this movie contains one of my ALL TIME favorite movie scenes: (mild spoiler) Clooney's dear friend just gets killed and after an exciting car chase leaving one terrorist barely alive, Clooney says nothing in the downpour of water, walks up to him and shoots him point blank. As much as I like snappy comeback and final last crass words, this scene completely shocked and pleased me, because this is how it should've been done in real life and in the movies. Other than that one scene, it's exciting, interesting, has a great pace and a fun puzzle to put together while watching. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    George Clooney + Nicole Kidman together equal James Bond and spare NY from nuclear destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every so often, this picture had some realism to it. Mostly it was a hectic and overlong, nervous and excited movie. A Russian has hijacked 10 nuclear warheads that he's transporting for sale, with one going to a Serb-Croat-Muslim who intends to detonate it at the UN building. Kidman is the Executive Branch operative and Clooney is the military operative. The story takes on James Bond proportions as they seek out what's going on and then attempt to stop it. There are 2 or 3 climaxes that extend the story's length. After awhile, I was fast-forwarding through the predictable chase scene in NY City. There is quite an elaborate car chase scene in Serbia (I think) in which Clooney uses the car to destroy three cars in pursuit. This scene works well. Clooney handles his part nicely. He never fails to know what to do and acts very quickly. Kidman keeps up with him. The movie glorifies the U.S. technical prowess. The depictions are unreal and fantastic, if not ridiculous. It makes for propaganda. Nuclear warheads on American soil in terrorist hands are the ultimate U.S. nightmare, and so that's what the movie shows. In a moment of realism, we learn that the terrorist is attacking NY out of retaliation for US and NATO interference in the old Yugoslavia and the deaths of his family. It's called blowback. The other U.S. bugaboo is Iran (horror! horror!) and so another plot element is warheads headed for Iran. It's all strictly comic book level and by the numbers action, a popcorn feature. Nothing deep here except sell tickets and pay the upkeep of the producers, staff and movie makers. With Dreamworks making it, I didn't expect much, and nothing much happened. Why were the James Bond movies more satisfying?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nicole Kidman Was Looking Sexy But Then Again Russians Are Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    M MALIK
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nicole kid-man was so sexy but clooney was looking gay & a wannabe tough guy. Russians are portrayed as bad guys again in this who wants to launch a nuclear attack on USA but why because the main bad guy got betrayed & wanted revenge . i really don't care for stuff like this anymore because the only movie i lover of bombs is broken arrow of john travolta. the climax of the movie is bad & rushed & you'll see why i love movies but this ant-Russian & all that stuff is gone too far.after 9-11 a lot of films came out with more concepts like the plus point was that they have Afghanistan & Pakistan & terrorist groups stories & osama you know what i am saying. i cant understand clooney this guy acts the same in every film & his hairstyle also never change. my rating of the peacemaker is 2/10 watch only for Nicole kid-man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better movie starring George Clooney and Nichole Kidman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie would have been just as good if it was a plot for a James Bond movie. US military and civilian are tasked to find a stolen nuclear bomb. Cliff hanger of course is its detonation time, and how the two will find the bomb. I seriously think that this is one of the best role George Clooney played. He looks so real as the military officer. His chemistry with Nichole Kidman is really good too. The movie is hard to rate in that it's really well put together, but acting is bit weak, and this takes away from the tension. There's not enough character in George Clooney's role to make him interesting. Like many others who likes this movie, I like it for the story, and the quality of the production. It's an intriguing story, and is worth a watch for its story alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tired clich&eacute; of a movie which at least has a good opening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toll-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1997, although very much relevant in today's world, The Peacemaker stars George Clooney and Nicole Kidman in this action thriller revolving around potential terrorist attacks in New York. The film takes us to a variety of countries as our two leads hunt down the men responsible for selling nuclear warheads to those hell bent on causing pain and disruption to a country they feel is responsible for destroying their families lives. The Peacemaker opens with a brilliant opening sequence where a corrupt Russian General steals nine nuclear war heads from a train transporting them across the country. In an attempt to cover up their actions they set off one of the bombs in the process, killing up to 15,000 people. The cover up however is not successful and Lt Tom Devoe (Clooney) sees straight through the smoke screen, and upon briefing the acting adviser Dr Julia Kelly (Kidman) the two dart off across the World on the trail of the missing warheads, both using very opposite techniques to find their answers. From Vienna to Eastern Europe to New York City, Clooney and Kidman do all they can to prevent one of the biggest disasters to occur in western civilisation. For starters there is nothing particularly original about this film. The premise is a slight variation on something we have seen so many times before. The problem with this is in the writing where included throughout are several clich&eacute;d moment that we have seen in many films of the same era. For example we have the typical cursing every time something bad is said or a gun is fired, we have the typical screaming sidekick teamed up with the unfazed hard man (Kidman and Clooney), and as well we have the run 'with only ten seconds to spare' and jump as the bomb explodes in the background, as a matter of fact we have that twice. It is a slight shame really considering the opening sequence is very well done, but the pacing there on in just drags until the next set piece which is then followed again by slow pacing before the next set piece. This can only be a fault in the writing where we are literally given all the stereotypes of this type of film in one two hour block. The best part about the writing is the B story involving a diplomat who has an agenda for his deadly act. The story is dripped in slowly at the beginning and then brought to the forefront for the final act. It is the best part about the story as it is something slightly different than your typical Russian baddie plot; however it isn't particularly the norm that a B story actually completely overtakes the main plot of a film for the final thirty minutes of it. It makes the opening ninety minutes feel a little clunky and shows how weak the main plot actually is. Some of these issues could be down to the direction, which although not entirely bad does seem a little flat. Mimi Leder does manage to get a decent performance from Clooney but Kidman doesn't seem out of her comfort zone. The opening sequence is very well directed, and the music really adds to the drama, but the other action sequences seem pretty lifeless, especially the chase scene through the streets of Vienna. Also something that was heavily noticed whilst watching was the amount of time taken to chase this man throughout New York without the bomb going off when he had put a time limit on the bomb for a much shorter amount of time. Put it this way an entire third act which is about twenty minutes of screen time told us it was only about seven minutes in their world. It was definitely not plausible and there is a way they could have got over this. The film isn't entirely bad but there is enough wrong with it to make it not particularly good. The tired clich&eacute;s really take over after such a promising start to proceedings. The film could have, and probably should have, been better but the lifeless way in which the story was told, and the dull action sequences, really hindered the possibilities the film could have had. The music was one of the standout points, composed by Hans Zimmer, and from knowing his work in this day and age it is very obviously his work and the soundtrack booms over every tiny piece of action, unfortunately the action fails to live up to the score. I can't particularly say I was disappointed with this film as the opening scene was definitely one I was pleased to have seen, the thing is I could have happily turned it off after the opening twenty minutes and have ended up seeing a much better film. 2 / 5 For more reviews: www.tolli-movieworld.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Persistently Relevant and Riveting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker has both the sophistication, intelligence, and the suspense of its contemporary action thrillers as Spy Game (2001) and Enemy of the State (1998). The balance in the characters both male and female, the good and the bad guys makes for this mainstream action movie raises the bar on its other contemporary movies. The script is both cerebral and action packed, well edited, and nicely paced. Perhaps the renewed geopolitical tension in the world today with nuclear Iran and North Korea as well as the spread of terrorism keeps this movie relevant for today's audiences. Overall, this is a nice fusion of drama, action, technology, and political message of sorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the subplots derailed the film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattrochman
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker was a good and watchable film. The opening was solid and the structure of the story seemed interesting. Unlike other films of this genre, some intelligent and investigative plot lines unfolded. But ultimately the film should have steered clear of the plot line involving the Yugoslav character. Chasing the weapons, solid action, but running along side a rather silly plot about a man who seeks to avenge the deaths of his wife and daughter, and the war at the heart of it all, by detonating a nuclear bomb in the UN in New York. It became sentimental, far-fetched and sent the plot off course. I can only describe it as destabilising the main plot and I think that this is why a lot of people thought it was 'ok' but not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A humble masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mihnerts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, the 5.9 average doesn't do justice to this movie. The truth is that 'The Peacemaker' is a masterpiece and the reason is simple: it's captivating, thrilling and engages the human mind without relying on cgi effects but on masterfully directed subtle action scenes. I do not want to analyze it more because if I do I will miss the point. I will only say this: in many reviews we can read that it's a decent film and has nothing new to offer to the genre... In reality this is the exceptional thing about this film: it takes common place material, used again and again, and transforms them to something brilliant. This is one definition for the word masterpiece on cinema! I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I miss the cold war......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two trains crash somewhere in Russia, one carrying a nuclear payload. A nuclear explosion follows the crash and the world is on alert... However, White House nuclear expert Dr. Julia Kelly doesn't think it was an accident. Special Operations Intelligence Officer Colonel Thomas Devoe doesn't think so either. Together they must unravel a conspiracy that goes from Europe to New York, to stop a terrorist who has no demands... before Out of Sight made Clooney officially the coolest man on the planet, he was the one from ER who seemed desperate to be a huge movie star. A few of his movies, including this one, were so high profile, but so poorly received and average at the box office. It's because they seem so unique with the synopsis, but the execution is so average. Here Clooney has a bit of a swagger wearing white trousers and smirking at Kidman, who justs gets in a fluster every now and again. Sounds like the perfect recipe for a romantic comedy. But this is about Nuclear Weapons going missing. And the film drags in places. One of dreamworks first releases, it does have its moments. The car chase is quite good, and a siege on a bridge is visually impressive, as is the claustrophobic feel of the final act. But for a film that is over two hours long, these really seem few and far between, when the rest of the time we are treated to heated debate. The two stars are good, and you can tell Clooney will be big, It's a good job he met Soderbergh though. Heaven knows what would have happened to his career otherwise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than I thought it might be . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was particularly interested in this film because I was curious how Hollywood would treat this type of scenario, and of course, anything with Nicole Kidman in it has to be at least somewhat entertaining. I actually worked for DOE, in the national labs at Berkeley and also Los Alomos, a number of years ago, and a consequence of such have become quite familiar with nuclear ordnance in its myriad forms, including the so-called "suitcase nukes" that both the former Soviet Union & the USA have developed. Make no mistake, these types of miniaturized nuclear devices do exist, including from decommissioned MRV ballistic missiles and the like. The concept of nuclear warheads, slipping into the wrong hands does very much exist, although in current times this may more likely come from Pakistan, or any variety of "rogue" states who could acquire such through third party brokers. As a side note, any of these types of nuclear devices do require periodic "refurbishing", the details of which I won't elaborate on, but after a certain length of time, the capacity for thermo-nuclear detonation does diminish. Having said all that, does the film realistically portray any of this actually translating into a potential situation? Well . . . not exactly, but I think it's interesting that at least the concept was presented in a not overly ridiculous fashion. Sadly, with tremendous irony, I noted the twin trade towers in several of the background scenes. How odd it is that history often unfolds in the least expected ways. It was, after all, not a miniaturized nuke that was the greatest act of terrorism and evil ever perpetrated on US citizens, but rather planes filled with people . . . and boxcutters as the weaponry of terror. Was the film entertaining? Yes. Could it have been done better? Not sure if I have a qualified answer, but it certainly could have been done much worse. A bit dated? Perhaps . . . but I still think it's worth the time to watch, and contemplate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Peacetakers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never actually seen an episode of ER. I actually took to the movies to appreciate George Clooney, and have since 1997's The Peacemaker. While this movie didn't get a lot of hype or admiration, I truly had a good time. Loved the wit and snappiness of Clooney's dialogue, the action, suspense and drive of the characters. While it's not perfect and has that annoying "An Improbable Jump Through Solid Glass to Escape" scene that I always doubt and some omitted scenes that would've been awesome to see  i.e. two trains colliding, it was an enormously fun ride that, surprisingly, still holds up today, 16 years later. The plot is the norm: with a extensive plan, terrorists seize a nuclear bomb and it's up to two unlikely government heroes to work together, on a global scale, to find out: where they're headed, what they're up to and why. What stands this above the rest, was a fresh and young Clooney doing his soon-to-be normal, but great, schtick. I happen to be a fan of his cocky, but smart, ambitious but laid back appeal. So, I always give him a pass. And this movie contains one of my ALL TIME favorite movie scenes: (mild spoiler) Clooney's dear friend just gets killed and after an exciting car chase leaving one terrorist barely alive, Clooney says nothing in the downpour of water, walks up to him and shoots him point blank. As much as I like snappy comeback and final last crass words, this scene completely shocked and pleased me, because this is how it should've been done in real life and in the movies. Other than that one scene, it's exciting, interesting, has a great pace and a fun puzzle to put together while watching. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    George Clooney + Nicole Kidman together equal James Bond and spare NY from nuclear destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every so often, this picture had some realism to it. Mostly it was a hectic and overlong, nervous and excited movie. A Russian has hijacked 10 nuclear warheads that he's transporting for sale, with one going to a Serb-Croat-Muslim who intends to detonate it at the UN building. Kidman is the Executive Branch operative and Clooney is the military operative. The story takes on James Bond proportions as they seek out what's going on and then attempt to stop it. There are 2 or 3 climaxes that extend the story's length. After awhile, I was fast-forwarding through the predictable chase scene in NY City. There is quite an elaborate car chase scene in Serbia (I think) in which Clooney uses the car to destroy three cars in pursuit. This scene works well. Clooney handles his part nicely. He never fails to know what to do and acts very quickly. Kidman keeps up with him. The movie glorifies the U.S. technical prowess. The depictions are unreal and fantastic, if not ridiculous. It makes for propaganda. Nuclear warheads on American soil in terrorist hands are the ultimate U.S. nightmare, and so that's what the movie shows. In a moment of realism, we learn that the terrorist is attacking NY out of retaliation for US and NATO interference in the old Yugoslavia and the deaths of his family. It's called blowback. The other U.S. bugaboo is Iran (horror! horror!) and so another plot element is warheads headed for Iran. It's all strictly comic book level and by the numbers action, a popcorn feature. Nothing deep here except sell tickets and pay the upkeep of the producers, staff and movie makers. With Dreamworks making it, I didn't expect much, and nothing much happened. Why were the James Bond movies more satisfying?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nicole Kidman Was Looking Sexy But Then Again Russians Are Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    M MALIK
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nicole kid-man was so sexy but clooney was looking gay & a wannabe tough guy. Russians are portrayed as bad guys again in this who wants to launch a nuclear attack on USA but why because the main bad guy got betrayed & wanted revenge . i really don't care for stuff like this anymore because the only movie i lover of bombs is broken arrow of john travolta. the climax of the movie is bad & rushed & you'll see why i love movies but this ant-Russian & all that stuff is gone too far.after 9-11 a lot of films came out with more concepts like the plus point was that they have Afghanistan & Pakistan & terrorist groups stories & osama you know what i am saying. i cant understand clooney this guy acts the same in every film & his hairstyle also never change. my rating of the peacemaker is 2/10 watch only for Nicole kid-man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better movie starring George Clooney and Nichole Kidman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie would have been just as good if it was a plot for a James Bond movie. US military and civilian are tasked to find a stolen nuclear bomb. Cliff hanger of course is its detonation time, and how the two will find the bomb. I seriously think that this is one of the best role George Clooney played. He looks so real as the military officer. His chemistry with Nichole Kidman is really good too. The movie is hard to rate in that it's really well put together, but acting is bit weak, and this takes away from the tension. There's not enough character in George Clooney's role to make him interesting. Like many others who likes this movie, I like it for the story, and the quality of the production. It's an intriguing story, and is worth a watch for its story alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tired clich&eacute; of a movie which at least has a good opening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toll-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1997, although very much relevant in today's world, The Peacemaker stars George Clooney and Nicole Kidman in this action thriller revolving around potential terrorist attacks in New York. The film takes us to a variety of countries as our two leads hunt down the men responsible for selling nuclear warheads to those hell bent on causing pain and disruption to a country they feel is responsible for destroying their families lives. The Peacemaker opens with a brilliant opening sequence where a corrupt Russian General steals nine nuclear war heads from a train transporting them across the country. In an attempt to cover up their actions they set off one of the bombs in the process, killing up to 15,000 people. The cover up however is not successful and Lt Tom Devoe (Clooney) sees straight through the smoke screen, and upon briefing the acting adviser Dr Julia Kelly (Kidman) the two dart off across the World on the trail of the missing warheads, both using very opposite techniques to find their answers. From Vienna to Eastern Europe to New York City, Clooney and Kidman do all they can to prevent one of the biggest disasters to occur in western civilisation. For starters there is nothing particularly original about this film. The premise is a slight variation on something we have seen so many times before. The problem with this is in the writing where included throughout are several clich&eacute;d moment that we have seen in many films of the same era. For example we have the typical cursing every time something bad is said or a gun is fired, we have the typical screaming sidekick teamed up with the unfazed hard man (Kidman and Clooney), and as well we have the run 'with only ten seconds to spare' and jump as the bomb explodes in the background, as a matter of fact we have that twice. It is a slight shame really considering the opening sequence is very well done, but the pacing there on in just drags until the next set piece which is then followed again by slow pacing before the next set piece. This can only be a fault in the writing where we are literally given all the stereotypes of this type of film in one two hour block. The best part about the writing is the B story involving a diplomat who has an agenda for his deadly act. The story is dripped in slowly at the beginning and then brought to the forefront for the final act. It is the best part about the story as it is something slightly different than your typical Russian baddie plot; however it isn't particularly the norm that a B story actually completely overtakes the main plot of a film for the final thirty minutes of it. It makes the opening ninety minutes feel a little clunky and shows how weak the main plot actually is. Some of these issues could be down to the direction, which although not entirely bad does seem a little flat. Mimi Leder does manage to get a decent performance from Clooney but Kidman doesn't seem out of her comfort zone. The opening sequence is very well directed, and the music really adds to the drama, but the other action sequences seem pretty lifeless, especially the chase scene through the streets of Vienna. Also something that was heavily noticed whilst watching was the amount of time taken to chase this man throughout New York without the bomb going off when he had put a time limit on the bomb for a much shorter amount of time. Put it this way an entire third act which is about twenty minutes of screen time told us it was only about seven minutes in their world. It was definitely not plausible and there is a way they could have got over this. The film isn't entirely bad but there is enough wrong with it to make it not particularly good. The tired clich&eacute;s really take over after such a promising start to proceedings. The film could have, and probably should have, been better but the lifeless way in which the story was told, and the dull action sequences, really hindered the possibilities the film could have had. The music was one of the standout points, composed by Hans Zimmer, and from knowing his work in this day and age it is very obviously his work and the soundtrack booms over every tiny piece of action, unfortunately the action fails to live up to the score. I can't particularly say I was disappointed with this film as the opening scene was definitely one I was pleased to have seen, the thing is I could have happily turned it off after the opening twenty minutes and have ended up seeing a much better film. 2 / 5 For more reviews: www.tolli-movieworld.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Persistently Relevant and Riveting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker has both the sophistication, intelligence, and the suspense of its contemporary action thrillers as Spy Game (2001) and Enemy of the State (1998). The balance in the characters both male and female, the good and the bad guys makes for this mainstream action movie raises the bar on its other contemporary movies. The script is both cerebral and action packed, well edited, and nicely paced. Perhaps the renewed geopolitical tension in the world today with nuclear Iran and North Korea as well as the spread of terrorism keeps this movie relevant for today's audiences. Overall, this is a nice fusion of drama, action, technology, and political message of sorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the subplots derailed the film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattrochman
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker was a good and watchable film. The opening was solid and the structure of the story seemed interesting. Unlike other films of this genre, some intelligent and investigative plot lines unfolded. But ultimately the film should have steered clear of the plot line involving the Yugoslav character. Chasing the weapons, solid action, but running along side a rather silly plot about a man who seeks to avenge the deaths of his wife and daughter, and the war at the heart of it all, by detonating a nuclear bomb in the UN in New York. It became sentimental, far-fetched and sent the plot off course. I can only describe it as destabilising the main plot and I think that this is why a lot of people thought it was 'ok' but not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A humble masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mihnerts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, the 5.9 average doesn't do justice to this movie. The truth is that 'The Peacemaker' is a masterpiece and the reason is simple: it's captivating, thrilling and engages the human mind without relying on cgi effects but on masterfully directed subtle action scenes. I do not want to analyze it more because if I do I will miss the point. I will only say this: in many reviews we can read that it's a decent film and has nothing new to offer to the genre... In reality this is the exceptional thing about this film: it takes common place material, used again and again, and transforms them to something brilliant. This is one definition for the word masterpiece on cinema! I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I miss the cold war......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two trains crash somewhere in Russia, one carrying a nuclear payload. A nuclear explosion follows the crash and the world is on alert... However, White House nuclear expert Dr. Julia Kelly doesn't think it was an accident. Special Operations Intelligence Officer Colonel Thomas Devoe doesn't think so either. Together they must unravel a conspiracy that goes from Europe to New York, to stop a terrorist who has no demands... before Out of Sight made Clooney officially the coolest man on the planet, he was the one from ER who seemed desperate to be a huge movie star. A few of his movies, including this one, were so high profile, but so poorly received and average at the box office. It's because they seem so unique with the synopsis, but the execution is so average. Here Clooney has a bit of a swagger wearing white trousers and smirking at Kidman, who justs gets in a fluster every now and again. Sounds like the perfect recipe for a romantic comedy. But this is about Nuclear Weapons going missing. And the film drags in places. One of dreamworks first releases, it does have its moments. The car chase is quite good, and a siege on a bridge is visually impressive, as is the claustrophobic feel of the final act. But for a film that is over two hours long, these really seem few and far between, when the rest of the time we are treated to heated debate. The two stars are good, and you can tell Clooney will be big, It's a good job he met Soderbergh though. Heaven knows what would have happened to his career otherwise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than I thought it might be . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was particularly interested in this film because I was curious how Hollywood would treat this type of scenario, and of course, anything with Nicole Kidman in it has to be at least somewhat entertaining. I actually worked for DOE, in the national labs at Berkeley and also Los Alomos, a number of years ago, and a consequence of such have become quite familiar with nuclear ordnance in its myriad forms, including the so-called "suitcase nukes" that both the former Soviet Union & the USA have developed. Make no mistake, these types of miniaturized nuclear devices do exist, including from decommissioned MRV ballistic missiles and the like. The concept of nuclear warheads, slipping into the wrong hands does very much exist, although in current times this may more likely come from Pakistan, or any variety of "rogue" states who could acquire such through third party brokers. As a side note, any of these types of nuclear devices do require periodic "refurbishing", the details of which I won't elaborate on, but after a certain length of time, the capacity for thermo-nuclear detonation does diminish. Having said all that, does the film realistically portray any of this actually translating into a potential situation? Well . . . not exactly, but I think it's interesting that at least the concept was presented in a not overly ridiculous fashion. Sadly, with tremendous irony, I noted the twin trade towers in several of the background scenes. How odd it is that history often unfolds in the least expected ways. It was, after all, not a miniaturized nuke that was the greatest act of terrorism and evil ever perpetrated on US citizens, but rather planes filled with people . . . and boxcutters as the weaponry of terror. Was the film entertaining? Yes. Could it have been done better? Not sure if I have a qualified answer, but it certainly could have been done much worse. A bit dated? Perhaps . . . but I still think it's worth the time to watch, and contemplate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Peacetakers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never actually seen an episode of ER. I actually took to the movies to appreciate George Clooney, and have since 1997's The Peacemaker. While this movie didn't get a lot of hype or admiration, I truly had a good time. Loved the wit and snappiness of Clooney's dialogue, the action, suspense and drive of the characters. While it's not perfect and has that annoying "An Improbable Jump Through Solid Glass to Escape" scene that I always doubt and some omitted scenes that would've been awesome to see  i.e. two trains colliding, it was an enormously fun ride that, surprisingly, still holds up today, 16 years later. The plot is the norm: with a extensive plan, terrorists seize a nuclear bomb and it's up to two unlikely government heroes to work together, on a global scale, to find out: where they're headed, what they're up to and why. What stands this above the rest, was a fresh and young Clooney doing his soon-to-be normal, but great, schtick. I happen to be a fan of his cocky, but smart, ambitious but laid back appeal. So, I always give him a pass. And this movie contains one of my ALL TIME favorite movie scenes: (mild spoiler) Clooney's dear friend just gets killed and after an exciting car chase leaving one terrorist barely alive, Clooney says nothing in the downpour of water, walks up to him and shoots him point blank. As much as I like snappy comeback and final last crass words, this scene completely shocked and pleased me, because this is how it should've been done in real life and in the movies. Other than that one scene, it's exciting, interesting, has a great pace and a fun puzzle to put together while watching. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    George Clooney + Nicole Kidman together equal James Bond and spare NY from nuclear destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every so often, this picture had some realism to it. Mostly it was a hectic and overlong, nervous and excited movie. A Russian has hijacked 10 nuclear warheads that he's transporting for sale, with one going to a Serb-Croat-Muslim who intends to detonate it at the UN building. Kidman is the Executive Branch operative and Clooney is the military operative. The story takes on James Bond proportions as they seek out what's going on and then attempt to stop it. There are 2 or 3 climaxes that extend the story's length. After awhile, I was fast-forwarding through the predictable chase scene in NY City. There is quite an elaborate car chase scene in Serbia (I think) in which Clooney uses the car to destroy three cars in pursuit. This scene works well. Clooney handles his part nicely. He never fails to know what to do and acts very quickly. Kidman keeps up with him. The movie glorifies the U.S. technical prowess. The depictions are unreal and fantastic, if not ridiculous. It makes for propaganda. Nuclear warheads on American soil in terrorist hands are the ultimate U.S. nightmare, and so that's what the movie shows. In a moment of realism, we learn that the terrorist is attacking NY out of retaliation for US and NATO interference in the old Yugoslavia and the deaths of his family. It's called blowback. The other U.S. bugaboo is Iran (horror! horror!) and so another plot element is warheads headed for Iran. It's all strictly comic book level and by the numbers action, a popcorn feature. Nothing deep here except sell tickets and pay the upkeep of the producers, staff and movie makers. With Dreamworks making it, I didn't expect much, and nothing much happened. Why were the James Bond movies more satisfying?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nicole Kidman Was Looking Sexy But Then Again Russians Are Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    M MALIK
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nicole kid-man was so sexy but clooney was looking gay & a wannabe tough guy. Russians are portrayed as bad guys again in this who wants to launch a nuclear attack on USA but why because the main bad guy got betrayed & wanted revenge . i really don't care for stuff like this anymore because the only movie i lover of bombs is broken arrow of john travolta. the climax of the movie is bad & rushed & you'll see why i love movies but this ant-Russian & all that stuff is gone too far.after 9-11 a lot of films came out with more concepts like the plus point was that they have Afghanistan & Pakistan & terrorist groups stories & osama you know what i am saying. i cant understand clooney this guy acts the same in every film & his hairstyle also never change. my rating of the peacemaker is 2/10 watch only for Nicole kid-man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better movie starring George Clooney and Nichole Kidman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie would have been just as good if it was a plot for a James Bond movie. US military and civilian are tasked to find a stolen nuclear bomb. Cliff hanger of course is its detonation time, and how the two will find the bomb. I seriously think that this is one of the best role George Clooney played. He looks so real as the military officer. His chemistry with Nichole Kidman is really good too. The movie is hard to rate in that it's really well put together, but acting is bit weak, and this takes away from the tension. There's not enough character in George Clooney's role to make him interesting. Like many others who likes this movie, I like it for the story, and the quality of the production. It's an intriguing story, and is worth a watch for its story alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tired clich&eacute; of a movie which at least has a good opening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toll-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1997, although very much relevant in today's world, The Peacemaker stars George Clooney and Nicole Kidman in this action thriller revolving around potential terrorist attacks in New York. The film takes us to a variety of countries as our two leads hunt down the men responsible for selling nuclear warheads to those hell bent on causing pain and disruption to a country they feel is responsible for destroying their families lives. The Peacemaker opens with a brilliant opening sequence where a corrupt Russian General steals nine nuclear war heads from a train transporting them across the country. In an attempt to cover up their actions they set off one of the bombs in the process, killing up to 15,000 people. The cover up however is not successful and Lt Tom Devoe (Clooney) sees straight through the smoke screen, and upon briefing the acting adviser Dr Julia Kelly (Kidman) the two dart off across the World on the trail of the missing warheads, both using very opposite techniques to find their answers. From Vienna to Eastern Europe to New York City, Clooney and Kidman do all they can to prevent one of the biggest disasters to occur in western civilisation. For starters there is nothing particularly original about this film. The premise is a slight variation on something we have seen so many times before. The problem with this is in the writing where included throughout are several clich&eacute;d moment that we have seen in many films of the same era. For example we have the typical cursing every time something bad is said or a gun is fired, we have the typical screaming sidekick teamed up with the unfazed hard man (Kidman and Clooney), and as well we have the run 'with only ten seconds to spare' and jump as the bomb explodes in the background, as a matter of fact we have that twice. It is a slight shame really considering the opening sequence is very well done, but the pacing there on in just drags until the next set piece which is then followed again by slow pacing before the next set piece. This can only be a fault in the writing where we are literally given all the stereotypes of this type of film in one two hour block. The best part about the writing is the B story involving a diplomat who has an agenda for his deadly act. The story is dripped in slowly at the beginning and then brought to the forefront for the final act. It is the best part about the story as it is something slightly different than your typical Russian baddie plot; however it isn't particularly the norm that a B story actually completely overtakes the main plot of a film for the final thirty minutes of it. It makes the opening ninety minutes feel a little clunky and shows how weak the main plot actually is. Some of these issues could be down to the direction, which although not entirely bad does seem a little flat. Mimi Leder does manage to get a decent performance from Clooney but Kidman doesn't seem out of her comfort zone. The opening sequence is very well directed, and the music really adds to the drama, but the other action sequences seem pretty lifeless, especially the chase scene through the streets of Vienna. Also something that was heavily noticed whilst watching was the amount of time taken to chase this man throughout New York without the bomb going off when he had put a time limit on the bomb for a much shorter amount of time. Put it this way an entire third act which is about twenty minutes of screen time told us it was only about seven minutes in their world. It was definitely not plausible and there is a way they could have got over this. The film isn't entirely bad but there is enough wrong with it to make it not particularly good. The tired clich&eacute;s really take over after such a promising start to proceedings. The film could have, and probably should have, been better but the lifeless way in which the story was told, and the dull action sequences, really hindered the possibilities the film could have had. The music was one of the standout points, composed by Hans Zimmer, and from knowing his work in this day and age it is very obviously his work and the soundtrack booms over every tiny piece of action, unfortunately the action fails to live up to the score. I can't particularly say I was disappointed with this film as the opening scene was definitely one I was pleased to have seen, the thing is I could have happily turned it off after the opening twenty minutes and have ended up seeing a much better film. 2 / 5 For more reviews: www.tolli-movieworld.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Persistently Relevant and Riveting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker has both the sophistication, intelligence, and the suspense of its contemporary action thrillers as Spy Game (2001) and Enemy of the State (1998). The balance in the characters both male and female, the good and the bad guys makes for this mainstream action movie raises the bar on its other contemporary movies. The script is both cerebral and action packed, well edited, and nicely paced. Perhaps the renewed geopolitical tension in the world today with nuclear Iran and North Korea as well as the spread of terrorism keeps this movie relevant for today's audiences. Overall, this is a nice fusion of drama, action, technology, and political message of sorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the subplots derailed the film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattrochman
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker was a good and watchable film. The opening was solid and the structure of the story seemed interesting. Unlike other films of this genre, some intelligent and investigative plot lines unfolded. But ultimately the film should have steered clear of the plot line involving the Yugoslav character. Chasing the weapons, solid action, but running along side a rather silly plot about a man who seeks to avenge the deaths of his wife and daughter, and the war at the heart of it all, by detonating a nuclear bomb in the UN in New York. It became sentimental, far-fetched and sent the plot off course. I can only describe it as destabilising the main plot and I think that this is why a lot of people thought it was 'ok' but not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A humble masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mihnerts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, the 5.9 average doesn't do justice to this movie. The truth is that 'The Peacemaker' is a masterpiece and the reason is simple: it's captivating, thrilling and engages the human mind without relying on cgi effects but on masterfully directed subtle action scenes. I do not want to analyze it more because if I do I will miss the point. I will only say this: in many reviews we can read that it's a decent film and has nothing new to offer to the genre... In reality this is the exceptional thing about this film: it takes common place material, used again and again, and transforms them to something brilliant. This is one definition for the word masterpiece on cinema! I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I miss the cold war......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two trains crash somewhere in Russia, one carrying a nuclear payload. A nuclear explosion follows the crash and the world is on alert... However, White House nuclear expert Dr. Julia Kelly doesn't think it was an accident. Special Operations Intelligence Officer Colonel Thomas Devoe doesn't think so either. Together they must unravel a conspiracy that goes from Europe to New York, to stop a terrorist who has no demands... before Out of Sight made Clooney officially the coolest man on the planet, he was the one from ER who seemed desperate to be a huge movie star. A few of his movies, including this one, were so high profile, but so poorly received and average at the box office. It's because they seem so unique with the synopsis, but the execution is so average. Here Clooney has a bit of a swagger wearing white trousers and smirking at Kidman, who justs gets in a fluster every now and again. Sounds like the perfect recipe for a romantic comedy. But this is about Nuclear Weapons going missing. And the film drags in places. One of dreamworks first releases, it does have its moments. The car chase is quite good, and a siege on a bridge is visually impressive, as is the claustrophobic feel of the final act. But for a film that is over two hours long, these really seem few and far between, when the rest of the time we are treated to heated debate. The two stars are good, and you can tell Clooney will be big, It's a good job he met Soderbergh though. Heaven knows what would have happened to his career otherwise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than I thought it might be . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was particularly interested in this film because I was curious how Hollywood would treat this type of scenario, and of course, anything with Nicole Kidman in it has to be at least somewhat entertaining. I actually worked for DOE, in the national labs at Berkeley and also Los Alomos, a number of years ago, and a consequence of such have become quite familiar with nuclear ordnance in its myriad forms, including the so-called "suitcase nukes" that both the former Soviet Union & the USA have developed. Make no mistake, these types of miniaturized nuclear devices do exist, including from decommissioned MRV ballistic missiles and the like. The concept of nuclear warheads, slipping into the wrong hands does very much exist, although in current times this may more likely come from Pakistan, or any variety of "rogue" states who could acquire such through third party brokers. As a side note, any of these types of nuclear devices do require periodic "refurbishing", the details of which I won't elaborate on, but after a certain length of time, the capacity for thermo-nuclear detonation does diminish. Having said all that, does the film realistically portray any of this actually translating into a potential situation? Well . . . not exactly, but I think it's interesting that at least the concept was presented in a not overly ridiculous fashion. Sadly, with tremendous irony, I noted the twin trade towers in several of the background scenes. How odd it is that history often unfolds in the least expected ways. It was, after all, not a miniaturized nuke that was the greatest act of terrorism and evil ever perpetrated on US citizens, but rather planes filled with people . . . and boxcutters as the weaponry of terror. Was the film entertaining? Yes. Could it have been done better? Not sure if I have a qualified answer, but it certainly could have been done much worse. A bit dated? Perhaps . . . but I still think it's worth the time to watch, and contemplate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Peacetakers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never actually seen an episode of ER. I actually took to the movies to appreciate George Clooney, and have since 1997's The Peacemaker. While this movie didn't get a lot of hype or admiration, I truly had a good time. Loved the wit and snappiness of Clooney's dialogue, the action, suspense and drive of the characters. While it's not perfect and has that annoying "An Improbable Jump Through Solid Glass to Escape" scene that I always doubt and some omitted scenes that would've been awesome to see  i.e. two trains colliding, it was an enormously fun ride that, surprisingly, still holds up today, 16 years later. The plot is the norm: with a extensive plan, terrorists seize a nuclear bomb and it's up to two unlikely government heroes to work together, on a global scale, to find out: where they're headed, what they're up to and why. What stands this above the rest, was a fresh and young Clooney doing his soon-to-be normal, but great, schtick. I happen to be a fan of his cocky, but smart, ambitious but laid back appeal. So, I always give him a pass. And this movie contains one of my ALL TIME favorite movie scenes: (mild spoiler) Clooney's dear friend just gets killed and after an exciting car chase leaving one terrorist barely alive, Clooney says nothing in the downpour of water, walks up to him and shoots him point blank. As much as I like snappy comeback and final last crass words, this scene completely shocked and pleased me, because this is how it should've been done in real life and in the movies. Other than that one scene, it's exciting, interesting, has a great pace and a fun puzzle to put together while watching. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    George Clooney + Nicole Kidman together equal James Bond and spare NY from nuclear destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every so often, this picture had some realism to it. Mostly it was a hectic and overlong, nervous and excited movie. A Russian has hijacked 10 nuclear warheads that he's transporting for sale, with one going to a Serb-Croat-Muslim who intends to detonate it at the UN building. Kidman is the Executive Branch operative and Clooney is the military operative. The story takes on James Bond proportions as they seek out what's going on and then attempt to stop it. There are 2 or 3 climaxes that extend the story's length. After awhile, I was fast-forwarding through the predictable chase scene in NY City. There is quite an elaborate car chase scene in Serbia (I think) in which Clooney uses the car to destroy three cars in pursuit. This scene works well. Clooney handles his part nicely. He never fails to know what to do and acts very quickly. Kidman keeps up with him. The movie glorifies the U.S. technical prowess. The depictions are unreal and fantastic, if not ridiculous. It makes for propaganda. Nuclear warheads on American soil in terrorist hands are the ultimate U.S. nightmare, and so that's what the movie shows. In a moment of realism, we learn that the terrorist is attacking NY out of retaliation for US and NATO interference in the old Yugoslavia and the deaths of his family. It's called blowback. The other U.S. bugaboo is Iran (horror! horror!) and so another plot element is warheads headed for Iran. It's all strictly comic book level and by the numbers action, a popcorn feature. Nothing deep here except sell tickets and pay the upkeep of the producers, staff and movie makers. With Dreamworks making it, I didn't expect much, and nothing much happened. Why were the James Bond movies more satisfying?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nicole Kidman Was Looking Sexy But Then Again Russians Are Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    M MALIK
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nicole kid-man was so sexy but clooney was looking gay & a wannabe tough guy. Russians are portrayed as bad guys again in this who wants to launch a nuclear attack on USA but why because the main bad guy got betrayed & wanted revenge . i really don't care for stuff like this anymore because the only movie i lover of bombs is broken arrow of john travolta. the climax of the movie is bad & rushed & you'll see why i love movies but this ant-Russian & all that stuff is gone too far.after 9-11 a lot of films came out with more concepts like the plus point was that they have Afghanistan & Pakistan & terrorist groups stories & osama you know what i am saying. i cant understand clooney this guy acts the same in every film & his hairstyle also never change. my rating of the peacemaker is 2/10 watch only for Nicole kid-man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better movie starring George Clooney and Nichole Kidman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie would have been just as good if it was a plot for a James Bond movie. US military and civilian are tasked to find a stolen nuclear bomb. Cliff hanger of course is its detonation time, and how the two will find the bomb. I seriously think that this is one of the best role George Clooney played. He looks so real as the military officer. His chemistry with Nichole Kidman is really good too. The movie is hard to rate in that it's really well put together, but acting is bit weak, and this takes away from the tension. There's not enough character in George Clooney's role to make him interesting. Like many others who likes this movie, I like it for the story, and the quality of the production. It's an intriguing story, and is worth a watch for its story alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tired clich&eacute; of a movie which at least has a good opening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toll-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1997, although very much relevant in today's world, The Peacemaker stars George Clooney and Nicole Kidman in this action thriller revolving around potential terrorist attacks in New York. The film takes us to a variety of countries as our two leads hunt down the men responsible for selling nuclear warheads to those hell bent on causing pain and disruption to a country they feel is responsible for destroying their families lives. The Peacemaker opens with a brilliant opening sequence where a corrupt Russian General steals nine nuclear war heads from a train transporting them across the country. In an attempt to cover up their actions they set off one of the bombs in the process, killing up to 15,000 people. The cover up however is not successful and Lt Tom Devoe (Clooney) sees straight through the smoke screen, and upon briefing the acting adviser Dr Julia Kelly (Kidman) the two dart off across the World on the trail of the missing warheads, both using very opposite techniques to find their answers. From Vienna to Eastern Europe to New York City, Clooney and Kidman do all they can to prevent one of the biggest disasters to occur in western civilisation. For starters there is nothing particularly original about this film. The premise is a slight variation on something we have seen so many times before. The problem with this is in the writing where included throughout are several clich&eacute;d moment that we have seen in many films of the same era. For example we have the typical cursing every time something bad is said or a gun is fired, we have the typical screaming sidekick teamed up with the unfazed hard man (Kidman and Clooney), and as well we have the run 'with only ten seconds to spare' and jump as the bomb explodes in the background, as a matter of fact we have that twice. It is a slight shame really considering the opening sequence is very well done, but the pacing there on in just drags until the next set piece which is then followed again by slow pacing before the next set piece. This can only be a fault in the writing where we are literally given all the stereotypes of this type of film in one two hour block. The best part about the writing is the B story involving a diplomat who has an agenda for his deadly act. The story is dripped in slowly at the beginning and then brought to the forefront for the final act. It is the best part about the story as it is something slightly different than your typical Russian baddie plot; however it isn't particularly the norm that a B story actually completely overtakes the main plot of a film for the final thirty minutes of it. It makes the opening ninety minutes feel a little clunky and shows how weak the main plot actually is. Some of these issues could be down to the direction, which although not entirely bad does seem a little flat. Mimi Leder does manage to get a decent performance from Clooney but Kidman doesn't seem out of her comfort zone. The opening sequence is very well directed, and the music really adds to the drama, but the other action sequences seem pretty lifeless, especially the chase scene through the streets of Vienna. Also something that was heavily noticed whilst watching was the amount of time taken to chase this man throughout New York without the bomb going off when he had put a time limit on the bomb for a much shorter amount of time. Put it this way an entire third act which is about twenty minutes of screen time told us it was only about seven minutes in their world. It was definitely not plausible and there is a way they could have got over this. The film isn't entirely bad but there is enough wrong with it to make it not particularly good. The tired clich&eacute;s really take over after such a promising start to proceedings. The film could have, and probably should have, been better but the lifeless way in which the story was told, and the dull action sequences, really hindered the possibilities the film could have had. The music was one of the standout points, composed by Hans Zimmer, and from knowing his work in this day and age it is very obviously his work and the soundtrack booms over every tiny piece of action, unfortunately the action fails to live up to the score. I can't particularly say I was disappointed with this film as the opening scene was definitely one I was pleased to have seen, the thing is I could have happily turned it off after the opening twenty minutes and have ended up seeing a much better film. 2 / 5 For more reviews: www.tolli-movieworld.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Persistently Relevant and Riveting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker has both the sophistication, intelligence, and the suspense of its contemporary action thrillers as Spy Game (2001) and Enemy of the State (1998). The balance in the characters both male and female, the good and the bad guys makes for this mainstream action movie raises the bar on its other contemporary movies. The script is both cerebral and action packed, well edited, and nicely paced. Perhaps the renewed geopolitical tension in the world today with nuclear Iran and North Korea as well as the spread of terrorism keeps this movie relevant for today's audiences. Overall, this is a nice fusion of drama, action, technology, and political message of sorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the subplots derailed the film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattrochman
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker was a good and watchable film. The opening was solid and the structure of the story seemed interesting. Unlike other films of this genre, some intelligent and investigative plot lines unfolded. But ultimately the film should have steered clear of the plot line involving the Yugoslav character. Chasing the weapons, solid action, but running along side a rather silly plot about a man who seeks to avenge the deaths of his wife and daughter, and the war at the heart of it all, by detonating a nuclear bomb in the UN in New York. It became sentimental, far-fetched and sent the plot off course. I can only describe it as destabilising the main plot and I think that this is why a lot of people thought it was 'ok' but not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A humble masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mihnerts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, the 5.9 average doesn't do justice to this movie. The truth is that 'The Peacemaker' is a masterpiece and the reason is simple: it's captivating, thrilling and engages the human mind without relying on cgi effects but on masterfully directed subtle action scenes. I do not want to analyze it more because if I do I will miss the point. I will only say this: in many reviews we can read that it's a decent film and has nothing new to offer to the genre... In reality this is the exceptional thing about this film: it takes common place material, used again and again, and transforms them to something brilliant. This is one definition for the word masterpiece on cinema! I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I miss the cold war......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two trains crash somewhere in Russia, one carrying a nuclear payload. A nuclear explosion follows the crash and the world is on alert... However, White House nuclear expert Dr. Julia Kelly doesn't think it was an accident. Special Operations Intelligence Officer Colonel Thomas Devoe doesn't think so either. Together they must unravel a conspiracy that goes from Europe to New York, to stop a terrorist who has no demands... before Out of Sight made Clooney officially the coolest man on the planet, he was the one from ER who seemed desperate to be a huge movie star. A few of his movies, including this one, were so high profile, but so poorly received and average at the box office. It's because they seem so unique with the synopsis, but the execution is so average. Here Clooney has a bit of a swagger wearing white trousers and smirking at Kidman, who justs gets in a fluster every now and again. Sounds like the perfect recipe for a romantic comedy. But this is about Nuclear Weapons going missing. And the film drags in places. One of dreamworks first releases, it does have its moments. The car chase is quite good, and a siege on a bridge is visually impressive, as is the claustrophobic feel of the final act. But for a film that is over two hours long, these really seem few and far between, when the rest of the time we are treated to heated debate. The two stars are good, and you can tell Clooney will be big, It's a good job he met Soderbergh though. Heaven knows what would have happened to his career otherwise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than I thought it might be . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was particularly interested in this film because I was curious how Hollywood would treat this type of scenario, and of course, anything with Nicole Kidman in it has to be at least somewhat entertaining. I actually worked for DOE, in the national labs at Berkeley and also Los Alomos, a number of years ago, and a consequence of such have become quite familiar with nuclear ordnance in its myriad forms, including the so-called "suitcase nukes" that both the former Soviet Union & the USA have developed. Make no mistake, these types of miniaturized nuclear devices do exist, including from decommissioned MRV ballistic missiles and the like. The concept of nuclear warheads, slipping into the wrong hands does very much exist, although in current times this may more likely come from Pakistan, or any variety of "rogue" states who could acquire such through third party brokers. As a side note, any of these types of nuclear devices do require periodic "refurbishing", the details of which I won't elaborate on, but after a certain length of time, the capacity for thermo-nuclear detonation does diminish. Having said all that, does the film realistically portray any of this actually translating into a potential situation? Well . . . not exactly, but I think it's interesting that at least the concept was presented in a not overly ridiculous fashion. Sadly, with tremendous irony, I noted the twin trade towers in several of the background scenes. How odd it is that history often unfolds in the least expected ways. It was, after all, not a miniaturized nuke that was the greatest act of terrorism and evil ever perpetrated on US citizens, but rather planes filled with people . . . and boxcutters as the weaponry of terror. Was the film entertaining? Yes. Could it have been done better? Not sure if I have a qualified answer, but it certainly could have been done much worse. A bit dated? Perhaps . . . but I still think it's worth the time to watch, and contemplate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Peacetakers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never actually seen an episode of ER. I actually took to the movies to appreciate George Clooney, and have since 1997's The Peacemaker. While this movie didn't get a lot of hype or admiration, I truly had a good time. Loved the wit and snappiness of Clooney's dialogue, the action, suspense and drive of the characters. While it's not perfect and has that annoying "An Improbable Jump Through Solid Glass to Escape" scene that I always doubt and some omitted scenes that would've been awesome to see  i.e. two trains colliding, it was an enormously fun ride that, surprisingly, still holds up today, 16 years later. The plot is the norm: with a extensive plan, terrorists seize a nuclear bomb and it's up to two unlikely government heroes to work together, on a global scale, to find out: where they're headed, what they're up to and why. What stands this above the rest, was a fresh and young Clooney doing his soon-to-be normal, but great, schtick. I happen to be a fan of his cocky, but smart, ambitious but laid back appeal. So, I always give him a pass. And this movie contains one of my ALL TIME favorite movie scenes: (mild spoiler) Clooney's dear friend just gets killed and after an exciting car chase leaving one terrorist barely alive, Clooney says nothing in the downpour of water, walks up to him and shoots him point blank. As much as I like snappy comeback and final last crass words, this scene completely shocked and pleased me, because this is how it should've been done in real life and in the movies. Other than that one scene, it's exciting, interesting, has a great pace and a fun puzzle to put together while watching. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    George Clooney + Nicole Kidman together equal James Bond and spare NY from nuclear destruction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Every so often, this picture had some realism to it. Mostly it was a hectic and overlong, nervous and excited movie. A Russian has hijacked 10 nuclear warheads that he's transporting for sale, with one going to a Serb-Croat-Muslim who intends to detonate it at the UN building. Kidman is the Executive Branch operative and Clooney is the military operative. The story takes on James Bond proportions as they seek out what's going on and then attempt to stop it. There are 2 or 3 climaxes that extend the story's length. After awhile, I was fast-forwarding through the predictable chase scene in NY City. There is quite an elaborate car chase scene in Serbia (I think) in which Clooney uses the car to destroy three cars in pursuit. This scene works well. Clooney handles his part nicely. He never fails to know what to do and acts very quickly. Kidman keeps up with him. The movie glorifies the U.S. technical prowess. The depictions are unreal and fantastic, if not ridiculous. It makes for propaganda. Nuclear warheads on American soil in terrorist hands are the ultimate U.S. nightmare, and so that's what the movie shows. In a moment of realism, we learn that the terrorist is attacking NY out of retaliation for US and NATO interference in the old Yugoslavia and the deaths of his family. It's called blowback. The other U.S. bugaboo is Iran (horror! horror!) and so another plot element is warheads headed for Iran. It's all strictly comic book level and by the numbers action, a popcorn feature. Nothing deep here except sell tickets and pay the upkeep of the producers, staff and movie makers. With Dreamworks making it, I didn't expect much, and nothing much happened. Why were the James Bond movies more satisfying?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nicole Kidman Was Looking Sexy But Then Again Russians Are Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    M MALIK
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nicole kid-man was so sexy but clooney was looking gay & a wannabe tough guy. Russians are portrayed as bad guys again in this who wants to launch a nuclear attack on USA but why because the main bad guy got betrayed & wanted revenge . i really don't care for stuff like this anymore because the only movie i lover of bombs is broken arrow of john travolta. the climax of the movie is bad & rushed & you'll see why i love movies but this ant-Russian & all that stuff is gone too far.after 9-11 a lot of films came out with more concepts like the plus point was that they have Afghanistan & Pakistan & terrorist groups stories & osama you know what i am saying. i cant understand clooney this guy acts the same in every film & his hairstyle also never change. my rating of the peacemaker is 2/10 watch only for Nicole kid-man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better movie starring George Clooney and Nichole Kidman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie would have been just as good if it was a plot for a James Bond movie. US military and civilian are tasked to find a stolen nuclear bomb. Cliff hanger of course is its detonation time, and how the two will find the bomb. I seriously think that this is one of the best role George Clooney played. He looks so real as the military officer. His chemistry with Nichole Kidman is really good too. The movie is hard to rate in that it's really well put together, but acting is bit weak, and this takes away from the tension. There's not enough character in George Clooney's role to make him interesting. Like many others who likes this movie, I like it for the story, and the quality of the production. It's an intriguing story, and is worth a watch for its story alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tired clich&eacute; of a movie which at least has a good opening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    toll-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1997, although very much relevant in today's world, The Peacemaker stars George Clooney and Nicole Kidman in this action thriller revolving around potential terrorist attacks in New York. The film takes us to a variety of countries as our two leads hunt down the men responsible for selling nuclear warheads to those hell bent on causing pain and disruption to a country they feel is responsible for destroying their families lives. The Peacemaker opens with a brilliant opening sequence where a corrupt Russian General steals nine nuclear war heads from a train transporting them across the country. In an attempt to cover up their actions they set off one of the bombs in the process, killing up to 15,000 people. The cover up however is not successful and Lt Tom Devoe (Clooney) sees straight through the smoke screen, and upon briefing the acting adviser Dr Julia Kelly (Kidman) the two dart off across the World on the trail of the missing warheads, both using very opposite techniques to find their answers. From Vienna to Eastern Europe to New York City, Clooney and Kidman do all they can to prevent one of the biggest disasters to occur in western civilisation. For starters there is nothing particularly original about this film. The premise is a slight variation on something we have seen so many times before. The problem with this is in the writing where included throughout are several clich&eacute;d moment that we have seen in many films of the same era. For example we have the typical cursing every time something bad is said or a gun is fired, we have the typical screaming sidekick teamed up with the unfazed hard man (Kidman and Clooney), and as well we have the run 'with only ten seconds to spare' and jump as the bomb explodes in the background, as a matter of fact we have that twice. It is a slight shame really considering the opening sequence is very well done, but the pacing there on in just drags until the next set piece which is then followed again by slow pacing before the next set piece. This can only be a fault in the writing where we are literally given all the stereotypes of this type of film in one two hour block. The best part about the writing is the B story involving a diplomat who has an agenda for his deadly act. The story is dripped in slowly at the beginning and then brought to the forefront for the final act. It is the best part about the story as it is something slightly different than your typical Russian baddie plot; however it isn't particularly the norm that a B story actually completely overtakes the main plot of a film for the final thirty minutes of it. It makes the opening ninety minutes feel a little clunky and shows how weak the main plot actually is. Some of these issues could be down to the direction, which although not entirely bad does seem a little flat. Mimi Leder does manage to get a decent performance from Clooney but Kidman doesn't seem out of her comfort zone. The opening sequence is very well directed, and the music really adds to the drama, but the other action sequences seem pretty lifeless, especially the chase scene through the streets of Vienna. Also something that was heavily noticed whilst watching was the amount of time taken to chase this man throughout New York without the bomb going off when he had put a time limit on the bomb for a much shorter amount of time. Put it this way an entire third act which is about twenty minutes of screen time told us it was only about seven minutes in their world. It was definitely not plausible and there is a way they could have got over this. The film isn't entirely bad but there is enough wrong with it to make it not particularly good. The tired clich&eacute;s really take over after such a promising start to proceedings. The film could have, and probably should have, been better but the lifeless way in which the story was told, and the dull action sequences, really hindered the possibilities the film could have had. The music was one of the standout points, composed by Hans Zimmer, and from knowing his work in this day and age it is very obviously his work and the soundtrack booms over every tiny piece of action, unfortunately the action fails to live up to the score. I can't particularly say I was disappointed with this film as the opening scene was definitely one I was pleased to have seen, the thing is I could have happily turned it off after the opening twenty minutes and have ended up seeing a much better film. 2 / 5 For more reviews: www.tolli-movieworld.blogspot.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Persistently Relevant and Riveting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker has both the sophistication, intelligence, and the suspense of its contemporary action thrillers as Spy Game (2001) and Enemy of the State (1998). The balance in the characters both male and female, the good and the bad guys makes for this mainstream action movie raises the bar on its other contemporary movies. The script is both cerebral and action packed, well edited, and nicely paced. Perhaps the renewed geopolitical tension in the world today with nuclear Iran and North Korea as well as the spread of terrorism keeps this movie relevant for today's audiences. Overall, this is a nice fusion of drama, action, technology, and political message of sorts.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the subplots derailed the film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mattrochman
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Peacemaker was a good and watchable film. The opening was solid and the structure of the story seemed interesting. Unlike other films of this genre, some intelligent and investigative plot lines unfolded. But ultimately the film should have steered clear of the plot line involving the Yugoslav character. Chasing the weapons, solid action, but running along side a rather silly plot about a man who seeks to avenge the deaths of his wife and daughter, and the war at the heart of it all, by detonating a nuclear bomb in the UN in New York. It became sentimental, far-fetched and sent the plot off course. I can only describe it as destabilising the main plot and I think that this is why a lot of people thought it was 'ok' but not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A humble masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mihnerts
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, the 5.9 average doesn't do justice to this movie. The truth is that 'The Peacemaker' is a masterpiece and the reason is simple: it's captivating, thrilling and engages the human mind without relying on cgi effects but on masterfully directed subtle action scenes. I do not want to analyze it more because if I do I will miss the point. I will only say this: in many reviews we can read that it's a decent film and has nothing new to offer to the genre... In reality this is the exceptional thing about this film: it takes common place material, used again and again, and transforms them to something brilliant. This is one definition for the word masterpiece on cinema! I loved it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I miss the cold war......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Two trains crash somewhere in Russia, one carrying a nuclear payload. A nuclear explosion follows the crash and the world is on alert... However, White House nuclear expert Dr. Julia Kelly doesn't think it was an accident. Special Operations Intelligence Officer Colonel Thomas Devoe doesn't think so either. Together they must unravel a conspiracy that goes from Europe to New York, to stop a terrorist who has no demands... before Out of Sight made Clooney officially the coolest man on the planet, he was the one from ER who seemed desperate to be a huge movie star. A few of his movies, including this one, were so high profile, but so poorly received and average at the box office. It's because they seem so unique with the synopsis, but the execution is so average. Here Clooney has a bit of a swagger wearing white trousers and smirking at Kidman, who justs gets in a fluster every now and again. Sounds like the perfect recipe for a romantic comedy. But this is about Nuclear Weapons going missing. And the film drags in places. One of dreamworks first releases, it does have its moments. The car chase is quite good, and a siege on a bridge is visually impressive, as is the claustrophobic feel of the final act. But for a film that is over two hours long, these really seem few and far between, when the rest of the time we are treated to heated debate. The two stars are good, and you can tell Clooney will be big, It's a good job he met Soderbergh though. Heaven knows what would have happened to his career otherwise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than I thought it might be . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles000
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was particularly interested in this film because I was curious how Hollywood would treat this type of scenario, and of course, anything with Nicole Kidman in it has to be at least somewhat entertaining. I actually worked for DOE, in the national labs at Berkeley and also Los Alomos, a number of years ago, and a consequence of such have become quite familiar with nuclear ordnance in its myriad forms, including the so-called "suitcase nukes" that both the former Soviet Union & the USA have developed. Make no mistake, these types of miniaturized nuclear devices do exist, including from decommissioned MRV ballistic missiles and the like. The concept of nuclear warheads, slipping into the wrong hands does very much exist, although in current times this may more likely come from Pakistan, or any variety of "rogue" states who could acquire such through third party brokers. As a side note, any of these types of nuclear devices do require periodic "refurbishing", the details of which I won't elaborate on, but after a certain length of time, the capacity for thermo-nuclear detonation does diminish. Having said all that, does the film realistically portray any of this actually translating into a potential situation? Well . . . not exactly, but I think it's interesting that at least the concept was presented in a not overly ridiculous fashion. Sadly, with tremendous irony, I noted the twin trade towers in several of the background scenes. How odd it is that history often unfolds in the least expected ways. It was, after all, not a miniaturized nuke that was the greatest act of terrorism and evil ever perpetrated on US citizens, but rather planes filled with people . . . and boxcutters as the weaponry of terror. Was the film entertaining? Yes. Could it have been done better? Not sure if I have a qualified answer, but it certainly could have been done much worse. A bit dated? Perhaps . . . but I still think it's worth the time to watch, and contemplate.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
