<filme>
 <id>
  88
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0108160
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Sintonia de Amor
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A recently-widowed man's son calls a radio talk show in an attempt to find his father a partner.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  After his wife Maggie passes away, Sam Baldwin and his adolescent son Jonah relocate from Chicago to Seattle to escape the grief associated with Maggie's death. Eighteen months later, Sam is still grieving and can't sleep. Although Jonah misses his mother, he wants his father to get a new wife despite Sam having not even contemplated dating again. On Christmas Eve, Sam, on Jonah's initiative, ends up pouring his heart out on a national radio talk show about his magical and perfect marriage to Maggie, and how much he still misses her. Among the many women who hears Sam's story and falls in love with him solely because of it is Annie Reed, a Baltimore based newspaper writer. Annie's infatuation with Sam's story and by association Sam himself is despite being already engaged. But Annie's relationship with her straight-laced fianc&eacute; Walter is unlike her dream love life in the movie . She even writes to Sam proposing they meet atop the Empire State Building on ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   radio
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   widower
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   grief
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   radio show
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Nora Ephron
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jeff Arch
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Nora Ephron
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Tom Hanks
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Meg Ryan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ross Malinger
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Magic " or Mayhem ??
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alxx0209
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a Tom Hanks movie ? I am a huge Hanks fan he has such a passion and commitment to every single movie he does. I have loved all of his movies that i have seen him in so far. and do I like him in this film? Well I suppose - This movie is about love and all its complications dealing with Sam / Annie and Jonah. The Three of them are trying to find " magic " in a relationship - I personally have not yet felt "magic" in a relationship - I have not even dated at all so I do not relate to " magic " but I can somehow imagine the delightful feeling in ones heart when you see the difference in Annie as the movie goes on and she learns what magic feels like. The movie seemed just a little slow in the beginning in my opinion but after a bit it has a certain pace to it that is enjoying. The movie reminds me of a few other films yet Hanks and Ryan are charming and The Kid also helps out the movie go forward / I also believe that Hanks other films success kind of help / Hurt this one in away - I mean Im not comparing it to his other roles but this one seems specifically about love - and I would say its like 70 % romantic and 30 % comedy but again I liked the movie for what it set up and Tom / Meg and the kid did a good job in this film - also a little note I feel that Rob Reiner and Rosie O' Donnell were just alright in there supporting roles but in my opinion they would be under minor roles for this movie. I have to mention a scene that I liked was Annie watching Sam and Jonah goofing around on the beach - thats were it seemed to click for Annie to realize she was in love with both them from just watching them goof around - being themselves , I believe from then on she felt deep down " magic" for Sam and even in away Jonah. That moment was something I would call a " spark " were it just was beautiful for what it was. That moment you could tell what her heart said to her. Final thoughts ? well Toms Hanks did an amazing job plays such likable and relatable characters ( including this one ) Meg did a decent job -Pullman who played Walter did alright the role kinda fell short - Like your about to marry her and you let her walk away ? He could have developed more. Also i would say like 2 or 3 slow bits that could have been tweaked. Other then that its a cute movie about love and Magic. Its worth watching once in your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hanks and Ryan Should Make More Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan should make more movies. As really this is one of a kind and sweet movie. Hanks character Sam loses his wife to cancer and his son Josh, wants Sam to be happy despite not wanting to ever date again. That is why they move from Chicago to Seattle to escape the sadness. But via a radio talk show station. Josh talks to the host as the USA in particular the women fall in love with Sam and his story despite never seeing him or knowing him that well. This also really strikes a nerve in Baltimore radio newspaper writer, Annie played by Ryan. As she wants to get to know this Sam despite being engaged to a straight laced Bill Pullman. A sweet and kind movie. As makes you want to really wished that both Hanks and Ryan made more movies. As Ryan has felled out with the public lately. But still a really sweet movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once more up the ESB
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-3758
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie again for the umpteenth time. I know going in that it blatantly plays on the emotions ... yet I still do it. It is perhaps one of the best feelgood movies out there. It's a believable story and it's wonderfully acted by all concerned. As a small footnote, might I highlight the tiny sequence when Jonah picks up a cab on arriving in NY. One of the two guys hailing cabs has just one line ... and it's fabulous: To the cab driver "Why don'tcha get further from the kerb next time buddy?!" It's such a small piece of dialogue, I think I missed it the first few times I watched the movie, but it's amazing how such a small thing never fails to make me cry ... with laughter. As against the blubbing I do through the rest of the movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No, just , no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wretched film is about Annie Reed (Meg Ryan) a Baltimore journalist who falls in love with Sam(Tom Hanks) when, at his son Jonah's(Ross Malinger)insistence he talks about his marriage to his late wife Maggie on a radio call-in talk show. Apparently she's one of many women who fell in love with Sam based on this lone qualification. Annie already had a fianc&eacute;e Walter(Bill Pullman) who seems like a really nice guy. Unfortunately for Walter, he doesn't meet Annie's dream romance so he has to go. The meeting is spurred on by the adolescent Jonah, who travels cross-country with his father in pursuit. Of course Sam and Annie fall in love and of course they live happily after after. Here are my problems with the film. First of all, Annie decides to dump a perfectly nice man based on a a stranger's telephone call. That is weird and disturbing. Of course, Sam here is a perfectly nice guy, but he could just as easily been the next Jeffery Dahmer. Next is her treatment of Walter who seems devoted to her, in response to his devotion she breaks up with him, on Valentine's Day of all days, to hook up with a guy she's never met or indeed seen. There is the behavior of the son Jonah who is able to get cross-country tickets without his father's permission and have his dad meet up with Annie. It is presumed that Sam and Annie will live happily ever after, but if Annie can dump a longtime beau like Walter over a phone call on a radio show, than who knows how long her relationship with Sam will last.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such wonderful comedy/romance movies are rare anymore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very entertaining movie is a present-day rarity, for seldom if ever do you find movies concerning a story where a strong void is filled in a person's life, and concomitantly you don't find far-fetched ways to do it. First of all, Sam Baldwin has just lost his wife in Chicago, and the depressed man wants to get away from it all and move to Seattle where he is definitely sleepless because of his recent loss, naturally. At the same time, his eight-year-old son Jonah wants a new mother. Meanwhile, in Baltimore the very attractive Annie Reed, after a dinner at her parent's home where she introduces her future husband to her family, is driving away when she listens to a talk-show hosted by Dr. Marcia Fieldstone who talks to Sam, whom she calls "Sleepless in Seattle". While listening to his voice Annie suddenly becomes taken with him, and then pursues him, thanks very much to the Internet. This is when the "fun" begins. She "seeks advice" from the classic Cary Grant-Deborah Kerr movie "An Affair to Remember", which she watches on t.v. very often. The story does have a warm and happy ending. The story has different settings-Chicago, New York, Baltimore, as well as Seattle. The very versatile Tom Hanks does his turn well, and the unusually appealing Meg Ryan captivated my attention in her role as Annie Reed. Ross Mallinger does acting well for a very young boy. Rosie O'Donnell is her nutty self as Annie's very close friend. Nora Ephron did a good job of writing and directing. Again, I wish they would make comedy/romances like this more often.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" comes very close to being the ideal contemporary American love story, and even with my reservations about some of the things in the film, I still feel it's a very good one. It's an unpretentious little jewel that demonstrates the true values of screen writing and acting, as both are used here shamelessly and with natural grace to manipulate the emotions of the audience. I admit the story is a bit absurd, but it's also somewhat the idea. And besides, in this age where people travel hundreds of miles to meet folks they've chatted with on the internet, is it so hard to believe that a woman would cross the entire country to learn about a widower whose voice she heard on the radio? Well, the Casanova in me would like to think it's not. The plot, though predictable, makes some daring twists. In most romantic comedies, the couple eyes each other from very early on. And although Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan do make an attractive movie-couple, they don't share even have a two-shot until the last ten minutes. For most of the movie, Mr. Hanks does not even know that Miss Ryan even exists, let alone that they are destined to be in love. It's not that he ignores her; it's because she spends most of the movie on the opposite side of the country from him. She hears him on the radio, speaking of his recently departed wife, is fascinated by what he has to say, and feels something that is best described, as the movie acknowledges, as "magic." I could use more derisory words toward somebody who would feel this way in real life about a voice, but that's good enough. The screenplay (written by director Nora Ephron and two menJeff Arch and David S. Ward) is also a bit insightful on, again, an unpretentious level. It does not delve deep into the psychological state we like to call love and affection, but it does make some interesting observations. First of all, Miss Ryan's character does acknowledge time and time again how absurd it is of her to fly from New York to Seattle to learn about a man she's only heard. There are also numerous touches upon how Hollywood's perception of sex and romance befalls some people. The key moment is when Rosie O'Donnell, as Miss Ryan's best friend, tells her flat out while watching "An Affair to Remember" that what she wants is not to be in love, but "to be in love in a movie." After all, how many of ussingle and once-singlehave not looked at movies like "Casablanca," "An Affair to Remember," "At First Sight," and such and not fantasized about passion that only seems to exist when an actor and actress play make-believe before a camera? Speaking of other films: that is another thing I adored about "Sleepless in Seattle." It has an uncanny ability to recall other films to effectsometimes comedic, sometimes insightful. A favorite moment of mine is when Mr. Hanks explains to his eight-year-old son (extremely well-acted by Ross Malinger) why he is uncomfortable about rushing into a new relationship so soon: he asks him if he ever saw "Fatal Attraction." The biggest homage(s), though, goes back to "An Affair to Remember." That wonderful 1957 film is shown on television screens numerous times throughout the movie, and at key points, Hugo Friedhofer's score even plays on the soundtrack. Being an obvious admirer of the said film, I found the references quite delightful and charming. If there is one thing I couldn't stand about "Sleepless in Seattle," I would have had to have been the constant usage of classic songs to carry along sequences. The opening credits display while a very jazzy version of "As Time Goes By" thumps in the background, but numbers such as "Stand By Your Man," "Stardust," and others are ever-present, reducing fine scenes into what appear to be limp music videos. There is a potentially great momentreduced to a merely good onewhere Miss Ryan, having traveled to Seattle, watches Mr. Hanks and his son as they play on the beach. It's a very good scene (Miss Ryan is kept at medium shots, Mr. Hanks and Mr. Malinger at distance, the montage is very nice) but the song playing in the background trivializes it. The film's musical score by Marc Shaiman is just fine, and I would have preferred to hear his piano motifs instead of a song. Only the movies can convince that two people could fall into deep, passionate love upon first sight. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the defining examples of that theory. After all, if Mr. Hanks and Miss Ryan could have such strong chemistry when they are not even sharing the same frame, one can only imagine what would lay down the road for their characters (and how moved we would be). But what is best about this movieapart from the fabulous writing and actingis its unostentatious manner. It does not make itself out to be any big deal, and just lets the romantic chemistry emerge on its admittedly old-fashioned terms. And I was more interested in the relationship between these people who have never met as opposed to most formula-films where the cute-boy meets cute-girl, they ogle for an hour, hate one another for twenty minutes, and reconcile at the end. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An affair to forget
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, today was a bank holiday and it was pouring rain outside so my wife and I thought we'd watch a family-oriented romantic-comedy, giving "Sleepless In Seattle" the nod. It's fair to say my wife liked it more than I did. For me it wasn't really very funny and worse, was guilty of over-sentimentality and coincidence. Nothing against Meg Ryan, but she hasn't got the kind of face that would stop you in your tracks the way she does at the airport with Tom Hanks' character's first view of her. Moreover her ditzy character doesn't seem too different (sans hysterical laugh) from the girl his son is so against him hooking up with. Oh yes, about the son, aged eight going on eighteen, going out with a fellow eight-year-old girl, quoting from Beatles' songs, having adult conversations with his dad and flying to New York on his own. As he would! Of course his toothy grin and mop of hair sweep aside any charges of embarrassing cringeworthiness, or at least that's what the director would have you think. I found the writing clich&eacute;d and gauche (a woman character cries when recounting the story of the "An Affair To Remember", Cary Grant / Deborah Kerr vehicle which informs much of the plot here; like when was the last time you cried explaining a movie plot),the thirty-something characters are cardboard-thin and irritating plus it seemed there had to be some old romantic song playing in the background of almost every scene. I couldn't get excited by the acting either, there being no chance for Hanks and Ryan to gell as they don't actually meet until their anti-climactic meeting atop the Empire State Building. Bill Paxton gets underused as Ryan's hypochondriac fianc&eacute; while Rosie O'Donnell irritates as her overly understanding boss. I have to admit I can't stand these male-female "buddy" relationships as demonstrated here by Hanks and Rob Reiner and Ryan and O'Donnell, they play out so artificially. Just about the only good for thing me about this film is that I'll probably seek out the earlier film, confident that it will eclipse this very slack and shallow 1980's production which it regrettably inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ultimate Chick Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emily B
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love love LOVE this movie! I have just seen it for about the tenth time and I always laugh, cry, and squeal at the romantic ending. The leads only had about 5 minutes total of screen time together, yet they have so much chemistry in the closing scene. Annie (Meg Ryan) is recently engaged to Walter (the spunky Bill Pullman, my crush from the nineties), and seems to be happy, until she hears 8-year-old Jonah on the radio. His mother died 18 months ago, and his Christmas wish is that his father will find a new wife so that he won't be so sad. His father Sam (Tom Hanks), then talks about how wonderful his wife was and how much he adored her. Something changes in Annie, and she realises there is something about this man that she has to learn more about. Many would call it stalking, others would call it romantic, but suddenly she is flying across the country for a glimpse of him. Out of all the women who wrote to his Dad, Jonah likes Annie's letter the best, and sets up a romantic first encounter on the top of the Empire State building. Awwwww!!! I think from the start everyone knew how it would end, but it's wonderful to watch. Every single actor is outstanding, especially the young boy who played Jonah, many movies have been ruined by horrible children who cannot act, but he's great, and doesn't try to be too cute. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Chicks' Movie Indeed: Superstitious & Maudlin, But Also Witty, Pleasant & Ultimately Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    faterson (faterson@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's difficult to enjoy a movie that you feel is built on a premise that is fundamentally false. I was, therefore, only able to enjoy _Sleepless in Seattle_ while gnashing my teeth quite frequently. _Sleepless in Seattle_ is about as subtle as a sledgehammer in driving home its message: that there exist phenomena such as "soul mate", "being destined for each other", "true love at first sight", etc. Its conception of "love" is extremely old-fashioned; it's supposed to be that thing where "one meets one", and "you are my everything", "you're the world to me". It's strange, but somehow you instantly feel that _Sleepless in Seattle_ is an irreligious movie; it's not that it would be *against religion*, but you get the definite feeling right from the start that "love" in its religious dimension is and will remain conspicuously absent from the movie. This is all the more remarkable in that _Sleepless in Seattle_ glorifies and uses motives from the 1957 Cary Grant & Deborah Kerr hit, _An Affair to Remember_ -- a romantic comedy as well, but where religion and religious feelings are as obviously present as they are non-existent in _Sleepless in Seattle_. I believe in none of those things such as "destiny", "soul mates", "being made for one another", "you're the only one", etc. And I'm sorry, but as the movie kept reiterating these motives ad nauseam (especially in many of the intentionally old-fashioned songs -- both original and "fake" new ones written in the old vein, frequently featuring awful, annoyingly maudlin lyrics -- that we get to listen to throughout the movie, from the opening to the closing credits), I just *had* to say to myself: "All this 'destingy stuff' is something typically enjoyed and believed by women." There's nothing wrong with a movie or book that makes it obvious that its author is a woman; however, this seemed to be *too* obvious in _Sleepless in Seattle_, detracting from the overall enjoyment. I was saying to myself, "This is a chicks' movie," long before Tom Hanks said the same thing about _An Affair to Remember_; but it's a verdict that is even more apropos in relation to _Sleepless in Seattle_. Speaking of the comparison to _An Affair to Remember_, it's weird that _Sleepless in Seattle_ seems more archaic than the movie that preceded it by almost 3 decades. Both movies feature wildly improbable, unrealistic story-lines; yet when you come to think of it, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr might meet on a luxury ship in 2012 just as they did back in 1957; it would no longer be a transatlantic voyage today, but a pleasurable cruise. Could, however, Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan interact, today, in the same way as shown in _Sleepless in Seattle_? Nope. This movie fairly screams at you: "Where's the Internet? Where are the mobile phones, emails, and social networks?" Only a few years later, and the movie's plot would be rendered unusable. Even as it is, great effort is required to suspend your disbelief; while _An Affair to Remember_ is unrealistic, _Sleepless in Seattle_ is doubly so. Or can anyone honestly believe that a loving father would not have alerted the police immediately upon learning that his 8-year-old son eloped on a transcontinental flight to New York unsupervised? Despite all these shortcomings, _Sleepless in Seattle_ manages to be enjoyable throughout, and unlike _An Affair to Remember_, I believe this movie gets better and better with every passing minute. I found the ending of _An Affair to Remember_ rather a let-down, but not here; I thought the Empire State Building finale of _Sleepless in Seattle_ was very nicely constructed, and genuinely moving. I'd say the main credit for the movie's success should go to the two leading stars. Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan both give brilliant, flawless performances. They seem thoroughly believable as persons or personalities, even while their actions do not. The two child actors, Ross Malinger and Gaby Hoffmann, are terrific as well. Rosie O'Donnell makes her presence felt forcefully in a supporting role; her delivery of several of the movie's wittiest lines, no matter how brief, is pitch-perfect. Victor Garber and Rob Reiner only get a few minutes of screen time, but they certainly make the most of them to shine and to delight the audience. (I thought I only noticed a single false note about the actors' performances. In a weird departure from their realistic mode of delivery throughout the movie, in a discussion at Sam's kitchen table, both Tom Hanks and Victor Garber get tearful while talking about the movie _The Dirty Dozen_. I thought the scene rang very false; it was as if a minute or two from your regular TV sitcom was suddenly inserted into _Sleepless in Seattle_; the only thing missing was canned laughter; I found the moment painful to watch, and not funny at all; fortunately, it only lasted a minute or so; and Rita Wilson did not join in the two actors' shenanigans, but rather rescued the scene thanks to remaining who she was supposed to be in the movie. I thought Hanks & Garber did not perform well in that particular brief and untypical moment, but it would be hard to blame them for it; rather, I'd say it was a mistake on the part of the screenwriter/director to include a heterogeneous moment like that in the script.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sleepless in Philidelphia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so a few months back I was hanging out in my bedroom surfing my Netflix app on my Wii, I was waiting for this show to come on and I had an hour to kill, so I see Sleepless in Seatle in the romance section listed. I usually don't watch romances, but with Tom Hanks in it I made an exception. I LOVED THIS MOVIE! The movie is about recently widower Sam and his son Jonha. Sam is extremely down because of his wife's demise, and his son fells horrible for him. Christmas Eve comes and Sam, is still down. So Jonha decides to call one of those call-in-radio shows to help his dad out. Meanwhile, Annie Reed is driving on a highway listening to show, when Sam begins to tell his story Annie starts crying historically and instantly falls in love with him. The whole movie shows both of them on their own quest, Sam to find a new soul-mate, and Annie to find Sam. This is one of those movie anyone can watch and automatically fall in love with! With movies like these you will always know there is someone for everyone, and the worst of things can be for the better! I give this movie a 10 for its excellence in story, character development, and dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Magic " or Mayhem ??
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alxx0209
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a Tom Hanks movie ? I am a huge Hanks fan he has such a passion and commitment to every single movie he does. I have loved all of his movies that i have seen him in so far. and do I like him in this film? Well I suppose - This movie is about love and all its complications dealing with Sam / Annie and Jonah. The Three of them are trying to find " magic " in a relationship - I personally have not yet felt "magic" in a relationship - I have not even dated at all so I do not relate to " magic " but I can somehow imagine the delightful feeling in ones heart when you see the difference in Annie as the movie goes on and she learns what magic feels like. The movie seemed just a little slow in the beginning in my opinion but after a bit it has a certain pace to it that is enjoying. The movie reminds me of a few other films yet Hanks and Ryan are charming and The Kid also helps out the movie go forward / I also believe that Hanks other films success kind of help / Hurt this one in away - I mean Im not comparing it to his other roles but this one seems specifically about love - and I would say its like 70 % romantic and 30 % comedy but again I liked the movie for what it set up and Tom / Meg and the kid did a good job in this film - also a little note I feel that Rob Reiner and Rosie O' Donnell were just alright in there supporting roles but in my opinion they would be under minor roles for this movie. I have to mention a scene that I liked was Annie watching Sam and Jonah goofing around on the beach - thats were it seemed to click for Annie to realize she was in love with both them from just watching them goof around - being themselves , I believe from then on she felt deep down " magic" for Sam and even in away Jonah. That moment was something I would call a " spark " were it just was beautiful for what it was. That moment you could tell what her heart said to her. Final thoughts ? well Toms Hanks did an amazing job plays such likable and relatable characters ( including this one ) Meg did a decent job -Pullman who played Walter did alright the role kinda fell short - Like your about to marry her and you let her walk away ? He could have developed more. Also i would say like 2 or 3 slow bits that could have been tweaked. Other then that its a cute movie about love and Magic. Its worth watching once in your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hanks and Ryan Should Make More Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan should make more movies. As really this is one of a kind and sweet movie. Hanks character Sam loses his wife to cancer and his son Josh, wants Sam to be happy despite not wanting to ever date again. That is why they move from Chicago to Seattle to escape the sadness. But via a radio talk show station. Josh talks to the host as the USA in particular the women fall in love with Sam and his story despite never seeing him or knowing him that well. This also really strikes a nerve in Baltimore radio newspaper writer, Annie played by Ryan. As she wants to get to know this Sam despite being engaged to a straight laced Bill Pullman. A sweet and kind movie. As makes you want to really wished that both Hanks and Ryan made more movies. As Ryan has felled out with the public lately. But still a really sweet movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once more up the ESB
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-3758
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie again for the umpteenth time. I know going in that it blatantly plays on the emotions ... yet I still do it. It is perhaps one of the best feelgood movies out there. It's a believable story and it's wonderfully acted by all concerned. As a small footnote, might I highlight the tiny sequence when Jonah picks up a cab on arriving in NY. One of the two guys hailing cabs has just one line ... and it's fabulous: To the cab driver "Why don'tcha get further from the kerb next time buddy?!" It's such a small piece of dialogue, I think I missed it the first few times I watched the movie, but it's amazing how such a small thing never fails to make me cry ... with laughter. As against the blubbing I do through the rest of the movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No, just , no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wretched film is about Annie Reed (Meg Ryan) a Baltimore journalist who falls in love with Sam(Tom Hanks) when, at his son Jonah's(Ross Malinger)insistence he talks about his marriage to his late wife Maggie on a radio call-in talk show. Apparently she's one of many women who fell in love with Sam based on this lone qualification. Annie already had a fianc&eacute;e Walter(Bill Pullman) who seems like a really nice guy. Unfortunately for Walter, he doesn't meet Annie's dream romance so he has to go. The meeting is spurred on by the adolescent Jonah, who travels cross-country with his father in pursuit. Of course Sam and Annie fall in love and of course they live happily after after. Here are my problems with the film. First of all, Annie decides to dump a perfectly nice man based on a a stranger's telephone call. That is weird and disturbing. Of course, Sam here is a perfectly nice guy, but he could just as easily been the next Jeffery Dahmer. Next is her treatment of Walter who seems devoted to her, in response to his devotion she breaks up with him, on Valentine's Day of all days, to hook up with a guy she's never met or indeed seen. There is the behavior of the son Jonah who is able to get cross-country tickets without his father's permission and have his dad meet up with Annie. It is presumed that Sam and Annie will live happily ever after, but if Annie can dump a longtime beau like Walter over a phone call on a radio show, than who knows how long her relationship with Sam will last.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such wonderful comedy/romance movies are rare anymore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very entertaining movie is a present-day rarity, for seldom if ever do you find movies concerning a story where a strong void is filled in a person's life, and concomitantly you don't find far-fetched ways to do it. First of all, Sam Baldwin has just lost his wife in Chicago, and the depressed man wants to get away from it all and move to Seattle where he is definitely sleepless because of his recent loss, naturally. At the same time, his eight-year-old son Jonah wants a new mother. Meanwhile, in Baltimore the very attractive Annie Reed, after a dinner at her parent's home where she introduces her future husband to her family, is driving away when she listens to a talk-show hosted by Dr. Marcia Fieldstone who talks to Sam, whom she calls "Sleepless in Seattle". While listening to his voice Annie suddenly becomes taken with him, and then pursues him, thanks very much to the Internet. This is when the "fun" begins. She "seeks advice" from the classic Cary Grant-Deborah Kerr movie "An Affair to Remember", which she watches on t.v. very often. The story does have a warm and happy ending. The story has different settings-Chicago, New York, Baltimore, as well as Seattle. The very versatile Tom Hanks does his turn well, and the unusually appealing Meg Ryan captivated my attention in her role as Annie Reed. Ross Mallinger does acting well for a very young boy. Rosie O'Donnell is her nutty self as Annie's very close friend. Nora Ephron did a good job of writing and directing. Again, I wish they would make comedy/romances like this more often.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" comes very close to being the ideal contemporary American love story, and even with my reservations about some of the things in the film, I still feel it's a very good one. It's an unpretentious little jewel that demonstrates the true values of screen writing and acting, as both are used here shamelessly and with natural grace to manipulate the emotions of the audience. I admit the story is a bit absurd, but it's also somewhat the idea. And besides, in this age where people travel hundreds of miles to meet folks they've chatted with on the internet, is it so hard to believe that a woman would cross the entire country to learn about a widower whose voice she heard on the radio? Well, the Casanova in me would like to think it's not. The plot, though predictable, makes some daring twists. In most romantic comedies, the couple eyes each other from very early on. And although Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan do make an attractive movie-couple, they don't share even have a two-shot until the last ten minutes. For most of the movie, Mr. Hanks does not even know that Miss Ryan even exists, let alone that they are destined to be in love. It's not that he ignores her; it's because she spends most of the movie on the opposite side of the country from him. She hears him on the radio, speaking of his recently departed wife, is fascinated by what he has to say, and feels something that is best described, as the movie acknowledges, as "magic." I could use more derisory words toward somebody who would feel this way in real life about a voice, but that's good enough. The screenplay (written by director Nora Ephron and two menJeff Arch and David S. Ward) is also a bit insightful on, again, an unpretentious level. It does not delve deep into the psychological state we like to call love and affection, but it does make some interesting observations. First of all, Miss Ryan's character does acknowledge time and time again how absurd it is of her to fly from New York to Seattle to learn about a man she's only heard. There are also numerous touches upon how Hollywood's perception of sex and romance befalls some people. The key moment is when Rosie O'Donnell, as Miss Ryan's best friend, tells her flat out while watching "An Affair to Remember" that what she wants is not to be in love, but "to be in love in a movie." After all, how many of ussingle and once-singlehave not looked at movies like "Casablanca," "An Affair to Remember," "At First Sight," and such and not fantasized about passion that only seems to exist when an actor and actress play make-believe before a camera? Speaking of other films: that is another thing I adored about "Sleepless in Seattle." It has an uncanny ability to recall other films to effectsometimes comedic, sometimes insightful. A favorite moment of mine is when Mr. Hanks explains to his eight-year-old son (extremely well-acted by Ross Malinger) why he is uncomfortable about rushing into a new relationship so soon: he asks him if he ever saw "Fatal Attraction." The biggest homage(s), though, goes back to "An Affair to Remember." That wonderful 1957 film is shown on television screens numerous times throughout the movie, and at key points, Hugo Friedhofer's score even plays on the soundtrack. Being an obvious admirer of the said film, I found the references quite delightful and charming. If there is one thing I couldn't stand about "Sleepless in Seattle," I would have had to have been the constant usage of classic songs to carry along sequences. The opening credits display while a very jazzy version of "As Time Goes By" thumps in the background, but numbers such as "Stand By Your Man," "Stardust," and others are ever-present, reducing fine scenes into what appear to be limp music videos. There is a potentially great momentreduced to a merely good onewhere Miss Ryan, having traveled to Seattle, watches Mr. Hanks and his son as they play on the beach. It's a very good scene (Miss Ryan is kept at medium shots, Mr. Hanks and Mr. Malinger at distance, the montage is very nice) but the song playing in the background trivializes it. The film's musical score by Marc Shaiman is just fine, and I would have preferred to hear his piano motifs instead of a song. Only the movies can convince that two people could fall into deep, passionate love upon first sight. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the defining examples of that theory. After all, if Mr. Hanks and Miss Ryan could have such strong chemistry when they are not even sharing the same frame, one can only imagine what would lay down the road for their characters (and how moved we would be). But what is best about this movieapart from the fabulous writing and actingis its unostentatious manner. It does not make itself out to be any big deal, and just lets the romantic chemistry emerge on its admittedly old-fashioned terms. And I was more interested in the relationship between these people who have never met as opposed to most formula-films where the cute-boy meets cute-girl, they ogle for an hour, hate one another for twenty minutes, and reconcile at the end. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An affair to forget
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, today was a bank holiday and it was pouring rain outside so my wife and I thought we'd watch a family-oriented romantic-comedy, giving "Sleepless In Seattle" the nod. It's fair to say my wife liked it more than I did. For me it wasn't really very funny and worse, was guilty of over-sentimentality and coincidence. Nothing against Meg Ryan, but she hasn't got the kind of face that would stop you in your tracks the way she does at the airport with Tom Hanks' character's first view of her. Moreover her ditzy character doesn't seem too different (sans hysterical laugh) from the girl his son is so against him hooking up with. Oh yes, about the son, aged eight going on eighteen, going out with a fellow eight-year-old girl, quoting from Beatles' songs, having adult conversations with his dad and flying to New York on his own. As he would! Of course his toothy grin and mop of hair sweep aside any charges of embarrassing cringeworthiness, or at least that's what the director would have you think. I found the writing clich&eacute;d and gauche (a woman character cries when recounting the story of the "An Affair To Remember", Cary Grant / Deborah Kerr vehicle which informs much of the plot here; like when was the last time you cried explaining a movie plot),the thirty-something characters are cardboard-thin and irritating plus it seemed there had to be some old romantic song playing in the background of almost every scene. I couldn't get excited by the acting either, there being no chance for Hanks and Ryan to gell as they don't actually meet until their anti-climactic meeting atop the Empire State Building. Bill Paxton gets underused as Ryan's hypochondriac fianc&eacute; while Rosie O'Donnell irritates as her overly understanding boss. I have to admit I can't stand these male-female "buddy" relationships as demonstrated here by Hanks and Rob Reiner and Ryan and O'Donnell, they play out so artificially. Just about the only good for thing me about this film is that I'll probably seek out the earlier film, confident that it will eclipse this very slack and shallow 1980's production which it regrettably inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ultimate Chick Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emily B
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love love LOVE this movie! I have just seen it for about the tenth time and I always laugh, cry, and squeal at the romantic ending. The leads only had about 5 minutes total of screen time together, yet they have so much chemistry in the closing scene. Annie (Meg Ryan) is recently engaged to Walter (the spunky Bill Pullman, my crush from the nineties), and seems to be happy, until she hears 8-year-old Jonah on the radio. His mother died 18 months ago, and his Christmas wish is that his father will find a new wife so that he won't be so sad. His father Sam (Tom Hanks), then talks about how wonderful his wife was and how much he adored her. Something changes in Annie, and she realises there is something about this man that she has to learn more about. Many would call it stalking, others would call it romantic, but suddenly she is flying across the country for a glimpse of him. Out of all the women who wrote to his Dad, Jonah likes Annie's letter the best, and sets up a romantic first encounter on the top of the Empire State building. Awwwww!!! I think from the start everyone knew how it would end, but it's wonderful to watch. Every single actor is outstanding, especially the young boy who played Jonah, many movies have been ruined by horrible children who cannot act, but he's great, and doesn't try to be too cute. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Chicks' Movie Indeed: Superstitious & Maudlin, But Also Witty, Pleasant & Ultimately Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    faterson (faterson@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's difficult to enjoy a movie that you feel is built on a premise that is fundamentally false. I was, therefore, only able to enjoy _Sleepless in Seattle_ while gnashing my teeth quite frequently. _Sleepless in Seattle_ is about as subtle as a sledgehammer in driving home its message: that there exist phenomena such as "soul mate", "being destined for each other", "true love at first sight", etc. Its conception of "love" is extremely old-fashioned; it's supposed to be that thing where "one meets one", and "you are my everything", "you're the world to me". It's strange, but somehow you instantly feel that _Sleepless in Seattle_ is an irreligious movie; it's not that it would be *against religion*, but you get the definite feeling right from the start that "love" in its religious dimension is and will remain conspicuously absent from the movie. This is all the more remarkable in that _Sleepless in Seattle_ glorifies and uses motives from the 1957 Cary Grant & Deborah Kerr hit, _An Affair to Remember_ -- a romantic comedy as well, but where religion and religious feelings are as obviously present as they are non-existent in _Sleepless in Seattle_. I believe in none of those things such as "destiny", "soul mates", "being made for one another", "you're the only one", etc. And I'm sorry, but as the movie kept reiterating these motives ad nauseam (especially in many of the intentionally old-fashioned songs -- both original and "fake" new ones written in the old vein, frequently featuring awful, annoyingly maudlin lyrics -- that we get to listen to throughout the movie, from the opening to the closing credits), I just *had* to say to myself: "All this 'destingy stuff' is something typically enjoyed and believed by women." There's nothing wrong with a movie or book that makes it obvious that its author is a woman; however, this seemed to be *too* obvious in _Sleepless in Seattle_, detracting from the overall enjoyment. I was saying to myself, "This is a chicks' movie," long before Tom Hanks said the same thing about _An Affair to Remember_; but it's a verdict that is even more apropos in relation to _Sleepless in Seattle_. Speaking of the comparison to _An Affair to Remember_, it's weird that _Sleepless in Seattle_ seems more archaic than the movie that preceded it by almost 3 decades. Both movies feature wildly improbable, unrealistic story-lines; yet when you come to think of it, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr might meet on a luxury ship in 2012 just as they did back in 1957; it would no longer be a transatlantic voyage today, but a pleasurable cruise. Could, however, Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan interact, today, in the same way as shown in _Sleepless in Seattle_? Nope. This movie fairly screams at you: "Where's the Internet? Where are the mobile phones, emails, and social networks?" Only a few years later, and the movie's plot would be rendered unusable. Even as it is, great effort is required to suspend your disbelief; while _An Affair to Remember_ is unrealistic, _Sleepless in Seattle_ is doubly so. Or can anyone honestly believe that a loving father would not have alerted the police immediately upon learning that his 8-year-old son eloped on a transcontinental flight to New York unsupervised? Despite all these shortcomings, _Sleepless in Seattle_ manages to be enjoyable throughout, and unlike _An Affair to Remember_, I believe this movie gets better and better with every passing minute. I found the ending of _An Affair to Remember_ rather a let-down, but not here; I thought the Empire State Building finale of _Sleepless in Seattle_ was very nicely constructed, and genuinely moving. I'd say the main credit for the movie's success should go to the two leading stars. Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan both give brilliant, flawless performances. They seem thoroughly believable as persons or personalities, even while their actions do not. The two child actors, Ross Malinger and Gaby Hoffmann, are terrific as well. Rosie O'Donnell makes her presence felt forcefully in a supporting role; her delivery of several of the movie's wittiest lines, no matter how brief, is pitch-perfect. Victor Garber and Rob Reiner only get a few minutes of screen time, but they certainly make the most of them to shine and to delight the audience. (I thought I only noticed a single false note about the actors' performances. In a weird departure from their realistic mode of delivery throughout the movie, in a discussion at Sam's kitchen table, both Tom Hanks and Victor Garber get tearful while talking about the movie _The Dirty Dozen_. I thought the scene rang very false; it was as if a minute or two from your regular TV sitcom was suddenly inserted into _Sleepless in Seattle_; the only thing missing was canned laughter; I found the moment painful to watch, and not funny at all; fortunately, it only lasted a minute or so; and Rita Wilson did not join in the two actors' shenanigans, but rather rescued the scene thanks to remaining who she was supposed to be in the movie. I thought Hanks & Garber did not perform well in that particular brief and untypical moment, but it would be hard to blame them for it; rather, I'd say it was a mistake on the part of the screenwriter/director to include a heterogeneous moment like that in the script.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sleepless in Philidelphia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so a few months back I was hanging out in my bedroom surfing my Netflix app on my Wii, I was waiting for this show to come on and I had an hour to kill, so I see Sleepless in Seatle in the romance section listed. I usually don't watch romances, but with Tom Hanks in it I made an exception. I LOVED THIS MOVIE! The movie is about recently widower Sam and his son Jonha. Sam is extremely down because of his wife's demise, and his son fells horrible for him. Christmas Eve comes and Sam, is still down. So Jonha decides to call one of those call-in-radio shows to help his dad out. Meanwhile, Annie Reed is driving on a highway listening to show, when Sam begins to tell his story Annie starts crying historically and instantly falls in love with him. The whole movie shows both of them on their own quest, Sam to find a new soul-mate, and Annie to find Sam. This is one of those movie anyone can watch and automatically fall in love with! With movies like these you will always know there is someone for everyone, and the worst of things can be for the better! I give this movie a 10 for its excellence in story, character development, and dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Magic " or Mayhem ??
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alxx0209
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a Tom Hanks movie ? I am a huge Hanks fan he has such a passion and commitment to every single movie he does. I have loved all of his movies that i have seen him in so far. and do I like him in this film? Well I suppose - This movie is about love and all its complications dealing with Sam / Annie and Jonah. The Three of them are trying to find " magic " in a relationship - I personally have not yet felt "magic" in a relationship - I have not even dated at all so I do not relate to " magic " but I can somehow imagine the delightful feeling in ones heart when you see the difference in Annie as the movie goes on and she learns what magic feels like. The movie seemed just a little slow in the beginning in my opinion but after a bit it has a certain pace to it that is enjoying. The movie reminds me of a few other films yet Hanks and Ryan are charming and The Kid also helps out the movie go forward / I also believe that Hanks other films success kind of help / Hurt this one in away - I mean Im not comparing it to his other roles but this one seems specifically about love - and I would say its like 70 % romantic and 30 % comedy but again I liked the movie for what it set up and Tom / Meg and the kid did a good job in this film - also a little note I feel that Rob Reiner and Rosie O' Donnell were just alright in there supporting roles but in my opinion they would be under minor roles for this movie. I have to mention a scene that I liked was Annie watching Sam and Jonah goofing around on the beach - thats were it seemed to click for Annie to realize she was in love with both them from just watching them goof around - being themselves , I believe from then on she felt deep down " magic" for Sam and even in away Jonah. That moment was something I would call a " spark " were it just was beautiful for what it was. That moment you could tell what her heart said to her. Final thoughts ? well Toms Hanks did an amazing job plays such likable and relatable characters ( including this one ) Meg did a decent job -Pullman who played Walter did alright the role kinda fell short - Like your about to marry her and you let her walk away ? He could have developed more. Also i would say like 2 or 3 slow bits that could have been tweaked. Other then that its a cute movie about love and Magic. Its worth watching once in your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hanks and Ryan Should Make More Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan should make more movies. As really this is one of a kind and sweet movie. Hanks character Sam loses his wife to cancer and his son Josh, wants Sam to be happy despite not wanting to ever date again. That is why they move from Chicago to Seattle to escape the sadness. But via a radio talk show station. Josh talks to the host as the USA in particular the women fall in love with Sam and his story despite never seeing him or knowing him that well. This also really strikes a nerve in Baltimore radio newspaper writer, Annie played by Ryan. As she wants to get to know this Sam despite being engaged to a straight laced Bill Pullman. A sweet and kind movie. As makes you want to really wished that both Hanks and Ryan made more movies. As Ryan has felled out with the public lately. But still a really sweet movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once more up the ESB
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-3758
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie again for the umpteenth time. I know going in that it blatantly plays on the emotions ... yet I still do it. It is perhaps one of the best feelgood movies out there. It's a believable story and it's wonderfully acted by all concerned. As a small footnote, might I highlight the tiny sequence when Jonah picks up a cab on arriving in NY. One of the two guys hailing cabs has just one line ... and it's fabulous: To the cab driver "Why don'tcha get further from the kerb next time buddy?!" It's such a small piece of dialogue, I think I missed it the first few times I watched the movie, but it's amazing how such a small thing never fails to make me cry ... with laughter. As against the blubbing I do through the rest of the movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No, just , no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wretched film is about Annie Reed (Meg Ryan) a Baltimore journalist who falls in love with Sam(Tom Hanks) when, at his son Jonah's(Ross Malinger)insistence he talks about his marriage to his late wife Maggie on a radio call-in talk show. Apparently she's one of many women who fell in love with Sam based on this lone qualification. Annie already had a fianc&eacute;e Walter(Bill Pullman) who seems like a really nice guy. Unfortunately for Walter, he doesn't meet Annie's dream romance so he has to go. The meeting is spurred on by the adolescent Jonah, who travels cross-country with his father in pursuit. Of course Sam and Annie fall in love and of course they live happily after after. Here are my problems with the film. First of all, Annie decides to dump a perfectly nice man based on a a stranger's telephone call. That is weird and disturbing. Of course, Sam here is a perfectly nice guy, but he could just as easily been the next Jeffery Dahmer. Next is her treatment of Walter who seems devoted to her, in response to his devotion she breaks up with him, on Valentine's Day of all days, to hook up with a guy she's never met or indeed seen. There is the behavior of the son Jonah who is able to get cross-country tickets without his father's permission and have his dad meet up with Annie. It is presumed that Sam and Annie will live happily ever after, but if Annie can dump a longtime beau like Walter over a phone call on a radio show, than who knows how long her relationship with Sam will last.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such wonderful comedy/romance movies are rare anymore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very entertaining movie is a present-day rarity, for seldom if ever do you find movies concerning a story where a strong void is filled in a person's life, and concomitantly you don't find far-fetched ways to do it. First of all, Sam Baldwin has just lost his wife in Chicago, and the depressed man wants to get away from it all and move to Seattle where he is definitely sleepless because of his recent loss, naturally. At the same time, his eight-year-old son Jonah wants a new mother. Meanwhile, in Baltimore the very attractive Annie Reed, after a dinner at her parent's home where she introduces her future husband to her family, is driving away when she listens to a talk-show hosted by Dr. Marcia Fieldstone who talks to Sam, whom she calls "Sleepless in Seattle". While listening to his voice Annie suddenly becomes taken with him, and then pursues him, thanks very much to the Internet. This is when the "fun" begins. She "seeks advice" from the classic Cary Grant-Deborah Kerr movie "An Affair to Remember", which she watches on t.v. very often. The story does have a warm and happy ending. The story has different settings-Chicago, New York, Baltimore, as well as Seattle. The very versatile Tom Hanks does his turn well, and the unusually appealing Meg Ryan captivated my attention in her role as Annie Reed. Ross Mallinger does acting well for a very young boy. Rosie O'Donnell is her nutty self as Annie's very close friend. Nora Ephron did a good job of writing and directing. Again, I wish they would make comedy/romances like this more often.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" comes very close to being the ideal contemporary American love story, and even with my reservations about some of the things in the film, I still feel it's a very good one. It's an unpretentious little jewel that demonstrates the true values of screen writing and acting, as both are used here shamelessly and with natural grace to manipulate the emotions of the audience. I admit the story is a bit absurd, but it's also somewhat the idea. And besides, in this age where people travel hundreds of miles to meet folks they've chatted with on the internet, is it so hard to believe that a woman would cross the entire country to learn about a widower whose voice she heard on the radio? Well, the Casanova in me would like to think it's not. The plot, though predictable, makes some daring twists. In most romantic comedies, the couple eyes each other from very early on. And although Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan do make an attractive movie-couple, they don't share even have a two-shot until the last ten minutes. For most of the movie, Mr. Hanks does not even know that Miss Ryan even exists, let alone that they are destined to be in love. It's not that he ignores her; it's because she spends most of the movie on the opposite side of the country from him. She hears him on the radio, speaking of his recently departed wife, is fascinated by what he has to say, and feels something that is best described, as the movie acknowledges, as "magic." I could use more derisory words toward somebody who would feel this way in real life about a voice, but that's good enough. The screenplay (written by director Nora Ephron and two menJeff Arch and David S. Ward) is also a bit insightful on, again, an unpretentious level. It does not delve deep into the psychological state we like to call love and affection, but it does make some interesting observations. First of all, Miss Ryan's character does acknowledge time and time again how absurd it is of her to fly from New York to Seattle to learn about a man she's only heard. There are also numerous touches upon how Hollywood's perception of sex and romance befalls some people. The key moment is when Rosie O'Donnell, as Miss Ryan's best friend, tells her flat out while watching "An Affair to Remember" that what she wants is not to be in love, but "to be in love in a movie." After all, how many of ussingle and once-singlehave not looked at movies like "Casablanca," "An Affair to Remember," "At First Sight," and such and not fantasized about passion that only seems to exist when an actor and actress play make-believe before a camera? Speaking of other films: that is another thing I adored about "Sleepless in Seattle." It has an uncanny ability to recall other films to effectsometimes comedic, sometimes insightful. A favorite moment of mine is when Mr. Hanks explains to his eight-year-old son (extremely well-acted by Ross Malinger) why he is uncomfortable about rushing into a new relationship so soon: he asks him if he ever saw "Fatal Attraction." The biggest homage(s), though, goes back to "An Affair to Remember." That wonderful 1957 film is shown on television screens numerous times throughout the movie, and at key points, Hugo Friedhofer's score even plays on the soundtrack. Being an obvious admirer of the said film, I found the references quite delightful and charming. If there is one thing I couldn't stand about "Sleepless in Seattle," I would have had to have been the constant usage of classic songs to carry along sequences. The opening credits display while a very jazzy version of "As Time Goes By" thumps in the background, but numbers such as "Stand By Your Man," "Stardust," and others are ever-present, reducing fine scenes into what appear to be limp music videos. There is a potentially great momentreduced to a merely good onewhere Miss Ryan, having traveled to Seattle, watches Mr. Hanks and his son as they play on the beach. It's a very good scene (Miss Ryan is kept at medium shots, Mr. Hanks and Mr. Malinger at distance, the montage is very nice) but the song playing in the background trivializes it. The film's musical score by Marc Shaiman is just fine, and I would have preferred to hear his piano motifs instead of a song. Only the movies can convince that two people could fall into deep, passionate love upon first sight. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the defining examples of that theory. After all, if Mr. Hanks and Miss Ryan could have such strong chemistry when they are not even sharing the same frame, one can only imagine what would lay down the road for their characters (and how moved we would be). But what is best about this movieapart from the fabulous writing and actingis its unostentatious manner. It does not make itself out to be any big deal, and just lets the romantic chemistry emerge on its admittedly old-fashioned terms. And I was more interested in the relationship between these people who have never met as opposed to most formula-films where the cute-boy meets cute-girl, they ogle for an hour, hate one another for twenty minutes, and reconcile at the end. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An affair to forget
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, today was a bank holiday and it was pouring rain outside so my wife and I thought we'd watch a family-oriented romantic-comedy, giving "Sleepless In Seattle" the nod. It's fair to say my wife liked it more than I did. For me it wasn't really very funny and worse, was guilty of over-sentimentality and coincidence. Nothing against Meg Ryan, but she hasn't got the kind of face that would stop you in your tracks the way she does at the airport with Tom Hanks' character's first view of her. Moreover her ditzy character doesn't seem too different (sans hysterical laugh) from the girl his son is so against him hooking up with. Oh yes, about the son, aged eight going on eighteen, going out with a fellow eight-year-old girl, quoting from Beatles' songs, having adult conversations with his dad and flying to New York on his own. As he would! Of course his toothy grin and mop of hair sweep aside any charges of embarrassing cringeworthiness, or at least that's what the director would have you think. I found the writing clich&eacute;d and gauche (a woman character cries when recounting the story of the "An Affair To Remember", Cary Grant / Deborah Kerr vehicle which informs much of the plot here; like when was the last time you cried explaining a movie plot),the thirty-something characters are cardboard-thin and irritating plus it seemed there had to be some old romantic song playing in the background of almost every scene. I couldn't get excited by the acting either, there being no chance for Hanks and Ryan to gell as they don't actually meet until their anti-climactic meeting atop the Empire State Building. Bill Paxton gets underused as Ryan's hypochondriac fianc&eacute; while Rosie O'Donnell irritates as her overly understanding boss. I have to admit I can't stand these male-female "buddy" relationships as demonstrated here by Hanks and Rob Reiner and Ryan and O'Donnell, they play out so artificially. Just about the only good for thing me about this film is that I'll probably seek out the earlier film, confident that it will eclipse this very slack and shallow 1980's production which it regrettably inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ultimate Chick Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emily B
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love love LOVE this movie! I have just seen it for about the tenth time and I always laugh, cry, and squeal at the romantic ending. The leads only had about 5 minutes total of screen time together, yet they have so much chemistry in the closing scene. Annie (Meg Ryan) is recently engaged to Walter (the spunky Bill Pullman, my crush from the nineties), and seems to be happy, until she hears 8-year-old Jonah on the radio. His mother died 18 months ago, and his Christmas wish is that his father will find a new wife so that he won't be so sad. His father Sam (Tom Hanks), then talks about how wonderful his wife was and how much he adored her. Something changes in Annie, and she realises there is something about this man that she has to learn more about. Many would call it stalking, others would call it romantic, but suddenly she is flying across the country for a glimpse of him. Out of all the women who wrote to his Dad, Jonah likes Annie's letter the best, and sets up a romantic first encounter on the top of the Empire State building. Awwwww!!! I think from the start everyone knew how it would end, but it's wonderful to watch. Every single actor is outstanding, especially the young boy who played Jonah, many movies have been ruined by horrible children who cannot act, but he's great, and doesn't try to be too cute. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Chicks' Movie Indeed: Superstitious & Maudlin, But Also Witty, Pleasant & Ultimately Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    faterson (faterson@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's difficult to enjoy a movie that you feel is built on a premise that is fundamentally false. I was, therefore, only able to enjoy _Sleepless in Seattle_ while gnashing my teeth quite frequently. _Sleepless in Seattle_ is about as subtle as a sledgehammer in driving home its message: that there exist phenomena such as "soul mate", "being destined for each other", "true love at first sight", etc. Its conception of "love" is extremely old-fashioned; it's supposed to be that thing where "one meets one", and "you are my everything", "you're the world to me". It's strange, but somehow you instantly feel that _Sleepless in Seattle_ is an irreligious movie; it's not that it would be *against religion*, but you get the definite feeling right from the start that "love" in its religious dimension is and will remain conspicuously absent from the movie. This is all the more remarkable in that _Sleepless in Seattle_ glorifies and uses motives from the 1957 Cary Grant & Deborah Kerr hit, _An Affair to Remember_ -- a romantic comedy as well, but where religion and religious feelings are as obviously present as they are non-existent in _Sleepless in Seattle_. I believe in none of those things such as "destiny", "soul mates", "being made for one another", "you're the only one", etc. And I'm sorry, but as the movie kept reiterating these motives ad nauseam (especially in many of the intentionally old-fashioned songs -- both original and "fake" new ones written in the old vein, frequently featuring awful, annoyingly maudlin lyrics -- that we get to listen to throughout the movie, from the opening to the closing credits), I just *had* to say to myself: "All this 'destingy stuff' is something typically enjoyed and believed by women." There's nothing wrong with a movie or book that makes it obvious that its author is a woman; however, this seemed to be *too* obvious in _Sleepless in Seattle_, detracting from the overall enjoyment. I was saying to myself, "This is a chicks' movie," long before Tom Hanks said the same thing about _An Affair to Remember_; but it's a verdict that is even more apropos in relation to _Sleepless in Seattle_. Speaking of the comparison to _An Affair to Remember_, it's weird that _Sleepless in Seattle_ seems more archaic than the movie that preceded it by almost 3 decades. Both movies feature wildly improbable, unrealistic story-lines; yet when you come to think of it, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr might meet on a luxury ship in 2012 just as they did back in 1957; it would no longer be a transatlantic voyage today, but a pleasurable cruise. Could, however, Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan interact, today, in the same way as shown in _Sleepless in Seattle_? Nope. This movie fairly screams at you: "Where's the Internet? Where are the mobile phones, emails, and social networks?" Only a few years later, and the movie's plot would be rendered unusable. Even as it is, great effort is required to suspend your disbelief; while _An Affair to Remember_ is unrealistic, _Sleepless in Seattle_ is doubly so. Or can anyone honestly believe that a loving father would not have alerted the police immediately upon learning that his 8-year-old son eloped on a transcontinental flight to New York unsupervised? Despite all these shortcomings, _Sleepless in Seattle_ manages to be enjoyable throughout, and unlike _An Affair to Remember_, I believe this movie gets better and better with every passing minute. I found the ending of _An Affair to Remember_ rather a let-down, but not here; I thought the Empire State Building finale of _Sleepless in Seattle_ was very nicely constructed, and genuinely moving. I'd say the main credit for the movie's success should go to the two leading stars. Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan both give brilliant, flawless performances. They seem thoroughly believable as persons or personalities, even while their actions do not. The two child actors, Ross Malinger and Gaby Hoffmann, are terrific as well. Rosie O'Donnell makes her presence felt forcefully in a supporting role; her delivery of several of the movie's wittiest lines, no matter how brief, is pitch-perfect. Victor Garber and Rob Reiner only get a few minutes of screen time, but they certainly make the most of them to shine and to delight the audience. (I thought I only noticed a single false note about the actors' performances. In a weird departure from their realistic mode of delivery throughout the movie, in a discussion at Sam's kitchen table, both Tom Hanks and Victor Garber get tearful while talking about the movie _The Dirty Dozen_. I thought the scene rang very false; it was as if a minute or two from your regular TV sitcom was suddenly inserted into _Sleepless in Seattle_; the only thing missing was canned laughter; I found the moment painful to watch, and not funny at all; fortunately, it only lasted a minute or so; and Rita Wilson did not join in the two actors' shenanigans, but rather rescued the scene thanks to remaining who she was supposed to be in the movie. I thought Hanks & Garber did not perform well in that particular brief and untypical moment, but it would be hard to blame them for it; rather, I'd say it was a mistake on the part of the screenwriter/director to include a heterogeneous moment like that in the script.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sleepless in Philidelphia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so a few months back I was hanging out in my bedroom surfing my Netflix app on my Wii, I was waiting for this show to come on and I had an hour to kill, so I see Sleepless in Seatle in the romance section listed. I usually don't watch romances, but with Tom Hanks in it I made an exception. I LOVED THIS MOVIE! The movie is about recently widower Sam and his son Jonha. Sam is extremely down because of his wife's demise, and his son fells horrible for him. Christmas Eve comes and Sam, is still down. So Jonha decides to call one of those call-in-radio shows to help his dad out. Meanwhile, Annie Reed is driving on a highway listening to show, when Sam begins to tell his story Annie starts crying historically and instantly falls in love with him. The whole movie shows both of them on their own quest, Sam to find a new soul-mate, and Annie to find Sam. This is one of those movie anyone can watch and automatically fall in love with! With movies like these you will always know there is someone for everyone, and the worst of things can be for the better! I give this movie a 10 for its excellence in story, character development, and dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Magic " or Mayhem ??
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alxx0209
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a Tom Hanks movie ? I am a huge Hanks fan he has such a passion and commitment to every single movie he does. I have loved all of his movies that i have seen him in so far. and do I like him in this film? Well I suppose - This movie is about love and all its complications dealing with Sam / Annie and Jonah. The Three of them are trying to find " magic " in a relationship - I personally have not yet felt "magic" in a relationship - I have not even dated at all so I do not relate to " magic " but I can somehow imagine the delightful feeling in ones heart when you see the difference in Annie as the movie goes on and she learns what magic feels like. The movie seemed just a little slow in the beginning in my opinion but after a bit it has a certain pace to it that is enjoying. The movie reminds me of a few other films yet Hanks and Ryan are charming and The Kid also helps out the movie go forward / I also believe that Hanks other films success kind of help / Hurt this one in away - I mean Im not comparing it to his other roles but this one seems specifically about love - and I would say its like 70 % romantic and 30 % comedy but again I liked the movie for what it set up and Tom / Meg and the kid did a good job in this film - also a little note I feel that Rob Reiner and Rosie O' Donnell were just alright in there supporting roles but in my opinion they would be under minor roles for this movie. I have to mention a scene that I liked was Annie watching Sam and Jonah goofing around on the beach - thats were it seemed to click for Annie to realize she was in love with both them from just watching them goof around - being themselves , I believe from then on she felt deep down " magic" for Sam and even in away Jonah. That moment was something I would call a " spark " were it just was beautiful for what it was. That moment you could tell what her heart said to her. Final thoughts ? well Toms Hanks did an amazing job plays such likable and relatable characters ( including this one ) Meg did a decent job -Pullman who played Walter did alright the role kinda fell short - Like your about to marry her and you let her walk away ? He could have developed more. Also i would say like 2 or 3 slow bits that could have been tweaked. Other then that its a cute movie about love and Magic. Its worth watching once in your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hanks and Ryan Should Make More Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan should make more movies. As really this is one of a kind and sweet movie. Hanks character Sam loses his wife to cancer and his son Josh, wants Sam to be happy despite not wanting to ever date again. That is why they move from Chicago to Seattle to escape the sadness. But via a radio talk show station. Josh talks to the host as the USA in particular the women fall in love with Sam and his story despite never seeing him or knowing him that well. This also really strikes a nerve in Baltimore radio newspaper writer, Annie played by Ryan. As she wants to get to know this Sam despite being engaged to a straight laced Bill Pullman. A sweet and kind movie. As makes you want to really wished that both Hanks and Ryan made more movies. As Ryan has felled out with the public lately. But still a really sweet movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once more up the ESB
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-3758
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie again for the umpteenth time. I know going in that it blatantly plays on the emotions ... yet I still do it. It is perhaps one of the best feelgood movies out there. It's a believable story and it's wonderfully acted by all concerned. As a small footnote, might I highlight the tiny sequence when Jonah picks up a cab on arriving in NY. One of the two guys hailing cabs has just one line ... and it's fabulous: To the cab driver "Why don'tcha get further from the kerb next time buddy?!" It's such a small piece of dialogue, I think I missed it the first few times I watched the movie, but it's amazing how such a small thing never fails to make me cry ... with laughter. As against the blubbing I do through the rest of the movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No, just , no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wretched film is about Annie Reed (Meg Ryan) a Baltimore journalist who falls in love with Sam(Tom Hanks) when, at his son Jonah's(Ross Malinger)insistence he talks about his marriage to his late wife Maggie on a radio call-in talk show. Apparently she's one of many women who fell in love with Sam based on this lone qualification. Annie already had a fianc&eacute;e Walter(Bill Pullman) who seems like a really nice guy. Unfortunately for Walter, he doesn't meet Annie's dream romance so he has to go. The meeting is spurred on by the adolescent Jonah, who travels cross-country with his father in pursuit. Of course Sam and Annie fall in love and of course they live happily after after. Here are my problems with the film. First of all, Annie decides to dump a perfectly nice man based on a a stranger's telephone call. That is weird and disturbing. Of course, Sam here is a perfectly nice guy, but he could just as easily been the next Jeffery Dahmer. Next is her treatment of Walter who seems devoted to her, in response to his devotion she breaks up with him, on Valentine's Day of all days, to hook up with a guy she's never met or indeed seen. There is the behavior of the son Jonah who is able to get cross-country tickets without his father's permission and have his dad meet up with Annie. It is presumed that Sam and Annie will live happily ever after, but if Annie can dump a longtime beau like Walter over a phone call on a radio show, than who knows how long her relationship with Sam will last.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such wonderful comedy/romance movies are rare anymore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very entertaining movie is a present-day rarity, for seldom if ever do you find movies concerning a story where a strong void is filled in a person's life, and concomitantly you don't find far-fetched ways to do it. First of all, Sam Baldwin has just lost his wife in Chicago, and the depressed man wants to get away from it all and move to Seattle where he is definitely sleepless because of his recent loss, naturally. At the same time, his eight-year-old son Jonah wants a new mother. Meanwhile, in Baltimore the very attractive Annie Reed, after a dinner at her parent's home where she introduces her future husband to her family, is driving away when she listens to a talk-show hosted by Dr. Marcia Fieldstone who talks to Sam, whom she calls "Sleepless in Seattle". While listening to his voice Annie suddenly becomes taken with him, and then pursues him, thanks very much to the Internet. This is when the "fun" begins. She "seeks advice" from the classic Cary Grant-Deborah Kerr movie "An Affair to Remember", which she watches on t.v. very often. The story does have a warm and happy ending. The story has different settings-Chicago, New York, Baltimore, as well as Seattle. The very versatile Tom Hanks does his turn well, and the unusually appealing Meg Ryan captivated my attention in her role as Annie Reed. Ross Mallinger does acting well for a very young boy. Rosie O'Donnell is her nutty self as Annie's very close friend. Nora Ephron did a good job of writing and directing. Again, I wish they would make comedy/romances like this more often.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" comes very close to being the ideal contemporary American love story, and even with my reservations about some of the things in the film, I still feel it's a very good one. It's an unpretentious little jewel that demonstrates the true values of screen writing and acting, as both are used here shamelessly and with natural grace to manipulate the emotions of the audience. I admit the story is a bit absurd, but it's also somewhat the idea. And besides, in this age where people travel hundreds of miles to meet folks they've chatted with on the internet, is it so hard to believe that a woman would cross the entire country to learn about a widower whose voice she heard on the radio? Well, the Casanova in me would like to think it's not. The plot, though predictable, makes some daring twists. In most romantic comedies, the couple eyes each other from very early on. And although Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan do make an attractive movie-couple, they don't share even have a two-shot until the last ten minutes. For most of the movie, Mr. Hanks does not even know that Miss Ryan even exists, let alone that they are destined to be in love. It's not that he ignores her; it's because she spends most of the movie on the opposite side of the country from him. She hears him on the radio, speaking of his recently departed wife, is fascinated by what he has to say, and feels something that is best described, as the movie acknowledges, as "magic." I could use more derisory words toward somebody who would feel this way in real life about a voice, but that's good enough. The screenplay (written by director Nora Ephron and two menJeff Arch and David S. Ward) is also a bit insightful on, again, an unpretentious level. It does not delve deep into the psychological state we like to call love and affection, but it does make some interesting observations. First of all, Miss Ryan's character does acknowledge time and time again how absurd it is of her to fly from New York to Seattle to learn about a man she's only heard. There are also numerous touches upon how Hollywood's perception of sex and romance befalls some people. The key moment is when Rosie O'Donnell, as Miss Ryan's best friend, tells her flat out while watching "An Affair to Remember" that what she wants is not to be in love, but "to be in love in a movie." After all, how many of ussingle and once-singlehave not looked at movies like "Casablanca," "An Affair to Remember," "At First Sight," and such and not fantasized about passion that only seems to exist when an actor and actress play make-believe before a camera? Speaking of other films: that is another thing I adored about "Sleepless in Seattle." It has an uncanny ability to recall other films to effectsometimes comedic, sometimes insightful. A favorite moment of mine is when Mr. Hanks explains to his eight-year-old son (extremely well-acted by Ross Malinger) why he is uncomfortable about rushing into a new relationship so soon: he asks him if he ever saw "Fatal Attraction." The biggest homage(s), though, goes back to "An Affair to Remember." That wonderful 1957 film is shown on television screens numerous times throughout the movie, and at key points, Hugo Friedhofer's score even plays on the soundtrack. Being an obvious admirer of the said film, I found the references quite delightful and charming. If there is one thing I couldn't stand about "Sleepless in Seattle," I would have had to have been the constant usage of classic songs to carry along sequences. The opening credits display while a very jazzy version of "As Time Goes By" thumps in the background, but numbers such as "Stand By Your Man," "Stardust," and others are ever-present, reducing fine scenes into what appear to be limp music videos. There is a potentially great momentreduced to a merely good onewhere Miss Ryan, having traveled to Seattle, watches Mr. Hanks and his son as they play on the beach. It's a very good scene (Miss Ryan is kept at medium shots, Mr. Hanks and Mr. Malinger at distance, the montage is very nice) but the song playing in the background trivializes it. The film's musical score by Marc Shaiman is just fine, and I would have preferred to hear his piano motifs instead of a song. Only the movies can convince that two people could fall into deep, passionate love upon first sight. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the defining examples of that theory. After all, if Mr. Hanks and Miss Ryan could have such strong chemistry when they are not even sharing the same frame, one can only imagine what would lay down the road for their characters (and how moved we would be). But what is best about this movieapart from the fabulous writing and actingis its unostentatious manner. It does not make itself out to be any big deal, and just lets the romantic chemistry emerge on its admittedly old-fashioned terms. And I was more interested in the relationship between these people who have never met as opposed to most formula-films where the cute-boy meets cute-girl, they ogle for an hour, hate one another for twenty minutes, and reconcile at the end. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An affair to forget
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, today was a bank holiday and it was pouring rain outside so my wife and I thought we'd watch a family-oriented romantic-comedy, giving "Sleepless In Seattle" the nod. It's fair to say my wife liked it more than I did. For me it wasn't really very funny and worse, was guilty of over-sentimentality and coincidence. Nothing against Meg Ryan, but she hasn't got the kind of face that would stop you in your tracks the way she does at the airport with Tom Hanks' character's first view of her. Moreover her ditzy character doesn't seem too different (sans hysterical laugh) from the girl his son is so against him hooking up with. Oh yes, about the son, aged eight going on eighteen, going out with a fellow eight-year-old girl, quoting from Beatles' songs, having adult conversations with his dad and flying to New York on his own. As he would! Of course his toothy grin and mop of hair sweep aside any charges of embarrassing cringeworthiness, or at least that's what the director would have you think. I found the writing clich&eacute;d and gauche (a woman character cries when recounting the story of the "An Affair To Remember", Cary Grant / Deborah Kerr vehicle which informs much of the plot here; like when was the last time you cried explaining a movie plot),the thirty-something characters are cardboard-thin and irritating plus it seemed there had to be some old romantic song playing in the background of almost every scene. I couldn't get excited by the acting either, there being no chance for Hanks and Ryan to gell as they don't actually meet until their anti-climactic meeting atop the Empire State Building. Bill Paxton gets underused as Ryan's hypochondriac fianc&eacute; while Rosie O'Donnell irritates as her overly understanding boss. I have to admit I can't stand these male-female "buddy" relationships as demonstrated here by Hanks and Rob Reiner and Ryan and O'Donnell, they play out so artificially. Just about the only good for thing me about this film is that I'll probably seek out the earlier film, confident that it will eclipse this very slack and shallow 1980's production which it regrettably inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ultimate Chick Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emily B
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love love LOVE this movie! I have just seen it for about the tenth time and I always laugh, cry, and squeal at the romantic ending. The leads only had about 5 minutes total of screen time together, yet they have so much chemistry in the closing scene. Annie (Meg Ryan) is recently engaged to Walter (the spunky Bill Pullman, my crush from the nineties), and seems to be happy, until she hears 8-year-old Jonah on the radio. His mother died 18 months ago, and his Christmas wish is that his father will find a new wife so that he won't be so sad. His father Sam (Tom Hanks), then talks about how wonderful his wife was and how much he adored her. Something changes in Annie, and she realises there is something about this man that she has to learn more about. Many would call it stalking, others would call it romantic, but suddenly she is flying across the country for a glimpse of him. Out of all the women who wrote to his Dad, Jonah likes Annie's letter the best, and sets up a romantic first encounter on the top of the Empire State building. Awwwww!!! I think from the start everyone knew how it would end, but it's wonderful to watch. Every single actor is outstanding, especially the young boy who played Jonah, many movies have been ruined by horrible children who cannot act, but he's great, and doesn't try to be too cute. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Chicks' Movie Indeed: Superstitious & Maudlin, But Also Witty, Pleasant & Ultimately Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    faterson (faterson@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's difficult to enjoy a movie that you feel is built on a premise that is fundamentally false. I was, therefore, only able to enjoy _Sleepless in Seattle_ while gnashing my teeth quite frequently. _Sleepless in Seattle_ is about as subtle as a sledgehammer in driving home its message: that there exist phenomena such as "soul mate", "being destined for each other", "true love at first sight", etc. Its conception of "love" is extremely old-fashioned; it's supposed to be that thing where "one meets one", and "you are my everything", "you're the world to me". It's strange, but somehow you instantly feel that _Sleepless in Seattle_ is an irreligious movie; it's not that it would be *against religion*, but you get the definite feeling right from the start that "love" in its religious dimension is and will remain conspicuously absent from the movie. This is all the more remarkable in that _Sleepless in Seattle_ glorifies and uses motives from the 1957 Cary Grant & Deborah Kerr hit, _An Affair to Remember_ -- a romantic comedy as well, but where religion and religious feelings are as obviously present as they are non-existent in _Sleepless in Seattle_. I believe in none of those things such as "destiny", "soul mates", "being made for one another", "you're the only one", etc. And I'm sorry, but as the movie kept reiterating these motives ad nauseam (especially in many of the intentionally old-fashioned songs -- both original and "fake" new ones written in the old vein, frequently featuring awful, annoyingly maudlin lyrics -- that we get to listen to throughout the movie, from the opening to the closing credits), I just *had* to say to myself: "All this 'destingy stuff' is something typically enjoyed and believed by women." There's nothing wrong with a movie or book that makes it obvious that its author is a woman; however, this seemed to be *too* obvious in _Sleepless in Seattle_, detracting from the overall enjoyment. I was saying to myself, "This is a chicks' movie," long before Tom Hanks said the same thing about _An Affair to Remember_; but it's a verdict that is even more apropos in relation to _Sleepless in Seattle_. Speaking of the comparison to _An Affair to Remember_, it's weird that _Sleepless in Seattle_ seems more archaic than the movie that preceded it by almost 3 decades. Both movies feature wildly improbable, unrealistic story-lines; yet when you come to think of it, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr might meet on a luxury ship in 2012 just as they did back in 1957; it would no longer be a transatlantic voyage today, but a pleasurable cruise. Could, however, Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan interact, today, in the same way as shown in _Sleepless in Seattle_? Nope. This movie fairly screams at you: "Where's the Internet? Where are the mobile phones, emails, and social networks?" Only a few years later, and the movie's plot would be rendered unusable. Even as it is, great effort is required to suspend your disbelief; while _An Affair to Remember_ is unrealistic, _Sleepless in Seattle_ is doubly so. Or can anyone honestly believe that a loving father would not have alerted the police immediately upon learning that his 8-year-old son eloped on a transcontinental flight to New York unsupervised? Despite all these shortcomings, _Sleepless in Seattle_ manages to be enjoyable throughout, and unlike _An Affair to Remember_, I believe this movie gets better and better with every passing minute. I found the ending of _An Affair to Remember_ rather a let-down, but not here; I thought the Empire State Building finale of _Sleepless in Seattle_ was very nicely constructed, and genuinely moving. I'd say the main credit for the movie's success should go to the two leading stars. Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan both give brilliant, flawless performances. They seem thoroughly believable as persons or personalities, even while their actions do not. The two child actors, Ross Malinger and Gaby Hoffmann, are terrific as well. Rosie O'Donnell makes her presence felt forcefully in a supporting role; her delivery of several of the movie's wittiest lines, no matter how brief, is pitch-perfect. Victor Garber and Rob Reiner only get a few minutes of screen time, but they certainly make the most of them to shine and to delight the audience. (I thought I only noticed a single false note about the actors' performances. In a weird departure from their realistic mode of delivery throughout the movie, in a discussion at Sam's kitchen table, both Tom Hanks and Victor Garber get tearful while talking about the movie _The Dirty Dozen_. I thought the scene rang very false; it was as if a minute or two from your regular TV sitcom was suddenly inserted into _Sleepless in Seattle_; the only thing missing was canned laughter; I found the moment painful to watch, and not funny at all; fortunately, it only lasted a minute or so; and Rita Wilson did not join in the two actors' shenanigans, but rather rescued the scene thanks to remaining who she was supposed to be in the movie. I thought Hanks & Garber did not perform well in that particular brief and untypical moment, but it would be hard to blame them for it; rather, I'd say it was a mistake on the part of the screenwriter/director to include a heterogeneous moment like that in the script.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sleepless in Philidelphia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so a few months back I was hanging out in my bedroom surfing my Netflix app on my Wii, I was waiting for this show to come on and I had an hour to kill, so I see Sleepless in Seatle in the romance section listed. I usually don't watch romances, but with Tom Hanks in it I made an exception. I LOVED THIS MOVIE! The movie is about recently widower Sam and his son Jonha. Sam is extremely down because of his wife's demise, and his son fells horrible for him. Christmas Eve comes and Sam, is still down. So Jonha decides to call one of those call-in-radio shows to help his dad out. Meanwhile, Annie Reed is driving on a highway listening to show, when Sam begins to tell his story Annie starts crying historically and instantly falls in love with him. The whole movie shows both of them on their own quest, Sam to find a new soul-mate, and Annie to find Sam. This is one of those movie anyone can watch and automatically fall in love with! With movies like these you will always know there is someone for everyone, and the worst of things can be for the better! I give this movie a 10 for its excellence in story, character development, and dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Magic " or Mayhem ??
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alxx0209
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a Tom Hanks movie ? I am a huge Hanks fan he has such a passion and commitment to every single movie he does. I have loved all of his movies that i have seen him in so far. and do I like him in this film? Well I suppose - This movie is about love and all its complications dealing with Sam / Annie and Jonah. The Three of them are trying to find " magic " in a relationship - I personally have not yet felt "magic" in a relationship - I have not even dated at all so I do not relate to " magic " but I can somehow imagine the delightful feeling in ones heart when you see the difference in Annie as the movie goes on and she learns what magic feels like. The movie seemed just a little slow in the beginning in my opinion but after a bit it has a certain pace to it that is enjoying. The movie reminds me of a few other films yet Hanks and Ryan are charming and The Kid also helps out the movie go forward / I also believe that Hanks other films success kind of help / Hurt this one in away - I mean Im not comparing it to his other roles but this one seems specifically about love - and I would say its like 70 % romantic and 30 % comedy but again I liked the movie for what it set up and Tom / Meg and the kid did a good job in this film - also a little note I feel that Rob Reiner and Rosie O' Donnell were just alright in there supporting roles but in my opinion they would be under minor roles for this movie. I have to mention a scene that I liked was Annie watching Sam and Jonah goofing around on the beach - thats were it seemed to click for Annie to realize she was in love with both them from just watching them goof around - being themselves , I believe from then on she felt deep down " magic" for Sam and even in away Jonah. That moment was something I would call a " spark " were it just was beautiful for what it was. That moment you could tell what her heart said to her. Final thoughts ? well Toms Hanks did an amazing job plays such likable and relatable characters ( including this one ) Meg did a decent job -Pullman who played Walter did alright the role kinda fell short - Like your about to marry her and you let her walk away ? He could have developed more. Also i would say like 2 or 3 slow bits that could have been tweaked. Other then that its a cute movie about love and Magic. Its worth watching once in your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hanks and Ryan Should Make More Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan should make more movies. As really this is one of a kind and sweet movie. Hanks character Sam loses his wife to cancer and his son Josh, wants Sam to be happy despite not wanting to ever date again. That is why they move from Chicago to Seattle to escape the sadness. But via a radio talk show station. Josh talks to the host as the USA in particular the women fall in love with Sam and his story despite never seeing him or knowing him that well. This also really strikes a nerve in Baltimore radio newspaper writer, Annie played by Ryan. As she wants to get to know this Sam despite being engaged to a straight laced Bill Pullman. A sweet and kind movie. As makes you want to really wished that both Hanks and Ryan made more movies. As Ryan has felled out with the public lately. But still a really sweet movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once more up the ESB
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-3758
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie again for the umpteenth time. I know going in that it blatantly plays on the emotions ... yet I still do it. It is perhaps one of the best feelgood movies out there. It's a believable story and it's wonderfully acted by all concerned. As a small footnote, might I highlight the tiny sequence when Jonah picks up a cab on arriving in NY. One of the two guys hailing cabs has just one line ... and it's fabulous: To the cab driver "Why don'tcha get further from the kerb next time buddy?!" It's such a small piece of dialogue, I think I missed it the first few times I watched the movie, but it's amazing how such a small thing never fails to make me cry ... with laughter. As against the blubbing I do through the rest of the movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No, just , no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wretched film is about Annie Reed (Meg Ryan) a Baltimore journalist who falls in love with Sam(Tom Hanks) when, at his son Jonah's(Ross Malinger)insistence he talks about his marriage to his late wife Maggie on a radio call-in talk show. Apparently she's one of many women who fell in love with Sam based on this lone qualification. Annie already had a fianc&eacute;e Walter(Bill Pullman) who seems like a really nice guy. Unfortunately for Walter, he doesn't meet Annie's dream romance so he has to go. The meeting is spurred on by the adolescent Jonah, who travels cross-country with his father in pursuit. Of course Sam and Annie fall in love and of course they live happily after after. Here are my problems with the film. First of all, Annie decides to dump a perfectly nice man based on a a stranger's telephone call. That is weird and disturbing. Of course, Sam here is a perfectly nice guy, but he could just as easily been the next Jeffery Dahmer. Next is her treatment of Walter who seems devoted to her, in response to his devotion she breaks up with him, on Valentine's Day of all days, to hook up with a guy she's never met or indeed seen. There is the behavior of the son Jonah who is able to get cross-country tickets without his father's permission and have his dad meet up with Annie. It is presumed that Sam and Annie will live happily ever after, but if Annie can dump a longtime beau like Walter over a phone call on a radio show, than who knows how long her relationship with Sam will last.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such wonderful comedy/romance movies are rare anymore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very entertaining movie is a present-day rarity, for seldom if ever do you find movies concerning a story where a strong void is filled in a person's life, and concomitantly you don't find far-fetched ways to do it. First of all, Sam Baldwin has just lost his wife in Chicago, and the depressed man wants to get away from it all and move to Seattle where he is definitely sleepless because of his recent loss, naturally. At the same time, his eight-year-old son Jonah wants a new mother. Meanwhile, in Baltimore the very attractive Annie Reed, after a dinner at her parent's home where she introduces her future husband to her family, is driving away when she listens to a talk-show hosted by Dr. Marcia Fieldstone who talks to Sam, whom she calls "Sleepless in Seattle". While listening to his voice Annie suddenly becomes taken with him, and then pursues him, thanks very much to the Internet. This is when the "fun" begins. She "seeks advice" from the classic Cary Grant-Deborah Kerr movie "An Affair to Remember", which she watches on t.v. very often. The story does have a warm and happy ending. The story has different settings-Chicago, New York, Baltimore, as well as Seattle. The very versatile Tom Hanks does his turn well, and the unusually appealing Meg Ryan captivated my attention in her role as Annie Reed. Ross Mallinger does acting well for a very young boy. Rosie O'Donnell is her nutty self as Annie's very close friend. Nora Ephron did a good job of writing and directing. Again, I wish they would make comedy/romances like this more often.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" comes very close to being the ideal contemporary American love story, and even with my reservations about some of the things in the film, I still feel it's a very good one. It's an unpretentious little jewel that demonstrates the true values of screen writing and acting, as both are used here shamelessly and with natural grace to manipulate the emotions of the audience. I admit the story is a bit absurd, but it's also somewhat the idea. And besides, in this age where people travel hundreds of miles to meet folks they've chatted with on the internet, is it so hard to believe that a woman would cross the entire country to learn about a widower whose voice she heard on the radio? Well, the Casanova in me would like to think it's not. The plot, though predictable, makes some daring twists. In most romantic comedies, the couple eyes each other from very early on. And although Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan do make an attractive movie-couple, they don't share even have a two-shot until the last ten minutes. For most of the movie, Mr. Hanks does not even know that Miss Ryan even exists, let alone that they are destined to be in love. It's not that he ignores her; it's because she spends most of the movie on the opposite side of the country from him. She hears him on the radio, speaking of his recently departed wife, is fascinated by what he has to say, and feels something that is best described, as the movie acknowledges, as "magic." I could use more derisory words toward somebody who would feel this way in real life about a voice, but that's good enough. The screenplay (written by director Nora Ephron and two menJeff Arch and David S. Ward) is also a bit insightful on, again, an unpretentious level. It does not delve deep into the psychological state we like to call love and affection, but it does make some interesting observations. First of all, Miss Ryan's character does acknowledge time and time again how absurd it is of her to fly from New York to Seattle to learn about a man she's only heard. There are also numerous touches upon how Hollywood's perception of sex and romance befalls some people. The key moment is when Rosie O'Donnell, as Miss Ryan's best friend, tells her flat out while watching "An Affair to Remember" that what she wants is not to be in love, but "to be in love in a movie." After all, how many of ussingle and once-singlehave not looked at movies like "Casablanca," "An Affair to Remember," "At First Sight," and such and not fantasized about passion that only seems to exist when an actor and actress play make-believe before a camera? Speaking of other films: that is another thing I adored about "Sleepless in Seattle." It has an uncanny ability to recall other films to effectsometimes comedic, sometimes insightful. A favorite moment of mine is when Mr. Hanks explains to his eight-year-old son (extremely well-acted by Ross Malinger) why he is uncomfortable about rushing into a new relationship so soon: he asks him if he ever saw "Fatal Attraction." The biggest homage(s), though, goes back to "An Affair to Remember." That wonderful 1957 film is shown on television screens numerous times throughout the movie, and at key points, Hugo Friedhofer's score even plays on the soundtrack. Being an obvious admirer of the said film, I found the references quite delightful and charming. If there is one thing I couldn't stand about "Sleepless in Seattle," I would have had to have been the constant usage of classic songs to carry along sequences. The opening credits display while a very jazzy version of "As Time Goes By" thumps in the background, but numbers such as "Stand By Your Man," "Stardust," and others are ever-present, reducing fine scenes into what appear to be limp music videos. There is a potentially great momentreduced to a merely good onewhere Miss Ryan, having traveled to Seattle, watches Mr. Hanks and his son as they play on the beach. It's a very good scene (Miss Ryan is kept at medium shots, Mr. Hanks and Mr. Malinger at distance, the montage is very nice) but the song playing in the background trivializes it. The film's musical score by Marc Shaiman is just fine, and I would have preferred to hear his piano motifs instead of a song. Only the movies can convince that two people could fall into deep, passionate love upon first sight. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the defining examples of that theory. After all, if Mr. Hanks and Miss Ryan could have such strong chemistry when they are not even sharing the same frame, one can only imagine what would lay down the road for their characters (and how moved we would be). But what is best about this movieapart from the fabulous writing and actingis its unostentatious manner. It does not make itself out to be any big deal, and just lets the romantic chemistry emerge on its admittedly old-fashioned terms. And I was more interested in the relationship between these people who have never met as opposed to most formula-films where the cute-boy meets cute-girl, they ogle for an hour, hate one another for twenty minutes, and reconcile at the end. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An affair to forget
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, today was a bank holiday and it was pouring rain outside so my wife and I thought we'd watch a family-oriented romantic-comedy, giving "Sleepless In Seattle" the nod. It's fair to say my wife liked it more than I did. For me it wasn't really very funny and worse, was guilty of over-sentimentality and coincidence. Nothing against Meg Ryan, but she hasn't got the kind of face that would stop you in your tracks the way she does at the airport with Tom Hanks' character's first view of her. Moreover her ditzy character doesn't seem too different (sans hysterical laugh) from the girl his son is so against him hooking up with. Oh yes, about the son, aged eight going on eighteen, going out with a fellow eight-year-old girl, quoting from Beatles' songs, having adult conversations with his dad and flying to New York on his own. As he would! Of course his toothy grin and mop of hair sweep aside any charges of embarrassing cringeworthiness, or at least that's what the director would have you think. I found the writing clich&eacute;d and gauche (a woman character cries when recounting the story of the "An Affair To Remember", Cary Grant / Deborah Kerr vehicle which informs much of the plot here; like when was the last time you cried explaining a movie plot),the thirty-something characters are cardboard-thin and irritating plus it seemed there had to be some old romantic song playing in the background of almost every scene. I couldn't get excited by the acting either, there being no chance for Hanks and Ryan to gell as they don't actually meet until their anti-climactic meeting atop the Empire State Building. Bill Paxton gets underused as Ryan's hypochondriac fianc&eacute; while Rosie O'Donnell irritates as her overly understanding boss. I have to admit I can't stand these male-female "buddy" relationships as demonstrated here by Hanks and Rob Reiner and Ryan and O'Donnell, they play out so artificially. Just about the only good for thing me about this film is that I'll probably seek out the earlier film, confident that it will eclipse this very slack and shallow 1980's production which it regrettably inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ultimate Chick Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emily B
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love love LOVE this movie! I have just seen it for about the tenth time and I always laugh, cry, and squeal at the romantic ending. The leads only had about 5 minutes total of screen time together, yet they have so much chemistry in the closing scene. Annie (Meg Ryan) is recently engaged to Walter (the spunky Bill Pullman, my crush from the nineties), and seems to be happy, until she hears 8-year-old Jonah on the radio. His mother died 18 months ago, and his Christmas wish is that his father will find a new wife so that he won't be so sad. His father Sam (Tom Hanks), then talks about how wonderful his wife was and how much he adored her. Something changes in Annie, and she realises there is something about this man that she has to learn more about. Many would call it stalking, others would call it romantic, but suddenly she is flying across the country for a glimpse of him. Out of all the women who wrote to his Dad, Jonah likes Annie's letter the best, and sets up a romantic first encounter on the top of the Empire State building. Awwwww!!! I think from the start everyone knew how it would end, but it's wonderful to watch. Every single actor is outstanding, especially the young boy who played Jonah, many movies have been ruined by horrible children who cannot act, but he's great, and doesn't try to be too cute. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Chicks' Movie Indeed: Superstitious & Maudlin, But Also Witty, Pleasant & Ultimately Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    faterson (faterson@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's difficult to enjoy a movie that you feel is built on a premise that is fundamentally false. I was, therefore, only able to enjoy _Sleepless in Seattle_ while gnashing my teeth quite frequently. _Sleepless in Seattle_ is about as subtle as a sledgehammer in driving home its message: that there exist phenomena such as "soul mate", "being destined for each other", "true love at first sight", etc. Its conception of "love" is extremely old-fashioned; it's supposed to be that thing where "one meets one", and "you are my everything", "you're the world to me". It's strange, but somehow you instantly feel that _Sleepless in Seattle_ is an irreligious movie; it's not that it would be *against religion*, but you get the definite feeling right from the start that "love" in its religious dimension is and will remain conspicuously absent from the movie. This is all the more remarkable in that _Sleepless in Seattle_ glorifies and uses motives from the 1957 Cary Grant & Deborah Kerr hit, _An Affair to Remember_ -- a romantic comedy as well, but where religion and religious feelings are as obviously present as they are non-existent in _Sleepless in Seattle_. I believe in none of those things such as "destiny", "soul mates", "being made for one another", "you're the only one", etc. And I'm sorry, but as the movie kept reiterating these motives ad nauseam (especially in many of the intentionally old-fashioned songs -- both original and "fake" new ones written in the old vein, frequently featuring awful, annoyingly maudlin lyrics -- that we get to listen to throughout the movie, from the opening to the closing credits), I just *had* to say to myself: "All this 'destingy stuff' is something typically enjoyed and believed by women." There's nothing wrong with a movie or book that makes it obvious that its author is a woman; however, this seemed to be *too* obvious in _Sleepless in Seattle_, detracting from the overall enjoyment. I was saying to myself, "This is a chicks' movie," long before Tom Hanks said the same thing about _An Affair to Remember_; but it's a verdict that is even more apropos in relation to _Sleepless in Seattle_. Speaking of the comparison to _An Affair to Remember_, it's weird that _Sleepless in Seattle_ seems more archaic than the movie that preceded it by almost 3 decades. Both movies feature wildly improbable, unrealistic story-lines; yet when you come to think of it, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr might meet on a luxury ship in 2012 just as they did back in 1957; it would no longer be a transatlantic voyage today, but a pleasurable cruise. Could, however, Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan interact, today, in the same way as shown in _Sleepless in Seattle_? Nope. This movie fairly screams at you: "Where's the Internet? Where are the mobile phones, emails, and social networks?" Only a few years later, and the movie's plot would be rendered unusable. Even as it is, great effort is required to suspend your disbelief; while _An Affair to Remember_ is unrealistic, _Sleepless in Seattle_ is doubly so. Or can anyone honestly believe that a loving father would not have alerted the police immediately upon learning that his 8-year-old son eloped on a transcontinental flight to New York unsupervised? Despite all these shortcomings, _Sleepless in Seattle_ manages to be enjoyable throughout, and unlike _An Affair to Remember_, I believe this movie gets better and better with every passing minute. I found the ending of _An Affair to Remember_ rather a let-down, but not here; I thought the Empire State Building finale of _Sleepless in Seattle_ was very nicely constructed, and genuinely moving. I'd say the main credit for the movie's success should go to the two leading stars. Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan both give brilliant, flawless performances. They seem thoroughly believable as persons or personalities, even while their actions do not. The two child actors, Ross Malinger and Gaby Hoffmann, are terrific as well. Rosie O'Donnell makes her presence felt forcefully in a supporting role; her delivery of several of the movie's wittiest lines, no matter how brief, is pitch-perfect. Victor Garber and Rob Reiner only get a few minutes of screen time, but they certainly make the most of them to shine and to delight the audience. (I thought I only noticed a single false note about the actors' performances. In a weird departure from their realistic mode of delivery throughout the movie, in a discussion at Sam's kitchen table, both Tom Hanks and Victor Garber get tearful while talking about the movie _The Dirty Dozen_. I thought the scene rang very false; it was as if a minute or two from your regular TV sitcom was suddenly inserted into _Sleepless in Seattle_; the only thing missing was canned laughter; I found the moment painful to watch, and not funny at all; fortunately, it only lasted a minute or so; and Rita Wilson did not join in the two actors' shenanigans, but rather rescued the scene thanks to remaining who she was supposed to be in the movie. I thought Hanks & Garber did not perform well in that particular brief and untypical moment, but it would be hard to blame them for it; rather, I'd say it was a mistake on the part of the screenwriter/director to include a heterogeneous moment like that in the script.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sleepless in Philidelphia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so a few months back I was hanging out in my bedroom surfing my Netflix app on my Wii, I was waiting for this show to come on and I had an hour to kill, so I see Sleepless in Seatle in the romance section listed. I usually don't watch romances, but with Tom Hanks in it I made an exception. I LOVED THIS MOVIE! The movie is about recently widower Sam and his son Jonha. Sam is extremely down because of his wife's demise, and his son fells horrible for him. Christmas Eve comes and Sam, is still down. So Jonha decides to call one of those call-in-radio shows to help his dad out. Meanwhile, Annie Reed is driving on a highway listening to show, when Sam begins to tell his story Annie starts crying historically and instantly falls in love with him. The whole movie shows both of them on their own quest, Sam to find a new soul-mate, and Annie to find Sam. This is one of those movie anyone can watch and automatically fall in love with! With movies like these you will always know there is someone for everyone, and the worst of things can be for the better! I give this movie a 10 for its excellence in story, character development, and dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Magic " or Mayhem ??
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alxx0209
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a Tom Hanks movie ? I am a huge Hanks fan he has such a passion and commitment to every single movie he does. I have loved all of his movies that i have seen him in so far. and do I like him in this film? Well I suppose - This movie is about love and all its complications dealing with Sam / Annie and Jonah. The Three of them are trying to find " magic " in a relationship - I personally have not yet felt "magic" in a relationship - I have not even dated at all so I do not relate to " magic " but I can somehow imagine the delightful feeling in ones heart when you see the difference in Annie as the movie goes on and she learns what magic feels like. The movie seemed just a little slow in the beginning in my opinion but after a bit it has a certain pace to it that is enjoying. The movie reminds me of a few other films yet Hanks and Ryan are charming and The Kid also helps out the movie go forward / I also believe that Hanks other films success kind of help / Hurt this one in away - I mean Im not comparing it to his other roles but this one seems specifically about love - and I would say its like 70 % romantic and 30 % comedy but again I liked the movie for what it set up and Tom / Meg and the kid did a good job in this film - also a little note I feel that Rob Reiner and Rosie O' Donnell were just alright in there supporting roles but in my opinion they would be under minor roles for this movie. I have to mention a scene that I liked was Annie watching Sam and Jonah goofing around on the beach - thats were it seemed to click for Annie to realize she was in love with both them from just watching them goof around - being themselves , I believe from then on she felt deep down " magic" for Sam and even in away Jonah. That moment was something I would call a " spark " were it just was beautiful for what it was. That moment you could tell what her heart said to her. Final thoughts ? well Toms Hanks did an amazing job plays such likable and relatable characters ( including this one ) Meg did a decent job -Pullman who played Walter did alright the role kinda fell short - Like your about to marry her and you let her walk away ? He could have developed more. Also i would say like 2 or 3 slow bits that could have been tweaked. Other then that its a cute movie about love and Magic. Its worth watching once in your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hanks and Ryan Should Make More Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan should make more movies. As really this is one of a kind and sweet movie. Hanks character Sam loses his wife to cancer and his son Josh, wants Sam to be happy despite not wanting to ever date again. That is why they move from Chicago to Seattle to escape the sadness. But via a radio talk show station. Josh talks to the host as the USA in particular the women fall in love with Sam and his story despite never seeing him or knowing him that well. This also really strikes a nerve in Baltimore radio newspaper writer, Annie played by Ryan. As she wants to get to know this Sam despite being engaged to a straight laced Bill Pullman. A sweet and kind movie. As makes you want to really wished that both Hanks and Ryan made more movies. As Ryan has felled out with the public lately. But still a really sweet movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once more up the ESB
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-3758
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie again for the umpteenth time. I know going in that it blatantly plays on the emotions ... yet I still do it. It is perhaps one of the best feelgood movies out there. It's a believable story and it's wonderfully acted by all concerned. As a small footnote, might I highlight the tiny sequence when Jonah picks up a cab on arriving in NY. One of the two guys hailing cabs has just one line ... and it's fabulous: To the cab driver "Why don'tcha get further from the kerb next time buddy?!" It's such a small piece of dialogue, I think I missed it the first few times I watched the movie, but it's amazing how such a small thing never fails to make me cry ... with laughter. As against the blubbing I do through the rest of the movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No, just , no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wretched film is about Annie Reed (Meg Ryan) a Baltimore journalist who falls in love with Sam(Tom Hanks) when, at his son Jonah's(Ross Malinger)insistence he talks about his marriage to his late wife Maggie on a radio call-in talk show. Apparently she's one of many women who fell in love with Sam based on this lone qualification. Annie already had a fianc&eacute;e Walter(Bill Pullman) who seems like a really nice guy. Unfortunately for Walter, he doesn't meet Annie's dream romance so he has to go. The meeting is spurred on by the adolescent Jonah, who travels cross-country with his father in pursuit. Of course Sam and Annie fall in love and of course they live happily after after. Here are my problems with the film. First of all, Annie decides to dump a perfectly nice man based on a a stranger's telephone call. That is weird and disturbing. Of course, Sam here is a perfectly nice guy, but he could just as easily been the next Jeffery Dahmer. Next is her treatment of Walter who seems devoted to her, in response to his devotion she breaks up with him, on Valentine's Day of all days, to hook up with a guy she's never met or indeed seen. There is the behavior of the son Jonah who is able to get cross-country tickets without his father's permission and have his dad meet up with Annie. It is presumed that Sam and Annie will live happily ever after, but if Annie can dump a longtime beau like Walter over a phone call on a radio show, than who knows how long her relationship with Sam will last.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such wonderful comedy/romance movies are rare anymore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very entertaining movie is a present-day rarity, for seldom if ever do you find movies concerning a story where a strong void is filled in a person's life, and concomitantly you don't find far-fetched ways to do it. First of all, Sam Baldwin has just lost his wife in Chicago, and the depressed man wants to get away from it all and move to Seattle where he is definitely sleepless because of his recent loss, naturally. At the same time, his eight-year-old son Jonah wants a new mother. Meanwhile, in Baltimore the very attractive Annie Reed, after a dinner at her parent's home where she introduces her future husband to her family, is driving away when she listens to a talk-show hosted by Dr. Marcia Fieldstone who talks to Sam, whom she calls "Sleepless in Seattle". While listening to his voice Annie suddenly becomes taken with him, and then pursues him, thanks very much to the Internet. This is when the "fun" begins. She "seeks advice" from the classic Cary Grant-Deborah Kerr movie "An Affair to Remember", which she watches on t.v. very often. The story does have a warm and happy ending. The story has different settings-Chicago, New York, Baltimore, as well as Seattle. The very versatile Tom Hanks does his turn well, and the unusually appealing Meg Ryan captivated my attention in her role as Annie Reed. Ross Mallinger does acting well for a very young boy. Rosie O'Donnell is her nutty self as Annie's very close friend. Nora Ephron did a good job of writing and directing. Again, I wish they would make comedy/romances like this more often.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" comes very close to being the ideal contemporary American love story, and even with my reservations about some of the things in the film, I still feel it's a very good one. It's an unpretentious little jewel that demonstrates the true values of screen writing and acting, as both are used here shamelessly and with natural grace to manipulate the emotions of the audience. I admit the story is a bit absurd, but it's also somewhat the idea. And besides, in this age where people travel hundreds of miles to meet folks they've chatted with on the internet, is it so hard to believe that a woman would cross the entire country to learn about a widower whose voice she heard on the radio? Well, the Casanova in me would like to think it's not. The plot, though predictable, makes some daring twists. In most romantic comedies, the couple eyes each other from very early on. And although Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan do make an attractive movie-couple, they don't share even have a two-shot until the last ten minutes. For most of the movie, Mr. Hanks does not even know that Miss Ryan even exists, let alone that they are destined to be in love. It's not that he ignores her; it's because she spends most of the movie on the opposite side of the country from him. She hears him on the radio, speaking of his recently departed wife, is fascinated by what he has to say, and feels something that is best described, as the movie acknowledges, as "magic." I could use more derisory words toward somebody who would feel this way in real life about a voice, but that's good enough. The screenplay (written by director Nora Ephron and two menJeff Arch and David S. Ward) is also a bit insightful on, again, an unpretentious level. It does not delve deep into the psychological state we like to call love and affection, but it does make some interesting observations. First of all, Miss Ryan's character does acknowledge time and time again how absurd it is of her to fly from New York to Seattle to learn about a man she's only heard. There are also numerous touches upon how Hollywood's perception of sex and romance befalls some people. The key moment is when Rosie O'Donnell, as Miss Ryan's best friend, tells her flat out while watching "An Affair to Remember" that what she wants is not to be in love, but "to be in love in a movie." After all, how many of ussingle and once-singlehave not looked at movies like "Casablanca," "An Affair to Remember," "At First Sight," and such and not fantasized about passion that only seems to exist when an actor and actress play make-believe before a camera? Speaking of other films: that is another thing I adored about "Sleepless in Seattle." It has an uncanny ability to recall other films to effectsometimes comedic, sometimes insightful. A favorite moment of mine is when Mr. Hanks explains to his eight-year-old son (extremely well-acted by Ross Malinger) why he is uncomfortable about rushing into a new relationship so soon: he asks him if he ever saw "Fatal Attraction." The biggest homage(s), though, goes back to "An Affair to Remember." That wonderful 1957 film is shown on television screens numerous times throughout the movie, and at key points, Hugo Friedhofer's score even plays on the soundtrack. Being an obvious admirer of the said film, I found the references quite delightful and charming. If there is one thing I couldn't stand about "Sleepless in Seattle," I would have had to have been the constant usage of classic songs to carry along sequences. The opening credits display while a very jazzy version of "As Time Goes By" thumps in the background, but numbers such as "Stand By Your Man," "Stardust," and others are ever-present, reducing fine scenes into what appear to be limp music videos. There is a potentially great momentreduced to a merely good onewhere Miss Ryan, having traveled to Seattle, watches Mr. Hanks and his son as they play on the beach. It's a very good scene (Miss Ryan is kept at medium shots, Mr. Hanks and Mr. Malinger at distance, the montage is very nice) but the song playing in the background trivializes it. The film's musical score by Marc Shaiman is just fine, and I would have preferred to hear his piano motifs instead of a song. Only the movies can convince that two people could fall into deep, passionate love upon first sight. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the defining examples of that theory. After all, if Mr. Hanks and Miss Ryan could have such strong chemistry when they are not even sharing the same frame, one can only imagine what would lay down the road for their characters (and how moved we would be). But what is best about this movieapart from the fabulous writing and actingis its unostentatious manner. It does not make itself out to be any big deal, and just lets the romantic chemistry emerge on its admittedly old-fashioned terms. And I was more interested in the relationship between these people who have never met as opposed to most formula-films where the cute-boy meets cute-girl, they ogle for an hour, hate one another for twenty minutes, and reconcile at the end. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An affair to forget
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, today was a bank holiday and it was pouring rain outside so my wife and I thought we'd watch a family-oriented romantic-comedy, giving "Sleepless In Seattle" the nod. It's fair to say my wife liked it more than I did. For me it wasn't really very funny and worse, was guilty of over-sentimentality and coincidence. Nothing against Meg Ryan, but she hasn't got the kind of face that would stop you in your tracks the way she does at the airport with Tom Hanks' character's first view of her. Moreover her ditzy character doesn't seem too different (sans hysterical laugh) from the girl his son is so against him hooking up with. Oh yes, about the son, aged eight going on eighteen, going out with a fellow eight-year-old girl, quoting from Beatles' songs, having adult conversations with his dad and flying to New York on his own. As he would! Of course his toothy grin and mop of hair sweep aside any charges of embarrassing cringeworthiness, or at least that's what the director would have you think. I found the writing clich&eacute;d and gauche (a woman character cries when recounting the story of the "An Affair To Remember", Cary Grant / Deborah Kerr vehicle which informs much of the plot here; like when was the last time you cried explaining a movie plot),the thirty-something characters are cardboard-thin and irritating plus it seemed there had to be some old romantic song playing in the background of almost every scene. I couldn't get excited by the acting either, there being no chance for Hanks and Ryan to gell as they don't actually meet until their anti-climactic meeting atop the Empire State Building. Bill Paxton gets underused as Ryan's hypochondriac fianc&eacute; while Rosie O'Donnell irritates as her overly understanding boss. I have to admit I can't stand these male-female "buddy" relationships as demonstrated here by Hanks and Rob Reiner and Ryan and O'Donnell, they play out so artificially. Just about the only good for thing me about this film is that I'll probably seek out the earlier film, confident that it will eclipse this very slack and shallow 1980's production which it regrettably inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ultimate Chick Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emily B
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love love LOVE this movie! I have just seen it for about the tenth time and I always laugh, cry, and squeal at the romantic ending. The leads only had about 5 minutes total of screen time together, yet they have so much chemistry in the closing scene. Annie (Meg Ryan) is recently engaged to Walter (the spunky Bill Pullman, my crush from the nineties), and seems to be happy, until she hears 8-year-old Jonah on the radio. His mother died 18 months ago, and his Christmas wish is that his father will find a new wife so that he won't be so sad. His father Sam (Tom Hanks), then talks about how wonderful his wife was and how much he adored her. Something changes in Annie, and she realises there is something about this man that she has to learn more about. Many would call it stalking, others would call it romantic, but suddenly she is flying across the country for a glimpse of him. Out of all the women who wrote to his Dad, Jonah likes Annie's letter the best, and sets up a romantic first encounter on the top of the Empire State building. Awwwww!!! I think from the start everyone knew how it would end, but it's wonderful to watch. Every single actor is outstanding, especially the young boy who played Jonah, many movies have been ruined by horrible children who cannot act, but he's great, and doesn't try to be too cute. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Chicks' Movie Indeed: Superstitious & Maudlin, But Also Witty, Pleasant & Ultimately Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    faterson (faterson@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's difficult to enjoy a movie that you feel is built on a premise that is fundamentally false. I was, therefore, only able to enjoy _Sleepless in Seattle_ while gnashing my teeth quite frequently. _Sleepless in Seattle_ is about as subtle as a sledgehammer in driving home its message: that there exist phenomena such as "soul mate", "being destined for each other", "true love at first sight", etc. Its conception of "love" is extremely old-fashioned; it's supposed to be that thing where "one meets one", and "you are my everything", "you're the world to me". It's strange, but somehow you instantly feel that _Sleepless in Seattle_ is an irreligious movie; it's not that it would be *against religion*, but you get the definite feeling right from the start that "love" in its religious dimension is and will remain conspicuously absent from the movie. This is all the more remarkable in that _Sleepless in Seattle_ glorifies and uses motives from the 1957 Cary Grant & Deborah Kerr hit, _An Affair to Remember_ -- a romantic comedy as well, but where religion and religious feelings are as obviously present as they are non-existent in _Sleepless in Seattle_. I believe in none of those things such as "destiny", "soul mates", "being made for one another", "you're the only one", etc. And I'm sorry, but as the movie kept reiterating these motives ad nauseam (especially in many of the intentionally old-fashioned songs -- both original and "fake" new ones written in the old vein, frequently featuring awful, annoyingly maudlin lyrics -- that we get to listen to throughout the movie, from the opening to the closing credits), I just *had* to say to myself: "All this 'destingy stuff' is something typically enjoyed and believed by women." There's nothing wrong with a movie or book that makes it obvious that its author is a woman; however, this seemed to be *too* obvious in _Sleepless in Seattle_, detracting from the overall enjoyment. I was saying to myself, "This is a chicks' movie," long before Tom Hanks said the same thing about _An Affair to Remember_; but it's a verdict that is even more apropos in relation to _Sleepless in Seattle_. Speaking of the comparison to _An Affair to Remember_, it's weird that _Sleepless in Seattle_ seems more archaic than the movie that preceded it by almost 3 decades. Both movies feature wildly improbable, unrealistic story-lines; yet when you come to think of it, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr might meet on a luxury ship in 2012 just as they did back in 1957; it would no longer be a transatlantic voyage today, but a pleasurable cruise. Could, however, Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan interact, today, in the same way as shown in _Sleepless in Seattle_? Nope. This movie fairly screams at you: "Where's the Internet? Where are the mobile phones, emails, and social networks?" Only a few years later, and the movie's plot would be rendered unusable. Even as it is, great effort is required to suspend your disbelief; while _An Affair to Remember_ is unrealistic, _Sleepless in Seattle_ is doubly so. Or can anyone honestly believe that a loving father would not have alerted the police immediately upon learning that his 8-year-old son eloped on a transcontinental flight to New York unsupervised? Despite all these shortcomings, _Sleepless in Seattle_ manages to be enjoyable throughout, and unlike _An Affair to Remember_, I believe this movie gets better and better with every passing minute. I found the ending of _An Affair to Remember_ rather a let-down, but not here; I thought the Empire State Building finale of _Sleepless in Seattle_ was very nicely constructed, and genuinely moving. I'd say the main credit for the movie's success should go to the two leading stars. Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan both give brilliant, flawless performances. They seem thoroughly believable as persons or personalities, even while their actions do not. The two child actors, Ross Malinger and Gaby Hoffmann, are terrific as well. Rosie O'Donnell makes her presence felt forcefully in a supporting role; her delivery of several of the movie's wittiest lines, no matter how brief, is pitch-perfect. Victor Garber and Rob Reiner only get a few minutes of screen time, but they certainly make the most of them to shine and to delight the audience. (I thought I only noticed a single false note about the actors' performances. In a weird departure from their realistic mode of delivery throughout the movie, in a discussion at Sam's kitchen table, both Tom Hanks and Victor Garber get tearful while talking about the movie _The Dirty Dozen_. I thought the scene rang very false; it was as if a minute or two from your regular TV sitcom was suddenly inserted into _Sleepless in Seattle_; the only thing missing was canned laughter; I found the moment painful to watch, and not funny at all; fortunately, it only lasted a minute or so; and Rita Wilson did not join in the two actors' shenanigans, but rather rescued the scene thanks to remaining who she was supposed to be in the movie. I thought Hanks & Garber did not perform well in that particular brief and untypical moment, but it would be hard to blame them for it; rather, I'd say it was a mistake on the part of the screenwriter/director to include a heterogeneous moment like that in the script.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sleepless in Philidelphia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so a few months back I was hanging out in my bedroom surfing my Netflix app on my Wii, I was waiting for this show to come on and I had an hour to kill, so I see Sleepless in Seatle in the romance section listed. I usually don't watch romances, but with Tom Hanks in it I made an exception. I LOVED THIS MOVIE! The movie is about recently widower Sam and his son Jonha. Sam is extremely down because of his wife's demise, and his son fells horrible for him. Christmas Eve comes and Sam, is still down. So Jonha decides to call one of those call-in-radio shows to help his dad out. Meanwhile, Annie Reed is driving on a highway listening to show, when Sam begins to tell his story Annie starts crying historically and instantly falls in love with him. The whole movie shows both of them on their own quest, Sam to find a new soul-mate, and Annie to find Sam. This is one of those movie anyone can watch and automatically fall in love with! With movies like these you will always know there is someone for everyone, and the worst of things can be for the better! I give this movie a 10 for its excellence in story, character development, and dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Magic " or Mayhem ??
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alxx0209
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a Tom Hanks movie ? I am a huge Hanks fan he has such a passion and commitment to every single movie he does. I have loved all of his movies that i have seen him in so far. and do I like him in this film? Well I suppose - This movie is about love and all its complications dealing with Sam / Annie and Jonah. The Three of them are trying to find " magic " in a relationship - I personally have not yet felt "magic" in a relationship - I have not even dated at all so I do not relate to " magic " but I can somehow imagine the delightful feeling in ones heart when you see the difference in Annie as the movie goes on and she learns what magic feels like. The movie seemed just a little slow in the beginning in my opinion but after a bit it has a certain pace to it that is enjoying. The movie reminds me of a few other films yet Hanks and Ryan are charming and The Kid also helps out the movie go forward / I also believe that Hanks other films success kind of help / Hurt this one in away - I mean Im not comparing it to his other roles but this one seems specifically about love - and I would say its like 70 % romantic and 30 % comedy but again I liked the movie for what it set up and Tom / Meg and the kid did a good job in this film - also a little note I feel that Rob Reiner and Rosie O' Donnell were just alright in there supporting roles but in my opinion they would be under minor roles for this movie. I have to mention a scene that I liked was Annie watching Sam and Jonah goofing around on the beach - thats were it seemed to click for Annie to realize she was in love with both them from just watching them goof around - being themselves , I believe from then on she felt deep down " magic" for Sam and even in away Jonah. That moment was something I would call a " spark " were it just was beautiful for what it was. That moment you could tell what her heart said to her. Final thoughts ? well Toms Hanks did an amazing job plays such likable and relatable characters ( including this one ) Meg did a decent job -Pullman who played Walter did alright the role kinda fell short - Like your about to marry her and you let her walk away ? He could have developed more. Also i would say like 2 or 3 slow bits that could have been tweaked. Other then that its a cute movie about love and Magic. Its worth watching once in your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hanks and Ryan Should Make More Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan should make more movies. As really this is one of a kind and sweet movie. Hanks character Sam loses his wife to cancer and his son Josh, wants Sam to be happy despite not wanting to ever date again. That is why they move from Chicago to Seattle to escape the sadness. But via a radio talk show station. Josh talks to the host as the USA in particular the women fall in love with Sam and his story despite never seeing him or knowing him that well. This also really strikes a nerve in Baltimore radio newspaper writer, Annie played by Ryan. As she wants to get to know this Sam despite being engaged to a straight laced Bill Pullman. A sweet and kind movie. As makes you want to really wished that both Hanks and Ryan made more movies. As Ryan has felled out with the public lately. But still a really sweet movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once more up the ESB
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-3758
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie again for the umpteenth time. I know going in that it blatantly plays on the emotions ... yet I still do it. It is perhaps one of the best feelgood movies out there. It's a believable story and it's wonderfully acted by all concerned. As a small footnote, might I highlight the tiny sequence when Jonah picks up a cab on arriving in NY. One of the two guys hailing cabs has just one line ... and it's fabulous: To the cab driver "Why don'tcha get further from the kerb next time buddy?!" It's such a small piece of dialogue, I think I missed it the first few times I watched the movie, but it's amazing how such a small thing never fails to make me cry ... with laughter. As against the blubbing I do through the rest of the movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No, just , no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wretched film is about Annie Reed (Meg Ryan) a Baltimore journalist who falls in love with Sam(Tom Hanks) when, at his son Jonah's(Ross Malinger)insistence he talks about his marriage to his late wife Maggie on a radio call-in talk show. Apparently she's one of many women who fell in love with Sam based on this lone qualification. Annie already had a fianc&eacute;e Walter(Bill Pullman) who seems like a really nice guy. Unfortunately for Walter, he doesn't meet Annie's dream romance so he has to go. The meeting is spurred on by the adolescent Jonah, who travels cross-country with his father in pursuit. Of course Sam and Annie fall in love and of course they live happily after after. Here are my problems with the film. First of all, Annie decides to dump a perfectly nice man based on a a stranger's telephone call. That is weird and disturbing. Of course, Sam here is a perfectly nice guy, but he could just as easily been the next Jeffery Dahmer. Next is her treatment of Walter who seems devoted to her, in response to his devotion she breaks up with him, on Valentine's Day of all days, to hook up with a guy she's never met or indeed seen. There is the behavior of the son Jonah who is able to get cross-country tickets without his father's permission and have his dad meet up with Annie. It is presumed that Sam and Annie will live happily ever after, but if Annie can dump a longtime beau like Walter over a phone call on a radio show, than who knows how long her relationship with Sam will last.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such wonderful comedy/romance movies are rare anymore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very entertaining movie is a present-day rarity, for seldom if ever do you find movies concerning a story where a strong void is filled in a person's life, and concomitantly you don't find far-fetched ways to do it. First of all, Sam Baldwin has just lost his wife in Chicago, and the depressed man wants to get away from it all and move to Seattle where he is definitely sleepless because of his recent loss, naturally. At the same time, his eight-year-old son Jonah wants a new mother. Meanwhile, in Baltimore the very attractive Annie Reed, after a dinner at her parent's home where she introduces her future husband to her family, is driving away when she listens to a talk-show hosted by Dr. Marcia Fieldstone who talks to Sam, whom she calls "Sleepless in Seattle". While listening to his voice Annie suddenly becomes taken with him, and then pursues him, thanks very much to the Internet. This is when the "fun" begins. She "seeks advice" from the classic Cary Grant-Deborah Kerr movie "An Affair to Remember", which she watches on t.v. very often. The story does have a warm and happy ending. The story has different settings-Chicago, New York, Baltimore, as well as Seattle. The very versatile Tom Hanks does his turn well, and the unusually appealing Meg Ryan captivated my attention in her role as Annie Reed. Ross Mallinger does acting well for a very young boy. Rosie O'Donnell is her nutty self as Annie's very close friend. Nora Ephron did a good job of writing and directing. Again, I wish they would make comedy/romances like this more often.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" comes very close to being the ideal contemporary American love story, and even with my reservations about some of the things in the film, I still feel it's a very good one. It's an unpretentious little jewel that demonstrates the true values of screen writing and acting, as both are used here shamelessly and with natural grace to manipulate the emotions of the audience. I admit the story is a bit absurd, but it's also somewhat the idea. And besides, in this age where people travel hundreds of miles to meet folks they've chatted with on the internet, is it so hard to believe that a woman would cross the entire country to learn about a widower whose voice she heard on the radio? Well, the Casanova in me would like to think it's not. The plot, though predictable, makes some daring twists. In most romantic comedies, the couple eyes each other from very early on. And although Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan do make an attractive movie-couple, they don't share even have a two-shot until the last ten minutes. For most of the movie, Mr. Hanks does not even know that Miss Ryan even exists, let alone that they are destined to be in love. It's not that he ignores her; it's because she spends most of the movie on the opposite side of the country from him. She hears him on the radio, speaking of his recently departed wife, is fascinated by what he has to say, and feels something that is best described, as the movie acknowledges, as "magic." I could use more derisory words toward somebody who would feel this way in real life about a voice, but that's good enough. The screenplay (written by director Nora Ephron and two menJeff Arch and David S. Ward) is also a bit insightful on, again, an unpretentious level. It does not delve deep into the psychological state we like to call love and affection, but it does make some interesting observations. First of all, Miss Ryan's character does acknowledge time and time again how absurd it is of her to fly from New York to Seattle to learn about a man she's only heard. There are also numerous touches upon how Hollywood's perception of sex and romance befalls some people. The key moment is when Rosie O'Donnell, as Miss Ryan's best friend, tells her flat out while watching "An Affair to Remember" that what she wants is not to be in love, but "to be in love in a movie." After all, how many of ussingle and once-singlehave not looked at movies like "Casablanca," "An Affair to Remember," "At First Sight," and such and not fantasized about passion that only seems to exist when an actor and actress play make-believe before a camera? Speaking of other films: that is another thing I adored about "Sleepless in Seattle." It has an uncanny ability to recall other films to effectsometimes comedic, sometimes insightful. A favorite moment of mine is when Mr. Hanks explains to his eight-year-old son (extremely well-acted by Ross Malinger) why he is uncomfortable about rushing into a new relationship so soon: he asks him if he ever saw "Fatal Attraction." The biggest homage(s), though, goes back to "An Affair to Remember." That wonderful 1957 film is shown on television screens numerous times throughout the movie, and at key points, Hugo Friedhofer's score even plays on the soundtrack. Being an obvious admirer of the said film, I found the references quite delightful and charming. If there is one thing I couldn't stand about "Sleepless in Seattle," I would have had to have been the constant usage of classic songs to carry along sequences. The opening credits display while a very jazzy version of "As Time Goes By" thumps in the background, but numbers such as "Stand By Your Man," "Stardust," and others are ever-present, reducing fine scenes into what appear to be limp music videos. There is a potentially great momentreduced to a merely good onewhere Miss Ryan, having traveled to Seattle, watches Mr. Hanks and his son as they play on the beach. It's a very good scene (Miss Ryan is kept at medium shots, Mr. Hanks and Mr. Malinger at distance, the montage is very nice) but the song playing in the background trivializes it. The film's musical score by Marc Shaiman is just fine, and I would have preferred to hear his piano motifs instead of a song. Only the movies can convince that two people could fall into deep, passionate love upon first sight. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the defining examples of that theory. After all, if Mr. Hanks and Miss Ryan could have such strong chemistry when they are not even sharing the same frame, one can only imagine what would lay down the road for their characters (and how moved we would be). But what is best about this movieapart from the fabulous writing and actingis its unostentatious manner. It does not make itself out to be any big deal, and just lets the romantic chemistry emerge on its admittedly old-fashioned terms. And I was more interested in the relationship between these people who have never met as opposed to most formula-films where the cute-boy meets cute-girl, they ogle for an hour, hate one another for twenty minutes, and reconcile at the end. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An affair to forget
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, today was a bank holiday and it was pouring rain outside so my wife and I thought we'd watch a family-oriented romantic-comedy, giving "Sleepless In Seattle" the nod. It's fair to say my wife liked it more than I did. For me it wasn't really very funny and worse, was guilty of over-sentimentality and coincidence. Nothing against Meg Ryan, but she hasn't got the kind of face that would stop you in your tracks the way she does at the airport with Tom Hanks' character's first view of her. Moreover her ditzy character doesn't seem too different (sans hysterical laugh) from the girl his son is so against him hooking up with. Oh yes, about the son, aged eight going on eighteen, going out with a fellow eight-year-old girl, quoting from Beatles' songs, having adult conversations with his dad and flying to New York on his own. As he would! Of course his toothy grin and mop of hair sweep aside any charges of embarrassing cringeworthiness, or at least that's what the director would have you think. I found the writing clich&eacute;d and gauche (a woman character cries when recounting the story of the "An Affair To Remember", Cary Grant / Deborah Kerr vehicle which informs much of the plot here; like when was the last time you cried explaining a movie plot),the thirty-something characters are cardboard-thin and irritating plus it seemed there had to be some old romantic song playing in the background of almost every scene. I couldn't get excited by the acting either, there being no chance for Hanks and Ryan to gell as they don't actually meet until their anti-climactic meeting atop the Empire State Building. Bill Paxton gets underused as Ryan's hypochondriac fianc&eacute; while Rosie O'Donnell irritates as her overly understanding boss. I have to admit I can't stand these male-female "buddy" relationships as demonstrated here by Hanks and Rob Reiner and Ryan and O'Donnell, they play out so artificially. Just about the only good for thing me about this film is that I'll probably seek out the earlier film, confident that it will eclipse this very slack and shallow 1980's production which it regrettably inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ultimate Chick Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emily B
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love love LOVE this movie! I have just seen it for about the tenth time and I always laugh, cry, and squeal at the romantic ending. The leads only had about 5 minutes total of screen time together, yet they have so much chemistry in the closing scene. Annie (Meg Ryan) is recently engaged to Walter (the spunky Bill Pullman, my crush from the nineties), and seems to be happy, until she hears 8-year-old Jonah on the radio. His mother died 18 months ago, and his Christmas wish is that his father will find a new wife so that he won't be so sad. His father Sam (Tom Hanks), then talks about how wonderful his wife was and how much he adored her. Something changes in Annie, and she realises there is something about this man that she has to learn more about. Many would call it stalking, others would call it romantic, but suddenly she is flying across the country for a glimpse of him. Out of all the women who wrote to his Dad, Jonah likes Annie's letter the best, and sets up a romantic first encounter on the top of the Empire State building. Awwwww!!! I think from the start everyone knew how it would end, but it's wonderful to watch. Every single actor is outstanding, especially the young boy who played Jonah, many movies have been ruined by horrible children who cannot act, but he's great, and doesn't try to be too cute. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Chicks' Movie Indeed: Superstitious & Maudlin, But Also Witty, Pleasant & Ultimately Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    faterson (faterson@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's difficult to enjoy a movie that you feel is built on a premise that is fundamentally false. I was, therefore, only able to enjoy _Sleepless in Seattle_ while gnashing my teeth quite frequently. _Sleepless in Seattle_ is about as subtle as a sledgehammer in driving home its message: that there exist phenomena such as "soul mate", "being destined for each other", "true love at first sight", etc. Its conception of "love" is extremely old-fashioned; it's supposed to be that thing where "one meets one", and "you are my everything", "you're the world to me". It's strange, but somehow you instantly feel that _Sleepless in Seattle_ is an irreligious movie; it's not that it would be *against religion*, but you get the definite feeling right from the start that "love" in its religious dimension is and will remain conspicuously absent from the movie. This is all the more remarkable in that _Sleepless in Seattle_ glorifies and uses motives from the 1957 Cary Grant & Deborah Kerr hit, _An Affair to Remember_ -- a romantic comedy as well, but where religion and religious feelings are as obviously present as they are non-existent in _Sleepless in Seattle_. I believe in none of those things such as "destiny", "soul mates", "being made for one another", "you're the only one", etc. And I'm sorry, but as the movie kept reiterating these motives ad nauseam (especially in many of the intentionally old-fashioned songs -- both original and "fake" new ones written in the old vein, frequently featuring awful, annoyingly maudlin lyrics -- that we get to listen to throughout the movie, from the opening to the closing credits), I just *had* to say to myself: "All this 'destingy stuff' is something typically enjoyed and believed by women." There's nothing wrong with a movie or book that makes it obvious that its author is a woman; however, this seemed to be *too* obvious in _Sleepless in Seattle_, detracting from the overall enjoyment. I was saying to myself, "This is a chicks' movie," long before Tom Hanks said the same thing about _An Affair to Remember_; but it's a verdict that is even more apropos in relation to _Sleepless in Seattle_. Speaking of the comparison to _An Affair to Remember_, it's weird that _Sleepless in Seattle_ seems more archaic than the movie that preceded it by almost 3 decades. Both movies feature wildly improbable, unrealistic story-lines; yet when you come to think of it, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr might meet on a luxury ship in 2012 just as they did back in 1957; it would no longer be a transatlantic voyage today, but a pleasurable cruise. Could, however, Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan interact, today, in the same way as shown in _Sleepless in Seattle_? Nope. This movie fairly screams at you: "Where's the Internet? Where are the mobile phones, emails, and social networks?" Only a few years later, and the movie's plot would be rendered unusable. Even as it is, great effort is required to suspend your disbelief; while _An Affair to Remember_ is unrealistic, _Sleepless in Seattle_ is doubly so. Or can anyone honestly believe that a loving father would not have alerted the police immediately upon learning that his 8-year-old son eloped on a transcontinental flight to New York unsupervised? Despite all these shortcomings, _Sleepless in Seattle_ manages to be enjoyable throughout, and unlike _An Affair to Remember_, I believe this movie gets better and better with every passing minute. I found the ending of _An Affair to Remember_ rather a let-down, but not here; I thought the Empire State Building finale of _Sleepless in Seattle_ was very nicely constructed, and genuinely moving. I'd say the main credit for the movie's success should go to the two leading stars. Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan both give brilliant, flawless performances. They seem thoroughly believable as persons or personalities, even while their actions do not. The two child actors, Ross Malinger and Gaby Hoffmann, are terrific as well. Rosie O'Donnell makes her presence felt forcefully in a supporting role; her delivery of several of the movie's wittiest lines, no matter how brief, is pitch-perfect. Victor Garber and Rob Reiner only get a few minutes of screen time, but they certainly make the most of them to shine and to delight the audience. (I thought I only noticed a single false note about the actors' performances. In a weird departure from their realistic mode of delivery throughout the movie, in a discussion at Sam's kitchen table, both Tom Hanks and Victor Garber get tearful while talking about the movie _The Dirty Dozen_. I thought the scene rang very false; it was as if a minute or two from your regular TV sitcom was suddenly inserted into _Sleepless in Seattle_; the only thing missing was canned laughter; I found the moment painful to watch, and not funny at all; fortunately, it only lasted a minute or so; and Rita Wilson did not join in the two actors' shenanigans, but rather rescued the scene thanks to remaining who she was supposed to be in the movie. I thought Hanks & Garber did not perform well in that particular brief and untypical moment, but it would be hard to blame them for it; rather, I'd say it was a mistake on the part of the screenwriter/director to include a heterogeneous moment like that in the script.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sleepless in Philidelphia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so a few months back I was hanging out in my bedroom surfing my Netflix app on my Wii, I was waiting for this show to come on and I had an hour to kill, so I see Sleepless in Seatle in the romance section listed. I usually don't watch romances, but with Tom Hanks in it I made an exception. I LOVED THIS MOVIE! The movie is about recently widower Sam and his son Jonha. Sam is extremely down because of his wife's demise, and his son fells horrible for him. Christmas Eve comes and Sam, is still down. So Jonha decides to call one of those call-in-radio shows to help his dad out. Meanwhile, Annie Reed is driving on a highway listening to show, when Sam begins to tell his story Annie starts crying historically and instantly falls in love with him. The whole movie shows both of them on their own quest, Sam to find a new soul-mate, and Annie to find Sam. This is one of those movie anyone can watch and automatically fall in love with! With movies like these you will always know there is someone for everyone, and the worst of things can be for the better! I give this movie a 10 for its excellence in story, character development, and dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Magic " or Mayhem ??
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alxx0209
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a Tom Hanks movie ? I am a huge Hanks fan he has such a passion and commitment to every single movie he does. I have loved all of his movies that i have seen him in so far. and do I like him in this film? Well I suppose - This movie is about love and all its complications dealing with Sam / Annie and Jonah. The Three of them are trying to find " magic " in a relationship - I personally have not yet felt "magic" in a relationship - I have not even dated at all so I do not relate to " magic " but I can somehow imagine the delightful feeling in ones heart when you see the difference in Annie as the movie goes on and she learns what magic feels like. The movie seemed just a little slow in the beginning in my opinion but after a bit it has a certain pace to it that is enjoying. The movie reminds me of a few other films yet Hanks and Ryan are charming and The Kid also helps out the movie go forward / I also believe that Hanks other films success kind of help / Hurt this one in away - I mean Im not comparing it to his other roles but this one seems specifically about love - and I would say its like 70 % romantic and 30 % comedy but again I liked the movie for what it set up and Tom / Meg and the kid did a good job in this film - also a little note I feel that Rob Reiner and Rosie O' Donnell were just alright in there supporting roles but in my opinion they would be under minor roles for this movie. I have to mention a scene that I liked was Annie watching Sam and Jonah goofing around on the beach - thats were it seemed to click for Annie to realize she was in love with both them from just watching them goof around - being themselves , I believe from then on she felt deep down " magic" for Sam and even in away Jonah. That moment was something I would call a " spark " were it just was beautiful for what it was. That moment you could tell what her heart said to her. Final thoughts ? well Toms Hanks did an amazing job plays such likable and relatable characters ( including this one ) Meg did a decent job -Pullman who played Walter did alright the role kinda fell short - Like your about to marry her and you let her walk away ? He could have developed more. Also i would say like 2 or 3 slow bits that could have been tweaked. Other then that its a cute movie about love and Magic. Its worth watching once in your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hanks and Ryan Should Make More Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan should make more movies. As really this is one of a kind and sweet movie. Hanks character Sam loses his wife to cancer and his son Josh, wants Sam to be happy despite not wanting to ever date again. That is why they move from Chicago to Seattle to escape the sadness. But via a radio talk show station. Josh talks to the host as the USA in particular the women fall in love with Sam and his story despite never seeing him or knowing him that well. This also really strikes a nerve in Baltimore radio newspaper writer, Annie played by Ryan. As she wants to get to know this Sam despite being engaged to a straight laced Bill Pullman. A sweet and kind movie. As makes you want to really wished that both Hanks and Ryan made more movies. As Ryan has felled out with the public lately. But still a really sweet movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once more up the ESB
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-3758
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie again for the umpteenth time. I know going in that it blatantly plays on the emotions ... yet I still do it. It is perhaps one of the best feelgood movies out there. It's a believable story and it's wonderfully acted by all concerned. As a small footnote, might I highlight the tiny sequence when Jonah picks up a cab on arriving in NY. One of the two guys hailing cabs has just one line ... and it's fabulous: To the cab driver "Why don'tcha get further from the kerb next time buddy?!" It's such a small piece of dialogue, I think I missed it the first few times I watched the movie, but it's amazing how such a small thing never fails to make me cry ... with laughter. As against the blubbing I do through the rest of the movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No, just , no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wretched film is about Annie Reed (Meg Ryan) a Baltimore journalist who falls in love with Sam(Tom Hanks) when, at his son Jonah's(Ross Malinger)insistence he talks about his marriage to his late wife Maggie on a radio call-in talk show. Apparently she's one of many women who fell in love with Sam based on this lone qualification. Annie already had a fianc&eacute;e Walter(Bill Pullman) who seems like a really nice guy. Unfortunately for Walter, he doesn't meet Annie's dream romance so he has to go. The meeting is spurred on by the adolescent Jonah, who travels cross-country with his father in pursuit. Of course Sam and Annie fall in love and of course they live happily after after. Here are my problems with the film. First of all, Annie decides to dump a perfectly nice man based on a a stranger's telephone call. That is weird and disturbing. Of course, Sam here is a perfectly nice guy, but he could just as easily been the next Jeffery Dahmer. Next is her treatment of Walter who seems devoted to her, in response to his devotion she breaks up with him, on Valentine's Day of all days, to hook up with a guy she's never met or indeed seen. There is the behavior of the son Jonah who is able to get cross-country tickets without his father's permission and have his dad meet up with Annie. It is presumed that Sam and Annie will live happily ever after, but if Annie can dump a longtime beau like Walter over a phone call on a radio show, than who knows how long her relationship with Sam will last.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such wonderful comedy/romance movies are rare anymore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very entertaining movie is a present-day rarity, for seldom if ever do you find movies concerning a story where a strong void is filled in a person's life, and concomitantly you don't find far-fetched ways to do it. First of all, Sam Baldwin has just lost his wife in Chicago, and the depressed man wants to get away from it all and move to Seattle where he is definitely sleepless because of his recent loss, naturally. At the same time, his eight-year-old son Jonah wants a new mother. Meanwhile, in Baltimore the very attractive Annie Reed, after a dinner at her parent's home where she introduces her future husband to her family, is driving away when she listens to a talk-show hosted by Dr. Marcia Fieldstone who talks to Sam, whom she calls "Sleepless in Seattle". While listening to his voice Annie suddenly becomes taken with him, and then pursues him, thanks very much to the Internet. This is when the "fun" begins. She "seeks advice" from the classic Cary Grant-Deborah Kerr movie "An Affair to Remember", which she watches on t.v. very often. The story does have a warm and happy ending. The story has different settings-Chicago, New York, Baltimore, as well as Seattle. The very versatile Tom Hanks does his turn well, and the unusually appealing Meg Ryan captivated my attention in her role as Annie Reed. Ross Mallinger does acting well for a very young boy. Rosie O'Donnell is her nutty self as Annie's very close friend. Nora Ephron did a good job of writing and directing. Again, I wish they would make comedy/romances like this more often.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" comes very close to being the ideal contemporary American love story, and even with my reservations about some of the things in the film, I still feel it's a very good one. It's an unpretentious little jewel that demonstrates the true values of screen writing and acting, as both are used here shamelessly and with natural grace to manipulate the emotions of the audience. I admit the story is a bit absurd, but it's also somewhat the idea. And besides, in this age where people travel hundreds of miles to meet folks they've chatted with on the internet, is it so hard to believe that a woman would cross the entire country to learn about a widower whose voice she heard on the radio? Well, the Casanova in me would like to think it's not. The plot, though predictable, makes some daring twists. In most romantic comedies, the couple eyes each other from very early on. And although Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan do make an attractive movie-couple, they don't share even have a two-shot until the last ten minutes. For most of the movie, Mr. Hanks does not even know that Miss Ryan even exists, let alone that they are destined to be in love. It's not that he ignores her; it's because she spends most of the movie on the opposite side of the country from him. She hears him on the radio, speaking of his recently departed wife, is fascinated by what he has to say, and feels something that is best described, as the movie acknowledges, as "magic." I could use more derisory words toward somebody who would feel this way in real life about a voice, but that's good enough. The screenplay (written by director Nora Ephron and two menJeff Arch and David S. Ward) is also a bit insightful on, again, an unpretentious level. It does not delve deep into the psychological state we like to call love and affection, but it does make some interesting observations. First of all, Miss Ryan's character does acknowledge time and time again how absurd it is of her to fly from New York to Seattle to learn about a man she's only heard. There are also numerous touches upon how Hollywood's perception of sex and romance befalls some people. The key moment is when Rosie O'Donnell, as Miss Ryan's best friend, tells her flat out while watching "An Affair to Remember" that what she wants is not to be in love, but "to be in love in a movie." After all, how many of ussingle and once-singlehave not looked at movies like "Casablanca," "An Affair to Remember," "At First Sight," and such and not fantasized about passion that only seems to exist when an actor and actress play make-believe before a camera? Speaking of other films: that is another thing I adored about "Sleepless in Seattle." It has an uncanny ability to recall other films to effectsometimes comedic, sometimes insightful. A favorite moment of mine is when Mr. Hanks explains to his eight-year-old son (extremely well-acted by Ross Malinger) why he is uncomfortable about rushing into a new relationship so soon: he asks him if he ever saw "Fatal Attraction." The biggest homage(s), though, goes back to "An Affair to Remember." That wonderful 1957 film is shown on television screens numerous times throughout the movie, and at key points, Hugo Friedhofer's score even plays on the soundtrack. Being an obvious admirer of the said film, I found the references quite delightful and charming. If there is one thing I couldn't stand about "Sleepless in Seattle," I would have had to have been the constant usage of classic songs to carry along sequences. The opening credits display while a very jazzy version of "As Time Goes By" thumps in the background, but numbers such as "Stand By Your Man," "Stardust," and others are ever-present, reducing fine scenes into what appear to be limp music videos. There is a potentially great momentreduced to a merely good onewhere Miss Ryan, having traveled to Seattle, watches Mr. Hanks and his son as they play on the beach. It's a very good scene (Miss Ryan is kept at medium shots, Mr. Hanks and Mr. Malinger at distance, the montage is very nice) but the song playing in the background trivializes it. The film's musical score by Marc Shaiman is just fine, and I would have preferred to hear his piano motifs instead of a song. Only the movies can convince that two people could fall into deep, passionate love upon first sight. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the defining examples of that theory. After all, if Mr. Hanks and Miss Ryan could have such strong chemistry when they are not even sharing the same frame, one can only imagine what would lay down the road for their characters (and how moved we would be). But what is best about this movieapart from the fabulous writing and actingis its unostentatious manner. It does not make itself out to be any big deal, and just lets the romantic chemistry emerge on its admittedly old-fashioned terms. And I was more interested in the relationship between these people who have never met as opposed to most formula-films where the cute-boy meets cute-girl, they ogle for an hour, hate one another for twenty minutes, and reconcile at the end. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An affair to forget
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, today was a bank holiday and it was pouring rain outside so my wife and I thought we'd watch a family-oriented romantic-comedy, giving "Sleepless In Seattle" the nod. It's fair to say my wife liked it more than I did. For me it wasn't really very funny and worse, was guilty of over-sentimentality and coincidence. Nothing against Meg Ryan, but she hasn't got the kind of face that would stop you in your tracks the way she does at the airport with Tom Hanks' character's first view of her. Moreover her ditzy character doesn't seem too different (sans hysterical laugh) from the girl his son is so against him hooking up with. Oh yes, about the son, aged eight going on eighteen, going out with a fellow eight-year-old girl, quoting from Beatles' songs, having adult conversations with his dad and flying to New York on his own. As he would! Of course his toothy grin and mop of hair sweep aside any charges of embarrassing cringeworthiness, or at least that's what the director would have you think. I found the writing clich&eacute;d and gauche (a woman character cries when recounting the story of the "An Affair To Remember", Cary Grant / Deborah Kerr vehicle which informs much of the plot here; like when was the last time you cried explaining a movie plot),the thirty-something characters are cardboard-thin and irritating plus it seemed there had to be some old romantic song playing in the background of almost every scene. I couldn't get excited by the acting either, there being no chance for Hanks and Ryan to gell as they don't actually meet until their anti-climactic meeting atop the Empire State Building. Bill Paxton gets underused as Ryan's hypochondriac fianc&eacute; while Rosie O'Donnell irritates as her overly understanding boss. I have to admit I can't stand these male-female "buddy" relationships as demonstrated here by Hanks and Rob Reiner and Ryan and O'Donnell, they play out so artificially. Just about the only good for thing me about this film is that I'll probably seek out the earlier film, confident that it will eclipse this very slack and shallow 1980's production which it regrettably inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ultimate Chick Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emily B
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love love LOVE this movie! I have just seen it for about the tenth time and I always laugh, cry, and squeal at the romantic ending. The leads only had about 5 minutes total of screen time together, yet they have so much chemistry in the closing scene. Annie (Meg Ryan) is recently engaged to Walter (the spunky Bill Pullman, my crush from the nineties), and seems to be happy, until she hears 8-year-old Jonah on the radio. His mother died 18 months ago, and his Christmas wish is that his father will find a new wife so that he won't be so sad. His father Sam (Tom Hanks), then talks about how wonderful his wife was and how much he adored her. Something changes in Annie, and she realises there is something about this man that she has to learn more about. Many would call it stalking, others would call it romantic, but suddenly she is flying across the country for a glimpse of him. Out of all the women who wrote to his Dad, Jonah likes Annie's letter the best, and sets up a romantic first encounter on the top of the Empire State building. Awwwww!!! I think from the start everyone knew how it would end, but it's wonderful to watch. Every single actor is outstanding, especially the young boy who played Jonah, many movies have been ruined by horrible children who cannot act, but he's great, and doesn't try to be too cute. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Chicks' Movie Indeed: Superstitious & Maudlin, But Also Witty, Pleasant & Ultimately Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    faterson (faterson@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's difficult to enjoy a movie that you feel is built on a premise that is fundamentally false. I was, therefore, only able to enjoy _Sleepless in Seattle_ while gnashing my teeth quite frequently. _Sleepless in Seattle_ is about as subtle as a sledgehammer in driving home its message: that there exist phenomena such as "soul mate", "being destined for each other", "true love at first sight", etc. Its conception of "love" is extremely old-fashioned; it's supposed to be that thing where "one meets one", and "you are my everything", "you're the world to me". It's strange, but somehow you instantly feel that _Sleepless in Seattle_ is an irreligious movie; it's not that it would be *against religion*, but you get the definite feeling right from the start that "love" in its religious dimension is and will remain conspicuously absent from the movie. This is all the more remarkable in that _Sleepless in Seattle_ glorifies and uses motives from the 1957 Cary Grant & Deborah Kerr hit, _An Affair to Remember_ -- a romantic comedy as well, but where religion and religious feelings are as obviously present as they are non-existent in _Sleepless in Seattle_. I believe in none of those things such as "destiny", "soul mates", "being made for one another", "you're the only one", etc. And I'm sorry, but as the movie kept reiterating these motives ad nauseam (especially in many of the intentionally old-fashioned songs -- both original and "fake" new ones written in the old vein, frequently featuring awful, annoyingly maudlin lyrics -- that we get to listen to throughout the movie, from the opening to the closing credits), I just *had* to say to myself: "All this 'destingy stuff' is something typically enjoyed and believed by women." There's nothing wrong with a movie or book that makes it obvious that its author is a woman; however, this seemed to be *too* obvious in _Sleepless in Seattle_, detracting from the overall enjoyment. I was saying to myself, "This is a chicks' movie," long before Tom Hanks said the same thing about _An Affair to Remember_; but it's a verdict that is even more apropos in relation to _Sleepless in Seattle_. Speaking of the comparison to _An Affair to Remember_, it's weird that _Sleepless in Seattle_ seems more archaic than the movie that preceded it by almost 3 decades. Both movies feature wildly improbable, unrealistic story-lines; yet when you come to think of it, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr might meet on a luxury ship in 2012 just as they did back in 1957; it would no longer be a transatlantic voyage today, but a pleasurable cruise. Could, however, Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan interact, today, in the same way as shown in _Sleepless in Seattle_? Nope. This movie fairly screams at you: "Where's the Internet? Where are the mobile phones, emails, and social networks?" Only a few years later, and the movie's plot would be rendered unusable. Even as it is, great effort is required to suspend your disbelief; while _An Affair to Remember_ is unrealistic, _Sleepless in Seattle_ is doubly so. Or can anyone honestly believe that a loving father would not have alerted the police immediately upon learning that his 8-year-old son eloped on a transcontinental flight to New York unsupervised? Despite all these shortcomings, _Sleepless in Seattle_ manages to be enjoyable throughout, and unlike _An Affair to Remember_, I believe this movie gets better and better with every passing minute. I found the ending of _An Affair to Remember_ rather a let-down, but not here; I thought the Empire State Building finale of _Sleepless in Seattle_ was very nicely constructed, and genuinely moving. I'd say the main credit for the movie's success should go to the two leading stars. Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan both give brilliant, flawless performances. They seem thoroughly believable as persons or personalities, even while their actions do not. The two child actors, Ross Malinger and Gaby Hoffmann, are terrific as well. Rosie O'Donnell makes her presence felt forcefully in a supporting role; her delivery of several of the movie's wittiest lines, no matter how brief, is pitch-perfect. Victor Garber and Rob Reiner only get a few minutes of screen time, but they certainly make the most of them to shine and to delight the audience. (I thought I only noticed a single false note about the actors' performances. In a weird departure from their realistic mode of delivery throughout the movie, in a discussion at Sam's kitchen table, both Tom Hanks and Victor Garber get tearful while talking about the movie _The Dirty Dozen_. I thought the scene rang very false; it was as if a minute or two from your regular TV sitcom was suddenly inserted into _Sleepless in Seattle_; the only thing missing was canned laughter; I found the moment painful to watch, and not funny at all; fortunately, it only lasted a minute or so; and Rita Wilson did not join in the two actors' shenanigans, but rather rescued the scene thanks to remaining who she was supposed to be in the movie. I thought Hanks & Garber did not perform well in that particular brief and untypical moment, but it would be hard to blame them for it; rather, I'd say it was a mistake on the part of the screenwriter/director to include a heterogeneous moment like that in the script.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sleepless in Philidelphia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so a few months back I was hanging out in my bedroom surfing my Netflix app on my Wii, I was waiting for this show to come on and I had an hour to kill, so I see Sleepless in Seatle in the romance section listed. I usually don't watch romances, but with Tom Hanks in it I made an exception. I LOVED THIS MOVIE! The movie is about recently widower Sam and his son Jonha. Sam is extremely down because of his wife's demise, and his son fells horrible for him. Christmas Eve comes and Sam, is still down. So Jonha decides to call one of those call-in-radio shows to help his dad out. Meanwhile, Annie Reed is driving on a highway listening to show, when Sam begins to tell his story Annie starts crying historically and instantly falls in love with him. The whole movie shows both of them on their own quest, Sam to find a new soul-mate, and Annie to find Sam. This is one of those movie anyone can watch and automatically fall in love with! With movies like these you will always know there is someone for everyone, and the worst of things can be for the better! I give this movie a 10 for its excellence in story, character development, and dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Magic " or Mayhem ??
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alxx0209
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a Tom Hanks movie ? I am a huge Hanks fan he has such a passion and commitment to every single movie he does. I have loved all of his movies that i have seen him in so far. and do I like him in this film? Well I suppose - This movie is about love and all its complications dealing with Sam / Annie and Jonah. The Three of them are trying to find " magic " in a relationship - I personally have not yet felt "magic" in a relationship - I have not even dated at all so I do not relate to " magic " but I can somehow imagine the delightful feeling in ones heart when you see the difference in Annie as the movie goes on and she learns what magic feels like. The movie seemed just a little slow in the beginning in my opinion but after a bit it has a certain pace to it that is enjoying. The movie reminds me of a few other films yet Hanks and Ryan are charming and The Kid also helps out the movie go forward / I also believe that Hanks other films success kind of help / Hurt this one in away - I mean Im not comparing it to his other roles but this one seems specifically about love - and I would say its like 70 % romantic and 30 % comedy but again I liked the movie for what it set up and Tom / Meg and the kid did a good job in this film - also a little note I feel that Rob Reiner and Rosie O' Donnell were just alright in there supporting roles but in my opinion they would be under minor roles for this movie. I have to mention a scene that I liked was Annie watching Sam and Jonah goofing around on the beach - thats were it seemed to click for Annie to realize she was in love with both them from just watching them goof around - being themselves , I believe from then on she felt deep down " magic" for Sam and even in away Jonah. That moment was something I would call a " spark " were it just was beautiful for what it was. That moment you could tell what her heart said to her. Final thoughts ? well Toms Hanks did an amazing job plays such likable and relatable characters ( including this one ) Meg did a decent job -Pullman who played Walter did alright the role kinda fell short - Like your about to marry her and you let her walk away ? He could have developed more. Also i would say like 2 or 3 slow bits that could have been tweaked. Other then that its a cute movie about love and Magic. Its worth watching once in your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hanks and Ryan Should Make More Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan should make more movies. As really this is one of a kind and sweet movie. Hanks character Sam loses his wife to cancer and his son Josh, wants Sam to be happy despite not wanting to ever date again. That is why they move from Chicago to Seattle to escape the sadness. But via a radio talk show station. Josh talks to the host as the USA in particular the women fall in love with Sam and his story despite never seeing him or knowing him that well. This also really strikes a nerve in Baltimore radio newspaper writer, Annie played by Ryan. As she wants to get to know this Sam despite being engaged to a straight laced Bill Pullman. A sweet and kind movie. As makes you want to really wished that both Hanks and Ryan made more movies. As Ryan has felled out with the public lately. But still a really sweet movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once more up the ESB
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-3758
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie again for the umpteenth time. I know going in that it blatantly plays on the emotions ... yet I still do it. It is perhaps one of the best feelgood movies out there. It's a believable story and it's wonderfully acted by all concerned. As a small footnote, might I highlight the tiny sequence when Jonah picks up a cab on arriving in NY. One of the two guys hailing cabs has just one line ... and it's fabulous: To the cab driver "Why don'tcha get further from the kerb next time buddy?!" It's such a small piece of dialogue, I think I missed it the first few times I watched the movie, but it's amazing how such a small thing never fails to make me cry ... with laughter. As against the blubbing I do through the rest of the movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No, just , no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wretched film is about Annie Reed (Meg Ryan) a Baltimore journalist who falls in love with Sam(Tom Hanks) when, at his son Jonah's(Ross Malinger)insistence he talks about his marriage to his late wife Maggie on a radio call-in talk show. Apparently she's one of many women who fell in love with Sam based on this lone qualification. Annie already had a fianc&eacute;e Walter(Bill Pullman) who seems like a really nice guy. Unfortunately for Walter, he doesn't meet Annie's dream romance so he has to go. The meeting is spurred on by the adolescent Jonah, who travels cross-country with his father in pursuit. Of course Sam and Annie fall in love and of course they live happily after after. Here are my problems with the film. First of all, Annie decides to dump a perfectly nice man based on a a stranger's telephone call. That is weird and disturbing. Of course, Sam here is a perfectly nice guy, but he could just as easily been the next Jeffery Dahmer. Next is her treatment of Walter who seems devoted to her, in response to his devotion she breaks up with him, on Valentine's Day of all days, to hook up with a guy she's never met or indeed seen. There is the behavior of the son Jonah who is able to get cross-country tickets without his father's permission and have his dad meet up with Annie. It is presumed that Sam and Annie will live happily ever after, but if Annie can dump a longtime beau like Walter over a phone call on a radio show, than who knows how long her relationship with Sam will last.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such wonderful comedy/romance movies are rare anymore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very entertaining movie is a present-day rarity, for seldom if ever do you find movies concerning a story where a strong void is filled in a person's life, and concomitantly you don't find far-fetched ways to do it. First of all, Sam Baldwin has just lost his wife in Chicago, and the depressed man wants to get away from it all and move to Seattle where he is definitely sleepless because of his recent loss, naturally. At the same time, his eight-year-old son Jonah wants a new mother. Meanwhile, in Baltimore the very attractive Annie Reed, after a dinner at her parent's home where she introduces her future husband to her family, is driving away when she listens to a talk-show hosted by Dr. Marcia Fieldstone who talks to Sam, whom she calls "Sleepless in Seattle". While listening to his voice Annie suddenly becomes taken with him, and then pursues him, thanks very much to the Internet. This is when the "fun" begins. She "seeks advice" from the classic Cary Grant-Deborah Kerr movie "An Affair to Remember", which she watches on t.v. very often. The story does have a warm and happy ending. The story has different settings-Chicago, New York, Baltimore, as well as Seattle. The very versatile Tom Hanks does his turn well, and the unusually appealing Meg Ryan captivated my attention in her role as Annie Reed. Ross Mallinger does acting well for a very young boy. Rosie O'Donnell is her nutty self as Annie's very close friend. Nora Ephron did a good job of writing and directing. Again, I wish they would make comedy/romances like this more often.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" comes very close to being the ideal contemporary American love story, and even with my reservations about some of the things in the film, I still feel it's a very good one. It's an unpretentious little jewel that demonstrates the true values of screen writing and acting, as both are used here shamelessly and with natural grace to manipulate the emotions of the audience. I admit the story is a bit absurd, but it's also somewhat the idea. And besides, in this age where people travel hundreds of miles to meet folks they've chatted with on the internet, is it so hard to believe that a woman would cross the entire country to learn about a widower whose voice she heard on the radio? Well, the Casanova in me would like to think it's not. The plot, though predictable, makes some daring twists. In most romantic comedies, the couple eyes each other from very early on. And although Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan do make an attractive movie-couple, they don't share even have a two-shot until the last ten minutes. For most of the movie, Mr. Hanks does not even know that Miss Ryan even exists, let alone that they are destined to be in love. It's not that he ignores her; it's because she spends most of the movie on the opposite side of the country from him. She hears him on the radio, speaking of his recently departed wife, is fascinated by what he has to say, and feels something that is best described, as the movie acknowledges, as "magic." I could use more derisory words toward somebody who would feel this way in real life about a voice, but that's good enough. The screenplay (written by director Nora Ephron and two menJeff Arch and David S. Ward) is also a bit insightful on, again, an unpretentious level. It does not delve deep into the psychological state we like to call love and affection, but it does make some interesting observations. First of all, Miss Ryan's character does acknowledge time and time again how absurd it is of her to fly from New York to Seattle to learn about a man she's only heard. There are also numerous touches upon how Hollywood's perception of sex and romance befalls some people. The key moment is when Rosie O'Donnell, as Miss Ryan's best friend, tells her flat out while watching "An Affair to Remember" that what she wants is not to be in love, but "to be in love in a movie." After all, how many of ussingle and once-singlehave not looked at movies like "Casablanca," "An Affair to Remember," "At First Sight," and such and not fantasized about passion that only seems to exist when an actor and actress play make-believe before a camera? Speaking of other films: that is another thing I adored about "Sleepless in Seattle." It has an uncanny ability to recall other films to effectsometimes comedic, sometimes insightful. A favorite moment of mine is when Mr. Hanks explains to his eight-year-old son (extremely well-acted by Ross Malinger) why he is uncomfortable about rushing into a new relationship so soon: he asks him if he ever saw "Fatal Attraction." The biggest homage(s), though, goes back to "An Affair to Remember." That wonderful 1957 film is shown on television screens numerous times throughout the movie, and at key points, Hugo Friedhofer's score even plays on the soundtrack. Being an obvious admirer of the said film, I found the references quite delightful and charming. If there is one thing I couldn't stand about "Sleepless in Seattle," I would have had to have been the constant usage of classic songs to carry along sequences. The opening credits display while a very jazzy version of "As Time Goes By" thumps in the background, but numbers such as "Stand By Your Man," "Stardust," and others are ever-present, reducing fine scenes into what appear to be limp music videos. There is a potentially great momentreduced to a merely good onewhere Miss Ryan, having traveled to Seattle, watches Mr. Hanks and his son as they play on the beach. It's a very good scene (Miss Ryan is kept at medium shots, Mr. Hanks and Mr. Malinger at distance, the montage is very nice) but the song playing in the background trivializes it. The film's musical score by Marc Shaiman is just fine, and I would have preferred to hear his piano motifs instead of a song. Only the movies can convince that two people could fall into deep, passionate love upon first sight. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the defining examples of that theory. After all, if Mr. Hanks and Miss Ryan could have such strong chemistry when they are not even sharing the same frame, one can only imagine what would lay down the road for their characters (and how moved we would be). But what is best about this movieapart from the fabulous writing and actingis its unostentatious manner. It does not make itself out to be any big deal, and just lets the romantic chemistry emerge on its admittedly old-fashioned terms. And I was more interested in the relationship between these people who have never met as opposed to most formula-films where the cute-boy meets cute-girl, they ogle for an hour, hate one another for twenty minutes, and reconcile at the end. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An affair to forget
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, today was a bank holiday and it was pouring rain outside so my wife and I thought we'd watch a family-oriented romantic-comedy, giving "Sleepless In Seattle" the nod. It's fair to say my wife liked it more than I did. For me it wasn't really very funny and worse, was guilty of over-sentimentality and coincidence. Nothing against Meg Ryan, but she hasn't got the kind of face that would stop you in your tracks the way she does at the airport with Tom Hanks' character's first view of her. Moreover her ditzy character doesn't seem too different (sans hysterical laugh) from the girl his son is so against him hooking up with. Oh yes, about the son, aged eight going on eighteen, going out with a fellow eight-year-old girl, quoting from Beatles' songs, having adult conversations with his dad and flying to New York on his own. As he would! Of course his toothy grin and mop of hair sweep aside any charges of embarrassing cringeworthiness, or at least that's what the director would have you think. I found the writing clich&eacute;d and gauche (a woman character cries when recounting the story of the "An Affair To Remember", Cary Grant / Deborah Kerr vehicle which informs much of the plot here; like when was the last time you cried explaining a movie plot),the thirty-something characters are cardboard-thin and irritating plus it seemed there had to be some old romantic song playing in the background of almost every scene. I couldn't get excited by the acting either, there being no chance for Hanks and Ryan to gell as they don't actually meet until their anti-climactic meeting atop the Empire State Building. Bill Paxton gets underused as Ryan's hypochondriac fianc&eacute; while Rosie O'Donnell irritates as her overly understanding boss. I have to admit I can't stand these male-female "buddy" relationships as demonstrated here by Hanks and Rob Reiner and Ryan and O'Donnell, they play out so artificially. Just about the only good for thing me about this film is that I'll probably seek out the earlier film, confident that it will eclipse this very slack and shallow 1980's production which it regrettably inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ultimate Chick Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emily B
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love love LOVE this movie! I have just seen it for about the tenth time and I always laugh, cry, and squeal at the romantic ending. The leads only had about 5 minutes total of screen time together, yet they have so much chemistry in the closing scene. Annie (Meg Ryan) is recently engaged to Walter (the spunky Bill Pullman, my crush from the nineties), and seems to be happy, until she hears 8-year-old Jonah on the radio. His mother died 18 months ago, and his Christmas wish is that his father will find a new wife so that he won't be so sad. His father Sam (Tom Hanks), then talks about how wonderful his wife was and how much he adored her. Something changes in Annie, and she realises there is something about this man that she has to learn more about. Many would call it stalking, others would call it romantic, but suddenly she is flying across the country for a glimpse of him. Out of all the women who wrote to his Dad, Jonah likes Annie's letter the best, and sets up a romantic first encounter on the top of the Empire State building. Awwwww!!! I think from the start everyone knew how it would end, but it's wonderful to watch. Every single actor is outstanding, especially the young boy who played Jonah, many movies have been ruined by horrible children who cannot act, but he's great, and doesn't try to be too cute. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Chicks' Movie Indeed: Superstitious & Maudlin, But Also Witty, Pleasant & Ultimately Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    faterson (faterson@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's difficult to enjoy a movie that you feel is built on a premise that is fundamentally false. I was, therefore, only able to enjoy _Sleepless in Seattle_ while gnashing my teeth quite frequently. _Sleepless in Seattle_ is about as subtle as a sledgehammer in driving home its message: that there exist phenomena such as "soul mate", "being destined for each other", "true love at first sight", etc. Its conception of "love" is extremely old-fashioned; it's supposed to be that thing where "one meets one", and "you are my everything", "you're the world to me". It's strange, but somehow you instantly feel that _Sleepless in Seattle_ is an irreligious movie; it's not that it would be *against religion*, but you get the definite feeling right from the start that "love" in its religious dimension is and will remain conspicuously absent from the movie. This is all the more remarkable in that _Sleepless in Seattle_ glorifies and uses motives from the 1957 Cary Grant & Deborah Kerr hit, _An Affair to Remember_ -- a romantic comedy as well, but where religion and religious feelings are as obviously present as they are non-existent in _Sleepless in Seattle_. I believe in none of those things such as "destiny", "soul mates", "being made for one another", "you're the only one", etc. And I'm sorry, but as the movie kept reiterating these motives ad nauseam (especially in many of the intentionally old-fashioned songs -- both original and "fake" new ones written in the old vein, frequently featuring awful, annoyingly maudlin lyrics -- that we get to listen to throughout the movie, from the opening to the closing credits), I just *had* to say to myself: "All this 'destingy stuff' is something typically enjoyed and believed by women." There's nothing wrong with a movie or book that makes it obvious that its author is a woman; however, this seemed to be *too* obvious in _Sleepless in Seattle_, detracting from the overall enjoyment. I was saying to myself, "This is a chicks' movie," long before Tom Hanks said the same thing about _An Affair to Remember_; but it's a verdict that is even more apropos in relation to _Sleepless in Seattle_. Speaking of the comparison to _An Affair to Remember_, it's weird that _Sleepless in Seattle_ seems more archaic than the movie that preceded it by almost 3 decades. Both movies feature wildly improbable, unrealistic story-lines; yet when you come to think of it, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr might meet on a luxury ship in 2012 just as they did back in 1957; it would no longer be a transatlantic voyage today, but a pleasurable cruise. Could, however, Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan interact, today, in the same way as shown in _Sleepless in Seattle_? Nope. This movie fairly screams at you: "Where's the Internet? Where are the mobile phones, emails, and social networks?" Only a few years later, and the movie's plot would be rendered unusable. Even as it is, great effort is required to suspend your disbelief; while _An Affair to Remember_ is unrealistic, _Sleepless in Seattle_ is doubly so. Or can anyone honestly believe that a loving father would not have alerted the police immediately upon learning that his 8-year-old son eloped on a transcontinental flight to New York unsupervised? Despite all these shortcomings, _Sleepless in Seattle_ manages to be enjoyable throughout, and unlike _An Affair to Remember_, I believe this movie gets better and better with every passing minute. I found the ending of _An Affair to Remember_ rather a let-down, but not here; I thought the Empire State Building finale of _Sleepless in Seattle_ was very nicely constructed, and genuinely moving. I'd say the main credit for the movie's success should go to the two leading stars. Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan both give brilliant, flawless performances. They seem thoroughly believable as persons or personalities, even while their actions do not. The two child actors, Ross Malinger and Gaby Hoffmann, are terrific as well. Rosie O'Donnell makes her presence felt forcefully in a supporting role; her delivery of several of the movie's wittiest lines, no matter how brief, is pitch-perfect. Victor Garber and Rob Reiner only get a few minutes of screen time, but they certainly make the most of them to shine and to delight the audience. (I thought I only noticed a single false note about the actors' performances. In a weird departure from their realistic mode of delivery throughout the movie, in a discussion at Sam's kitchen table, both Tom Hanks and Victor Garber get tearful while talking about the movie _The Dirty Dozen_. I thought the scene rang very false; it was as if a minute or two from your regular TV sitcom was suddenly inserted into _Sleepless in Seattle_; the only thing missing was canned laughter; I found the moment painful to watch, and not funny at all; fortunately, it only lasted a minute or so; and Rita Wilson did not join in the two actors' shenanigans, but rather rescued the scene thanks to remaining who she was supposed to be in the movie. I thought Hanks & Garber did not perform well in that particular brief and untypical moment, but it would be hard to blame them for it; rather, I'd say it was a mistake on the part of the screenwriter/director to include a heterogeneous moment like that in the script.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sleepless in Philidelphia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so a few months back I was hanging out in my bedroom surfing my Netflix app on my Wii, I was waiting for this show to come on and I had an hour to kill, so I see Sleepless in Seatle in the romance section listed. I usually don't watch romances, but with Tom Hanks in it I made an exception. I LOVED THIS MOVIE! The movie is about recently widower Sam and his son Jonha. Sam is extremely down because of his wife's demise, and his son fells horrible for him. Christmas Eve comes and Sam, is still down. So Jonha decides to call one of those call-in-radio shows to help his dad out. Meanwhile, Annie Reed is driving on a highway listening to show, when Sam begins to tell his story Annie starts crying historically and instantly falls in love with him. The whole movie shows both of them on their own quest, Sam to find a new soul-mate, and Annie to find Sam. This is one of those movie anyone can watch and automatically fall in love with! With movies like these you will always know there is someone for everyone, and the worst of things can be for the better! I give this movie a 10 for its excellence in story, character development, and dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Magic " or Mayhem ??
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alxx0209
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a Tom Hanks movie ? I am a huge Hanks fan he has such a passion and commitment to every single movie he does. I have loved all of his movies that i have seen him in so far. and do I like him in this film? Well I suppose - This movie is about love and all its complications dealing with Sam / Annie and Jonah. The Three of them are trying to find " magic " in a relationship - I personally have not yet felt "magic" in a relationship - I have not even dated at all so I do not relate to " magic " but I can somehow imagine the delightful feeling in ones heart when you see the difference in Annie as the movie goes on and she learns what magic feels like. The movie seemed just a little slow in the beginning in my opinion but after a bit it has a certain pace to it that is enjoying. The movie reminds me of a few other films yet Hanks and Ryan are charming and The Kid also helps out the movie go forward / I also believe that Hanks other films success kind of help / Hurt this one in away - I mean Im not comparing it to his other roles but this one seems specifically about love - and I would say its like 70 % romantic and 30 % comedy but again I liked the movie for what it set up and Tom / Meg and the kid did a good job in this film - also a little note I feel that Rob Reiner and Rosie O' Donnell were just alright in there supporting roles but in my opinion they would be under minor roles for this movie. I have to mention a scene that I liked was Annie watching Sam and Jonah goofing around on the beach - thats were it seemed to click for Annie to realize she was in love with both them from just watching them goof around - being themselves , I believe from then on she felt deep down " magic" for Sam and even in away Jonah. That moment was something I would call a " spark " were it just was beautiful for what it was. That moment you could tell what her heart said to her. Final thoughts ? well Toms Hanks did an amazing job plays such likable and relatable characters ( including this one ) Meg did a decent job -Pullman who played Walter did alright the role kinda fell short - Like your about to marry her and you let her walk away ? He could have developed more. Also i would say like 2 or 3 slow bits that could have been tweaked. Other then that its a cute movie about love and Magic. Its worth watching once in your life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hanks and Ryan Should Make More Movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan should make more movies. As really this is one of a kind and sweet movie. Hanks character Sam loses his wife to cancer and his son Josh, wants Sam to be happy despite not wanting to ever date again. That is why they move from Chicago to Seattle to escape the sadness. But via a radio talk show station. Josh talks to the host as the USA in particular the women fall in love with Sam and his story despite never seeing him or knowing him that well. This also really strikes a nerve in Baltimore radio newspaper writer, Annie played by Ryan. As she wants to get to know this Sam despite being engaged to a straight laced Bill Pullman. A sweet and kind movie. As makes you want to really wished that both Hanks and Ryan made more movies. As Ryan has felled out with the public lately. But still a really sweet movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once more up the ESB
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john-3758
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this movie again for the umpteenth time. I know going in that it blatantly plays on the emotions ... yet I still do it. It is perhaps one of the best feelgood movies out there. It's a believable story and it's wonderfully acted by all concerned. As a small footnote, might I highlight the tiny sequence when Jonah picks up a cab on arriving in NY. One of the two guys hailing cabs has just one line ... and it's fabulous: To the cab driver "Why don'tcha get further from the kerb next time buddy?!" It's such a small piece of dialogue, I think I missed it the first few times I watched the movie, but it's amazing how such a small thing never fails to make me cry ... with laughter. As against the blubbing I do through the rest of the movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No, just , no.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thunderclancat
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This wretched film is about Annie Reed (Meg Ryan) a Baltimore journalist who falls in love with Sam(Tom Hanks) when, at his son Jonah's(Ross Malinger)insistence he talks about his marriage to his late wife Maggie on a radio call-in talk show. Apparently she's one of many women who fell in love with Sam based on this lone qualification. Annie already had a fianc&eacute;e Walter(Bill Pullman) who seems like a really nice guy. Unfortunately for Walter, he doesn't meet Annie's dream romance so he has to go. The meeting is spurred on by the adolescent Jonah, who travels cross-country with his father in pursuit. Of course Sam and Annie fall in love and of course they live happily after after. Here are my problems with the film. First of all, Annie decides to dump a perfectly nice man based on a a stranger's telephone call. That is weird and disturbing. Of course, Sam here is a perfectly nice guy, but he could just as easily been the next Jeffery Dahmer. Next is her treatment of Walter who seems devoted to her, in response to his devotion she breaks up with him, on Valentine's Day of all days, to hook up with a guy she's never met or indeed seen. There is the behavior of the son Jonah who is able to get cross-country tickets without his father's permission and have his dad meet up with Annie. It is presumed that Sam and Annie will live happily ever after, but if Annie can dump a longtime beau like Walter over a phone call on a radio show, than who knows how long her relationship with Sam will last.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such wonderful comedy/romance movies are rare anymore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This very entertaining movie is a present-day rarity, for seldom if ever do you find movies concerning a story where a strong void is filled in a person's life, and concomitantly you don't find far-fetched ways to do it. First of all, Sam Baldwin has just lost his wife in Chicago, and the depressed man wants to get away from it all and move to Seattle where he is definitely sleepless because of his recent loss, naturally. At the same time, his eight-year-old son Jonah wants a new mother. Meanwhile, in Baltimore the very attractive Annie Reed, after a dinner at her parent's home where she introduces her future husband to her family, is driving away when she listens to a talk-show hosted by Dr. Marcia Fieldstone who talks to Sam, whom she calls "Sleepless in Seattle". While listening to his voice Annie suddenly becomes taken with him, and then pursues him, thanks very much to the Internet. This is when the "fun" begins. She "seeks advice" from the classic Cary Grant-Deborah Kerr movie "An Affair to Remember", which she watches on t.v. very often. The story does have a warm and happy ending. The story has different settings-Chicago, New York, Baltimore, as well as Seattle. The very versatile Tom Hanks does his turn well, and the unusually appealing Meg Ryan captivated my attention in her role as Annie Reed. Ross Mallinger does acting well for a very young boy. Rosie O'Donnell is her nutty self as Annie's very close friend. Nora Ephron did a good job of writing and directing. Again, I wish they would make comedy/romances like this more often.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Sleepless in Seattle" comes very close to being the ideal contemporary American love story, and even with my reservations about some of the things in the film, I still feel it's a very good one. It's an unpretentious little jewel that demonstrates the true values of screen writing and acting, as both are used here shamelessly and with natural grace to manipulate the emotions of the audience. I admit the story is a bit absurd, but it's also somewhat the idea. And besides, in this age where people travel hundreds of miles to meet folks they've chatted with on the internet, is it so hard to believe that a woman would cross the entire country to learn about a widower whose voice she heard on the radio? Well, the Casanova in me would like to think it's not. The plot, though predictable, makes some daring twists. In most romantic comedies, the couple eyes each other from very early on. And although Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan do make an attractive movie-couple, they don't share even have a two-shot until the last ten minutes. For most of the movie, Mr. Hanks does not even know that Miss Ryan even exists, let alone that they are destined to be in love. It's not that he ignores her; it's because she spends most of the movie on the opposite side of the country from him. She hears him on the radio, speaking of his recently departed wife, is fascinated by what he has to say, and feels something that is best described, as the movie acknowledges, as "magic." I could use more derisory words toward somebody who would feel this way in real life about a voice, but that's good enough. The screenplay (written by director Nora Ephron and two menJeff Arch and David S. Ward) is also a bit insightful on, again, an unpretentious level. It does not delve deep into the psychological state we like to call love and affection, but it does make some interesting observations. First of all, Miss Ryan's character does acknowledge time and time again how absurd it is of her to fly from New York to Seattle to learn about a man she's only heard. There are also numerous touches upon how Hollywood's perception of sex and romance befalls some people. The key moment is when Rosie O'Donnell, as Miss Ryan's best friend, tells her flat out while watching "An Affair to Remember" that what she wants is not to be in love, but "to be in love in a movie." After all, how many of ussingle and once-singlehave not looked at movies like "Casablanca," "An Affair to Remember," "At First Sight," and such and not fantasized about passion that only seems to exist when an actor and actress play make-believe before a camera? Speaking of other films: that is another thing I adored about "Sleepless in Seattle." It has an uncanny ability to recall other films to effectsometimes comedic, sometimes insightful. A favorite moment of mine is when Mr. Hanks explains to his eight-year-old son (extremely well-acted by Ross Malinger) why he is uncomfortable about rushing into a new relationship so soon: he asks him if he ever saw "Fatal Attraction." The biggest homage(s), though, goes back to "An Affair to Remember." That wonderful 1957 film is shown on television screens numerous times throughout the movie, and at key points, Hugo Friedhofer's score even plays on the soundtrack. Being an obvious admirer of the said film, I found the references quite delightful and charming. If there is one thing I couldn't stand about "Sleepless in Seattle," I would have had to have been the constant usage of classic songs to carry along sequences. The opening credits display while a very jazzy version of "As Time Goes By" thumps in the background, but numbers such as "Stand By Your Man," "Stardust," and others are ever-present, reducing fine scenes into what appear to be limp music videos. There is a potentially great momentreduced to a merely good onewhere Miss Ryan, having traveled to Seattle, watches Mr. Hanks and his son as they play on the beach. It's a very good scene (Miss Ryan is kept at medium shots, Mr. Hanks and Mr. Malinger at distance, the montage is very nice) but the song playing in the background trivializes it. The film's musical score by Marc Shaiman is just fine, and I would have preferred to hear his piano motifs instead of a song. Only the movies can convince that two people could fall into deep, passionate love upon first sight. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the defining examples of that theory. After all, if Mr. Hanks and Miss Ryan could have such strong chemistry when they are not even sharing the same frame, one can only imagine what would lay down the road for their characters (and how moved we would be). But what is best about this movieapart from the fabulous writing and actingis its unostentatious manner. It does not make itself out to be any big deal, and just lets the romantic chemistry emerge on its admittedly old-fashioned terms. And I was more interested in the relationship between these people who have never met as opposed to most formula-films where the cute-boy meets cute-girl, they ogle for an hour, hate one another for twenty minutes, and reconcile at the end. "Sleepless in Seattle" is one of the more significant romantic comedies of the last 20 years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An affair to forget
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, today was a bank holiday and it was pouring rain outside so my wife and I thought we'd watch a family-oriented romantic-comedy, giving "Sleepless In Seattle" the nod. It's fair to say my wife liked it more than I did. For me it wasn't really very funny and worse, was guilty of over-sentimentality and coincidence. Nothing against Meg Ryan, but she hasn't got the kind of face that would stop you in your tracks the way she does at the airport with Tom Hanks' character's first view of her. Moreover her ditzy character doesn't seem too different (sans hysterical laugh) from the girl his son is so against him hooking up with. Oh yes, about the son, aged eight going on eighteen, going out with a fellow eight-year-old girl, quoting from Beatles' songs, having adult conversations with his dad and flying to New York on his own. As he would! Of course his toothy grin and mop of hair sweep aside any charges of embarrassing cringeworthiness, or at least that's what the director would have you think. I found the writing clich&eacute;d and gauche (a woman character cries when recounting the story of the "An Affair To Remember", Cary Grant / Deborah Kerr vehicle which informs much of the plot here; like when was the last time you cried explaining a movie plot),the thirty-something characters are cardboard-thin and irritating plus it seemed there had to be some old romantic song playing in the background of almost every scene. I couldn't get excited by the acting either, there being no chance for Hanks and Ryan to gell as they don't actually meet until their anti-climactic meeting atop the Empire State Building. Bill Paxton gets underused as Ryan's hypochondriac fianc&eacute; while Rosie O'Donnell irritates as her overly understanding boss. I have to admit I can't stand these male-female "buddy" relationships as demonstrated here by Hanks and Rob Reiner and Ryan and O'Donnell, they play out so artificially. Just about the only good for thing me about this film is that I'll probably seek out the earlier film, confident that it will eclipse this very slack and shallow 1980's production which it regrettably inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ultimate Chick Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emily B
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love love LOVE this movie! I have just seen it for about the tenth time and I always laugh, cry, and squeal at the romantic ending. The leads only had about 5 minutes total of screen time together, yet they have so much chemistry in the closing scene. Annie (Meg Ryan) is recently engaged to Walter (the spunky Bill Pullman, my crush from the nineties), and seems to be happy, until she hears 8-year-old Jonah on the radio. His mother died 18 months ago, and his Christmas wish is that his father will find a new wife so that he won't be so sad. His father Sam (Tom Hanks), then talks about how wonderful his wife was and how much he adored her. Something changes in Annie, and she realises there is something about this man that she has to learn more about. Many would call it stalking, others would call it romantic, but suddenly she is flying across the country for a glimpse of him. Out of all the women who wrote to his Dad, Jonah likes Annie's letter the best, and sets up a romantic first encounter on the top of the Empire State building. Awwwww!!! I think from the start everyone knew how it would end, but it's wonderful to watch. Every single actor is outstanding, especially the young boy who played Jonah, many movies have been ruined by horrible children who cannot act, but he's great, and doesn't try to be too cute. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Chicks' Movie Indeed: Superstitious & Maudlin, But Also Witty, Pleasant & Ultimately Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    faterson (faterson@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's difficult to enjoy a movie that you feel is built on a premise that is fundamentally false. I was, therefore, only able to enjoy _Sleepless in Seattle_ while gnashing my teeth quite frequently. _Sleepless in Seattle_ is about as subtle as a sledgehammer in driving home its message: that there exist phenomena such as "soul mate", "being destined for each other", "true love at first sight", etc. Its conception of "love" is extremely old-fashioned; it's supposed to be that thing where "one meets one", and "you are my everything", "you're the world to me". It's strange, but somehow you instantly feel that _Sleepless in Seattle_ is an irreligious movie; it's not that it would be *against religion*, but you get the definite feeling right from the start that "love" in its religious dimension is and will remain conspicuously absent from the movie. This is all the more remarkable in that _Sleepless in Seattle_ glorifies and uses motives from the 1957 Cary Grant & Deborah Kerr hit, _An Affair to Remember_ -- a romantic comedy as well, but where religion and religious feelings are as obviously present as they are non-existent in _Sleepless in Seattle_. I believe in none of those things such as "destiny", "soul mates", "being made for one another", "you're the only one", etc. And I'm sorry, but as the movie kept reiterating these motives ad nauseam (especially in many of the intentionally old-fashioned songs -- both original and "fake" new ones written in the old vein, frequently featuring awful, annoyingly maudlin lyrics -- that we get to listen to throughout the movie, from the opening to the closing credits), I just *had* to say to myself: "All this 'destingy stuff' is something typically enjoyed and believed by women." There's nothing wrong with a movie or book that makes it obvious that its author is a woman; however, this seemed to be *too* obvious in _Sleepless in Seattle_, detracting from the overall enjoyment. I was saying to myself, "This is a chicks' movie," long before Tom Hanks said the same thing about _An Affair to Remember_; but it's a verdict that is even more apropos in relation to _Sleepless in Seattle_. Speaking of the comparison to _An Affair to Remember_, it's weird that _Sleepless in Seattle_ seems more archaic than the movie that preceded it by almost 3 decades. Both movies feature wildly improbable, unrealistic story-lines; yet when you come to think of it, Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr might meet on a luxury ship in 2012 just as they did back in 1957; it would no longer be a transatlantic voyage today, but a pleasurable cruise. Could, however, Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan interact, today, in the same way as shown in _Sleepless in Seattle_? Nope. This movie fairly screams at you: "Where's the Internet? Where are the mobile phones, emails, and social networks?" Only a few years later, and the movie's plot would be rendered unusable. Even as it is, great effort is required to suspend your disbelief; while _An Affair to Remember_ is unrealistic, _Sleepless in Seattle_ is doubly so. Or can anyone honestly believe that a loving father would not have alerted the police immediately upon learning that his 8-year-old son eloped on a transcontinental flight to New York unsupervised? Despite all these shortcomings, _Sleepless in Seattle_ manages to be enjoyable throughout, and unlike _An Affair to Remember_, I believe this movie gets better and better with every passing minute. I found the ending of _An Affair to Remember_ rather a let-down, but not here; I thought the Empire State Building finale of _Sleepless in Seattle_ was very nicely constructed, and genuinely moving. I'd say the main credit for the movie's success should go to the two leading stars. Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan both give brilliant, flawless performances. They seem thoroughly believable as persons or personalities, even while their actions do not. The two child actors, Ross Malinger and Gaby Hoffmann, are terrific as well. Rosie O'Donnell makes her presence felt forcefully in a supporting role; her delivery of several of the movie's wittiest lines, no matter how brief, is pitch-perfect. Victor Garber and Rob Reiner only get a few minutes of screen time, but they certainly make the most of them to shine and to delight the audience. (I thought I only noticed a single false note about the actors' performances. In a weird departure from their realistic mode of delivery throughout the movie, in a discussion at Sam's kitchen table, both Tom Hanks and Victor Garber get tearful while talking about the movie _The Dirty Dozen_. I thought the scene rang very false; it was as if a minute or two from your regular TV sitcom was suddenly inserted into _Sleepless in Seattle_; the only thing missing was canned laughter; I found the moment painful to watch, and not funny at all; fortunately, it only lasted a minute or so; and Rita Wilson did not join in the two actors' shenanigans, but rather rescued the scene thanks to remaining who she was supposed to be in the movie. I thought Hanks & Garber did not perform well in that particular brief and untypical moment, but it would be hard to blame them for it; rather, I'd say it was a mistake on the part of the screenwriter/director to include a heterogeneous moment like that in the script.)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sleepless in Philidelphia
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisureRebellion
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so a few months back I was hanging out in my bedroom surfing my Netflix app on my Wii, I was waiting for this show to come on and I had an hour to kill, so I see Sleepless in Seatle in the romance section listed. I usually don't watch romances, but with Tom Hanks in it I made an exception. I LOVED THIS MOVIE! The movie is about recently widower Sam and his son Jonha. Sam is extremely down because of his wife's demise, and his son fells horrible for him. Christmas Eve comes and Sam, is still down. So Jonha decides to call one of those call-in-radio shows to help his dad out. Meanwhile, Annie Reed is driving on a highway listening to show, when Sam begins to tell his story Annie starts crying historically and instantly falls in love with him. The whole movie shows both of them on their own quest, Sam to find a new soul-mate, and Annie to find Sam. This is one of those movie anyone can watch and automatically fall in love with! With movies like these you will always know there is someone for everyone, and the worst of things can be for the better! I give this movie a 10 for its excellence in story, character development, and dialog.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
