<filme>
 <id>
  881
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119695
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Tudo Por Dinheiro
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Sought by police and criminals, a small-time huckster makes a deal with a TV newsman for protection.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Chris Tucker is a small time con man who instantly becomes famous after a murder, wanted dead or alive, his only hope is a journalist named James Russell (Sheen).
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fugitive
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   buddy comedy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   los angeles california
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Brett Ratner
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Joel Cohen
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Alec Sokolow
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Charlie Sheen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Chris Tucker
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Heather Locklear
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    movie sucks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Twenty five million dollars was spent on this movie, those are earth dollars mind you not lunar cash or martian money, a fortune amassed to make an action-comedy. A dull humorless wretched affair entirely populated by unlikable fake characters. Do you know how much money twenty five million dollars is? Imagine it as yours for a moment, you have twenty five million dollars, think of all you can do with that much filthy loot, now do you want to invest all of that money in a Charlie Sheen/ Chris Tucker movie? Have you seen Money Talks? Well that's the script, would that script read to you like a twenty five million dollar idea? Oh my God! What I would do with twenty five million dollars if I was going to make a movie! No matter how insane or ridiculous the movie more than likely would be Lord Lord it would be better than Money Talks. Money Talks is the bottom of the barrel folks, if you cant do better than this movie you need to get out of the movie biz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Tucker Rocks in "Money Talks!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the feverishly-paced, interracial action comedy "Money Talks," hyper-kinetic comic Chris Tucker plays Franklin Hatchett, a two-bit, street-wise, ticket-scalping hustler pursued by a trigger-happy Belgian diamond smugglers, thuggish loan sharks, corrupt cops, and his own pregnant girlfriend. In his first starring role, Tucker clearly wants to imitate Eddie Murphy. Co-starring Charlie Sheen as a frustrated news reporter, a persuasive supporting cast, featuring Paul Sorvino and Heather Locklear, and crackling direction by Brett Ratner in his debut, "Money Talks" is nothing but rambunctious fun. The key to "Money Talks" is whether you find Chris Tucker either entertaining or obnoxious as a whiny-voiced dynamo whose motor-mouth never stops. If you've seen the doper farce "Friday" or last summer's mega-budget science fiction saga "The Fifth Element," you'll recognize Tucker by his bulging cue-ball eyes, pouting bottom lip, and beetle brows. Acting like Buckwheat with a subversive attitude, Tucker's trademark is his helium-pitched, fast-paced delivery with profanity between every other word. He can rattle off a line of dialogue faster than a Federal Express commercial. When Tucker isn't dodging bullets and careening in cars in "Money Talks," he is jive-talking and wise-cracking with the kind of brazen effrontery that either makes you laugh harder or aggravates you to no end. The screenplay by "Toy Story" scribes Joel Cohen and Alec Sokolow uses the classic theme of mistaken identity. Franklin is raking in some cool bucks as a scammer who fences stolen property at his car wash. Along comes scoop-hungry television news reporter James Russell (Charlie Sheen of "Platoon") who gets Hatchett arrested for soliciting goods. The incredulous Hatchett winds up shackled to an unidentified Belgian crook. Nobody recognizes the infamous Raymond Villard (G&eacute;rard Isma&euml;l of "Sp&eacute;cial Police"). During a routine bus transfer, Villard's henchmen blow up the vehicle and rescue their boss. Franklin survives by virtue of his being cuffed to the evil Villard. Aboard their escape helicopter, Franklin learns about a cache of $15 million in diamonds. Before the villains can kill him, our hero bails out of the chopper and splashes into the ocean. But Franklin is only leaping from one frying pan to another. It seems the L.A.P.D. has accused him of killing the fourteen prisoners and two police guards on the bus. Hatchett contacts Russell because he believes the news reporter might help him. Russell agrees to harbor the fugitive so he can get an exclusive as well as convince his British boss Barclay (David Warner of "Titanic") to re-hire him. Even that backfires when Russell finds himself implicated in Franklin's crime. Although the Cohen and Sokolow screenplay adheres to a predictable formula, the story generates enough thrills and chills as well as a neatly planted surprise or two to pass muster. Basically, "Money Talks" amounts to a chase thriller with all the villains pursuing Franklin. They're prepared to kill Franklin as well as anybody else who gets in their way. Meanwhile, not only must Russell keep Franklin alive, he also must humor the wealthy parents of his bride-to-be Grace Cipriani ("Melrose Place's" Heather Locklear). Happily, the plot confines both Grace and her catty mom Connie (Veronica Cartwright of "Alien") to their mansion. A lesser script would have involved them in a kidnapping plot. Most of the time, the film focuses on Franklin's center camera efforts to negotiate with his various enemies and adversaries. Freshman helmer Ratner supercharges the action with such momentum that it rarely let up on it fast and furious pace. If the second to a winning comedy is maintaining a lively, timely, breakneck clip, Ratner succeeds in spades. "Money Talks" careens from one plot twist to the next with marvelous abandon. Ratner nimbly directs a genuinely exciting chase scene, an explosive assault-on-the-bus scene, and the gunslinging pyrotechnical finale at the Los Angeles Coliseum where everybody wields a weapon. When he isn't proving his talent helming these second-unit action scenes, Ratner has fun playing Tucker and Sheen off each other. The solid, dependable, square-jawed Sheen makes a convincing straight man for Tucker. He is a news reporter with aspirations to join CBS-TV's "60 Minutes." Sheen's scenes with Tucker crackle with live-wire energy as the two spar with each other. The fierce, pugnacious camaraderie between these guys recalls the feisty relationship between Eddie Murphy and Nick Nolte in "48 Hrs," and that's what makes Tucker and Sheen such an offbeat and hilarious pair. Wolfish G&eacute;rard Isma&euml;l turns in an appropriately guttural performance that captures the hard-edged notoriety of the Belgian antagonist. The rest of the cast, including Sorvino as Russell's future father-in-law, Veronica Cartwright as the sneering wife, and Locklear as Russell's pretty bride acquit themselves well in peripheral roles. In minor roles, Paul Gleason of "Trading Places" stands out as a sympathetic but suspicious Lieutenant Bobby Pickett and Michael Wright as one of Franklin's schoolyard chums. "Money Talks" compares favorably to the old buddy comedies of Richard Pryor and Gene Wilder because it only wants to be a rollicking barrel of monkeys. If Chris Tucker can keep making agile comedies that click like "Money Talks," then Eddie Murphy has something to worry about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    staged memory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ruiresende84 (ruiresende84@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is another chapter of that kind of trend in comedy/action films: the biracial leading couple. This began with Lethal Weapon. There the comedy balance was divided between Glover and Gibson. But a lot of versions have come after, including the 3rd Die Hard, that thing with Rodman/Van Damme, or this film. It's as lame and short sight as any formula, but it worked for while. It doesn't anymore, and now while we see this, we wonder how it ever worked. This can only have a mild appeal on 2 levels: .you saw the films while you were teenager, and so they become part of larger memories of your evolution, and seeing them is a wink at yourself. .you assume how lame they are, and watch them on that base, as much as you watch a b film, filled with bad sets and laughable story lines, and assume that for the duration of the film. I did both of the above. But i know there's nothing here. There's actually an attempt to create a competent ending, the idea of a literal stage, where all the characters are brought, and all conflicts resolved, using the multiple possibilities that mise-en-sc&egrave;ne allows. But it's all worked out through a vulgar shootout, and a few body fights with no history. My opinion: 1/5 http://www.7eyes.wordpress.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Buddy Comic Action, Starring Chris Tucker & Some Explosions !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Joel Cohen) and (Alec Sokolow) wrote a mild script. However there was potential that I waited from the scriptwriters of (Toy Story  1995) and (Goodbye Lover  1998) to use, while they didn't. There are situations where the comedy could have been produced better (the party), or produced (the arm dealer's lair), but the action was the main point I guess, so it sure lost more chances for laughs. The buddy formula couldn't be felt. I mean (Charlie Sheen) wasn't given much of a character. All the lights are spotted on (Chris Tucker). Over and above, (Sheen) didn't do anything more than his usual Siberian performance and combing his hair well. They could have easily replaced him with a cardboard cutout ! Although he's not that charismatic, and too annoying in many places, (Tucker) proved that he can be a star in a movie. I just hated his method that whenever the camera is rolling; "I must not stop talking and talking and talking" to an extent where they should have renamed the movie (Chris Tucker Talks)!.. It's not funny at all. Anyway, he sure looked better, and talked less in director (Brett Ratner)'s next movies (Rush Hour). But maybe it gives you a hint about the reason why (Tucker) doesn't work much out of that franchise. The start is really good and inspiring. And there is fair action, especially at the third act. However the second act went astray a bit. Some violence bothered me as well, but not like the very last scene, where the 2 leads accept a portion of stolen diamonds for themselves, even the clean-cut reporter. It's a matter that will inflame more loud objections 2 years later in another action comedy; (Money Train). In 1997, the buddy formula was sizzling. I believe it's the (Lethal Weapon)'s effect. Many buddy comedies were released : (Out to Sea), (Fathers' Day), (Gone Fishin'), (Good Burger), (Mousehunt), (Nothing to Lose), and (Trial and Error). Many buddy action too : (Men in Black), (Double Team), and (The Edge). I think (Money Talks) is a reasonable action, somehow far from being a comedy, and originally not a complete "buddy" movie, being so close to one man show. Not bad man, and not excellent show either. Well, averagely entertaining is the word then. Seriously there was nothing super but that chain of explosions at the end, which if there was more like it; it could have fit as better buddy for (Tucker) !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film.....totally awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justtall
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Money Talk is totally a great film. Its one of my personal favorites, its one of the few movies that I can watch over and over again and laugh hard like it was my first time watching it. This film is centered on the duo of Franklin Hatchet, a hustler, and James Russell a very popular News reporter, and all of the problems they encounter. They're caught in crossfire between the cops, crooks, and commandos trying to receive a fortune of diamonds. Franklin was played by hilarious actor Chris Tucker and James played by Charlie Sheen. Their duo is totally ironic and unplanned; here you have a news reporter that had once reported a story explaining on how dangerous and bad Franklin was and here he was befriending him. One thing that I admired about the role of Franklin was his ability to socialize and make people laugh. For example James Russell was very stern about befriending and even being spotted around with Franklin, but Franklin's personality was so outrageous that Mr. Russell just couldn't resist. Chris Tucker did an amazing job playing the role of Franklin, Chris Tucker is the star of the movie, and his jokes were just so crazy and funny! It's like even if he didn't say anything his facial expressions alone are just funny! Chris was just so comedic in the movie that he didn't have to "try" to be funny he just naturally is. This movie is action meets comedy, the two genres are equal throughout the film, and I'm not a big fan of action but this movie is the only exception. Great Film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Tucker + Charlie Sheen = Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lahhlay M
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Classic Action Comedy. This in my opinion is Chris Tucker at his best. From the opening scene to the end, Chris Tucker is hilarious. From the funny looking hair cut to the cussing and singing, he reminds you of Eddie Murphy in Beverly Hills Cop. Charlie Sheen also does an impressive job. The action scenes are not spectacular, but it does a good job. Money talks is a good blend of Guns/Explosions and laughter. If your a fan of 48 Hours, Nothing To Lose or any other Action Comedy, Money talks is a must see. 7.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Tucker and Paul Sorvino should have had more scenes together
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie that made director Brett Ratner a recognizable name is mostly another white-yuppie-and-black-ghetto-guy-have-to-join-up kind of story (summer 1997 also saw the release of the Tim Robbins-Martin Lawrence buddy comedy "Nothing to Lose"). But as far as I'm concerned, Chris Tucker - who earlier that summer had starred in "The Fifth Element" - is always funny enough to merit at least some recognition; and anyway, this sort of flick is supposed to be silly. While Charlie Sheen is far less entertaining in his role, Paul Sorvino played such an interesting character that I agreed with one of my friends that he and Chris Tucker should have gotten more scenes together. Truth be told, I'd actually never heard of Vic Damone until I saw this movie. OK, so maybe we could be cynical and say that Chris Tucker just gets the same role in every movie. I still consider him funny, and I wish to assert that "Money Talks" is good for a few laughs. Worth seeing if only for that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i reject your reality and substitute my own...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wombathappiness
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1) unregistered helicopters ALWAYS get to fly at low altitudes through out a city without drawing any suspicion from the police or military 2)a buss loaded with enough c4 to blow it in half and ten feet in the air will always leave survivors 3) police always open fire on an unarmed man in the middle of a crowded restaurant. 4) a local street reporter can afford a 10,000sq ft. apartment in l.a. 5) Chris tucker deserves any type of a career at all these are all realities in coo coo ville, the wonderful land where this script was born. a land where the rivers run with gold and sugar falls from the sky. it's just a shame that Charlie Sheen and Principal Vernon got drug into this travesty
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Idea, But The On Screen Chemistry Wasn't There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fiendish_Dramaturgy
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a valiant effort by Tucker, in developing the formula he would later use with Jackie Chan. This character's behavior is identical to his later character of the Rush Hour line (trilogy?) with one exception...he was still a bit in Ruby Rod mode from the Fifth Element. That fact alone lends at least some amusement to this almost "workshop" attempt between Charlie Sheen and Chris Tucker. Thankfully, Tucker hit in with Chan whose personality kicks it with Tucker's over the top, sometimes flamboyant, mostly big mouth style. Sheen played it too close to the vest. His character here is rather silent, but that's better than the few scenes in which he actually speaks, as Sheen's dialog delivery here will make most audiences cringe. It seems as though he's attempting the quiet brooding bad guy persona of Mel Gibson in the Lethal Weapon franchise, but Sheen just doesn't seem to pull it off. Nor does he pull off the "hip" bad boy persona he attempts on again and off again, throughout this work. Sheen must have been off his game here, as we all know that the bad boy is something he CAN do well..or could, at least, when he was younger. This was filmed in 1996/1997, so I have to assume he was just off his game, as that was the heyday of his nefarious bad boy personal life. This work is still a bit entertaining, if you can manage to ignore Sheen, and just enjoy the fun story line, the awesome performance by Paul Sorvino and funny man Chris Tucker, and the somewhat decent action/comedy blend. All in all, if you're bored, this is a fun choice, but if you have to make time for it, it may be somewhat of a disappointment. It rates 5.9/10 from... the Fiend :.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This funny, lively, often violent action comedy is well done.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A low-level smooth talking hustler by the name of Franlin Hatchet (Chris Tucker) is on the run from the police, after a jailbreak. Which he is falsely accused of planning a violent jailbreak. Now the whole city is on his trail and the only one, who could clear his name is an ambitious television reporter James Russell (Charlie Sheen). Which is the only reason why Franklin was sent to prison, because of James. Now together, they find each other mixed-up with cops, crooks and euro-trash bad guys. Which Franklin knows that the man (Gerard Ismael) was chained-up with in the bus. He was trying to retrieve a fortune in diamonds. Directed by Brett Rather (Rush Hour Trilogy, X-Men 3:The Last Stand, Red Dragon) made an highly entertaining comedy with enough thrills and humour. Although the premise is familiar but Tucker's energetic comical performance makes this worth watching. DVD has an sharp anamorphic Widescreen (2.35:1) transfer (also in Pan & Scan) and an strong-Dolby Digital 5.1 Surround Sound. DVD includes the original theatrical trailer, cast information and star highlights by Tucker and Sheen. After the box office success of this film, Tucker went on the one of the leads of the "Rush Hour" movies. Paul Sorvino is amusingly cast as Russell's future father-in-law. Written by Joel Cohen and Alec Sokolow. Which they wrote films together like "Garfield", "Garfield:A Tale of Two Kitties" and "Toy Story". Tucker also executive produced the film. Super 35. (****/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    movie sucks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Twenty five million dollars was spent on this movie, those are earth dollars mind you not lunar cash or martian money, a fortune amassed to make an action-comedy. A dull humorless wretched affair entirely populated by unlikable fake characters. Do you know how much money twenty five million dollars is? Imagine it as yours for a moment, you have twenty five million dollars, think of all you can do with that much filthy loot, now do you want to invest all of that money in a Charlie Sheen/ Chris Tucker movie? Have you seen Money Talks? Well that's the script, would that script read to you like a twenty five million dollar idea? Oh my God! What I would do with twenty five million dollars if I was going to make a movie! No matter how insane or ridiculous the movie more than likely would be Lord Lord it would be better than Money Talks. Money Talks is the bottom of the barrel folks, if you cant do better than this movie you need to get out of the movie biz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Tucker Rocks in "Money Talks!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the feverishly-paced, interracial action comedy "Money Talks," hyper-kinetic comic Chris Tucker plays Franklin Hatchett, a two-bit, street-wise, ticket-scalping hustler pursued by a trigger-happy Belgian diamond smugglers, thuggish loan sharks, corrupt cops, and his own pregnant girlfriend. In his first starring role, Tucker clearly wants to imitate Eddie Murphy. Co-starring Charlie Sheen as a frustrated news reporter, a persuasive supporting cast, featuring Paul Sorvino and Heather Locklear, and crackling direction by Brett Ratner in his debut, "Money Talks" is nothing but rambunctious fun. The key to "Money Talks" is whether you find Chris Tucker either entertaining or obnoxious as a whiny-voiced dynamo whose motor-mouth never stops. If you've seen the doper farce "Friday" or last summer's mega-budget science fiction saga "The Fifth Element," you'll recognize Tucker by his bulging cue-ball eyes, pouting bottom lip, and beetle brows. Acting like Buckwheat with a subversive attitude, Tucker's trademark is his helium-pitched, fast-paced delivery with profanity between every other word. He can rattle off a line of dialogue faster than a Federal Express commercial. When Tucker isn't dodging bullets and careening in cars in "Money Talks," he is jive-talking and wise-cracking with the kind of brazen effrontery that either makes you laugh harder or aggravates you to no end. The screenplay by "Toy Story" scribes Joel Cohen and Alec Sokolow uses the classic theme of mistaken identity. Franklin is raking in some cool bucks as a scammer who fences stolen property at his car wash. Along comes scoop-hungry television news reporter James Russell (Charlie Sheen of "Platoon") who gets Hatchett arrested for soliciting goods. The incredulous Hatchett winds up shackled to an unidentified Belgian crook. Nobody recognizes the infamous Raymond Villard (G&eacute;rard Isma&euml;l of "Sp&eacute;cial Police"). During a routine bus transfer, Villard's henchmen blow up the vehicle and rescue their boss. Franklin survives by virtue of his being cuffed to the evil Villard. Aboard their escape helicopter, Franklin learns about a cache of $15 million in diamonds. Before the villains can kill him, our hero bails out of the chopper and splashes into the ocean. But Franklin is only leaping from one frying pan to another. It seems the L.A.P.D. has accused him of killing the fourteen prisoners and two police guards on the bus. Hatchett contacts Russell because he believes the news reporter might help him. Russell agrees to harbor the fugitive so he can get an exclusive as well as convince his British boss Barclay (David Warner of "Titanic") to re-hire him. Even that backfires when Russell finds himself implicated in Franklin's crime. Although the Cohen and Sokolow screenplay adheres to a predictable formula, the story generates enough thrills and chills as well as a neatly planted surprise or two to pass muster. Basically, "Money Talks" amounts to a chase thriller with all the villains pursuing Franklin. They're prepared to kill Franklin as well as anybody else who gets in their way. Meanwhile, not only must Russell keep Franklin alive, he also must humor the wealthy parents of his bride-to-be Grace Cipriani ("Melrose Place's" Heather Locklear). Happily, the plot confines both Grace and her catty mom Connie (Veronica Cartwright of "Alien") to their mansion. A lesser script would have involved them in a kidnapping plot. Most of the time, the film focuses on Franklin's center camera efforts to negotiate with his various enemies and adversaries. Freshman helmer Ratner supercharges the action with such momentum that it rarely let up on it fast and furious pace. If the second to a winning comedy is maintaining a lively, timely, breakneck clip, Ratner succeeds in spades. "Money Talks" careens from one plot twist to the next with marvelous abandon. Ratner nimbly directs a genuinely exciting chase scene, an explosive assault-on-the-bus scene, and the gunslinging pyrotechnical finale at the Los Angeles Coliseum where everybody wields a weapon. When he isn't proving his talent helming these second-unit action scenes, Ratner has fun playing Tucker and Sheen off each other. The solid, dependable, square-jawed Sheen makes a convincing straight man for Tucker. He is a news reporter with aspirations to join CBS-TV's "60 Minutes." Sheen's scenes with Tucker crackle with live-wire energy as the two spar with each other. The fierce, pugnacious camaraderie between these guys recalls the feisty relationship between Eddie Murphy and Nick Nolte in "48 Hrs," and that's what makes Tucker and Sheen such an offbeat and hilarious pair. Wolfish G&eacute;rard Isma&euml;l turns in an appropriately guttural performance that captures the hard-edged notoriety of the Belgian antagonist. The rest of the cast, including Sorvino as Russell's future father-in-law, Veronica Cartwright as the sneering wife, and Locklear as Russell's pretty bride acquit themselves well in peripheral roles. In minor roles, Paul Gleason of "Trading Places" stands out as a sympathetic but suspicious Lieutenant Bobby Pickett and Michael Wright as one of Franklin's schoolyard chums. "Money Talks" compares favorably to the old buddy comedies of Richard Pryor and Gene Wilder because it only wants to be a rollicking barrel of monkeys. If Chris Tucker can keep making agile comedies that click like "Money Talks," then Eddie Murphy has something to worry about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    staged memory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ruiresende84 (ruiresende84@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is another chapter of that kind of trend in comedy/action films: the biracial leading couple. This began with Lethal Weapon. There the comedy balance was divided between Glover and Gibson. But a lot of versions have come after, including the 3rd Die Hard, that thing with Rodman/Van Damme, or this film. It's as lame and short sight as any formula, but it worked for while. It doesn't anymore, and now while we see this, we wonder how it ever worked. This can only have a mild appeal on 2 levels: .you saw the films while you were teenager, and so they become part of larger memories of your evolution, and seeing them is a wink at yourself. .you assume how lame they are, and watch them on that base, as much as you watch a b film, filled with bad sets and laughable story lines, and assume that for the duration of the film. I did both of the above. But i know there's nothing here. There's actually an attempt to create a competent ending, the idea of a literal stage, where all the characters are brought, and all conflicts resolved, using the multiple possibilities that mise-en-sc&egrave;ne allows. But it's all worked out through a vulgar shootout, and a few body fights with no history. My opinion: 1/5 http://www.7eyes.wordpress.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Buddy Comic Action, Starring Chris Tucker & Some Explosions !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Joel Cohen) and (Alec Sokolow) wrote a mild script. However there was potential that I waited from the scriptwriters of (Toy Story  1995) and (Goodbye Lover  1998) to use, while they didn't. There are situations where the comedy could have been produced better (the party), or produced (the arm dealer's lair), but the action was the main point I guess, so it sure lost more chances for laughs. The buddy formula couldn't be felt. I mean (Charlie Sheen) wasn't given much of a character. All the lights are spotted on (Chris Tucker). Over and above, (Sheen) didn't do anything more than his usual Siberian performance and combing his hair well. They could have easily replaced him with a cardboard cutout ! Although he's not that charismatic, and too annoying in many places, (Tucker) proved that he can be a star in a movie. I just hated his method that whenever the camera is rolling; "I must not stop talking and talking and talking" to an extent where they should have renamed the movie (Chris Tucker Talks)!.. It's not funny at all. Anyway, he sure looked better, and talked less in director (Brett Ratner)'s next movies (Rush Hour). But maybe it gives you a hint about the reason why (Tucker) doesn't work much out of that franchise. The start is really good and inspiring. And there is fair action, especially at the third act. However the second act went astray a bit. Some violence bothered me as well, but not like the very last scene, where the 2 leads accept a portion of stolen diamonds for themselves, even the clean-cut reporter. It's a matter that will inflame more loud objections 2 years later in another action comedy; (Money Train). In 1997, the buddy formula was sizzling. I believe it's the (Lethal Weapon)'s effect. Many buddy comedies were released : (Out to Sea), (Fathers' Day), (Gone Fishin'), (Good Burger), (Mousehunt), (Nothing to Lose), and (Trial and Error). Many buddy action too : (Men in Black), (Double Team), and (The Edge). I think (Money Talks) is a reasonable action, somehow far from being a comedy, and originally not a complete "buddy" movie, being so close to one man show. Not bad man, and not excellent show either. Well, averagely entertaining is the word then. Seriously there was nothing super but that chain of explosions at the end, which if there was more like it; it could have fit as better buddy for (Tucker) !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film.....totally awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justtall
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Money Talk is totally a great film. Its one of my personal favorites, its one of the few movies that I can watch over and over again and laugh hard like it was my first time watching it. This film is centered on the duo of Franklin Hatchet, a hustler, and James Russell a very popular News reporter, and all of the problems they encounter. They're caught in crossfire between the cops, crooks, and commandos trying to receive a fortune of diamonds. Franklin was played by hilarious actor Chris Tucker and James played by Charlie Sheen. Their duo is totally ironic and unplanned; here you have a news reporter that had once reported a story explaining on how dangerous and bad Franklin was and here he was befriending him. One thing that I admired about the role of Franklin was his ability to socialize and make people laugh. For example James Russell was very stern about befriending and even being spotted around with Franklin, but Franklin's personality was so outrageous that Mr. Russell just couldn't resist. Chris Tucker did an amazing job playing the role of Franklin, Chris Tucker is the star of the movie, and his jokes were just so crazy and funny! It's like even if he didn't say anything his facial expressions alone are just funny! Chris was just so comedic in the movie that he didn't have to "try" to be funny he just naturally is. This movie is action meets comedy, the two genres are equal throughout the film, and I'm not a big fan of action but this movie is the only exception. Great Film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Tucker + Charlie Sheen = Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lahhlay M
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Classic Action Comedy. This in my opinion is Chris Tucker at his best. From the opening scene to the end, Chris Tucker is hilarious. From the funny looking hair cut to the cussing and singing, he reminds you of Eddie Murphy in Beverly Hills Cop. Charlie Sheen also does an impressive job. The action scenes are not spectacular, but it does a good job. Money talks is a good blend of Guns/Explosions and laughter. If your a fan of 48 Hours, Nothing To Lose or any other Action Comedy, Money talks is a must see. 7.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Tucker and Paul Sorvino should have had more scenes together
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie that made director Brett Ratner a recognizable name is mostly another white-yuppie-and-black-ghetto-guy-have-to-join-up kind of story (summer 1997 also saw the release of the Tim Robbins-Martin Lawrence buddy comedy "Nothing to Lose"). But as far as I'm concerned, Chris Tucker - who earlier that summer had starred in "The Fifth Element" - is always funny enough to merit at least some recognition; and anyway, this sort of flick is supposed to be silly. While Charlie Sheen is far less entertaining in his role, Paul Sorvino played such an interesting character that I agreed with one of my friends that he and Chris Tucker should have gotten more scenes together. Truth be told, I'd actually never heard of Vic Damone until I saw this movie. OK, so maybe we could be cynical and say that Chris Tucker just gets the same role in every movie. I still consider him funny, and I wish to assert that "Money Talks" is good for a few laughs. Worth seeing if only for that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i reject your reality and substitute my own...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wombathappiness
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1) unregistered helicopters ALWAYS get to fly at low altitudes through out a city without drawing any suspicion from the police or military 2)a buss loaded with enough c4 to blow it in half and ten feet in the air will always leave survivors 3) police always open fire on an unarmed man in the middle of a crowded restaurant. 4) a local street reporter can afford a 10,000sq ft. apartment in l.a. 5) Chris tucker deserves any type of a career at all these are all realities in coo coo ville, the wonderful land where this script was born. a land where the rivers run with gold and sugar falls from the sky. it's just a shame that Charlie Sheen and Principal Vernon got drug into this travesty
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Idea, But The On Screen Chemistry Wasn't There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fiendish_Dramaturgy
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a valiant effort by Tucker, in developing the formula he would later use with Jackie Chan. This character's behavior is identical to his later character of the Rush Hour line (trilogy?) with one exception...he was still a bit in Ruby Rod mode from the Fifth Element. That fact alone lends at least some amusement to this almost "workshop" attempt between Charlie Sheen and Chris Tucker. Thankfully, Tucker hit in with Chan whose personality kicks it with Tucker's over the top, sometimes flamboyant, mostly big mouth style. Sheen played it too close to the vest. His character here is rather silent, but that's better than the few scenes in which he actually speaks, as Sheen's dialog delivery here will make most audiences cringe. It seems as though he's attempting the quiet brooding bad guy persona of Mel Gibson in the Lethal Weapon franchise, but Sheen just doesn't seem to pull it off. Nor does he pull off the "hip" bad boy persona he attempts on again and off again, throughout this work. Sheen must have been off his game here, as we all know that the bad boy is something he CAN do well..or could, at least, when he was younger. This was filmed in 1996/1997, so I have to assume he was just off his game, as that was the heyday of his nefarious bad boy personal life. This work is still a bit entertaining, if you can manage to ignore Sheen, and just enjoy the fun story line, the awesome performance by Paul Sorvino and funny man Chris Tucker, and the somewhat decent action/comedy blend. All in all, if you're bored, this is a fun choice, but if you have to make time for it, it may be somewhat of a disappointment. It rates 5.9/10 from... the Fiend :.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This funny, lively, often violent action comedy is well done.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A low-level smooth talking hustler by the name of Franlin Hatchet (Chris Tucker) is on the run from the police, after a jailbreak. Which he is falsely accused of planning a violent jailbreak. Now the whole city is on his trail and the only one, who could clear his name is an ambitious television reporter James Russell (Charlie Sheen). Which is the only reason why Franklin was sent to prison, because of James. Now together, they find each other mixed-up with cops, crooks and euro-trash bad guys. Which Franklin knows that the man (Gerard Ismael) was chained-up with in the bus. He was trying to retrieve a fortune in diamonds. Directed by Brett Rather (Rush Hour Trilogy, X-Men 3:The Last Stand, Red Dragon) made an highly entertaining comedy with enough thrills and humour. Although the premise is familiar but Tucker's energetic comical performance makes this worth watching. DVD has an sharp anamorphic Widescreen (2.35:1) transfer (also in Pan & Scan) and an strong-Dolby Digital 5.1 Surround Sound. DVD includes the original theatrical trailer, cast information and star highlights by Tucker and Sheen. After the box office success of this film, Tucker went on the one of the leads of the "Rush Hour" movies. Paul Sorvino is amusingly cast as Russell's future father-in-law. Written by Joel Cohen and Alec Sokolow. Which they wrote films together like "Garfield", "Garfield:A Tale of Two Kitties" and "Toy Story". Tucker also executive produced the film. Super 35. (****/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    movie sucks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Twenty five million dollars was spent on this movie, those are earth dollars mind you not lunar cash or martian money, a fortune amassed to make an action-comedy. A dull humorless wretched affair entirely populated by unlikable fake characters. Do you know how much money twenty five million dollars is? Imagine it as yours for a moment, you have twenty five million dollars, think of all you can do with that much filthy loot, now do you want to invest all of that money in a Charlie Sheen/ Chris Tucker movie? Have you seen Money Talks? Well that's the script, would that script read to you like a twenty five million dollar idea? Oh my God! What I would do with twenty five million dollars if I was going to make a movie! No matter how insane or ridiculous the movie more than likely would be Lord Lord it would be better than Money Talks. Money Talks is the bottom of the barrel folks, if you cant do better than this movie you need to get out of the movie biz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Tucker Rocks in "Money Talks!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the feverishly-paced, interracial action comedy "Money Talks," hyper-kinetic comic Chris Tucker plays Franklin Hatchett, a two-bit, street-wise, ticket-scalping hustler pursued by a trigger-happy Belgian diamond smugglers, thuggish loan sharks, corrupt cops, and his own pregnant girlfriend. In his first starring role, Tucker clearly wants to imitate Eddie Murphy. Co-starring Charlie Sheen as a frustrated news reporter, a persuasive supporting cast, featuring Paul Sorvino and Heather Locklear, and crackling direction by Brett Ratner in his debut, "Money Talks" is nothing but rambunctious fun. The key to "Money Talks" is whether you find Chris Tucker either entertaining or obnoxious as a whiny-voiced dynamo whose motor-mouth never stops. If you've seen the doper farce "Friday" or last summer's mega-budget science fiction saga "The Fifth Element," you'll recognize Tucker by his bulging cue-ball eyes, pouting bottom lip, and beetle brows. Acting like Buckwheat with a subversive attitude, Tucker's trademark is his helium-pitched, fast-paced delivery with profanity between every other word. He can rattle off a line of dialogue faster than a Federal Express commercial. When Tucker isn't dodging bullets and careening in cars in "Money Talks," he is jive-talking and wise-cracking with the kind of brazen effrontery that either makes you laugh harder or aggravates you to no end. The screenplay by "Toy Story" scribes Joel Cohen and Alec Sokolow uses the classic theme of mistaken identity. Franklin is raking in some cool bucks as a scammer who fences stolen property at his car wash. Along comes scoop-hungry television news reporter James Russell (Charlie Sheen of "Platoon") who gets Hatchett arrested for soliciting goods. The incredulous Hatchett winds up shackled to an unidentified Belgian crook. Nobody recognizes the infamous Raymond Villard (G&eacute;rard Isma&euml;l of "Sp&eacute;cial Police"). During a routine bus transfer, Villard's henchmen blow up the vehicle and rescue their boss. Franklin survives by virtue of his being cuffed to the evil Villard. Aboard their escape helicopter, Franklin learns about a cache of $15 million in diamonds. Before the villains can kill him, our hero bails out of the chopper and splashes into the ocean. But Franklin is only leaping from one frying pan to another. It seems the L.A.P.D. has accused him of killing the fourteen prisoners and two police guards on the bus. Hatchett contacts Russell because he believes the news reporter might help him. Russell agrees to harbor the fugitive so he can get an exclusive as well as convince his British boss Barclay (David Warner of "Titanic") to re-hire him. Even that backfires when Russell finds himself implicated in Franklin's crime. Although the Cohen and Sokolow screenplay adheres to a predictable formula, the story generates enough thrills and chills as well as a neatly planted surprise or two to pass muster. Basically, "Money Talks" amounts to a chase thriller with all the villains pursuing Franklin. They're prepared to kill Franklin as well as anybody else who gets in their way. Meanwhile, not only must Russell keep Franklin alive, he also must humor the wealthy parents of his bride-to-be Grace Cipriani ("Melrose Place's" Heather Locklear). Happily, the plot confines both Grace and her catty mom Connie (Veronica Cartwright of "Alien") to their mansion. A lesser script would have involved them in a kidnapping plot. Most of the time, the film focuses on Franklin's center camera efforts to negotiate with his various enemies and adversaries. Freshman helmer Ratner supercharges the action with such momentum that it rarely let up on it fast and furious pace. If the second to a winning comedy is maintaining a lively, timely, breakneck clip, Ratner succeeds in spades. "Money Talks" careens from one plot twist to the next with marvelous abandon. Ratner nimbly directs a genuinely exciting chase scene, an explosive assault-on-the-bus scene, and the gunslinging pyrotechnical finale at the Los Angeles Coliseum where everybody wields a weapon. When he isn't proving his talent helming these second-unit action scenes, Ratner has fun playing Tucker and Sheen off each other. The solid, dependable, square-jawed Sheen makes a convincing straight man for Tucker. He is a news reporter with aspirations to join CBS-TV's "60 Minutes." Sheen's scenes with Tucker crackle with live-wire energy as the two spar with each other. The fierce, pugnacious camaraderie between these guys recalls the feisty relationship between Eddie Murphy and Nick Nolte in "48 Hrs," and that's what makes Tucker and Sheen such an offbeat and hilarious pair. Wolfish G&eacute;rard Isma&euml;l turns in an appropriately guttural performance that captures the hard-edged notoriety of the Belgian antagonist. The rest of the cast, including Sorvino as Russell's future father-in-law, Veronica Cartwright as the sneering wife, and Locklear as Russell's pretty bride acquit themselves well in peripheral roles. In minor roles, Paul Gleason of "Trading Places" stands out as a sympathetic but suspicious Lieutenant Bobby Pickett and Michael Wright as one of Franklin's schoolyard chums. "Money Talks" compares favorably to the old buddy comedies of Richard Pryor and Gene Wilder because it only wants to be a rollicking barrel of monkeys. If Chris Tucker can keep making agile comedies that click like "Money Talks," then Eddie Murphy has something to worry about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    staged memory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ruiresende84 (ruiresende84@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is another chapter of that kind of trend in comedy/action films: the biracial leading couple. This began with Lethal Weapon. There the comedy balance was divided between Glover and Gibson. But a lot of versions have come after, including the 3rd Die Hard, that thing with Rodman/Van Damme, or this film. It's as lame and short sight as any formula, but it worked for while. It doesn't anymore, and now while we see this, we wonder how it ever worked. This can only have a mild appeal on 2 levels: .you saw the films while you were teenager, and so they become part of larger memories of your evolution, and seeing them is a wink at yourself. .you assume how lame they are, and watch them on that base, as much as you watch a b film, filled with bad sets and laughable story lines, and assume that for the duration of the film. I did both of the above. But i know there's nothing here. There's actually an attempt to create a competent ending, the idea of a literal stage, where all the characters are brought, and all conflicts resolved, using the multiple possibilities that mise-en-sc&egrave;ne allows. But it's all worked out through a vulgar shootout, and a few body fights with no history. My opinion: 1/5 http://www.7eyes.wordpress.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Buddy Comic Action, Starring Chris Tucker & Some Explosions !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Joel Cohen) and (Alec Sokolow) wrote a mild script. However there was potential that I waited from the scriptwriters of (Toy Story  1995) and (Goodbye Lover  1998) to use, while they didn't. There are situations where the comedy could have been produced better (the party), or produced (the arm dealer's lair), but the action was the main point I guess, so it sure lost more chances for laughs. The buddy formula couldn't be felt. I mean (Charlie Sheen) wasn't given much of a character. All the lights are spotted on (Chris Tucker). Over and above, (Sheen) didn't do anything more than his usual Siberian performance and combing his hair well. They could have easily replaced him with a cardboard cutout ! Although he's not that charismatic, and too annoying in many places, (Tucker) proved that he can be a star in a movie. I just hated his method that whenever the camera is rolling; "I must not stop talking and talking and talking" to an extent where they should have renamed the movie (Chris Tucker Talks)!.. It's not funny at all. Anyway, he sure looked better, and talked less in director (Brett Ratner)'s next movies (Rush Hour). But maybe it gives you a hint about the reason why (Tucker) doesn't work much out of that franchise. The start is really good and inspiring. And there is fair action, especially at the third act. However the second act went astray a bit. Some violence bothered me as well, but not like the very last scene, where the 2 leads accept a portion of stolen diamonds for themselves, even the clean-cut reporter. It's a matter that will inflame more loud objections 2 years later in another action comedy; (Money Train). In 1997, the buddy formula was sizzling. I believe it's the (Lethal Weapon)'s effect. Many buddy comedies were released : (Out to Sea), (Fathers' Day), (Gone Fishin'), (Good Burger), (Mousehunt), (Nothing to Lose), and (Trial and Error). Many buddy action too : (Men in Black), (Double Team), and (The Edge). I think (Money Talks) is a reasonable action, somehow far from being a comedy, and originally not a complete "buddy" movie, being so close to one man show. Not bad man, and not excellent show either. Well, averagely entertaining is the word then. Seriously there was nothing super but that chain of explosions at the end, which if there was more like it; it could have fit as better buddy for (Tucker) !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film.....totally awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justtall
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Money Talk is totally a great film. Its one of my personal favorites, its one of the few movies that I can watch over and over again and laugh hard like it was my first time watching it. This film is centered on the duo of Franklin Hatchet, a hustler, and James Russell a very popular News reporter, and all of the problems they encounter. They're caught in crossfire between the cops, crooks, and commandos trying to receive a fortune of diamonds. Franklin was played by hilarious actor Chris Tucker and James played by Charlie Sheen. Their duo is totally ironic and unplanned; here you have a news reporter that had once reported a story explaining on how dangerous and bad Franklin was and here he was befriending him. One thing that I admired about the role of Franklin was his ability to socialize and make people laugh. For example James Russell was very stern about befriending and even being spotted around with Franklin, but Franklin's personality was so outrageous that Mr. Russell just couldn't resist. Chris Tucker did an amazing job playing the role of Franklin, Chris Tucker is the star of the movie, and his jokes were just so crazy and funny! It's like even if he didn't say anything his facial expressions alone are just funny! Chris was just so comedic in the movie that he didn't have to "try" to be funny he just naturally is. This movie is action meets comedy, the two genres are equal throughout the film, and I'm not a big fan of action but this movie is the only exception. Great Film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Tucker + Charlie Sheen = Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lahhlay M
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Classic Action Comedy. This in my opinion is Chris Tucker at his best. From the opening scene to the end, Chris Tucker is hilarious. From the funny looking hair cut to the cussing and singing, he reminds you of Eddie Murphy in Beverly Hills Cop. Charlie Sheen also does an impressive job. The action scenes are not spectacular, but it does a good job. Money talks is a good blend of Guns/Explosions and laughter. If your a fan of 48 Hours, Nothing To Lose or any other Action Comedy, Money talks is a must see. 7.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Tucker and Paul Sorvino should have had more scenes together
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie that made director Brett Ratner a recognizable name is mostly another white-yuppie-and-black-ghetto-guy-have-to-join-up kind of story (summer 1997 also saw the release of the Tim Robbins-Martin Lawrence buddy comedy "Nothing to Lose"). But as far as I'm concerned, Chris Tucker - who earlier that summer had starred in "The Fifth Element" - is always funny enough to merit at least some recognition; and anyway, this sort of flick is supposed to be silly. While Charlie Sheen is far less entertaining in his role, Paul Sorvino played such an interesting character that I agreed with one of my friends that he and Chris Tucker should have gotten more scenes together. Truth be told, I'd actually never heard of Vic Damone until I saw this movie. OK, so maybe we could be cynical and say that Chris Tucker just gets the same role in every movie. I still consider him funny, and I wish to assert that "Money Talks" is good for a few laughs. Worth seeing if only for that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i reject your reality and substitute my own...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wombathappiness
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1) unregistered helicopters ALWAYS get to fly at low altitudes through out a city without drawing any suspicion from the police or military 2)a buss loaded with enough c4 to blow it in half and ten feet in the air will always leave survivors 3) police always open fire on an unarmed man in the middle of a crowded restaurant. 4) a local street reporter can afford a 10,000sq ft. apartment in l.a. 5) Chris tucker deserves any type of a career at all these are all realities in coo coo ville, the wonderful land where this script was born. a land where the rivers run with gold and sugar falls from the sky. it's just a shame that Charlie Sheen and Principal Vernon got drug into this travesty
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Idea, But The On Screen Chemistry Wasn't There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fiendish_Dramaturgy
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a valiant effort by Tucker, in developing the formula he would later use with Jackie Chan. This character's behavior is identical to his later character of the Rush Hour line (trilogy?) with one exception...he was still a bit in Ruby Rod mode from the Fifth Element. That fact alone lends at least some amusement to this almost "workshop" attempt between Charlie Sheen and Chris Tucker. Thankfully, Tucker hit in with Chan whose personality kicks it with Tucker's over the top, sometimes flamboyant, mostly big mouth style. Sheen played it too close to the vest. His character here is rather silent, but that's better than the few scenes in which he actually speaks, as Sheen's dialog delivery here will make most audiences cringe. It seems as though he's attempting the quiet brooding bad guy persona of Mel Gibson in the Lethal Weapon franchise, but Sheen just doesn't seem to pull it off. Nor does he pull off the "hip" bad boy persona he attempts on again and off again, throughout this work. Sheen must have been off his game here, as we all know that the bad boy is something he CAN do well..or could, at least, when he was younger. This was filmed in 1996/1997, so I have to assume he was just off his game, as that was the heyday of his nefarious bad boy personal life. This work is still a bit entertaining, if you can manage to ignore Sheen, and just enjoy the fun story line, the awesome performance by Paul Sorvino and funny man Chris Tucker, and the somewhat decent action/comedy blend. All in all, if you're bored, this is a fun choice, but if you have to make time for it, it may be somewhat of a disappointment. It rates 5.9/10 from... the Fiend :.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This funny, lively, often violent action comedy is well done.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A low-level smooth talking hustler by the name of Franlin Hatchet (Chris Tucker) is on the run from the police, after a jailbreak. Which he is falsely accused of planning a violent jailbreak. Now the whole city is on his trail and the only one, who could clear his name is an ambitious television reporter James Russell (Charlie Sheen). Which is the only reason why Franklin was sent to prison, because of James. Now together, they find each other mixed-up with cops, crooks and euro-trash bad guys. Which Franklin knows that the man (Gerard Ismael) was chained-up with in the bus. He was trying to retrieve a fortune in diamonds. Directed by Brett Rather (Rush Hour Trilogy, X-Men 3:The Last Stand, Red Dragon) made an highly entertaining comedy with enough thrills and humour. Although the premise is familiar but Tucker's energetic comical performance makes this worth watching. DVD has an sharp anamorphic Widescreen (2.35:1) transfer (also in Pan & Scan) and an strong-Dolby Digital 5.1 Surround Sound. DVD includes the original theatrical trailer, cast information and star highlights by Tucker and Sheen. After the box office success of this film, Tucker went on the one of the leads of the "Rush Hour" movies. Paul Sorvino is amusingly cast as Russell's future father-in-law. Written by Joel Cohen and Alec Sokolow. Which they wrote films together like "Garfield", "Garfield:A Tale of Two Kitties" and "Toy Story". Tucker also executive produced the film. Super 35. (****/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    movie sucks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jessegehrig
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Twenty five million dollars was spent on this movie, those are earth dollars mind you not lunar cash or martian money, a fortune amassed to make an action-comedy. A dull humorless wretched affair entirely populated by unlikable fake characters. Do you know how much money twenty five million dollars is? Imagine it as yours for a moment, you have twenty five million dollars, think of all you can do with that much filthy loot, now do you want to invest all of that money in a Charlie Sheen/ Chris Tucker movie? Have you seen Money Talks? Well that's the script, would that script read to you like a twenty five million dollar idea? Oh my God! What I would do with twenty five million dollars if I was going to make a movie! No matter how insane or ridiculous the movie more than likely would be Lord Lord it would be better than Money Talks. Money Talks is the bottom of the barrel folks, if you cant do better than this movie you need to get out of the movie biz.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Tucker Rocks in "Money Talks!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the feverishly-paced, interracial action comedy "Money Talks," hyper-kinetic comic Chris Tucker plays Franklin Hatchett, a two-bit, street-wise, ticket-scalping hustler pursued by a trigger-happy Belgian diamond smugglers, thuggish loan sharks, corrupt cops, and his own pregnant girlfriend. In his first starring role, Tucker clearly wants to imitate Eddie Murphy. Co-starring Charlie Sheen as a frustrated news reporter, a persuasive supporting cast, featuring Paul Sorvino and Heather Locklear, and crackling direction by Brett Ratner in his debut, "Money Talks" is nothing but rambunctious fun. The key to "Money Talks" is whether you find Chris Tucker either entertaining or obnoxious as a whiny-voiced dynamo whose motor-mouth never stops. If you've seen the doper farce "Friday" or last summer's mega-budget science fiction saga "The Fifth Element," you'll recognize Tucker by his bulging cue-ball eyes, pouting bottom lip, and beetle brows. Acting like Buckwheat with a subversive attitude, Tucker's trademark is his helium-pitched, fast-paced delivery with profanity between every other word. He can rattle off a line of dialogue faster than a Federal Express commercial. When Tucker isn't dodging bullets and careening in cars in "Money Talks," he is jive-talking and wise-cracking with the kind of brazen effrontery that either makes you laugh harder or aggravates you to no end. The screenplay by "Toy Story" scribes Joel Cohen and Alec Sokolow uses the classic theme of mistaken identity. Franklin is raking in some cool bucks as a scammer who fences stolen property at his car wash. Along comes scoop-hungry television news reporter James Russell (Charlie Sheen of "Platoon") who gets Hatchett arrested for soliciting goods. The incredulous Hatchett winds up shackled to an unidentified Belgian crook. Nobody recognizes the infamous Raymond Villard (G&eacute;rard Isma&euml;l of "Sp&eacute;cial Police"). During a routine bus transfer, Villard's henchmen blow up the vehicle and rescue their boss. Franklin survives by virtue of his being cuffed to the evil Villard. Aboard their escape helicopter, Franklin learns about a cache of $15 million in diamonds. Before the villains can kill him, our hero bails out of the chopper and splashes into the ocean. But Franklin is only leaping from one frying pan to another. It seems the L.A.P.D. has accused him of killing the fourteen prisoners and two police guards on the bus. Hatchett contacts Russell because he believes the news reporter might help him. Russell agrees to harbor the fugitive so he can get an exclusive as well as convince his British boss Barclay (David Warner of "Titanic") to re-hire him. Even that backfires when Russell finds himself implicated in Franklin's crime. Although the Cohen and Sokolow screenplay adheres to a predictable formula, the story generates enough thrills and chills as well as a neatly planted surprise or two to pass muster. Basically, "Money Talks" amounts to a chase thriller with all the villains pursuing Franklin. They're prepared to kill Franklin as well as anybody else who gets in their way. Meanwhile, not only must Russell keep Franklin alive, he also must humor the wealthy parents of his bride-to-be Grace Cipriani ("Melrose Place's" Heather Locklear). Happily, the plot confines both Grace and her catty mom Connie (Veronica Cartwright of "Alien") to their mansion. A lesser script would have involved them in a kidnapping plot. Most of the time, the film focuses on Franklin's center camera efforts to negotiate with his various enemies and adversaries. Freshman helmer Ratner supercharges the action with such momentum that it rarely let up on it fast and furious pace. If the second to a winning comedy is maintaining a lively, timely, breakneck clip, Ratner succeeds in spades. "Money Talks" careens from one plot twist to the next with marvelous abandon. Ratner nimbly directs a genuinely exciting chase scene, an explosive assault-on-the-bus scene, and the gunslinging pyrotechnical finale at the Los Angeles Coliseum where everybody wields a weapon. When he isn't proving his talent helming these second-unit action scenes, Ratner has fun playing Tucker and Sheen off each other. The solid, dependable, square-jawed Sheen makes a convincing straight man for Tucker. He is a news reporter with aspirations to join CBS-TV's "60 Minutes." Sheen's scenes with Tucker crackle with live-wire energy as the two spar with each other. The fierce, pugnacious camaraderie between these guys recalls the feisty relationship between Eddie Murphy and Nick Nolte in "48 Hrs," and that's what makes Tucker and Sheen such an offbeat and hilarious pair. Wolfish G&eacute;rard Isma&euml;l turns in an appropriately guttural performance that captures the hard-edged notoriety of the Belgian antagonist. The rest of the cast, including Sorvino as Russell's future father-in-law, Veronica Cartwright as the sneering wife, and Locklear as Russell's pretty bride acquit themselves well in peripheral roles. In minor roles, Paul Gleason of "Trading Places" stands out as a sympathetic but suspicious Lieutenant Bobby Pickett and Michael Wright as one of Franklin's schoolyard chums. "Money Talks" compares favorably to the old buddy comedies of Richard Pryor and Gene Wilder because it only wants to be a rollicking barrel of monkeys. If Chris Tucker can keep making agile comedies that click like "Money Talks," then Eddie Murphy has something to worry about.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    staged memory
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ruiresende84 (ruiresende84@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is another chapter of that kind of trend in comedy/action films: the biracial leading couple. This began with Lethal Weapon. There the comedy balance was divided between Glover and Gibson. But a lot of versions have come after, including the 3rd Die Hard, that thing with Rodman/Van Damme, or this film. It's as lame and short sight as any formula, but it worked for while. It doesn't anymore, and now while we see this, we wonder how it ever worked. This can only have a mild appeal on 2 levels: .you saw the films while you were teenager, and so they become part of larger memories of your evolution, and seeing them is a wink at yourself. .you assume how lame they are, and watch them on that base, as much as you watch a b film, filled with bad sets and laughable story lines, and assume that for the duration of the film. I did both of the above. But i know there's nothing here. There's actually an attempt to create a competent ending, the idea of a literal stage, where all the characters are brought, and all conflicts resolved, using the multiple possibilities that mise-en-sc&egrave;ne allows. But it's all worked out through a vulgar shootout, and a few body fights with no history. My opinion: 1/5 http://www.7eyes.wordpress.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Buddy Comic Action, Starring Chris Tucker & Some Explosions !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Joel Cohen) and (Alec Sokolow) wrote a mild script. However there was potential that I waited from the scriptwriters of (Toy Story  1995) and (Goodbye Lover  1998) to use, while they didn't. There are situations where the comedy could have been produced better (the party), or produced (the arm dealer's lair), but the action was the main point I guess, so it sure lost more chances for laughs. The buddy formula couldn't be felt. I mean (Charlie Sheen) wasn't given much of a character. All the lights are spotted on (Chris Tucker). Over and above, (Sheen) didn't do anything more than his usual Siberian performance and combing his hair well. They could have easily replaced him with a cardboard cutout ! Although he's not that charismatic, and too annoying in many places, (Tucker) proved that he can be a star in a movie. I just hated his method that whenever the camera is rolling; "I must not stop talking and talking and talking" to an extent where they should have renamed the movie (Chris Tucker Talks)!.. It's not funny at all. Anyway, he sure looked better, and talked less in director (Brett Ratner)'s next movies (Rush Hour). But maybe it gives you a hint about the reason why (Tucker) doesn't work much out of that franchise. The start is really good and inspiring. And there is fair action, especially at the third act. However the second act went astray a bit. Some violence bothered me as well, but not like the very last scene, where the 2 leads accept a portion of stolen diamonds for themselves, even the clean-cut reporter. It's a matter that will inflame more loud objections 2 years later in another action comedy; (Money Train). In 1997, the buddy formula was sizzling. I believe it's the (Lethal Weapon)'s effect. Many buddy comedies were released : (Out to Sea), (Fathers' Day), (Gone Fishin'), (Good Burger), (Mousehunt), (Nothing to Lose), and (Trial and Error). Many buddy action too : (Men in Black), (Double Team), and (The Edge). I think (Money Talks) is a reasonable action, somehow far from being a comedy, and originally not a complete "buddy" movie, being so close to one man show. Not bad man, and not excellent show either. Well, averagely entertaining is the word then. Seriously there was nothing super but that chain of explosions at the end, which if there was more like it; it could have fit as better buddy for (Tucker) !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great film.....totally awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    justtall
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Money Talk is totally a great film. Its one of my personal favorites, its one of the few movies that I can watch over and over again and laugh hard like it was my first time watching it. This film is centered on the duo of Franklin Hatchet, a hustler, and James Russell a very popular News reporter, and all of the problems they encounter. They're caught in crossfire between the cops, crooks, and commandos trying to receive a fortune of diamonds. Franklin was played by hilarious actor Chris Tucker and James played by Charlie Sheen. Their duo is totally ironic and unplanned; here you have a news reporter that had once reported a story explaining on how dangerous and bad Franklin was and here he was befriending him. One thing that I admired about the role of Franklin was his ability to socialize and make people laugh. For example James Russell was very stern about befriending and even being spotted around with Franklin, but Franklin's personality was so outrageous that Mr. Russell just couldn't resist. Chris Tucker did an amazing job playing the role of Franklin, Chris Tucker is the star of the movie, and his jokes were just so crazy and funny! It's like even if he didn't say anything his facial expressions alone are just funny! Chris was just so comedic in the movie that he didn't have to "try" to be funny he just naturally is. This movie is action meets comedy, the two genres are equal throughout the film, and I'm not a big fan of action but this movie is the only exception. Great Film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Tucker + Charlie Sheen = Brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lahhlay M
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Classic Action Comedy. This in my opinion is Chris Tucker at his best. From the opening scene to the end, Chris Tucker is hilarious. From the funny looking hair cut to the cussing and singing, he reminds you of Eddie Murphy in Beverly Hills Cop. Charlie Sheen also does an impressive job. The action scenes are not spectacular, but it does a good job. Money talks is a good blend of Guns/Explosions and laughter. If your a fan of 48 Hours, Nothing To Lose or any other Action Comedy, Money talks is a must see. 7.4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Tucker and Paul Sorvino should have had more scenes together
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie that made director Brett Ratner a recognizable name is mostly another white-yuppie-and-black-ghetto-guy-have-to-join-up kind of story (summer 1997 also saw the release of the Tim Robbins-Martin Lawrence buddy comedy "Nothing to Lose"). But as far as I'm concerned, Chris Tucker - who earlier that summer had starred in "The Fifth Element" - is always funny enough to merit at least some recognition; and anyway, this sort of flick is supposed to be silly. While Charlie Sheen is far less entertaining in his role, Paul Sorvino played such an interesting character that I agreed with one of my friends that he and Chris Tucker should have gotten more scenes together. Truth be told, I'd actually never heard of Vic Damone until I saw this movie. OK, so maybe we could be cynical and say that Chris Tucker just gets the same role in every movie. I still consider him funny, and I wish to assert that "Money Talks" is good for a few laughs. Worth seeing if only for that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i reject your reality and substitute my own...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wombathappiness
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1) unregistered helicopters ALWAYS get to fly at low altitudes through out a city without drawing any suspicion from the police or military 2)a buss loaded with enough c4 to blow it in half and ten feet in the air will always leave survivors 3) police always open fire on an unarmed man in the middle of a crowded restaurant. 4) a local street reporter can afford a 10,000sq ft. apartment in l.a. 5) Chris tucker deserves any type of a career at all these are all realities in coo coo ville, the wonderful land where this script was born. a land where the rivers run with gold and sugar falls from the sky. it's just a shame that Charlie Sheen and Principal Vernon got drug into this travesty
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Idea, But The On Screen Chemistry Wasn't There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fiendish_Dramaturgy
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was a valiant effort by Tucker, in developing the formula he would later use with Jackie Chan. This character's behavior is identical to his later character of the Rush Hour line (trilogy?) with one exception...he was still a bit in Ruby Rod mode from the Fifth Element. That fact alone lends at least some amusement to this almost "workshop" attempt between Charlie Sheen and Chris Tucker. Thankfully, Tucker hit in with Chan whose personality kicks it with Tucker's over the top, sometimes flamboyant, mostly big mouth style. Sheen played it too close to the vest. His character here is rather silent, but that's better than the few scenes in which he actually speaks, as Sheen's dialog delivery here will make most audiences cringe. It seems as though he's attempting the quiet brooding bad guy persona of Mel Gibson in the Lethal Weapon franchise, but Sheen just doesn't seem to pull it off. Nor does he pull off the "hip" bad boy persona he attempts on again and off again, throughout this work. Sheen must have been off his game here, as we all know that the bad boy is something he CAN do well..or could, at least, when he was younger. This was filmed in 1996/1997, so I have to assume he was just off his game, as that was the heyday of his nefarious bad boy personal life. This work is still a bit entertaining, if you can manage to ignore Sheen, and just enjoy the fun story line, the awesome performance by Paul Sorvino and funny man Chris Tucker, and the somewhat decent action/comedy blend. All in all, if you're bored, this is a fun choice, but if you have to make time for it, it may be somewhat of a disappointment. It rates 5.9/10 from... the Fiend :.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This funny, lively, often violent action comedy is well done.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A low-level smooth talking hustler by the name of Franlin Hatchet (Chris Tucker) is on the run from the police, after a jailbreak. Which he is falsely accused of planning a violent jailbreak. Now the whole city is on his trail and the only one, who could clear his name is an ambitious television reporter James Russell (Charlie Sheen). Which is the only reason why Franklin was sent to prison, because of James. Now together, they find each other mixed-up with cops, crooks and euro-trash bad guys. Which Franklin knows that the man (Gerard Ismael) was chained-up with in the bus. He was trying to retrieve a fortune in diamonds. Directed by Brett Rather (Rush Hour Trilogy, X-Men 3:The Last Stand, Red Dragon) made an highly entertaining comedy with enough thrills and humour. Although the premise is familiar but Tucker's energetic comical performance makes this worth watching. DVD has an sharp anamorphic Widescreen (2.35:1) transfer (also in Pan & Scan) and an strong-Dolby Digital 5.1 Surround Sound. DVD includes the original theatrical trailer, cast information and star highlights by Tucker and Sheen. After the box office success of this film, Tucker went on the one of the leads of the "Rush Hour" movies. Paul Sorvino is amusingly cast as Russell's future father-in-law. Written by Joel Cohen and Alec Sokolow. Which they wrote films together like "Garfield", "Garfield:A Tale of Two Kitties" and "Toy Story". Tucker also executive produced the film. Super 35. (****/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
