<filme>
 <id>
  883
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120303
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  No Embalo da Am&eacute;rica
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Karchy (Brad Renfro) is a boy in school who has moved from Hungary to America in the 1960's. He is struggling in school and trying to adjust to America's culture. He then hears about a ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Karchy (Brad Renfro) is a boy in school who has moved from Hungary to America in the 1960's. He is struggling in school and trying to adjust to America's culture. He then hears about a radio DJ Billy Magic (Kevin Bacon) who holds a contest for a Student Hall of Fame every week. When Karchy finally wins after several weeks, he spends more time with Billy Magic...a man with money, girls, and glam. Karchy thinks that by spending time with Magic, he can become "cool". He then starts telling lies, to make himself seem greater than he really is. But when his lies begin hurting the people he cares about, he realizes that it isn't worth telling lies if it affects your friends. Afterwards, he learns to accept himself for the person he is, and gives up lying. And as for Billy Magic, it turns out that he pays his price for all the lies that he has told as well....
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   hall of fame
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   radio
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1960s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   money
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   radio dj
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Guy Ferland
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Joe Eszterhas
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kevin Bacon
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Brad Renfro
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Maximilian Schell
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worshiping the wrong idol .............
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Renfro is sucked into the glitzy world of ego maniacal disc jockey Billy Magic, Kevin Bacon. It is Cleveland, 1961, and Bacon finds Renfro the perfect patsy for assisting him in a payola racket. I could have done without the melodramatic subplot of Renfro and his Father, Maximilian Schell, sweating their Citizenship Papers, as it merely detracts from the main story. The 60s atmosphere is well done, with some great cars and an outstanding soundtrack. I wish the movie had focused more on Bacon's corrupt character, because the supporting cast, other than Calista Flockheart, as a love interest, is mostly wasted. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Telling Lies, Such Sweet Big Lies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know in another time and in another age in Hollywood the story told in Telling Lies In America about the Fifties and the age of payola might have had Brad Renfro's character be a populist hero if it were Frank Capra doing it. Billy Wilder or Preston Sturges might have made Kevin Bacon's character one of their acid studies in cynicism. As it is Telling Lies In America is a good film with an accurate depiction of the times it's set in. But it falls way short of a classic. Brad Renfro plays a 17 year old high school student, a refugee from the Hungarian Rebellion with his father Maximilian Schell who would desperately like to fit in. The father who was a doctor in Hungary now working some menial job while waiting his citizenship spends a ton of money to get Renfro into some private Catholic school. Still with all the handicaps of an immigrant, Renfro who's now deep in America's rock and roll culture hits on a plan to gain instant popularity. Some radio station with disc jockey Kevin Bacon is running a popularity contest, the high school hall of fame. If someone has friends write in postcards suggesting a person they get into this high school hall of fame. So what does Renfro do, but forge a bunch of postcards and he gets his entr&eacute;e with Kevin Bacon who offers him a job as an assistant, basically a glorified go-for. Of course it's all one big scam because Kevin Bacon is hip deep in the world of payola where he accepts all kinds of favors in sealed envelopes from agents to play their artist's records on his show. What he needed was a kid naive enough not to question what's going on around him and just be grateful for the relatively large amounts of money he's earning with Bacon as opposed to Renfro's previous job in a poultry market. It was the Fifties and I well remember a lot of rock and roll disc jockeys losing their careers over this, the most famous being Alan Freed. Kevin Bacon who has made a good career in villainous character parts is one cynical creep in this film. Two generations before, Kirk Douglas would have gone to town on this role. Maximilian Schell should also be praised as the wise father who because of the generation gap has different ideas about the American dream than Renfro. But there's no mistaking the bond these two have for each other. Telling Lies In America has a lot of good elements and it's an interesting story. But it's short of a master director to make it a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pants on Fire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the early 1960s, Cleveland, Ohio immigrant teenager Brad Renfro (as Karchy Jonas) struggles with adolescence and assimilation. Mr. Renfro is working on eradicating the remnants of his Hungarian accent (his "th" sound). Meanwhile, slick disc jockey Kevin Bacon (as Billy Magic) arrives in town (one step ahead of the law), to spin "sweaty collar and dirty fingernail music" on the local rock 'n' roll radio station. Mr. Bacon is a payola player, who needs an underage kid to handle money illegal exchanges. When Renfro cheats on a radio contest, Bacon offers him big bucks to serve as "unwitting accomplice"... Bacon swaggers through his role with perfection. And, Renfro is incredible, in a very difficult role; capturing the vulnerability of youth, as he struggles to both adopt and resist Bacon's seductive persona. Calista Flockhart (as Diney Majeski) is very effective, as Renfro's "older woman" love interest. Their performances should have received some award consideration. Maximilian Schell (as Istvan Jonas) would have been more believable as Renfro's grandfather, to support the obviously wider than envisioned cultural gap between the characters. A few of the scenes are silly, but many more work, due to director Guy Ferland and his convincing cast. "I make things up sometimes," Renfro reveals. Don't we all. "Telling Lies in America" certainly breaks no new ground - but, it revisits cinematic themes in great style. The film builds to a fine conclusion, and the music is terrific. ******** Telling Lies in America (8/2/97) Guy Ferland ~ Brad Renfro, Kevin Bacon, Calista Flockhart, Maximilian Schell
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Movie About Lying & America !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply lying is all over the world, all over the history, or rather it's inseparable part in the human nature (even in its most respectable figures like George Washington !). But the thing to assure here is that lying is definitely more profitable in America ! This movie makes its main character triumphs when he finishes his predicament by lying (in the trial), and gains his goal /the American nationality when he attested to the other's lies, not to mention the situation of the black singer and how he already attests to the announcer's lie as co-writer of his hit song just to be popular. The movie was such an eloquent when it paralleled the boy's insistence and bravery to lie in the face of justice, with him getting rid of his infantile innocence (the lisp) in the same time to be ultimately American Man ! Lying in any society is a way of living to achieve what do you want but with something to lose; here it was his love (logically as his highest truth). I didn't like only the confession of the announcer (the professional swindler) at the end that he didn't have anything to do with writing the black singer's song; that was sudden incomprehensible idealism !? (Joe Eszterhas) in one rare time gives us something to think instead of the regular amount of grand sex and violence. Although I'm not sure that the journey of (Karchy 'Chucky' Jonas) presented the experiment's essence of (Eszterhas) himself but I'm sure that it's his American book of wisdom. Actually the movie's philosophy proves that if you lied then you must grasp that all of the rest will lie to you, so you've got to : comprehend it, to attest it (if it gives you any profit), and the most important of all not to believe it ! As we don't lose when we lie (the boy reached the famous announcer by false letters) but we lose when we believe the lie (like the boy when he believed in the announcer as a mentor and an idol). So It's not just a movie, it's some amusing as well as toughing lesson about pragmatism ! The most crafty and witty meaning this movie shows impliedly is that if you want to be an American mature then you must be a brave lair ! Sense the smartness of it while observing the success of one fat lair at one gigantic communication medium (the radio at the 1950s as the mass media), and the lie of the boy at the end which made him eventually an American citizen. So If all the people would lie then who'll going to believe ? In fact It's a world where truth is something not only rare but not that needed also !! It might be the biggest satire about lying and the American splendor from the time of George Washington to the 1950s (where the events take place) till the 1990s where this movie had been made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad Renfro, RIP
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Renfro's untimely death brought this movie to mind. I haven't seen Joe Esterhasz's "Telling Lies in America" in a few years, but I remember that it was a good movie, Esterhasz's reputation notwithstanding. It goes like this. Karchy Jonas (Renfro) is a Hungarian immigrant in Ohio in the early '60s. He has trouble fitting in with the world around him, partly due to his trouble pronouncing a "th" sound, and feels disenchanted with the Catholic church that he and his father Istvan (Maximilian Schell) attend. But when he hooks up with DJ Billy Magic (Kevin Bacon), his luck changes...with some strings attached. I interpret this movie as sort of the flip side of "American Graffiti". In that case, they were all the same ilk and all fit in with everything. In this case, Karchy tries to fit in but has trouble doing it, and so his only option is to hook up with the shady Billy. More than just a nostalgia piece - though there are some oldies - we see Karchy's inner conflict between his desire to be a modern American, and trying to maintain his ties with his past. Overall, I recommend this one. I think that it would have been kind of fun to play that trick with the confession booth. And just remember what people tell you about Spanish flower. Also starring Calista Flockhart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie is a gem!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EighthSense
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll try not to repeat all of what the other reviewers have written already. Kevin Bacon is unbelievable in this role, he wears his part as a slick, sexy, supremely confident and laid-back DJ so well. He makes it impossible to imagine any other actor in this role. Every scene he appears in is to be savored. His voice is ideally suited for the broadcasts he makes. Seeing his easy charm and friendly manner is no wonder the young, innocent Kartchie idolized him. Visually, the movie is beautiful, rich, with a great soundtrack, excellent screenplay, in short, 100% enjoyment. Very nicely photographed, with very good sound direction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    okay but potentially excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spj-4
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this movie was okay but not excellent It had the makings of excellence but didn't deliver mastery. 'Frustrating' is a word that comes to mind for my opinion of it. I liked its music, even its plot, & innocence of some of its characters. I liked too, the underlying moral dilemmas of a young man of sincere & genuine character struggling with the plight inflicted upon him & them in broader prospectives. But it has unimportant matters glossed over, without explanation or rationality, except for naivety for the gullible. Like the DJ Bacon character & his prot&eacute;g&eacute; (& others supposedly exacting this scenario in other cities) but so detached from the reality of their situations. LIES is the underlying motive of integrity in situations anything but far from black & white. So it could have been the title of a film disguising lies. But it was not guilty of that by truer assessment. So what about layers of LIES??? Are little white lies beyond a couple of persons, not surely to be distinguished from blatant & career or character destructive lies, layer upon layer, lawyer upon lawyer, judge upon judge, to be evaluated as lies??? So a movie that is 7 out of 10 is neither 5 or 9 out of 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Liars
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Telling Lies in America" is a film that seems to have gone directly to video. It certainly deserved a wider audience because what Guy Ferland, the director does with the screen play Joe Eszterhas wrote for the film. Mr. Eszterhas is a man that can write, although some of his efforts have misfired. If you haven't seen the film, perhaps you should stop reading here. The basic problem with the film is the casting of Brad Renfro as the main character of the film. While this actor is not a bad actor, he seems miscast as this Karchy Jonas. Most comments in this forum focus on the fact Karchy has no accent, but having been in Cleveland for about seven years, explain that he already has a command of the language. Yes, he might stumble upon certain words, as shown in the film, but basically the character is believable. The only thing is that Mr. Renfro looks an older fourteen, rather than the seventeen he is in the film. This fact becomes painfully apparent in his relationship with Diney, and with the older woman Billy decides to have him experience sex for the first time. We are not saying it's not possible, because it can easily have been the case, which might have been derived from an experience of Mr. Eszterhas life. The other thing that doesn't ring true is the relationship between Karchy and his father. It appears that he can do whatever he wants and it's OK with the old man. Usually in the case of immigrant families, it's just the opposite. People immigrating to this country tend to be more protective, demanding discipline and obedience that is nowhere to be seen in the film. Also, Karchy's behavior in school would have probably grounded him forever, but it never comes into play. The marvelous Kevin Bacon is the best asset this film has going for itself. Not only is Mr. Bacon the most versatile of the current actors working in films, he brings such an intelligent take to his take on Billy Magic, the DJ of the local radio station that sees right through the lies Karchy Jonas tells. Being a liar himself, Billy can pick a liar whenever he sees one, as is the case when he meets Jonas. Billy Magic has no scruples. He takes money from the record companies, but he has Karchy pick the envelopes. The cast is good. Maximilian Schell, plays the father, Dr. Jonas, a man so decent, one wonders where did Karchy go wrong. He seems to be a loving father, albeit a distant one. Is it perhaps the fact that the son has embraced the American culture with too much gusto? That might explain the difference, although Karchy is never disrespectful to the old man. Calista Flockhart is seen as Diney, the mousy worker at the poultry shop where young Karchy works after school. Ms. Flockhart is perfect as the older girl that inspires love in the young man. Luke Wilson is seen as the man in charge of the shop. Paul Dooley makes a wonderful Father Norton, the man who dares put Karchy in his place. Notable in the film is the use of the popular songs that one hears in the sound track. It made perfect sense the use of those tunes since the background is a popular radio station that catered to teenagers. This is a film that should be seen by more people because of the good work the director and screen writer have done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ever felt like an outsider? Sure, lots of times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    helpless_dancer
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Interesting and well done look at the American pop scene in the sexy sixties. Featuring a oversexed, insecure loser named Karchy who teams up with another oversexed loser disc jockey intent on preying and playing just one more gig in the nowhere business of top 40 music. The charismatic DJ, a burned out cynic, has a history of using unpopular teens to make illegal profits or to cheat them in business deals; which, of course, continues as he rolls into a new town amid a flurry of excitement and adulation. As the rollicking DJ and the impressionable teen play out their drama, another is occurring as Karchy tries to woo an older woman who, for some reason, shows an interest in the love struck teen. Different from most of the gunk coming out today: well worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anent Soundtrack
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (SaxoTenor@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a performing musician in Paris, France in the 1960's I often used to play a tune entitled "Night Walk". In this movie the same tune is played but is called "Sleep Walk". How could the same tune have two titles? Does anyone know the answer to that? Otherwise the film was not so hot unless you have nostalgia for views of Cleveland, Ohio. How come the Hungarian refugee had no foreign accent? And I failed to understand why the George Washington question and answer session gave the judge the right to allow citizenship for both the father and son in spite of the fact that the son had obviously lied to the Grand Jury. Oh well! It's only a movie and doesn't necessarily have to be believable, n'est-ce pas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worshiping the wrong idol .............
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Renfro is sucked into the glitzy world of ego maniacal disc jockey Billy Magic, Kevin Bacon. It is Cleveland, 1961, and Bacon finds Renfro the perfect patsy for assisting him in a payola racket. I could have done without the melodramatic subplot of Renfro and his Father, Maximilian Schell, sweating their Citizenship Papers, as it merely detracts from the main story. The 60s atmosphere is well done, with some great cars and an outstanding soundtrack. I wish the movie had focused more on Bacon's corrupt character, because the supporting cast, other than Calista Flockheart, as a love interest, is mostly wasted. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Telling Lies, Such Sweet Big Lies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know in another time and in another age in Hollywood the story told in Telling Lies In America about the Fifties and the age of payola might have had Brad Renfro's character be a populist hero if it were Frank Capra doing it. Billy Wilder or Preston Sturges might have made Kevin Bacon's character one of their acid studies in cynicism. As it is Telling Lies In America is a good film with an accurate depiction of the times it's set in. But it falls way short of a classic. Brad Renfro plays a 17 year old high school student, a refugee from the Hungarian Rebellion with his father Maximilian Schell who would desperately like to fit in. The father who was a doctor in Hungary now working some menial job while waiting his citizenship spends a ton of money to get Renfro into some private Catholic school. Still with all the handicaps of an immigrant, Renfro who's now deep in America's rock and roll culture hits on a plan to gain instant popularity. Some radio station with disc jockey Kevin Bacon is running a popularity contest, the high school hall of fame. If someone has friends write in postcards suggesting a person they get into this high school hall of fame. So what does Renfro do, but forge a bunch of postcards and he gets his entr&eacute;e with Kevin Bacon who offers him a job as an assistant, basically a glorified go-for. Of course it's all one big scam because Kevin Bacon is hip deep in the world of payola where he accepts all kinds of favors in sealed envelopes from agents to play their artist's records on his show. What he needed was a kid naive enough not to question what's going on around him and just be grateful for the relatively large amounts of money he's earning with Bacon as opposed to Renfro's previous job in a poultry market. It was the Fifties and I well remember a lot of rock and roll disc jockeys losing their careers over this, the most famous being Alan Freed. Kevin Bacon who has made a good career in villainous character parts is one cynical creep in this film. Two generations before, Kirk Douglas would have gone to town on this role. Maximilian Schell should also be praised as the wise father who because of the generation gap has different ideas about the American dream than Renfro. But there's no mistaking the bond these two have for each other. Telling Lies In America has a lot of good elements and it's an interesting story. But it's short of a master director to make it a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pants on Fire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the early 1960s, Cleveland, Ohio immigrant teenager Brad Renfro (as Karchy Jonas) struggles with adolescence and assimilation. Mr. Renfro is working on eradicating the remnants of his Hungarian accent (his "th" sound). Meanwhile, slick disc jockey Kevin Bacon (as Billy Magic) arrives in town (one step ahead of the law), to spin "sweaty collar and dirty fingernail music" on the local rock 'n' roll radio station. Mr. Bacon is a payola player, who needs an underage kid to handle money illegal exchanges. When Renfro cheats on a radio contest, Bacon offers him big bucks to serve as "unwitting accomplice"... Bacon swaggers through his role with perfection. And, Renfro is incredible, in a very difficult role; capturing the vulnerability of youth, as he struggles to both adopt and resist Bacon's seductive persona. Calista Flockhart (as Diney Majeski) is very effective, as Renfro's "older woman" love interest. Their performances should have received some award consideration. Maximilian Schell (as Istvan Jonas) would have been more believable as Renfro's grandfather, to support the obviously wider than envisioned cultural gap between the characters. A few of the scenes are silly, but many more work, due to director Guy Ferland and his convincing cast. "I make things up sometimes," Renfro reveals. Don't we all. "Telling Lies in America" certainly breaks no new ground - but, it revisits cinematic themes in great style. The film builds to a fine conclusion, and the music is terrific. ******** Telling Lies in America (8/2/97) Guy Ferland ~ Brad Renfro, Kevin Bacon, Calista Flockhart, Maximilian Schell
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Movie About Lying & America !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply lying is all over the world, all over the history, or rather it's inseparable part in the human nature (even in its most respectable figures like George Washington !). But the thing to assure here is that lying is definitely more profitable in America ! This movie makes its main character triumphs when he finishes his predicament by lying (in the trial), and gains his goal /the American nationality when he attested to the other's lies, not to mention the situation of the black singer and how he already attests to the announcer's lie as co-writer of his hit song just to be popular. The movie was such an eloquent when it paralleled the boy's insistence and bravery to lie in the face of justice, with him getting rid of his infantile innocence (the lisp) in the same time to be ultimately American Man ! Lying in any society is a way of living to achieve what do you want but with something to lose; here it was his love (logically as his highest truth). I didn't like only the confession of the announcer (the professional swindler) at the end that he didn't have anything to do with writing the black singer's song; that was sudden incomprehensible idealism !? (Joe Eszterhas) in one rare time gives us something to think instead of the regular amount of grand sex and violence. Although I'm not sure that the journey of (Karchy 'Chucky' Jonas) presented the experiment's essence of (Eszterhas) himself but I'm sure that it's his American book of wisdom. Actually the movie's philosophy proves that if you lied then you must grasp that all of the rest will lie to you, so you've got to : comprehend it, to attest it (if it gives you any profit), and the most important of all not to believe it ! As we don't lose when we lie (the boy reached the famous announcer by false letters) but we lose when we believe the lie (like the boy when he believed in the announcer as a mentor and an idol). So It's not just a movie, it's some amusing as well as toughing lesson about pragmatism ! The most crafty and witty meaning this movie shows impliedly is that if you want to be an American mature then you must be a brave lair ! Sense the smartness of it while observing the success of one fat lair at one gigantic communication medium (the radio at the 1950s as the mass media), and the lie of the boy at the end which made him eventually an American citizen. So If all the people would lie then who'll going to believe ? In fact It's a world where truth is something not only rare but not that needed also !! It might be the biggest satire about lying and the American splendor from the time of George Washington to the 1950s (where the events take place) till the 1990s where this movie had been made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad Renfro, RIP
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Renfro's untimely death brought this movie to mind. I haven't seen Joe Esterhasz's "Telling Lies in America" in a few years, but I remember that it was a good movie, Esterhasz's reputation notwithstanding. It goes like this. Karchy Jonas (Renfro) is a Hungarian immigrant in Ohio in the early '60s. He has trouble fitting in with the world around him, partly due to his trouble pronouncing a "th" sound, and feels disenchanted with the Catholic church that he and his father Istvan (Maximilian Schell) attend. But when he hooks up with DJ Billy Magic (Kevin Bacon), his luck changes...with some strings attached. I interpret this movie as sort of the flip side of "American Graffiti". In that case, they were all the same ilk and all fit in with everything. In this case, Karchy tries to fit in but has trouble doing it, and so his only option is to hook up with the shady Billy. More than just a nostalgia piece - though there are some oldies - we see Karchy's inner conflict between his desire to be a modern American, and trying to maintain his ties with his past. Overall, I recommend this one. I think that it would have been kind of fun to play that trick with the confession booth. And just remember what people tell you about Spanish flower. Also starring Calista Flockhart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie is a gem!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EighthSense
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll try not to repeat all of what the other reviewers have written already. Kevin Bacon is unbelievable in this role, he wears his part as a slick, sexy, supremely confident and laid-back DJ so well. He makes it impossible to imagine any other actor in this role. Every scene he appears in is to be savored. His voice is ideally suited for the broadcasts he makes. Seeing his easy charm and friendly manner is no wonder the young, innocent Kartchie idolized him. Visually, the movie is beautiful, rich, with a great soundtrack, excellent screenplay, in short, 100% enjoyment. Very nicely photographed, with very good sound direction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    okay but potentially excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spj-4
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this movie was okay but not excellent It had the makings of excellence but didn't deliver mastery. 'Frustrating' is a word that comes to mind for my opinion of it. I liked its music, even its plot, & innocence of some of its characters. I liked too, the underlying moral dilemmas of a young man of sincere & genuine character struggling with the plight inflicted upon him & them in broader prospectives. But it has unimportant matters glossed over, without explanation or rationality, except for naivety for the gullible. Like the DJ Bacon character & his prot&eacute;g&eacute; (& others supposedly exacting this scenario in other cities) but so detached from the reality of their situations. LIES is the underlying motive of integrity in situations anything but far from black & white. So it could have been the title of a film disguising lies. But it was not guilty of that by truer assessment. So what about layers of LIES??? Are little white lies beyond a couple of persons, not surely to be distinguished from blatant & career or character destructive lies, layer upon layer, lawyer upon lawyer, judge upon judge, to be evaluated as lies??? So a movie that is 7 out of 10 is neither 5 or 9 out of 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Liars
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Telling Lies in America" is a film that seems to have gone directly to video. It certainly deserved a wider audience because what Guy Ferland, the director does with the screen play Joe Eszterhas wrote for the film. Mr. Eszterhas is a man that can write, although some of his efforts have misfired. If you haven't seen the film, perhaps you should stop reading here. The basic problem with the film is the casting of Brad Renfro as the main character of the film. While this actor is not a bad actor, he seems miscast as this Karchy Jonas. Most comments in this forum focus on the fact Karchy has no accent, but having been in Cleveland for about seven years, explain that he already has a command of the language. Yes, he might stumble upon certain words, as shown in the film, but basically the character is believable. The only thing is that Mr. Renfro looks an older fourteen, rather than the seventeen he is in the film. This fact becomes painfully apparent in his relationship with Diney, and with the older woman Billy decides to have him experience sex for the first time. We are not saying it's not possible, because it can easily have been the case, which might have been derived from an experience of Mr. Eszterhas life. The other thing that doesn't ring true is the relationship between Karchy and his father. It appears that he can do whatever he wants and it's OK with the old man. Usually in the case of immigrant families, it's just the opposite. People immigrating to this country tend to be more protective, demanding discipline and obedience that is nowhere to be seen in the film. Also, Karchy's behavior in school would have probably grounded him forever, but it never comes into play. The marvelous Kevin Bacon is the best asset this film has going for itself. Not only is Mr. Bacon the most versatile of the current actors working in films, he brings such an intelligent take to his take on Billy Magic, the DJ of the local radio station that sees right through the lies Karchy Jonas tells. Being a liar himself, Billy can pick a liar whenever he sees one, as is the case when he meets Jonas. Billy Magic has no scruples. He takes money from the record companies, but he has Karchy pick the envelopes. The cast is good. Maximilian Schell, plays the father, Dr. Jonas, a man so decent, one wonders where did Karchy go wrong. He seems to be a loving father, albeit a distant one. Is it perhaps the fact that the son has embraced the American culture with too much gusto? That might explain the difference, although Karchy is never disrespectful to the old man. Calista Flockhart is seen as Diney, the mousy worker at the poultry shop where young Karchy works after school. Ms. Flockhart is perfect as the older girl that inspires love in the young man. Luke Wilson is seen as the man in charge of the shop. Paul Dooley makes a wonderful Father Norton, the man who dares put Karchy in his place. Notable in the film is the use of the popular songs that one hears in the sound track. It made perfect sense the use of those tunes since the background is a popular radio station that catered to teenagers. This is a film that should be seen by more people because of the good work the director and screen writer have done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ever felt like an outsider? Sure, lots of times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    helpless_dancer
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Interesting and well done look at the American pop scene in the sexy sixties. Featuring a oversexed, insecure loser named Karchy who teams up with another oversexed loser disc jockey intent on preying and playing just one more gig in the nowhere business of top 40 music. The charismatic DJ, a burned out cynic, has a history of using unpopular teens to make illegal profits or to cheat them in business deals; which, of course, continues as he rolls into a new town amid a flurry of excitement and adulation. As the rollicking DJ and the impressionable teen play out their drama, another is occurring as Karchy tries to woo an older woman who, for some reason, shows an interest in the love struck teen. Different from most of the gunk coming out today: well worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anent Soundtrack
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (SaxoTenor@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a performing musician in Paris, France in the 1960's I often used to play a tune entitled "Night Walk". In this movie the same tune is played but is called "Sleep Walk". How could the same tune have two titles? Does anyone know the answer to that? Otherwise the film was not so hot unless you have nostalgia for views of Cleveland, Ohio. How come the Hungarian refugee had no foreign accent? And I failed to understand why the George Washington question and answer session gave the judge the right to allow citizenship for both the father and son in spite of the fact that the son had obviously lied to the Grand Jury. Oh well! It's only a movie and doesn't necessarily have to be believable, n'est-ce pas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worshiping the wrong idol .............
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Renfro is sucked into the glitzy world of ego maniacal disc jockey Billy Magic, Kevin Bacon. It is Cleveland, 1961, and Bacon finds Renfro the perfect patsy for assisting him in a payola racket. I could have done without the melodramatic subplot of Renfro and his Father, Maximilian Schell, sweating their Citizenship Papers, as it merely detracts from the main story. The 60s atmosphere is well done, with some great cars and an outstanding soundtrack. I wish the movie had focused more on Bacon's corrupt character, because the supporting cast, other than Calista Flockheart, as a love interest, is mostly wasted. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Telling Lies, Such Sweet Big Lies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know in another time and in another age in Hollywood the story told in Telling Lies In America about the Fifties and the age of payola might have had Brad Renfro's character be a populist hero if it were Frank Capra doing it. Billy Wilder or Preston Sturges might have made Kevin Bacon's character one of their acid studies in cynicism. As it is Telling Lies In America is a good film with an accurate depiction of the times it's set in. But it falls way short of a classic. Brad Renfro plays a 17 year old high school student, a refugee from the Hungarian Rebellion with his father Maximilian Schell who would desperately like to fit in. The father who was a doctor in Hungary now working some menial job while waiting his citizenship spends a ton of money to get Renfro into some private Catholic school. Still with all the handicaps of an immigrant, Renfro who's now deep in America's rock and roll culture hits on a plan to gain instant popularity. Some radio station with disc jockey Kevin Bacon is running a popularity contest, the high school hall of fame. If someone has friends write in postcards suggesting a person they get into this high school hall of fame. So what does Renfro do, but forge a bunch of postcards and he gets his entr&eacute;e with Kevin Bacon who offers him a job as an assistant, basically a glorified go-for. Of course it's all one big scam because Kevin Bacon is hip deep in the world of payola where he accepts all kinds of favors in sealed envelopes from agents to play their artist's records on his show. What he needed was a kid naive enough not to question what's going on around him and just be grateful for the relatively large amounts of money he's earning with Bacon as opposed to Renfro's previous job in a poultry market. It was the Fifties and I well remember a lot of rock and roll disc jockeys losing their careers over this, the most famous being Alan Freed. Kevin Bacon who has made a good career in villainous character parts is one cynical creep in this film. Two generations before, Kirk Douglas would have gone to town on this role. Maximilian Schell should also be praised as the wise father who because of the generation gap has different ideas about the American dream than Renfro. But there's no mistaking the bond these two have for each other. Telling Lies In America has a lot of good elements and it's an interesting story. But it's short of a master director to make it a classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pants on Fire
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the early 1960s, Cleveland, Ohio immigrant teenager Brad Renfro (as Karchy Jonas) struggles with adolescence and assimilation. Mr. Renfro is working on eradicating the remnants of his Hungarian accent (his "th" sound). Meanwhile, slick disc jockey Kevin Bacon (as Billy Magic) arrives in town (one step ahead of the law), to spin "sweaty collar and dirty fingernail music" on the local rock 'n' roll radio station. Mr. Bacon is a payola player, who needs an underage kid to handle money illegal exchanges. When Renfro cheats on a radio contest, Bacon offers him big bucks to serve as "unwitting accomplice"... Bacon swaggers through his role with perfection. And, Renfro is incredible, in a very difficult role; capturing the vulnerability of youth, as he struggles to both adopt and resist Bacon's seductive persona. Calista Flockhart (as Diney Majeski) is very effective, as Renfro's "older woman" love interest. Their performances should have received some award consideration. Maximilian Schell (as Istvan Jonas) would have been more believable as Renfro's grandfather, to support the obviously wider than envisioned cultural gap between the characters. A few of the scenes are silly, but many more work, due to director Guy Ferland and his convincing cast. "I make things up sometimes," Renfro reveals. Don't we all. "Telling Lies in America" certainly breaks no new ground - but, it revisits cinematic themes in great style. The film builds to a fine conclusion, and the music is terrific. ******** Telling Lies in America (8/2/97) Guy Ferland ~ Brad Renfro, Kevin Bacon, Calista Flockhart, Maximilian Schell
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Movie About Lying & America !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply lying is all over the world, all over the history, or rather it's inseparable part in the human nature (even in its most respectable figures like George Washington !). But the thing to assure here is that lying is definitely more profitable in America ! This movie makes its main character triumphs when he finishes his predicament by lying (in the trial), and gains his goal /the American nationality when he attested to the other's lies, not to mention the situation of the black singer and how he already attests to the announcer's lie as co-writer of his hit song just to be popular. The movie was such an eloquent when it paralleled the boy's insistence and bravery to lie in the face of justice, with him getting rid of his infantile innocence (the lisp) in the same time to be ultimately American Man ! Lying in any society is a way of living to achieve what do you want but with something to lose; here it was his love (logically as his highest truth). I didn't like only the confession of the announcer (the professional swindler) at the end that he didn't have anything to do with writing the black singer's song; that was sudden incomprehensible idealism !? (Joe Eszterhas) in one rare time gives us something to think instead of the regular amount of grand sex and violence. Although I'm not sure that the journey of (Karchy 'Chucky' Jonas) presented the experiment's essence of (Eszterhas) himself but I'm sure that it's his American book of wisdom. Actually the movie's philosophy proves that if you lied then you must grasp that all of the rest will lie to you, so you've got to : comprehend it, to attest it (if it gives you any profit), and the most important of all not to believe it ! As we don't lose when we lie (the boy reached the famous announcer by false letters) but we lose when we believe the lie (like the boy when he believed in the announcer as a mentor and an idol). So It's not just a movie, it's some amusing as well as toughing lesson about pragmatism ! The most crafty and witty meaning this movie shows impliedly is that if you want to be an American mature then you must be a brave lair ! Sense the smartness of it while observing the success of one fat lair at one gigantic communication medium (the radio at the 1950s as the mass media), and the lie of the boy at the end which made him eventually an American citizen. So If all the people would lie then who'll going to believe ? In fact It's a world where truth is something not only rare but not that needed also !! It might be the biggest satire about lying and the American splendor from the time of George Washington to the 1950s (where the events take place) till the 1990s where this movie had been made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad Renfro, RIP
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Renfro's untimely death brought this movie to mind. I haven't seen Joe Esterhasz's "Telling Lies in America" in a few years, but I remember that it was a good movie, Esterhasz's reputation notwithstanding. It goes like this. Karchy Jonas (Renfro) is a Hungarian immigrant in Ohio in the early '60s. He has trouble fitting in with the world around him, partly due to his trouble pronouncing a "th" sound, and feels disenchanted with the Catholic church that he and his father Istvan (Maximilian Schell) attend. But when he hooks up with DJ Billy Magic (Kevin Bacon), his luck changes...with some strings attached. I interpret this movie as sort of the flip side of "American Graffiti". In that case, they were all the same ilk and all fit in with everything. In this case, Karchy tries to fit in but has trouble doing it, and so his only option is to hook up with the shady Billy. More than just a nostalgia piece - though there are some oldies - we see Karchy's inner conflict between his desire to be a modern American, and trying to maintain his ties with his past. Overall, I recommend this one. I think that it would have been kind of fun to play that trick with the confession booth. And just remember what people tell you about Spanish flower. Also starring Calista Flockhart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie is a gem!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EighthSense
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'll try not to repeat all of what the other reviewers have written already. Kevin Bacon is unbelievable in this role, he wears his part as a slick, sexy, supremely confident and laid-back DJ so well. He makes it impossible to imagine any other actor in this role. Every scene he appears in is to be savored. His voice is ideally suited for the broadcasts he makes. Seeing his easy charm and friendly manner is no wonder the young, innocent Kartchie idolized him. Visually, the movie is beautiful, rich, with a great soundtrack, excellent screenplay, in short, 100% enjoyment. Very nicely photographed, with very good sound direction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    okay but potentially excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spj-4
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this movie was okay but not excellent It had the makings of excellence but didn't deliver mastery. 'Frustrating' is a word that comes to mind for my opinion of it. I liked its music, even its plot, & innocence of some of its characters. I liked too, the underlying moral dilemmas of a young man of sincere & genuine character struggling with the plight inflicted upon him & them in broader prospectives. But it has unimportant matters glossed over, without explanation or rationality, except for naivety for the gullible. Like the DJ Bacon character & his prot&eacute;g&eacute; (& others supposedly exacting this scenario in other cities) but so detached from the reality of their situations. LIES is the underlying motive of integrity in situations anything but far from black & white. So it could have been the title of a film disguising lies. But it was not guilty of that by truer assessment. So what about layers of LIES??? Are little white lies beyond a couple of persons, not surely to be distinguished from blatant & career or character destructive lies, layer upon layer, lawyer upon lawyer, judge upon judge, to be evaluated as lies??? So a movie that is 7 out of 10 is neither 5 or 9 out of 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Liars
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jotix100
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Telling Lies in America" is a film that seems to have gone directly to video. It certainly deserved a wider audience because what Guy Ferland, the director does with the screen play Joe Eszterhas wrote for the film. Mr. Eszterhas is a man that can write, although some of his efforts have misfired. If you haven't seen the film, perhaps you should stop reading here. The basic problem with the film is the casting of Brad Renfro as the main character of the film. While this actor is not a bad actor, he seems miscast as this Karchy Jonas. Most comments in this forum focus on the fact Karchy has no accent, but having been in Cleveland for about seven years, explain that he already has a command of the language. Yes, he might stumble upon certain words, as shown in the film, but basically the character is believable. The only thing is that Mr. Renfro looks an older fourteen, rather than the seventeen he is in the film. This fact becomes painfully apparent in his relationship with Diney, and with the older woman Billy decides to have him experience sex for the first time. We are not saying it's not possible, because it can easily have been the case, which might have been derived from an experience of Mr. Eszterhas life. The other thing that doesn't ring true is the relationship between Karchy and his father. It appears that he can do whatever he wants and it's OK with the old man. Usually in the case of immigrant families, it's just the opposite. People immigrating to this country tend to be more protective, demanding discipline and obedience that is nowhere to be seen in the film. Also, Karchy's behavior in school would have probably grounded him forever, but it never comes into play. The marvelous Kevin Bacon is the best asset this film has going for itself. Not only is Mr. Bacon the most versatile of the current actors working in films, he brings such an intelligent take to his take on Billy Magic, the DJ of the local radio station that sees right through the lies Karchy Jonas tells. Being a liar himself, Billy can pick a liar whenever he sees one, as is the case when he meets Jonas. Billy Magic has no scruples. He takes money from the record companies, but he has Karchy pick the envelopes. The cast is good. Maximilian Schell, plays the father, Dr. Jonas, a man so decent, one wonders where did Karchy go wrong. He seems to be a loving father, albeit a distant one. Is it perhaps the fact that the son has embraced the American culture with too much gusto? That might explain the difference, although Karchy is never disrespectful to the old man. Calista Flockhart is seen as Diney, the mousy worker at the poultry shop where young Karchy works after school. Ms. Flockhart is perfect as the older girl that inspires love in the young man. Luke Wilson is seen as the man in charge of the shop. Paul Dooley makes a wonderful Father Norton, the man who dares put Karchy in his place. Notable in the film is the use of the popular songs that one hears in the sound track. It made perfect sense the use of those tunes since the background is a popular radio station that catered to teenagers. This is a film that should be seen by more people because of the good work the director and screen writer have done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ever felt like an outsider? Sure, lots of times.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    helpless_dancer
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Interesting and well done look at the American pop scene in the sexy sixties. Featuring a oversexed, insecure loser named Karchy who teams up with another oversexed loser disc jockey intent on preying and playing just one more gig in the nowhere business of top 40 music. The charismatic DJ, a burned out cynic, has a history of using unpopular teens to make illegal profits or to cheat them in business deals; which, of course, continues as he rolls into a new town amid a flurry of excitement and adulation. As the rollicking DJ and the impressionable teen play out their drama, another is occurring as Karchy tries to woo an older woman who, for some reason, shows an interest in the love struck teen. Different from most of the gunk coming out today: well worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Anent Soundtrack
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (SaxoTenor@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I was a performing musician in Paris, France in the 1960's I often used to play a tune entitled "Night Walk". In this movie the same tune is played but is called "Sleep Walk". How could the same tune have two titles? Does anyone know the answer to that? Otherwise the film was not so hot unless you have nostalgia for views of Cleveland, Ohio. How come the Hungarian refugee had no foreign accent? And I failed to understand why the George Washington question and answer session gave the judge the right to allow citizenship for both the father and son in spite of the fact that the son had obviously lied to the Grand Jury. Oh well! It's only a movie and doesn't necessarily have to be believable, n'est-ce pas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
