<filme>
 <id>
  884
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120539
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Year of the Horse
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  This film documents Neil Young and Crazy Horse's 1996 concert tour. Jim Jarmusch interviews the band about their long history, and we see backstage footage from the 1970s and 1980s.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  This film documents Neil Young and Crazy Horse's 1996 concert tour. Jim Jarmusch interviews the band about their long history, and we see backstage footage from the 1970s and 1980s.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Documentary
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   neil young
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   interview
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1970s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1980s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1960s
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jim Jarmusch
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Shakey Pictures
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Neil Young
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jim Jarmusch
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ralph Molina
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Red Box
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Faragher
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Felt obliged to write a review as none of the reviews posted so far seem to have been from people who saw this at the cinema. I was lucky enough to catch this in 97 at a film festival and the memory of it still lingers. The talking heads interviews are unmemorable, but the live concert footage is incredible. It's some of the rawest, most powerful and yet subtly controlled rock music to have ever been captured. I's also nice to see some essentially middle-aged guys rock out big time. It's hypnotic and savage, and every time Neil hits his custom big red box and kicks into a solo you can feel the passion oozing from the man. If you want something polished you'd be better of with some Pet Shop Boy's videos, but if you're after authentic blood, sweat and tears take a chance on this. And for god's sake either turn it up very loud or better still put some cans on and get the full effect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Different but That Doesn't Mean Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Year of the Horse (1997) ** (out of 4) I can respect what Jim Jarmusch was going for. I mean, it's clear that the ugliness of this film was done on purpose but just because you respect someone for trying something different doesn't mean you have to be entertained by it. This documentary, the director's only to date, takes a look at Neil Young and Crazy Horse's 1996 tour with interviews with those involved as they discuss the history of the group. This includes a rather rocky road in the 1970s and various re-gatherings leading up to the '96 tour. Right from the start in big bold letters we're told about the 8mm, 16mm and various other formats used to create this film but whatever they were going for must have gotten lost in the mix because the end result is a pretty ugly film to look at and listen to. I understand the visuals of the film were probably meant to capture the mood and spirit of the music but by filming this way they've also delivered some rather ugly audio. I've heard a lot of people get upset over the selection of songs but as I've grown as a Young fan I've realized that he does what he wants and that includes releasing something with not too many hits. I didn't mind the song selection as the performances were quite good but sadly I thought the actual audio quality didn't do them justice. There was an interesting take on "Tonight's the Night" and a clever mix between an old and new performance of "Like a Hurricane" that was very good. With that said, the ugliness of the film also has some pretty boring interviews where Young and the band just keep talking and talking and quite often it's about a rather uninteresting subject. There's no question that Young die hards will want to check this out but others should probably avoid it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As great as RUST NEVER SLEEPS.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin P (mera_bullar@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The point of this film is to catch the essence of Neil Young & Crazy Horse's strange sound. Their sound is interesting because it is based on pure emotions (according to Neil Young), and not so much on technical skills (if you listen to drummer Ralph Molina he plays like a 10-year old). This film should therefore appeal to anyone who's interested in music. In addition to that, in contains fantastic live performance by one of the truly great rock bands. Why this film is good? It IS the essence of Crazy Horse - it is lo-fi, filmed with a shaky 8mm camera (but the sound is okay). It's trashy American feeling with the random interviews (like when guitarist "Poncho" questions why Jarmusch is doing this film) and all the on-the-road footage is also contributing to explaining how they work as a band, and therefore why the sound like they do. This film reflects the trashiness of Crazy Horse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One for the fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Jarmusch (Broken Flowers, Ghost Dog: The Way of the Samurai) directed this documentary (his only one) of Neil Young and Crazy Horse's 1996 concert tour. Jarmusch's grainy, home-movie style make this a very interesting film as we look into the background of the band. Ten songs including "F*ckin' up", "Slips Away", and "Tonight's the Night". The only complaint I had about the music was Neil Young's guitar solos. They seemed to go on forever. This movie is really for Neil Young fans. 20+ years of music history in a couple of hours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the music and off-beat style makes up any of the lulls in the interviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't say that Year of the Horse, director Jim Jarmusch's only documentary, is one of the all-time great rock-docs (i.e. Woodstock, Last Waltz, Pink Floyd Live at Pompeii), but it does have many good things going for it, not the least of which the performances. Although some of the interview footage goes into some lulls and conventions (i.e. 'deep' explanations of how the band works, the fights, the self-conscious attitude of being in a film trying to capture 25 years in 2 hours), it's not as boring as I would've expected from the interviews. Some people have said this is like a Spinal Tap film that takes itself too seriously, and I can see where that criticism could stand. However, Jarmusch has a lot of pride in his experimental style, shooting only with 16mm & 8mm, mostly grainy or home-video style. The results are something of a very personal view into Young and his Crazy Horse people, some of whom seem to be more 'there' than others. A couple of segments though, like when Jarmusch reads from the bible to Young, or vintage footage of Scottish views on the band/shenanigans with the band in a hotel room, are quite entertaining on their own. But for those looking for just the music instead of the interviews or talk, the film may or may not meet your expectations, depending on how much of a Neil Young fan &/or Neil Young & Crazy Horse fan you are. If you're of the latter, it's probably a must-see, with songs like "F***in' up", "Slips Away", "Tonight's the Night", and a couple of songs I've just plain never heard of before seeing the film. There's also the finale, with a half retro Young and present-day (1996 present day) performance of "Like a Hurricane", which will probably be the highlight for those who only are familiar with the hits of Neil Young, or for anyone. The best thing that I can say about the performances, as a little more than a casual observer/listener to Young/Crazy Horse's music, is that there is always this uncommon energy between all the players in the band. Even if what they're singing is loud or distorted or "grunge", they are having fun on stage, and the camaraderie is an enjoyable part of the performances. Jarmusch's style with these scenes ranges from wild and cool, to a step or two away from being a little pretentious or, worse, MTV style editing. Most of the time though, his vision works for the material, and in the end what we get is more of a glimpse at what Young & Crazy Horse are all about- a pure form of rock & roll, harder than the solo Young stuff if not as hard as the rockers of today, and its definitely not of the 'corporate' product pool. B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7 for Neil fans -1 for just about anyone else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bhu73
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A supposed documentary of the 1996 tour by Neil Young and Crazy Horse, I got the feeling that the interviews were conducted with Neil standing just out of shot with a loaded weapon or paycheck. There is nothing revelatory about the interviews, most of the perfomance footage is average.... this is really only likely to appeal to the diehard.... I'm one of them and I struggled....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seemed like it ran a year
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    helpless_dancer
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You better like Neil or this will be an interminable trip through bad music hell. Not nearly as good as his '72 film "Journey Through the Past", it still had a few fun moments but was mostly dull interviews and grainy, endless concert footage. Young needs to drop the gangsta/rapper look; in fact the entire band appears to be a bunch of washed up, burnt out, middle aged head banger wannabes who look to have been ridden hard and put up wet. I was particularly amused by Pancho as he kept insisting the producers couldn't sew up 30 years of Crazy Horse with a camera and a couple of questions. What's to sew up? Drugs, whores, bad music, and a never ending childhood wouldn't beg more than 2 queries at most. I admit to liking a few of Young's songs but for the most part I consider him a 2 bit guitarist who pushes grunge a bit too far.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A portrait of an artist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggiesda
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're a Neil Young fan, you will love this movie. The music is outstanding, almost mind-altering in it's depth and beauty. Yes, I call it beautiful even though it's raw and riotous, even though it's crude and vulgar, even though it sometimes feels like the harrowing of hell, it's beautiful music. Young's music is incomparable and his live performance shows you what an artist looks like when he's under the influence of his muse. He gives a succinct insight into his vision of true rock music: it never gets comfortable, it never gets tame, it never gets easy. Neil Young is in a class with Bob Dylan and Keith Jarrett: artists completely dedicated to their work. I highly recommend this movie. Jarmusch does an incredible job of combining 3 decades worth of footage into this 1996 tour. The interview with Jim Jarmusch and Young is very interesting: two artists talking about what they do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very interesting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonas Kyratzes
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Jarmusch has always been one of my favorite directors, and I also happen to be a fan of Neil Young's music. I found this documentary very interesting and well-made. I suppose that it's not for everybody, though. Jarmusch can be a little strange at times (I like that, but other people might not).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good concert film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mml-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been a moderate Neil Young fan for years but never saw him play.I've always enjoyed the chunky feedback laden sound of his work with Crazy Horse but never realized how much like the Grateful Dead they were. As I watched the three guitarists together on stage, they reminded me of the witches in Macbeth in the way that they huddled together, bouncing up and down, churning out this amazing wall of sound and power. While it wasn't "The Last Waltz", I thought it was pretty good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Red Box
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Faragher
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Felt obliged to write a review as none of the reviews posted so far seem to have been from people who saw this at the cinema. I was lucky enough to catch this in 97 at a film festival and the memory of it still lingers. The talking heads interviews are unmemorable, but the live concert footage is incredible. It's some of the rawest, most powerful and yet subtly controlled rock music to have ever been captured. I's also nice to see some essentially middle-aged guys rock out big time. It's hypnotic and savage, and every time Neil hits his custom big red box and kicks into a solo you can feel the passion oozing from the man. If you want something polished you'd be better of with some Pet Shop Boy's videos, but if you're after authentic blood, sweat and tears take a chance on this. And for god's sake either turn it up very loud or better still put some cans on and get the full effect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Different but That Doesn't Mean Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Year of the Horse (1997) ** (out of 4) I can respect what Jim Jarmusch was going for. I mean, it's clear that the ugliness of this film was done on purpose but just because you respect someone for trying something different doesn't mean you have to be entertained by it. This documentary, the director's only to date, takes a look at Neil Young and Crazy Horse's 1996 tour with interviews with those involved as they discuss the history of the group. This includes a rather rocky road in the 1970s and various re-gatherings leading up to the '96 tour. Right from the start in big bold letters we're told about the 8mm, 16mm and various other formats used to create this film but whatever they were going for must have gotten lost in the mix because the end result is a pretty ugly film to look at and listen to. I understand the visuals of the film were probably meant to capture the mood and spirit of the music but by filming this way they've also delivered some rather ugly audio. I've heard a lot of people get upset over the selection of songs but as I've grown as a Young fan I've realized that he does what he wants and that includes releasing something with not too many hits. I didn't mind the song selection as the performances were quite good but sadly I thought the actual audio quality didn't do them justice. There was an interesting take on "Tonight's the Night" and a clever mix between an old and new performance of "Like a Hurricane" that was very good. With that said, the ugliness of the film also has some pretty boring interviews where Young and the band just keep talking and talking and quite often it's about a rather uninteresting subject. There's no question that Young die hards will want to check this out but others should probably avoid it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As great as RUST NEVER SLEEPS.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin P (mera_bullar@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The point of this film is to catch the essence of Neil Young & Crazy Horse's strange sound. Their sound is interesting because it is based on pure emotions (according to Neil Young), and not so much on technical skills (if you listen to drummer Ralph Molina he plays like a 10-year old). This film should therefore appeal to anyone who's interested in music. In addition to that, in contains fantastic live performance by one of the truly great rock bands. Why this film is good? It IS the essence of Crazy Horse - it is lo-fi, filmed with a shaky 8mm camera (but the sound is okay). It's trashy American feeling with the random interviews (like when guitarist "Poncho" questions why Jarmusch is doing this film) and all the on-the-road footage is also contributing to explaining how they work as a band, and therefore why the sound like they do. This film reflects the trashiness of Crazy Horse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One for the fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Jarmusch (Broken Flowers, Ghost Dog: The Way of the Samurai) directed this documentary (his only one) of Neil Young and Crazy Horse's 1996 concert tour. Jarmusch's grainy, home-movie style make this a very interesting film as we look into the background of the band. Ten songs including "F*ckin' up", "Slips Away", and "Tonight's the Night". The only complaint I had about the music was Neil Young's guitar solos. They seemed to go on forever. This movie is really for Neil Young fans. 20+ years of music history in a couple of hours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the music and off-beat style makes up any of the lulls in the interviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't say that Year of the Horse, director Jim Jarmusch's only documentary, is one of the all-time great rock-docs (i.e. Woodstock, Last Waltz, Pink Floyd Live at Pompeii), but it does have many good things going for it, not the least of which the performances. Although some of the interview footage goes into some lulls and conventions (i.e. 'deep' explanations of how the band works, the fights, the self-conscious attitude of being in a film trying to capture 25 years in 2 hours), it's not as boring as I would've expected from the interviews. Some people have said this is like a Spinal Tap film that takes itself too seriously, and I can see where that criticism could stand. However, Jarmusch has a lot of pride in his experimental style, shooting only with 16mm & 8mm, mostly grainy or home-video style. The results are something of a very personal view into Young and his Crazy Horse people, some of whom seem to be more 'there' than others. A couple of segments though, like when Jarmusch reads from the bible to Young, or vintage footage of Scottish views on the band/shenanigans with the band in a hotel room, are quite entertaining on their own. But for those looking for just the music instead of the interviews or talk, the film may or may not meet your expectations, depending on how much of a Neil Young fan &/or Neil Young & Crazy Horse fan you are. If you're of the latter, it's probably a must-see, with songs like "F***in' up", "Slips Away", "Tonight's the Night", and a couple of songs I've just plain never heard of before seeing the film. There's also the finale, with a half retro Young and present-day (1996 present day) performance of "Like a Hurricane", which will probably be the highlight for those who only are familiar with the hits of Neil Young, or for anyone. The best thing that I can say about the performances, as a little more than a casual observer/listener to Young/Crazy Horse's music, is that there is always this uncommon energy between all the players in the band. Even if what they're singing is loud or distorted or "grunge", they are having fun on stage, and the camaraderie is an enjoyable part of the performances. Jarmusch's style with these scenes ranges from wild and cool, to a step or two away from being a little pretentious or, worse, MTV style editing. Most of the time though, his vision works for the material, and in the end what we get is more of a glimpse at what Young & Crazy Horse are all about- a pure form of rock & roll, harder than the solo Young stuff if not as hard as the rockers of today, and its definitely not of the 'corporate' product pool. B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7 for Neil fans -1 for just about anyone else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bhu73
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A supposed documentary of the 1996 tour by Neil Young and Crazy Horse, I got the feeling that the interviews were conducted with Neil standing just out of shot with a loaded weapon or paycheck. There is nothing revelatory about the interviews, most of the perfomance footage is average.... this is really only likely to appeal to the diehard.... I'm one of them and I struggled....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seemed like it ran a year
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    helpless_dancer
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You better like Neil or this will be an interminable trip through bad music hell. Not nearly as good as his '72 film "Journey Through the Past", it still had a few fun moments but was mostly dull interviews and grainy, endless concert footage. Young needs to drop the gangsta/rapper look; in fact the entire band appears to be a bunch of washed up, burnt out, middle aged head banger wannabes who look to have been ridden hard and put up wet. I was particularly amused by Pancho as he kept insisting the producers couldn't sew up 30 years of Crazy Horse with a camera and a couple of questions. What's to sew up? Drugs, whores, bad music, and a never ending childhood wouldn't beg more than 2 queries at most. I admit to liking a few of Young's songs but for the most part I consider him a 2 bit guitarist who pushes grunge a bit too far.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A portrait of an artist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggiesda
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're a Neil Young fan, you will love this movie. The music is outstanding, almost mind-altering in it's depth and beauty. Yes, I call it beautiful even though it's raw and riotous, even though it's crude and vulgar, even though it sometimes feels like the harrowing of hell, it's beautiful music. Young's music is incomparable and his live performance shows you what an artist looks like when he's under the influence of his muse. He gives a succinct insight into his vision of true rock music: it never gets comfortable, it never gets tame, it never gets easy. Neil Young is in a class with Bob Dylan and Keith Jarrett: artists completely dedicated to their work. I highly recommend this movie. Jarmusch does an incredible job of combining 3 decades worth of footage into this 1996 tour. The interview with Jim Jarmusch and Young is very interesting: two artists talking about what they do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very interesting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonas Kyratzes
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Jarmusch has always been one of my favorite directors, and I also happen to be a fan of Neil Young's music. I found this documentary very interesting and well-made. I suppose that it's not for everybody, though. Jarmusch can be a little strange at times (I like that, but other people might not).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good concert film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mml-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been a moderate Neil Young fan for years but never saw him play.I've always enjoyed the chunky feedback laden sound of his work with Crazy Horse but never realized how much like the Grateful Dead they were. As I watched the three guitarists together on stage, they reminded me of the witches in Macbeth in the way that they huddled together, bouncing up and down, churning out this amazing wall of sound and power. While it wasn't "The Last Waltz", I thought it was pretty good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Big Red Box
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Faragher
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Felt obliged to write a review as none of the reviews posted so far seem to have been from people who saw this at the cinema. I was lucky enough to catch this in 97 at a film festival and the memory of it still lingers. The talking heads interviews are unmemorable, but the live concert footage is incredible. It's some of the rawest, most powerful and yet subtly controlled rock music to have ever been captured. I's also nice to see some essentially middle-aged guys rock out big time. It's hypnotic and savage, and every time Neil hits his custom big red box and kicks into a solo you can feel the passion oozing from the man. If you want something polished you'd be better of with some Pet Shop Boy's videos, but if you're after authentic blood, sweat and tears take a chance on this. And for god's sake either turn it up very loud or better still put some cans on and get the full effect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Different but That Doesn't Mean Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Year of the Horse (1997) ** (out of 4) I can respect what Jim Jarmusch was going for. I mean, it's clear that the ugliness of this film was done on purpose but just because you respect someone for trying something different doesn't mean you have to be entertained by it. This documentary, the director's only to date, takes a look at Neil Young and Crazy Horse's 1996 tour with interviews with those involved as they discuss the history of the group. This includes a rather rocky road in the 1970s and various re-gatherings leading up to the '96 tour. Right from the start in big bold letters we're told about the 8mm, 16mm and various other formats used to create this film but whatever they were going for must have gotten lost in the mix because the end result is a pretty ugly film to look at and listen to. I understand the visuals of the film were probably meant to capture the mood and spirit of the music but by filming this way they've also delivered some rather ugly audio. I've heard a lot of people get upset over the selection of songs but as I've grown as a Young fan I've realized that he does what he wants and that includes releasing something with not too many hits. I didn't mind the song selection as the performances were quite good but sadly I thought the actual audio quality didn't do them justice. There was an interesting take on "Tonight's the Night" and a clever mix between an old and new performance of "Like a Hurricane" that was very good. With that said, the ugliness of the film also has some pretty boring interviews where Young and the band just keep talking and talking and quite often it's about a rather uninteresting subject. There's no question that Young die hards will want to check this out but others should probably avoid it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As great as RUST NEVER SLEEPS.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Martin P (mera_bullar@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The point of this film is to catch the essence of Neil Young & Crazy Horse's strange sound. Their sound is interesting because it is based on pure emotions (according to Neil Young), and not so much on technical skills (if you listen to drummer Ralph Molina he plays like a 10-year old). This film should therefore appeal to anyone who's interested in music. In addition to that, in contains fantastic live performance by one of the truly great rock bands. Why this film is good? It IS the essence of Crazy Horse - it is lo-fi, filmed with a shaky 8mm camera (but the sound is okay). It's trashy American feeling with the random interviews (like when guitarist "Poncho" questions why Jarmusch is doing this film) and all the on-the-road footage is also contributing to explaining how they work as a band, and therefore why the sound like they do. This film reflects the trashiness of Crazy Horse.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One for the fans
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/6/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Jarmusch (Broken Flowers, Ghost Dog: The Way of the Samurai) directed this documentary (his only one) of Neil Young and Crazy Horse's 1996 concert tour. Jarmusch's grainy, home-movie style make this a very interesting film as we look into the background of the band. Ten songs including "F*ckin' up", "Slips Away", and "Tonight's the Night". The only complaint I had about the music was Neil Young's guitar solos. They seemed to go on forever. This movie is really for Neil Young fans. 20+ years of music history in a couple of hours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the music and off-beat style makes up any of the lulls in the interviews
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wouldn't say that Year of the Horse, director Jim Jarmusch's only documentary, is one of the all-time great rock-docs (i.e. Woodstock, Last Waltz, Pink Floyd Live at Pompeii), but it does have many good things going for it, not the least of which the performances. Although some of the interview footage goes into some lulls and conventions (i.e. 'deep' explanations of how the band works, the fights, the self-conscious attitude of being in a film trying to capture 25 years in 2 hours), it's not as boring as I would've expected from the interviews. Some people have said this is like a Spinal Tap film that takes itself too seriously, and I can see where that criticism could stand. However, Jarmusch has a lot of pride in his experimental style, shooting only with 16mm & 8mm, mostly grainy or home-video style. The results are something of a very personal view into Young and his Crazy Horse people, some of whom seem to be more 'there' than others. A couple of segments though, like when Jarmusch reads from the bible to Young, or vintage footage of Scottish views on the band/shenanigans with the band in a hotel room, are quite entertaining on their own. But for those looking for just the music instead of the interviews or talk, the film may or may not meet your expectations, depending on how much of a Neil Young fan &/or Neil Young & Crazy Horse fan you are. If you're of the latter, it's probably a must-see, with songs like "F***in' up", "Slips Away", "Tonight's the Night", and a couple of songs I've just plain never heard of before seeing the film. There's also the finale, with a half retro Young and present-day (1996 present day) performance of "Like a Hurricane", which will probably be the highlight for those who only are familiar with the hits of Neil Young, or for anyone. The best thing that I can say about the performances, as a little more than a casual observer/listener to Young/Crazy Horse's music, is that there is always this uncommon energy between all the players in the band. Even if what they're singing is loud or distorted or "grunge", they are having fun on stage, and the camaraderie is an enjoyable part of the performances. Jarmusch's style with these scenes ranges from wild and cool, to a step or two away from being a little pretentious or, worse, MTV style editing. Most of the time though, his vision works for the material, and in the end what we get is more of a glimpse at what Young & Crazy Horse are all about- a pure form of rock & roll, harder than the solo Young stuff if not as hard as the rockers of today, and its definitely not of the 'corporate' product pool. B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7 for Neil fans -1 for just about anyone else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bhu73
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A supposed documentary of the 1996 tour by Neil Young and Crazy Horse, I got the feeling that the interviews were conducted with Neil standing just out of shot with a loaded weapon or paycheck. There is nothing revelatory about the interviews, most of the perfomance footage is average.... this is really only likely to appeal to the diehard.... I'm one of them and I struggled....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seemed like it ran a year
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    helpless_dancer
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You better like Neil or this will be an interminable trip through bad music hell. Not nearly as good as his '72 film "Journey Through the Past", it still had a few fun moments but was mostly dull interviews and grainy, endless concert footage. Young needs to drop the gangsta/rapper look; in fact the entire band appears to be a bunch of washed up, burnt out, middle aged head banger wannabes who look to have been ridden hard and put up wet. I was particularly amused by Pancho as he kept insisting the producers couldn't sew up 30 years of Crazy Horse with a camera and a couple of questions. What's to sew up? Drugs, whores, bad music, and a never ending childhood wouldn't beg more than 2 queries at most. I admit to liking a few of Young's songs but for the most part I consider him a 2 bit guitarist who pushes grunge a bit too far.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A portrait of an artist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    maggiesda
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/3/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you're a Neil Young fan, you will love this movie. The music is outstanding, almost mind-altering in it's depth and beauty. Yes, I call it beautiful even though it's raw and riotous, even though it's crude and vulgar, even though it sometimes feels like the harrowing of hell, it's beautiful music. Young's music is incomparable and his live performance shows you what an artist looks like when he's under the influence of his muse. He gives a succinct insight into his vision of true rock music: it never gets comfortable, it never gets tame, it never gets easy. Neil Young is in a class with Bob Dylan and Keith Jarrett: artists completely dedicated to their work. I highly recommend this movie. Jarmusch does an incredible job of combining 3 decades worth of footage into this 1996 tour. The interview with Jim Jarmusch and Young is very interesting: two artists talking about what they do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very interesting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonas Kyratzes
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Jarmusch has always been one of my favorite directors, and I also happen to be a fan of Neil Young's music. I found this documentary very interesting and well-made. I suppose that it's not for everybody, though. Jarmusch can be a little strange at times (I like that, but other people might not).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good concert film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mml-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've been a moderate Neil Young fan for years but never saw him play.I've always enjoyed the chunky feedback laden sound of his work with Crazy Horse but never realized how much like the Grateful Dead they were. As I watched the three guitarists together on stage, they reminded me of the witches in Macbeth in the way that they huddled together, bouncing up and down, churning out this amazing wall of sound and power. While it wasn't "The Last Waltz", I thought it was pretty good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
