<filme>
 <id>
  887
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119080
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Amores Divididos
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The story is set in 1962 Louisiana. The big Batiste family is headed by charming doctor Louis. Though he is married to beautiful Roz, he has a weakness for attractive women patients. One ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The story is set in 1962 Louisiana. The big Batiste family is headed by charming doctor Louis. Though he is married to beautiful Roz, he has a weakness for attractive women patients. One day Louis is flirting with married and sexy Metty Mereaux, not knowing that he is observed by his youngest idealistic daughter Eve, who is there by accident. Eve can not forget the incident which is traumatic for her naivete and shares a secret with older sister Cisely. Lies start to roll...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   doctor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   louisiana
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   secret
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   spider
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   father daughter relationship
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Kasi Lemmons
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Kasi Lemmons
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Samuel L. Jackson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jurnee Smollett-Bell
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Meagan Good
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great family drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons wrote and directed "Eve's Bayou," with such precision that I'm astounded that she hasn't had anything as good since this feature. Orson Welles is still famous for "Citizen Kane" after which he never reached such heights again. Samuel L. Jackson is a doctor who has a monogamy problem, constantly cheating on his wife, played by Lynn Whitfield. They have two daughters, Eve of the title, Jurnee Smollett is awesome as the lead character of this story and her sister Cisely(Meagan Good) is also a charming child actress. The two worship their father but they eventually discover his shortcomings as a husband. The two young sisters steal this film, an absorbing, tragic family drama of Shakespearean proportions. Lemmons has created a memorable classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love Love Love It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LOVE LOVE LOVE IT!!!!! One of my ALL TIME favorite movies ever made. Brilliant acting by the whole cast. Eve's Bayou is a spectacular movie. The color and scenery is wonderful and the people are elegant and troubled. Even the character's names stir up visions of dark swamp water and sultry heat. The story is told and seen through the eyes of little Eve Batiste played by a wonderful young actress named Jurnee Smollett. Eve takes us deep into her world which is filled with colorful characters and complex personalities.Diahann Carroll is fabulous as the old fortune teller Elzora with her insane laughter. Debbi Morgan as Aunt Mozelle Batiste Delacroix is something to behold. Aunt Mozelle has promised her family that she will not use her "second sight" to tell fortunes, but neighbors won't let her keep her promise. They seek her out to find missing husbands anyway. Lynn Whitfied as the manor born wife is beautiful and poised as she tries to keep her family together in spite of her wandering husband (Samuel L. Jackson). Jackson is very sexy in this movie and his character has roving eyes as well as roving hands that don't stop even when he is caught in a compromising position by his youngest daughter, Eve. This starts a set of events that lead to the total destruction of an already deeply troubled family.Although this movie did not make history at the box office my guess is that it will become a cult classic. Years from now this movie will be viewed for what it is, a brilliantly produced film. You can literally feel the Louisiana heat from Eve's Bayou. danceability. Amsterdam
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of the '90s -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evehands
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - which i am embarrassed to admit we only went to see because of the coincidence of the name!! But this absurd 'excuse' to see a film we'd heard nothing about (no publicity or marketing - just an option among several others at our local multiplex cinema, lured in by a beautiful poster which it turned out proved to be a foretaste of a gorgeously shot movie) paid off richly. We are seldom impressed as we were with 'Eve's Bayou'; this layering of memories, filtered through the perceptions of three distinctly different women, was such an intelligent and suspenseful use of the much-abused medium of film, that I thought about and remembered it yesterday after 11 years (!) and decided to rent it again; I am confident I will like it just as much on second viewing. Now that i know it was a low budget first outing for the (female) director (whose DP was likewise female - something which is STILL an anomaly, even today, where commercially released features are concerned), I am simply blown away....Roger Ebert is absolutely right; the fact that this was not nominated for an Academy Award means they were simply not paying attention; for shame! It ought to have been a runaway success, and at very least nominated for Best Director, Best Supporting Actress(es), Best DP, Best Costumes, Best Screenplay. Unfortunately, Kasi Lemmons' follow- up to this (the gruesomely dark 'Valentine' something-or-other) was nowhere near as accomplished as this (though it was still good, by any movie standards). Perhaps she lost heart after being so overlooked? (and if so, who could blame her?!). I hope this film gets a re-release and much belated marketing 'push', with a perhaps more prominent placing at the local DVD stores, at least (I'm having to order my rented copy in 'cause it's not in the store...)!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flaaaaaaaaaaaawwwwwwwless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been a TOTAL fan of Lynn Whitfield and Debbi Morgan for YEARS, I KNEW I would be in for a treat. This overlooked film is indeed a wonder and in time will place among one of the finest movies ever made. It is multi-layered and deals with some extremely sensitive issues all the while painting a beautiful tapestry of African-American life in the Louisianna bayou. For those of you who have not seen it, it deals with the awakening of a father and his daughters one summer and the emotions that accompany this learning. The young Eve is brilliantly played by Smollett and Debbi Morgan gives a knockout performance that you crave to see over and over again. Diahann Carroll works you because her character is not at all glamorous but pivotal to the plot as Eve comes to realize the responsibility of her "gift" and learns the truth of the age-old adage, "Be careful what you wish for, for you just might get it." Samuel L. Jackson is wonderful as usual and perfectly cast. While his character is not necessarily sympathetic, he is totally understandable and for a little girl who worships her father he is perfectly cast. While some aspects of the father-daughter relationship may be somewhat uncomfortable, the director does a beautiful job bringing the complexity of these issues to the screen and I heartily applaud her. This is one that belongs in any movie collection and one where African-American life is celebrated and treated with the utmost respect and honesty. Hats off to a wonderful production!!!!!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine family drama set in 1960s Louisiana.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is the name of the small settlement along the bayou that former slave Eve gave her name to. The story is told from a young girl's point of view, Eve Batiste (Jurnee Smollett), who is narrating as an adult. It was filmed in Louisiana, in the bayou areas north of Lake Pontchartrain, north of New Orleans. I particularly like the exposition during the last scene where Eve describes our lives and memories as an intricate tapestry of all of our memories. This movie is about Eve's memories. The movie starts by saying that Eve was 11 years old when she killed her father. We don't find out what she means until the very end. Her father is small time doctor Louis Batiste (Samuel L. Jackson) who mostly makes routine house calls, dispenses aspirin, and flirts with the lonely ladies. He says he loves his wife, he appears to be a good father to his 2 daughters and son, but occasionally strays, and that is what gets him in hot water. Meagan Good is fine as the older sister Cisely Batiste. Lynn Whitfield is also good as the wife and mother Roz Batiste. SPOILERS. When Eve wanders into the storage shed during a party, and falls asleep, she awakens to find her dad and Mrs Mereaux engaged in sexual activity. This scares her, but what really gets her going is when sis tells her that dad made advances towards her, then hit her when she withdrew. Little Eve decided she needed to have her dad dead, goes to voodoo lady Elzora (Diahann Carroll) for a spell. What really gets dad is when Mrs Mereaux's husband shows up and finds him and his wife together at a bar. He tells Loius to never speak to his wife again or he will kill him. Louis smiles and yells 'good night Matty', and the jealous husband shoots and kills him. So, Eve really was responsible, because it was she in an earlier conversation that hinted to Mr Mereaux that her dad and his wife 'both seemed to come home late a lot.' Eve feels bad when she later finds out her sister's story was not true, she had been the one who made an advance by kissing dad as a mistress might, and dad rejected that which made sis mad enough to lie about it. Of interest to me, Branford Marsalis had a small role as friend Harry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich family saga with an interesting twist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prop03
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is now showing on cable here in Australia, and is a far better than average offering. Written and directed by Kasi Lemmons, the film is a powerful family drama set in the sixties in the south of the USA. It stars Samuel L Jackson as a small town doctor with a wandering eye. The story is told from the viewpoint of his middle child, Eve, wonderfully played by Jurnee Smollett, who sees her middle-class family life threatened by her father's infidelities. No tale set in a bayou village could exist without references to black magic and voodoo, and this film also has them as a rather central part of the plot. But these elements are handled skilfully and believably, and heighten the tension that develops. One of the interesting tools used by Lemmons is to tell and retell a story from different characters' perspectives, asking the viewer to determine which is more truthful, and indeed, whether the truth is paramount. Jackson gives a sparkling performance as Dr Louis Batiste, a man of warmth and generosity who is well regarded by the local community that he serves. His family is seemingly a happy and close one, until the children begin to question some of the adult behaviour they witness. Jurnee Smollett's Eve is the main protagonist around whom much of the story is centred, and she effortlessly moves back and forth between being a precocious brat and a young woman with powerful emotions. The rest of the cast is also very good, including a voluptuous Lisa Nicole Carson as the temptress Mattie Mereaux, and Diahann Carroll as a bayou witch. This film moves along at a good pace and is a little more than you might expect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is a 90s Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesewintersundays
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer/director Kasi Lemmons and her outstanding cast have outdone themselves in the sublime "Eve's Bayou." "Eve's Bayou" is fleet but not in a hurry. The scenes are clear and lean against the richness of the setting, but they flow leisurely toward the climax, like a punt bearing two lovers languidly downstream. "Eve's Bayou" is such a great story, partly because Lemmons herself is a master storyteller who is particularly gifted at strong endings, partly because the splendid cast embodies the characters so fully that the events actually seem to be happening to them, instead of unfolding from a screenplay. What a beautiful film it is: Not an overdecorated "period" portrait, but a film in which the people move easily through town and country homes and landscapes which frame and define them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Elegant and Deeply Disquieting Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    throughtheyellowgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons ''Eve's Bayou,'' is an elegant and deeply disquieting drama that became 1997's highest grossing independent film. The tenuous bonds that hold the Batiste, a highly accomplished African-American family, together have finally come undone. Spouses cheat; secrets are held -- lies are told ; parents and children share households but have no common ground. Beautifully acted as it is, "Eve's Bayou" still elects to keep its characters and their emotions at a distance. They remain as hidden from the viewer as they are from one another, which is an essential part of the film's disturbing power. Mrs. Lemmons daringly chooses to keep her story's motivational mysteries unexplained, leaving this richly observed film open to the viewer's assessments. Yet the sense of imbalance is ever-present and strong. Films like "Eve's Bayou" are not easily summarized; they don't have that slick "high concept" one-sentence peg that makes them easy to sell. Maybe all I've said still leaves you wondering what the movie is about. But some of the best movies are like this: They show everyday life, carefully observed, and as we grow to know the people in the film, maybe we find out something about ourselves. The fact that Lemmons is able to combine these qualities with turmoil, loneliness and even tragedy make the movie very rare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding, Outstanding, Outstanding!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeofmyangels
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons has invigorated and enriched her debut film, "Eve's Bayou", through the use of a thousand details, a strong sense of time and place, outstanding characterizations and a display of energy and cinematic flair that marks an advance on any other film released in 1997. Lemmons works with such piercing fervor and intelligence that "Eve's Bayou" just about transcends its tidy moral design. "Eve's Bayou" is as good a compromise of fact and fiction as you could hope for -- and still call it a movie. Lemmons directed this with a single-mindedness and attention to detail that makes it riveting. She doesn't make the mistake of adding cornball little subplots to popularize the material; she knows she has a great story, and she tells it with such realism that feels like we're apart of the Batiste family. This is a powerful story, one of 1997's best films, told with great clarity and acted like a finely tuned powerful fire(bravo Debbi Morgan).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Sad and Yet Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    girlkeepscomingloose
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" perfectly captures the melancholia that sometimes settles on a body like the gloaming, when the dying light seems profoundly sad and yet magical. Based on the short film "Dr. Hugo" (available on the DVD), this is a gem in the debut film making crown for writer/director Kasi Lemmons. Lemmons, with customary nuance and visual brilliance, crumbles the upper crust while breaking hearts with this poignant portrait of the Batiste, a wealthy African American family dwelling on a beautiful/haunting Louisiana bayou. While virtually every scene resonates with longing, there is one that is a masterpiece of unspoken words -- and somehow calls up visions of Ingmar Bergman's great family dramas. Debbi Morgan and young Jurnee Smollet -- who provide outstanding performances -- are supported by a host of deft players, and the detailed re-creation of this small universe is in all ways remarkable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great family drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons wrote and directed "Eve's Bayou," with such precision that I'm astounded that she hasn't had anything as good since this feature. Orson Welles is still famous for "Citizen Kane" after which he never reached such heights again. Samuel L. Jackson is a doctor who has a monogamy problem, constantly cheating on his wife, played by Lynn Whitfield. They have two daughters, Eve of the title, Jurnee Smollett is awesome as the lead character of this story and her sister Cisely(Meagan Good) is also a charming child actress. The two worship their father but they eventually discover his shortcomings as a husband. The two young sisters steal this film, an absorbing, tragic family drama of Shakespearean proportions. Lemmons has created a memorable classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love Love Love It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LOVE LOVE LOVE IT!!!!! One of my ALL TIME favorite movies ever made. Brilliant acting by the whole cast. Eve's Bayou is a spectacular movie. The color and scenery is wonderful and the people are elegant and troubled. Even the character's names stir up visions of dark swamp water and sultry heat. The story is told and seen through the eyes of little Eve Batiste played by a wonderful young actress named Jurnee Smollett. Eve takes us deep into her world which is filled with colorful characters and complex personalities.Diahann Carroll is fabulous as the old fortune teller Elzora with her insane laughter. Debbi Morgan as Aunt Mozelle Batiste Delacroix is something to behold. Aunt Mozelle has promised her family that she will not use her "second sight" to tell fortunes, but neighbors won't let her keep her promise. They seek her out to find missing husbands anyway. Lynn Whitfied as the manor born wife is beautiful and poised as she tries to keep her family together in spite of her wandering husband (Samuel L. Jackson). Jackson is very sexy in this movie and his character has roving eyes as well as roving hands that don't stop even when he is caught in a compromising position by his youngest daughter, Eve. This starts a set of events that lead to the total destruction of an already deeply troubled family.Although this movie did not make history at the box office my guess is that it will become a cult classic. Years from now this movie will be viewed for what it is, a brilliantly produced film. You can literally feel the Louisiana heat from Eve's Bayou. danceability. Amsterdam
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of the '90s -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evehands
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - which i am embarrassed to admit we only went to see because of the coincidence of the name!! But this absurd 'excuse' to see a film we'd heard nothing about (no publicity or marketing - just an option among several others at our local multiplex cinema, lured in by a beautiful poster which it turned out proved to be a foretaste of a gorgeously shot movie) paid off richly. We are seldom impressed as we were with 'Eve's Bayou'; this layering of memories, filtered through the perceptions of three distinctly different women, was such an intelligent and suspenseful use of the much-abused medium of film, that I thought about and remembered it yesterday after 11 years (!) and decided to rent it again; I am confident I will like it just as much on second viewing. Now that i know it was a low budget first outing for the (female) director (whose DP was likewise female - something which is STILL an anomaly, even today, where commercially released features are concerned), I am simply blown away....Roger Ebert is absolutely right; the fact that this was not nominated for an Academy Award means they were simply not paying attention; for shame! It ought to have been a runaway success, and at very least nominated for Best Director, Best Supporting Actress(es), Best DP, Best Costumes, Best Screenplay. Unfortunately, Kasi Lemmons' follow- up to this (the gruesomely dark 'Valentine' something-or-other) was nowhere near as accomplished as this (though it was still good, by any movie standards). Perhaps she lost heart after being so overlooked? (and if so, who could blame her?!). I hope this film gets a re-release and much belated marketing 'push', with a perhaps more prominent placing at the local DVD stores, at least (I'm having to order my rented copy in 'cause it's not in the store...)!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flaaaaaaaaaaaawwwwwwwless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been a TOTAL fan of Lynn Whitfield and Debbi Morgan for YEARS, I KNEW I would be in for a treat. This overlooked film is indeed a wonder and in time will place among one of the finest movies ever made. It is multi-layered and deals with some extremely sensitive issues all the while painting a beautiful tapestry of African-American life in the Louisianna bayou. For those of you who have not seen it, it deals with the awakening of a father and his daughters one summer and the emotions that accompany this learning. The young Eve is brilliantly played by Smollett and Debbi Morgan gives a knockout performance that you crave to see over and over again. Diahann Carroll works you because her character is not at all glamorous but pivotal to the plot as Eve comes to realize the responsibility of her "gift" and learns the truth of the age-old adage, "Be careful what you wish for, for you just might get it." Samuel L. Jackson is wonderful as usual and perfectly cast. While his character is not necessarily sympathetic, he is totally understandable and for a little girl who worships her father he is perfectly cast. While some aspects of the father-daughter relationship may be somewhat uncomfortable, the director does a beautiful job bringing the complexity of these issues to the screen and I heartily applaud her. This is one that belongs in any movie collection and one where African-American life is celebrated and treated with the utmost respect and honesty. Hats off to a wonderful production!!!!!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine family drama set in 1960s Louisiana.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is the name of the small settlement along the bayou that former slave Eve gave her name to. The story is told from a young girl's point of view, Eve Batiste (Jurnee Smollett), who is narrating as an adult. It was filmed in Louisiana, in the bayou areas north of Lake Pontchartrain, north of New Orleans. I particularly like the exposition during the last scene where Eve describes our lives and memories as an intricate tapestry of all of our memories. This movie is about Eve's memories. The movie starts by saying that Eve was 11 years old when she killed her father. We don't find out what she means until the very end. Her father is small time doctor Louis Batiste (Samuel L. Jackson) who mostly makes routine house calls, dispenses aspirin, and flirts with the lonely ladies. He says he loves his wife, he appears to be a good father to his 2 daughters and son, but occasionally strays, and that is what gets him in hot water. Meagan Good is fine as the older sister Cisely Batiste. Lynn Whitfield is also good as the wife and mother Roz Batiste. SPOILERS. When Eve wanders into the storage shed during a party, and falls asleep, she awakens to find her dad and Mrs Mereaux engaged in sexual activity. This scares her, but what really gets her going is when sis tells her that dad made advances towards her, then hit her when she withdrew. Little Eve decided she needed to have her dad dead, goes to voodoo lady Elzora (Diahann Carroll) for a spell. What really gets dad is when Mrs Mereaux's husband shows up and finds him and his wife together at a bar. He tells Loius to never speak to his wife again or he will kill him. Louis smiles and yells 'good night Matty', and the jealous husband shoots and kills him. So, Eve really was responsible, because it was she in an earlier conversation that hinted to Mr Mereaux that her dad and his wife 'both seemed to come home late a lot.' Eve feels bad when she later finds out her sister's story was not true, she had been the one who made an advance by kissing dad as a mistress might, and dad rejected that which made sis mad enough to lie about it. Of interest to me, Branford Marsalis had a small role as friend Harry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich family saga with an interesting twist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prop03
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is now showing on cable here in Australia, and is a far better than average offering. Written and directed by Kasi Lemmons, the film is a powerful family drama set in the sixties in the south of the USA. It stars Samuel L Jackson as a small town doctor with a wandering eye. The story is told from the viewpoint of his middle child, Eve, wonderfully played by Jurnee Smollett, who sees her middle-class family life threatened by her father's infidelities. No tale set in a bayou village could exist without references to black magic and voodoo, and this film also has them as a rather central part of the plot. But these elements are handled skilfully and believably, and heighten the tension that develops. One of the interesting tools used by Lemmons is to tell and retell a story from different characters' perspectives, asking the viewer to determine which is more truthful, and indeed, whether the truth is paramount. Jackson gives a sparkling performance as Dr Louis Batiste, a man of warmth and generosity who is well regarded by the local community that he serves. His family is seemingly a happy and close one, until the children begin to question some of the adult behaviour they witness. Jurnee Smollett's Eve is the main protagonist around whom much of the story is centred, and she effortlessly moves back and forth between being a precocious brat and a young woman with powerful emotions. The rest of the cast is also very good, including a voluptuous Lisa Nicole Carson as the temptress Mattie Mereaux, and Diahann Carroll as a bayou witch. This film moves along at a good pace and is a little more than you might expect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is a 90s Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesewintersundays
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer/director Kasi Lemmons and her outstanding cast have outdone themselves in the sublime "Eve's Bayou." "Eve's Bayou" is fleet but not in a hurry. The scenes are clear and lean against the richness of the setting, but they flow leisurely toward the climax, like a punt bearing two lovers languidly downstream. "Eve's Bayou" is such a great story, partly because Lemmons herself is a master storyteller who is particularly gifted at strong endings, partly because the splendid cast embodies the characters so fully that the events actually seem to be happening to them, instead of unfolding from a screenplay. What a beautiful film it is: Not an overdecorated "period" portrait, but a film in which the people move easily through town and country homes and landscapes which frame and define them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Elegant and Deeply Disquieting Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    throughtheyellowgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons ''Eve's Bayou,'' is an elegant and deeply disquieting drama that became 1997's highest grossing independent film. The tenuous bonds that hold the Batiste, a highly accomplished African-American family, together have finally come undone. Spouses cheat; secrets are held -- lies are told ; parents and children share households but have no common ground. Beautifully acted as it is, "Eve's Bayou" still elects to keep its characters and their emotions at a distance. They remain as hidden from the viewer as they are from one another, which is an essential part of the film's disturbing power. Mrs. Lemmons daringly chooses to keep her story's motivational mysteries unexplained, leaving this richly observed film open to the viewer's assessments. Yet the sense of imbalance is ever-present and strong. Films like "Eve's Bayou" are not easily summarized; they don't have that slick "high concept" one-sentence peg that makes them easy to sell. Maybe all I've said still leaves you wondering what the movie is about. But some of the best movies are like this: They show everyday life, carefully observed, and as we grow to know the people in the film, maybe we find out something about ourselves. The fact that Lemmons is able to combine these qualities with turmoil, loneliness and even tragedy make the movie very rare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding, Outstanding, Outstanding!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeofmyangels
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons has invigorated and enriched her debut film, "Eve's Bayou", through the use of a thousand details, a strong sense of time and place, outstanding characterizations and a display of energy and cinematic flair that marks an advance on any other film released in 1997. Lemmons works with such piercing fervor and intelligence that "Eve's Bayou" just about transcends its tidy moral design. "Eve's Bayou" is as good a compromise of fact and fiction as you could hope for -- and still call it a movie. Lemmons directed this with a single-mindedness and attention to detail that makes it riveting. She doesn't make the mistake of adding cornball little subplots to popularize the material; she knows she has a great story, and she tells it with such realism that feels like we're apart of the Batiste family. This is a powerful story, one of 1997's best films, told with great clarity and acted like a finely tuned powerful fire(bravo Debbi Morgan).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Sad and Yet Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    girlkeepscomingloose
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" perfectly captures the melancholia that sometimes settles on a body like the gloaming, when the dying light seems profoundly sad and yet magical. Based on the short film "Dr. Hugo" (available on the DVD), this is a gem in the debut film making crown for writer/director Kasi Lemmons. Lemmons, with customary nuance and visual brilliance, crumbles the upper crust while breaking hearts with this poignant portrait of the Batiste, a wealthy African American family dwelling on a beautiful/haunting Louisiana bayou. While virtually every scene resonates with longing, there is one that is a masterpiece of unspoken words -- and somehow calls up visions of Ingmar Bergman's great family dramas. Debbi Morgan and young Jurnee Smollet -- who provide outstanding performances -- are supported by a host of deft players, and the detailed re-creation of this small universe is in all ways remarkable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great family drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons wrote and directed "Eve's Bayou," with such precision that I'm astounded that she hasn't had anything as good since this feature. Orson Welles is still famous for "Citizen Kane" after which he never reached such heights again. Samuel L. Jackson is a doctor who has a monogamy problem, constantly cheating on his wife, played by Lynn Whitfield. They have two daughters, Eve of the title, Jurnee Smollett is awesome as the lead character of this story and her sister Cisely(Meagan Good) is also a charming child actress. The two worship their father but they eventually discover his shortcomings as a husband. The two young sisters steal this film, an absorbing, tragic family drama of Shakespearean proportions. Lemmons has created a memorable classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love Love Love It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LOVE LOVE LOVE IT!!!!! One of my ALL TIME favorite movies ever made. Brilliant acting by the whole cast. Eve's Bayou is a spectacular movie. The color and scenery is wonderful and the people are elegant and troubled. Even the character's names stir up visions of dark swamp water and sultry heat. The story is told and seen through the eyes of little Eve Batiste played by a wonderful young actress named Jurnee Smollett. Eve takes us deep into her world which is filled with colorful characters and complex personalities.Diahann Carroll is fabulous as the old fortune teller Elzora with her insane laughter. Debbi Morgan as Aunt Mozelle Batiste Delacroix is something to behold. Aunt Mozelle has promised her family that she will not use her "second sight" to tell fortunes, but neighbors won't let her keep her promise. They seek her out to find missing husbands anyway. Lynn Whitfied as the manor born wife is beautiful and poised as she tries to keep her family together in spite of her wandering husband (Samuel L. Jackson). Jackson is very sexy in this movie and his character has roving eyes as well as roving hands that don't stop even when he is caught in a compromising position by his youngest daughter, Eve. This starts a set of events that lead to the total destruction of an already deeply troubled family.Although this movie did not make history at the box office my guess is that it will become a cult classic. Years from now this movie will be viewed for what it is, a brilliantly produced film. You can literally feel the Louisiana heat from Eve's Bayou. danceability. Amsterdam
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of the '90s -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evehands
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - which i am embarrassed to admit we only went to see because of the coincidence of the name!! But this absurd 'excuse' to see a film we'd heard nothing about (no publicity or marketing - just an option among several others at our local multiplex cinema, lured in by a beautiful poster which it turned out proved to be a foretaste of a gorgeously shot movie) paid off richly. We are seldom impressed as we were with 'Eve's Bayou'; this layering of memories, filtered through the perceptions of three distinctly different women, was such an intelligent and suspenseful use of the much-abused medium of film, that I thought about and remembered it yesterday after 11 years (!) and decided to rent it again; I am confident I will like it just as much on second viewing. Now that i know it was a low budget first outing for the (female) director (whose DP was likewise female - something which is STILL an anomaly, even today, where commercially released features are concerned), I am simply blown away....Roger Ebert is absolutely right; the fact that this was not nominated for an Academy Award means they were simply not paying attention; for shame! It ought to have been a runaway success, and at very least nominated for Best Director, Best Supporting Actress(es), Best DP, Best Costumes, Best Screenplay. Unfortunately, Kasi Lemmons' follow- up to this (the gruesomely dark 'Valentine' something-or-other) was nowhere near as accomplished as this (though it was still good, by any movie standards). Perhaps she lost heart after being so overlooked? (and if so, who could blame her?!). I hope this film gets a re-release and much belated marketing 'push', with a perhaps more prominent placing at the local DVD stores, at least (I'm having to order my rented copy in 'cause it's not in the store...)!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flaaaaaaaaaaaawwwwwwwless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been a TOTAL fan of Lynn Whitfield and Debbi Morgan for YEARS, I KNEW I would be in for a treat. This overlooked film is indeed a wonder and in time will place among one of the finest movies ever made. It is multi-layered and deals with some extremely sensitive issues all the while painting a beautiful tapestry of African-American life in the Louisianna bayou. For those of you who have not seen it, it deals with the awakening of a father and his daughters one summer and the emotions that accompany this learning. The young Eve is brilliantly played by Smollett and Debbi Morgan gives a knockout performance that you crave to see over and over again. Diahann Carroll works you because her character is not at all glamorous but pivotal to the plot as Eve comes to realize the responsibility of her "gift" and learns the truth of the age-old adage, "Be careful what you wish for, for you just might get it." Samuel L. Jackson is wonderful as usual and perfectly cast. While his character is not necessarily sympathetic, he is totally understandable and for a little girl who worships her father he is perfectly cast. While some aspects of the father-daughter relationship may be somewhat uncomfortable, the director does a beautiful job bringing the complexity of these issues to the screen and I heartily applaud her. This is one that belongs in any movie collection and one where African-American life is celebrated and treated with the utmost respect and honesty. Hats off to a wonderful production!!!!!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine family drama set in 1960s Louisiana.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is the name of the small settlement along the bayou that former slave Eve gave her name to. The story is told from a young girl's point of view, Eve Batiste (Jurnee Smollett), who is narrating as an adult. It was filmed in Louisiana, in the bayou areas north of Lake Pontchartrain, north of New Orleans. I particularly like the exposition during the last scene where Eve describes our lives and memories as an intricate tapestry of all of our memories. This movie is about Eve's memories. The movie starts by saying that Eve was 11 years old when she killed her father. We don't find out what she means until the very end. Her father is small time doctor Louis Batiste (Samuel L. Jackson) who mostly makes routine house calls, dispenses aspirin, and flirts with the lonely ladies. He says he loves his wife, he appears to be a good father to his 2 daughters and son, but occasionally strays, and that is what gets him in hot water. Meagan Good is fine as the older sister Cisely Batiste. Lynn Whitfield is also good as the wife and mother Roz Batiste. SPOILERS. When Eve wanders into the storage shed during a party, and falls asleep, she awakens to find her dad and Mrs Mereaux engaged in sexual activity. This scares her, but what really gets her going is when sis tells her that dad made advances towards her, then hit her when she withdrew. Little Eve decided she needed to have her dad dead, goes to voodoo lady Elzora (Diahann Carroll) for a spell. What really gets dad is when Mrs Mereaux's husband shows up and finds him and his wife together at a bar. He tells Loius to never speak to his wife again or he will kill him. Louis smiles and yells 'good night Matty', and the jealous husband shoots and kills him. So, Eve really was responsible, because it was she in an earlier conversation that hinted to Mr Mereaux that her dad and his wife 'both seemed to come home late a lot.' Eve feels bad when she later finds out her sister's story was not true, she had been the one who made an advance by kissing dad as a mistress might, and dad rejected that which made sis mad enough to lie about it. Of interest to me, Branford Marsalis had a small role as friend Harry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich family saga with an interesting twist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prop03
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is now showing on cable here in Australia, and is a far better than average offering. Written and directed by Kasi Lemmons, the film is a powerful family drama set in the sixties in the south of the USA. It stars Samuel L Jackson as a small town doctor with a wandering eye. The story is told from the viewpoint of his middle child, Eve, wonderfully played by Jurnee Smollett, who sees her middle-class family life threatened by her father's infidelities. No tale set in a bayou village could exist without references to black magic and voodoo, and this film also has them as a rather central part of the plot. But these elements are handled skilfully and believably, and heighten the tension that develops. One of the interesting tools used by Lemmons is to tell and retell a story from different characters' perspectives, asking the viewer to determine which is more truthful, and indeed, whether the truth is paramount. Jackson gives a sparkling performance as Dr Louis Batiste, a man of warmth and generosity who is well regarded by the local community that he serves. His family is seemingly a happy and close one, until the children begin to question some of the adult behaviour they witness. Jurnee Smollett's Eve is the main protagonist around whom much of the story is centred, and she effortlessly moves back and forth between being a precocious brat and a young woman with powerful emotions. The rest of the cast is also very good, including a voluptuous Lisa Nicole Carson as the temptress Mattie Mereaux, and Diahann Carroll as a bayou witch. This film moves along at a good pace and is a little more than you might expect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is a 90s Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesewintersundays
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer/director Kasi Lemmons and her outstanding cast have outdone themselves in the sublime "Eve's Bayou." "Eve's Bayou" is fleet but not in a hurry. The scenes are clear and lean against the richness of the setting, but they flow leisurely toward the climax, like a punt bearing two lovers languidly downstream. "Eve's Bayou" is such a great story, partly because Lemmons herself is a master storyteller who is particularly gifted at strong endings, partly because the splendid cast embodies the characters so fully that the events actually seem to be happening to them, instead of unfolding from a screenplay. What a beautiful film it is: Not an overdecorated "period" portrait, but a film in which the people move easily through town and country homes and landscapes which frame and define them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Elegant and Deeply Disquieting Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    throughtheyellowgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons ''Eve's Bayou,'' is an elegant and deeply disquieting drama that became 1997's highest grossing independent film. The tenuous bonds that hold the Batiste, a highly accomplished African-American family, together have finally come undone. Spouses cheat; secrets are held -- lies are told ; parents and children share households but have no common ground. Beautifully acted as it is, "Eve's Bayou" still elects to keep its characters and their emotions at a distance. They remain as hidden from the viewer as they are from one another, which is an essential part of the film's disturbing power. Mrs. Lemmons daringly chooses to keep her story's motivational mysteries unexplained, leaving this richly observed film open to the viewer's assessments. Yet the sense of imbalance is ever-present and strong. Films like "Eve's Bayou" are not easily summarized; they don't have that slick "high concept" one-sentence peg that makes them easy to sell. Maybe all I've said still leaves you wondering what the movie is about. But some of the best movies are like this: They show everyday life, carefully observed, and as we grow to know the people in the film, maybe we find out something about ourselves. The fact that Lemmons is able to combine these qualities with turmoil, loneliness and even tragedy make the movie very rare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding, Outstanding, Outstanding!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeofmyangels
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons has invigorated and enriched her debut film, "Eve's Bayou", through the use of a thousand details, a strong sense of time and place, outstanding characterizations and a display of energy and cinematic flair that marks an advance on any other film released in 1997. Lemmons works with such piercing fervor and intelligence that "Eve's Bayou" just about transcends its tidy moral design. "Eve's Bayou" is as good a compromise of fact and fiction as you could hope for -- and still call it a movie. Lemmons directed this with a single-mindedness and attention to detail that makes it riveting. She doesn't make the mistake of adding cornball little subplots to popularize the material; she knows she has a great story, and she tells it with such realism that feels like we're apart of the Batiste family. This is a powerful story, one of 1997's best films, told with great clarity and acted like a finely tuned powerful fire(bravo Debbi Morgan).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Sad and Yet Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    girlkeepscomingloose
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" perfectly captures the melancholia that sometimes settles on a body like the gloaming, when the dying light seems profoundly sad and yet magical. Based on the short film "Dr. Hugo" (available on the DVD), this is a gem in the debut film making crown for writer/director Kasi Lemmons. Lemmons, with customary nuance and visual brilliance, crumbles the upper crust while breaking hearts with this poignant portrait of the Batiste, a wealthy African American family dwelling on a beautiful/haunting Louisiana bayou. While virtually every scene resonates with longing, there is one that is a masterpiece of unspoken words -- and somehow calls up visions of Ingmar Bergman's great family dramas. Debbi Morgan and young Jurnee Smollet -- who provide outstanding performances -- are supported by a host of deft players, and the detailed re-creation of this small universe is in all ways remarkable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great family drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons wrote and directed "Eve's Bayou," with such precision that I'm astounded that she hasn't had anything as good since this feature. Orson Welles is still famous for "Citizen Kane" after which he never reached such heights again. Samuel L. Jackson is a doctor who has a monogamy problem, constantly cheating on his wife, played by Lynn Whitfield. They have two daughters, Eve of the title, Jurnee Smollett is awesome as the lead character of this story and her sister Cisely(Meagan Good) is also a charming child actress. The two worship their father but they eventually discover his shortcomings as a husband. The two young sisters steal this film, an absorbing, tragic family drama of Shakespearean proportions. Lemmons has created a memorable classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love Love Love It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LOVE LOVE LOVE IT!!!!! One of my ALL TIME favorite movies ever made. Brilliant acting by the whole cast. Eve's Bayou is a spectacular movie. The color and scenery is wonderful and the people are elegant and troubled. Even the character's names stir up visions of dark swamp water and sultry heat. The story is told and seen through the eyes of little Eve Batiste played by a wonderful young actress named Jurnee Smollett. Eve takes us deep into her world which is filled with colorful characters and complex personalities.Diahann Carroll is fabulous as the old fortune teller Elzora with her insane laughter. Debbi Morgan as Aunt Mozelle Batiste Delacroix is something to behold. Aunt Mozelle has promised her family that she will not use her "second sight" to tell fortunes, but neighbors won't let her keep her promise. They seek her out to find missing husbands anyway. Lynn Whitfied as the manor born wife is beautiful and poised as she tries to keep her family together in spite of her wandering husband (Samuel L. Jackson). Jackson is very sexy in this movie and his character has roving eyes as well as roving hands that don't stop even when he is caught in a compromising position by his youngest daughter, Eve. This starts a set of events that lead to the total destruction of an already deeply troubled family.Although this movie did not make history at the box office my guess is that it will become a cult classic. Years from now this movie will be viewed for what it is, a brilliantly produced film. You can literally feel the Louisiana heat from Eve's Bayou. danceability. Amsterdam
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of the '90s -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evehands
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - which i am embarrassed to admit we only went to see because of the coincidence of the name!! But this absurd 'excuse' to see a film we'd heard nothing about (no publicity or marketing - just an option among several others at our local multiplex cinema, lured in by a beautiful poster which it turned out proved to be a foretaste of a gorgeously shot movie) paid off richly. We are seldom impressed as we were with 'Eve's Bayou'; this layering of memories, filtered through the perceptions of three distinctly different women, was such an intelligent and suspenseful use of the much-abused medium of film, that I thought about and remembered it yesterday after 11 years (!) and decided to rent it again; I am confident I will like it just as much on second viewing. Now that i know it was a low budget first outing for the (female) director (whose DP was likewise female - something which is STILL an anomaly, even today, where commercially released features are concerned), I am simply blown away....Roger Ebert is absolutely right; the fact that this was not nominated for an Academy Award means they were simply not paying attention; for shame! It ought to have been a runaway success, and at very least nominated for Best Director, Best Supporting Actress(es), Best DP, Best Costumes, Best Screenplay. Unfortunately, Kasi Lemmons' follow- up to this (the gruesomely dark 'Valentine' something-or-other) was nowhere near as accomplished as this (though it was still good, by any movie standards). Perhaps she lost heart after being so overlooked? (and if so, who could blame her?!). I hope this film gets a re-release and much belated marketing 'push', with a perhaps more prominent placing at the local DVD stores, at least (I'm having to order my rented copy in 'cause it's not in the store...)!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flaaaaaaaaaaaawwwwwwwless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been a TOTAL fan of Lynn Whitfield and Debbi Morgan for YEARS, I KNEW I would be in for a treat. This overlooked film is indeed a wonder and in time will place among one of the finest movies ever made. It is multi-layered and deals with some extremely sensitive issues all the while painting a beautiful tapestry of African-American life in the Louisianna bayou. For those of you who have not seen it, it deals with the awakening of a father and his daughters one summer and the emotions that accompany this learning. The young Eve is brilliantly played by Smollett and Debbi Morgan gives a knockout performance that you crave to see over and over again. Diahann Carroll works you because her character is not at all glamorous but pivotal to the plot as Eve comes to realize the responsibility of her "gift" and learns the truth of the age-old adage, "Be careful what you wish for, for you just might get it." Samuel L. Jackson is wonderful as usual and perfectly cast. While his character is not necessarily sympathetic, he is totally understandable and for a little girl who worships her father he is perfectly cast. While some aspects of the father-daughter relationship may be somewhat uncomfortable, the director does a beautiful job bringing the complexity of these issues to the screen and I heartily applaud her. This is one that belongs in any movie collection and one where African-American life is celebrated and treated with the utmost respect and honesty. Hats off to a wonderful production!!!!!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine family drama set in 1960s Louisiana.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is the name of the small settlement along the bayou that former slave Eve gave her name to. The story is told from a young girl's point of view, Eve Batiste (Jurnee Smollett), who is narrating as an adult. It was filmed in Louisiana, in the bayou areas north of Lake Pontchartrain, north of New Orleans. I particularly like the exposition during the last scene where Eve describes our lives and memories as an intricate tapestry of all of our memories. This movie is about Eve's memories. The movie starts by saying that Eve was 11 years old when she killed her father. We don't find out what she means until the very end. Her father is small time doctor Louis Batiste (Samuel L. Jackson) who mostly makes routine house calls, dispenses aspirin, and flirts with the lonely ladies. He says he loves his wife, he appears to be a good father to his 2 daughters and son, but occasionally strays, and that is what gets him in hot water. Meagan Good is fine as the older sister Cisely Batiste. Lynn Whitfield is also good as the wife and mother Roz Batiste. SPOILERS. When Eve wanders into the storage shed during a party, and falls asleep, she awakens to find her dad and Mrs Mereaux engaged in sexual activity. This scares her, but what really gets her going is when sis tells her that dad made advances towards her, then hit her when she withdrew. Little Eve decided she needed to have her dad dead, goes to voodoo lady Elzora (Diahann Carroll) for a spell. What really gets dad is when Mrs Mereaux's husband shows up and finds him and his wife together at a bar. He tells Loius to never speak to his wife again or he will kill him. Louis smiles and yells 'good night Matty', and the jealous husband shoots and kills him. So, Eve really was responsible, because it was she in an earlier conversation that hinted to Mr Mereaux that her dad and his wife 'both seemed to come home late a lot.' Eve feels bad when she later finds out her sister's story was not true, she had been the one who made an advance by kissing dad as a mistress might, and dad rejected that which made sis mad enough to lie about it. Of interest to me, Branford Marsalis had a small role as friend Harry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich family saga with an interesting twist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prop03
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is now showing on cable here in Australia, and is a far better than average offering. Written and directed by Kasi Lemmons, the film is a powerful family drama set in the sixties in the south of the USA. It stars Samuel L Jackson as a small town doctor with a wandering eye. The story is told from the viewpoint of his middle child, Eve, wonderfully played by Jurnee Smollett, who sees her middle-class family life threatened by her father's infidelities. No tale set in a bayou village could exist without references to black magic and voodoo, and this film also has them as a rather central part of the plot. But these elements are handled skilfully and believably, and heighten the tension that develops. One of the interesting tools used by Lemmons is to tell and retell a story from different characters' perspectives, asking the viewer to determine which is more truthful, and indeed, whether the truth is paramount. Jackson gives a sparkling performance as Dr Louis Batiste, a man of warmth and generosity who is well regarded by the local community that he serves. His family is seemingly a happy and close one, until the children begin to question some of the adult behaviour they witness. Jurnee Smollett's Eve is the main protagonist around whom much of the story is centred, and she effortlessly moves back and forth between being a precocious brat and a young woman with powerful emotions. The rest of the cast is also very good, including a voluptuous Lisa Nicole Carson as the temptress Mattie Mereaux, and Diahann Carroll as a bayou witch. This film moves along at a good pace and is a little more than you might expect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is a 90s Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesewintersundays
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer/director Kasi Lemmons and her outstanding cast have outdone themselves in the sublime "Eve's Bayou." "Eve's Bayou" is fleet but not in a hurry. The scenes are clear and lean against the richness of the setting, but they flow leisurely toward the climax, like a punt bearing two lovers languidly downstream. "Eve's Bayou" is such a great story, partly because Lemmons herself is a master storyteller who is particularly gifted at strong endings, partly because the splendid cast embodies the characters so fully that the events actually seem to be happening to them, instead of unfolding from a screenplay. What a beautiful film it is: Not an overdecorated "period" portrait, but a film in which the people move easily through town and country homes and landscapes which frame and define them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Elegant and Deeply Disquieting Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    throughtheyellowgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons ''Eve's Bayou,'' is an elegant and deeply disquieting drama that became 1997's highest grossing independent film. The tenuous bonds that hold the Batiste, a highly accomplished African-American family, together have finally come undone. Spouses cheat; secrets are held -- lies are told ; parents and children share households but have no common ground. Beautifully acted as it is, "Eve's Bayou" still elects to keep its characters and their emotions at a distance. They remain as hidden from the viewer as they are from one another, which is an essential part of the film's disturbing power. Mrs. Lemmons daringly chooses to keep her story's motivational mysteries unexplained, leaving this richly observed film open to the viewer's assessments. Yet the sense of imbalance is ever-present and strong. Films like "Eve's Bayou" are not easily summarized; they don't have that slick "high concept" one-sentence peg that makes them easy to sell. Maybe all I've said still leaves you wondering what the movie is about. But some of the best movies are like this: They show everyday life, carefully observed, and as we grow to know the people in the film, maybe we find out something about ourselves. The fact that Lemmons is able to combine these qualities with turmoil, loneliness and even tragedy make the movie very rare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding, Outstanding, Outstanding!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeofmyangels
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons has invigorated and enriched her debut film, "Eve's Bayou", through the use of a thousand details, a strong sense of time and place, outstanding characterizations and a display of energy and cinematic flair that marks an advance on any other film released in 1997. Lemmons works with such piercing fervor and intelligence that "Eve's Bayou" just about transcends its tidy moral design. "Eve's Bayou" is as good a compromise of fact and fiction as you could hope for -- and still call it a movie. Lemmons directed this with a single-mindedness and attention to detail that makes it riveting. She doesn't make the mistake of adding cornball little subplots to popularize the material; she knows she has a great story, and she tells it with such realism that feels like we're apart of the Batiste family. This is a powerful story, one of 1997's best films, told with great clarity and acted like a finely tuned powerful fire(bravo Debbi Morgan).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Sad and Yet Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    girlkeepscomingloose
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" perfectly captures the melancholia that sometimes settles on a body like the gloaming, when the dying light seems profoundly sad and yet magical. Based on the short film "Dr. Hugo" (available on the DVD), this is a gem in the debut film making crown for writer/director Kasi Lemmons. Lemmons, with customary nuance and visual brilliance, crumbles the upper crust while breaking hearts with this poignant portrait of the Batiste, a wealthy African American family dwelling on a beautiful/haunting Louisiana bayou. While virtually every scene resonates with longing, there is one that is a masterpiece of unspoken words -- and somehow calls up visions of Ingmar Bergman's great family dramas. Debbi Morgan and young Jurnee Smollet -- who provide outstanding performances -- are supported by a host of deft players, and the detailed re-creation of this small universe is in all ways remarkable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great family drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons wrote and directed "Eve's Bayou," with such precision that I'm astounded that she hasn't had anything as good since this feature. Orson Welles is still famous for "Citizen Kane" after which he never reached such heights again. Samuel L. Jackson is a doctor who has a monogamy problem, constantly cheating on his wife, played by Lynn Whitfield. They have two daughters, Eve of the title, Jurnee Smollett is awesome as the lead character of this story and her sister Cisely(Meagan Good) is also a charming child actress. The two worship their father but they eventually discover his shortcomings as a husband. The two young sisters steal this film, an absorbing, tragic family drama of Shakespearean proportions. Lemmons has created a memorable classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love Love Love It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LOVE LOVE LOVE IT!!!!! One of my ALL TIME favorite movies ever made. Brilliant acting by the whole cast. Eve's Bayou is a spectacular movie. The color and scenery is wonderful and the people are elegant and troubled. Even the character's names stir up visions of dark swamp water and sultry heat. The story is told and seen through the eyes of little Eve Batiste played by a wonderful young actress named Jurnee Smollett. Eve takes us deep into her world which is filled with colorful characters and complex personalities.Diahann Carroll is fabulous as the old fortune teller Elzora with her insane laughter. Debbi Morgan as Aunt Mozelle Batiste Delacroix is something to behold. Aunt Mozelle has promised her family that she will not use her "second sight" to tell fortunes, but neighbors won't let her keep her promise. They seek her out to find missing husbands anyway. Lynn Whitfied as the manor born wife is beautiful and poised as she tries to keep her family together in spite of her wandering husband (Samuel L. Jackson). Jackson is very sexy in this movie and his character has roving eyes as well as roving hands that don't stop even when he is caught in a compromising position by his youngest daughter, Eve. This starts a set of events that lead to the total destruction of an already deeply troubled family.Although this movie did not make history at the box office my guess is that it will become a cult classic. Years from now this movie will be viewed for what it is, a brilliantly produced film. You can literally feel the Louisiana heat from Eve's Bayou. danceability. Amsterdam
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of the '90s -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evehands
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - which i am embarrassed to admit we only went to see because of the coincidence of the name!! But this absurd 'excuse' to see a film we'd heard nothing about (no publicity or marketing - just an option among several others at our local multiplex cinema, lured in by a beautiful poster which it turned out proved to be a foretaste of a gorgeously shot movie) paid off richly. We are seldom impressed as we were with 'Eve's Bayou'; this layering of memories, filtered through the perceptions of three distinctly different women, was such an intelligent and suspenseful use of the much-abused medium of film, that I thought about and remembered it yesterday after 11 years (!) and decided to rent it again; I am confident I will like it just as much on second viewing. Now that i know it was a low budget first outing for the (female) director (whose DP was likewise female - something which is STILL an anomaly, even today, where commercially released features are concerned), I am simply blown away....Roger Ebert is absolutely right; the fact that this was not nominated for an Academy Award means they were simply not paying attention; for shame! It ought to have been a runaway success, and at very least nominated for Best Director, Best Supporting Actress(es), Best DP, Best Costumes, Best Screenplay. Unfortunately, Kasi Lemmons' follow- up to this (the gruesomely dark 'Valentine' something-or-other) was nowhere near as accomplished as this (though it was still good, by any movie standards). Perhaps she lost heart after being so overlooked? (and if so, who could blame her?!). I hope this film gets a re-release and much belated marketing 'push', with a perhaps more prominent placing at the local DVD stores, at least (I'm having to order my rented copy in 'cause it's not in the store...)!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flaaaaaaaaaaaawwwwwwwless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been a TOTAL fan of Lynn Whitfield and Debbi Morgan for YEARS, I KNEW I would be in for a treat. This overlooked film is indeed a wonder and in time will place among one of the finest movies ever made. It is multi-layered and deals with some extremely sensitive issues all the while painting a beautiful tapestry of African-American life in the Louisianna bayou. For those of you who have not seen it, it deals with the awakening of a father and his daughters one summer and the emotions that accompany this learning. The young Eve is brilliantly played by Smollett and Debbi Morgan gives a knockout performance that you crave to see over and over again. Diahann Carroll works you because her character is not at all glamorous but pivotal to the plot as Eve comes to realize the responsibility of her "gift" and learns the truth of the age-old adage, "Be careful what you wish for, for you just might get it." Samuel L. Jackson is wonderful as usual and perfectly cast. While his character is not necessarily sympathetic, he is totally understandable and for a little girl who worships her father he is perfectly cast. While some aspects of the father-daughter relationship may be somewhat uncomfortable, the director does a beautiful job bringing the complexity of these issues to the screen and I heartily applaud her. This is one that belongs in any movie collection and one where African-American life is celebrated and treated with the utmost respect and honesty. Hats off to a wonderful production!!!!!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine family drama set in 1960s Louisiana.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is the name of the small settlement along the bayou that former slave Eve gave her name to. The story is told from a young girl's point of view, Eve Batiste (Jurnee Smollett), who is narrating as an adult. It was filmed in Louisiana, in the bayou areas north of Lake Pontchartrain, north of New Orleans. I particularly like the exposition during the last scene where Eve describes our lives and memories as an intricate tapestry of all of our memories. This movie is about Eve's memories. The movie starts by saying that Eve was 11 years old when she killed her father. We don't find out what she means until the very end. Her father is small time doctor Louis Batiste (Samuel L. Jackson) who mostly makes routine house calls, dispenses aspirin, and flirts with the lonely ladies. He says he loves his wife, he appears to be a good father to his 2 daughters and son, but occasionally strays, and that is what gets him in hot water. Meagan Good is fine as the older sister Cisely Batiste. Lynn Whitfield is also good as the wife and mother Roz Batiste. SPOILERS. When Eve wanders into the storage shed during a party, and falls asleep, she awakens to find her dad and Mrs Mereaux engaged in sexual activity. This scares her, but what really gets her going is when sis tells her that dad made advances towards her, then hit her when she withdrew. Little Eve decided she needed to have her dad dead, goes to voodoo lady Elzora (Diahann Carroll) for a spell. What really gets dad is when Mrs Mereaux's husband shows up and finds him and his wife together at a bar. He tells Loius to never speak to his wife again or he will kill him. Louis smiles and yells 'good night Matty', and the jealous husband shoots and kills him. So, Eve really was responsible, because it was she in an earlier conversation that hinted to Mr Mereaux that her dad and his wife 'both seemed to come home late a lot.' Eve feels bad when she later finds out her sister's story was not true, she had been the one who made an advance by kissing dad as a mistress might, and dad rejected that which made sis mad enough to lie about it. Of interest to me, Branford Marsalis had a small role as friend Harry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich family saga with an interesting twist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prop03
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is now showing on cable here in Australia, and is a far better than average offering. Written and directed by Kasi Lemmons, the film is a powerful family drama set in the sixties in the south of the USA. It stars Samuel L Jackson as a small town doctor with a wandering eye. The story is told from the viewpoint of his middle child, Eve, wonderfully played by Jurnee Smollett, who sees her middle-class family life threatened by her father's infidelities. No tale set in a bayou village could exist without references to black magic and voodoo, and this film also has them as a rather central part of the plot. But these elements are handled skilfully and believably, and heighten the tension that develops. One of the interesting tools used by Lemmons is to tell and retell a story from different characters' perspectives, asking the viewer to determine which is more truthful, and indeed, whether the truth is paramount. Jackson gives a sparkling performance as Dr Louis Batiste, a man of warmth and generosity who is well regarded by the local community that he serves. His family is seemingly a happy and close one, until the children begin to question some of the adult behaviour they witness. Jurnee Smollett's Eve is the main protagonist around whom much of the story is centred, and she effortlessly moves back and forth between being a precocious brat and a young woman with powerful emotions. The rest of the cast is also very good, including a voluptuous Lisa Nicole Carson as the temptress Mattie Mereaux, and Diahann Carroll as a bayou witch. This film moves along at a good pace and is a little more than you might expect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is a 90s Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesewintersundays
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer/director Kasi Lemmons and her outstanding cast have outdone themselves in the sublime "Eve's Bayou." "Eve's Bayou" is fleet but not in a hurry. The scenes are clear and lean against the richness of the setting, but they flow leisurely toward the climax, like a punt bearing two lovers languidly downstream. "Eve's Bayou" is such a great story, partly because Lemmons herself is a master storyteller who is particularly gifted at strong endings, partly because the splendid cast embodies the characters so fully that the events actually seem to be happening to them, instead of unfolding from a screenplay. What a beautiful film it is: Not an overdecorated "period" portrait, but a film in which the people move easily through town and country homes and landscapes which frame and define them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Elegant and Deeply Disquieting Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    throughtheyellowgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons ''Eve's Bayou,'' is an elegant and deeply disquieting drama that became 1997's highest grossing independent film. The tenuous bonds that hold the Batiste, a highly accomplished African-American family, together have finally come undone. Spouses cheat; secrets are held -- lies are told ; parents and children share households but have no common ground. Beautifully acted as it is, "Eve's Bayou" still elects to keep its characters and their emotions at a distance. They remain as hidden from the viewer as they are from one another, which is an essential part of the film's disturbing power. Mrs. Lemmons daringly chooses to keep her story's motivational mysteries unexplained, leaving this richly observed film open to the viewer's assessments. Yet the sense of imbalance is ever-present and strong. Films like "Eve's Bayou" are not easily summarized; they don't have that slick "high concept" one-sentence peg that makes them easy to sell. Maybe all I've said still leaves you wondering what the movie is about. But some of the best movies are like this: They show everyday life, carefully observed, and as we grow to know the people in the film, maybe we find out something about ourselves. The fact that Lemmons is able to combine these qualities with turmoil, loneliness and even tragedy make the movie very rare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding, Outstanding, Outstanding!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeofmyangels
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons has invigorated and enriched her debut film, "Eve's Bayou", through the use of a thousand details, a strong sense of time and place, outstanding characterizations and a display of energy and cinematic flair that marks an advance on any other film released in 1997. Lemmons works with such piercing fervor and intelligence that "Eve's Bayou" just about transcends its tidy moral design. "Eve's Bayou" is as good a compromise of fact and fiction as you could hope for -- and still call it a movie. Lemmons directed this with a single-mindedness and attention to detail that makes it riveting. She doesn't make the mistake of adding cornball little subplots to popularize the material; she knows she has a great story, and she tells it with such realism that feels like we're apart of the Batiste family. This is a powerful story, one of 1997's best films, told with great clarity and acted like a finely tuned powerful fire(bravo Debbi Morgan).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Sad and Yet Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    girlkeepscomingloose
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" perfectly captures the melancholia that sometimes settles on a body like the gloaming, when the dying light seems profoundly sad and yet magical. Based on the short film "Dr. Hugo" (available on the DVD), this is a gem in the debut film making crown for writer/director Kasi Lemmons. Lemmons, with customary nuance and visual brilliance, crumbles the upper crust while breaking hearts with this poignant portrait of the Batiste, a wealthy African American family dwelling on a beautiful/haunting Louisiana bayou. While virtually every scene resonates with longing, there is one that is a masterpiece of unspoken words -- and somehow calls up visions of Ingmar Bergman's great family dramas. Debbi Morgan and young Jurnee Smollet -- who provide outstanding performances -- are supported by a host of deft players, and the detailed re-creation of this small universe is in all ways remarkable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great family drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons wrote and directed "Eve's Bayou," with such precision that I'm astounded that she hasn't had anything as good since this feature. Orson Welles is still famous for "Citizen Kane" after which he never reached such heights again. Samuel L. Jackson is a doctor who has a monogamy problem, constantly cheating on his wife, played by Lynn Whitfield. They have two daughters, Eve of the title, Jurnee Smollett is awesome as the lead character of this story and her sister Cisely(Meagan Good) is also a charming child actress. The two worship their father but they eventually discover his shortcomings as a husband. The two young sisters steal this film, an absorbing, tragic family drama of Shakespearean proportions. Lemmons has created a memorable classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love Love Love It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LOVE LOVE LOVE IT!!!!! One of my ALL TIME favorite movies ever made. Brilliant acting by the whole cast. Eve's Bayou is a spectacular movie. The color and scenery is wonderful and the people are elegant and troubled. Even the character's names stir up visions of dark swamp water and sultry heat. The story is told and seen through the eyes of little Eve Batiste played by a wonderful young actress named Jurnee Smollett. Eve takes us deep into her world which is filled with colorful characters and complex personalities.Diahann Carroll is fabulous as the old fortune teller Elzora with her insane laughter. Debbi Morgan as Aunt Mozelle Batiste Delacroix is something to behold. Aunt Mozelle has promised her family that she will not use her "second sight" to tell fortunes, but neighbors won't let her keep her promise. They seek her out to find missing husbands anyway. Lynn Whitfied as the manor born wife is beautiful and poised as she tries to keep her family together in spite of her wandering husband (Samuel L. Jackson). Jackson is very sexy in this movie and his character has roving eyes as well as roving hands that don't stop even when he is caught in a compromising position by his youngest daughter, Eve. This starts a set of events that lead to the total destruction of an already deeply troubled family.Although this movie did not make history at the box office my guess is that it will become a cult classic. Years from now this movie will be viewed for what it is, a brilliantly produced film. You can literally feel the Louisiana heat from Eve's Bayou. danceability. Amsterdam
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of the '90s -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evehands
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - which i am embarrassed to admit we only went to see because of the coincidence of the name!! But this absurd 'excuse' to see a film we'd heard nothing about (no publicity or marketing - just an option among several others at our local multiplex cinema, lured in by a beautiful poster which it turned out proved to be a foretaste of a gorgeously shot movie) paid off richly. We are seldom impressed as we were with 'Eve's Bayou'; this layering of memories, filtered through the perceptions of three distinctly different women, was such an intelligent and suspenseful use of the much-abused medium of film, that I thought about and remembered it yesterday after 11 years (!) and decided to rent it again; I am confident I will like it just as much on second viewing. Now that i know it was a low budget first outing for the (female) director (whose DP was likewise female - something which is STILL an anomaly, even today, where commercially released features are concerned), I am simply blown away....Roger Ebert is absolutely right; the fact that this was not nominated for an Academy Award means they were simply not paying attention; for shame! It ought to have been a runaway success, and at very least nominated for Best Director, Best Supporting Actress(es), Best DP, Best Costumes, Best Screenplay. Unfortunately, Kasi Lemmons' follow- up to this (the gruesomely dark 'Valentine' something-or-other) was nowhere near as accomplished as this (though it was still good, by any movie standards). Perhaps she lost heart after being so overlooked? (and if so, who could blame her?!). I hope this film gets a re-release and much belated marketing 'push', with a perhaps more prominent placing at the local DVD stores, at least (I'm having to order my rented copy in 'cause it's not in the store...)!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flaaaaaaaaaaaawwwwwwwless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been a TOTAL fan of Lynn Whitfield and Debbi Morgan for YEARS, I KNEW I would be in for a treat. This overlooked film is indeed a wonder and in time will place among one of the finest movies ever made. It is multi-layered and deals with some extremely sensitive issues all the while painting a beautiful tapestry of African-American life in the Louisianna bayou. For those of you who have not seen it, it deals with the awakening of a father and his daughters one summer and the emotions that accompany this learning. The young Eve is brilliantly played by Smollett and Debbi Morgan gives a knockout performance that you crave to see over and over again. Diahann Carroll works you because her character is not at all glamorous but pivotal to the plot as Eve comes to realize the responsibility of her "gift" and learns the truth of the age-old adage, "Be careful what you wish for, for you just might get it." Samuel L. Jackson is wonderful as usual and perfectly cast. While his character is not necessarily sympathetic, he is totally understandable and for a little girl who worships her father he is perfectly cast. While some aspects of the father-daughter relationship may be somewhat uncomfortable, the director does a beautiful job bringing the complexity of these issues to the screen and I heartily applaud her. This is one that belongs in any movie collection and one where African-American life is celebrated and treated with the utmost respect and honesty. Hats off to a wonderful production!!!!!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine family drama set in 1960s Louisiana.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is the name of the small settlement along the bayou that former slave Eve gave her name to. The story is told from a young girl's point of view, Eve Batiste (Jurnee Smollett), who is narrating as an adult. It was filmed in Louisiana, in the bayou areas north of Lake Pontchartrain, north of New Orleans. I particularly like the exposition during the last scene where Eve describes our lives and memories as an intricate tapestry of all of our memories. This movie is about Eve's memories. The movie starts by saying that Eve was 11 years old when she killed her father. We don't find out what she means until the very end. Her father is small time doctor Louis Batiste (Samuel L. Jackson) who mostly makes routine house calls, dispenses aspirin, and flirts with the lonely ladies. He says he loves his wife, he appears to be a good father to his 2 daughters and son, but occasionally strays, and that is what gets him in hot water. Meagan Good is fine as the older sister Cisely Batiste. Lynn Whitfield is also good as the wife and mother Roz Batiste. SPOILERS. When Eve wanders into the storage shed during a party, and falls asleep, she awakens to find her dad and Mrs Mereaux engaged in sexual activity. This scares her, but what really gets her going is when sis tells her that dad made advances towards her, then hit her when she withdrew. Little Eve decided she needed to have her dad dead, goes to voodoo lady Elzora (Diahann Carroll) for a spell. What really gets dad is when Mrs Mereaux's husband shows up and finds him and his wife together at a bar. He tells Loius to never speak to his wife again or he will kill him. Louis smiles and yells 'good night Matty', and the jealous husband shoots and kills him. So, Eve really was responsible, because it was she in an earlier conversation that hinted to Mr Mereaux that her dad and his wife 'both seemed to come home late a lot.' Eve feels bad when she later finds out her sister's story was not true, she had been the one who made an advance by kissing dad as a mistress might, and dad rejected that which made sis mad enough to lie about it. Of interest to me, Branford Marsalis had a small role as friend Harry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich family saga with an interesting twist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prop03
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is now showing on cable here in Australia, and is a far better than average offering. Written and directed by Kasi Lemmons, the film is a powerful family drama set in the sixties in the south of the USA. It stars Samuel L Jackson as a small town doctor with a wandering eye. The story is told from the viewpoint of his middle child, Eve, wonderfully played by Jurnee Smollett, who sees her middle-class family life threatened by her father's infidelities. No tale set in a bayou village could exist without references to black magic and voodoo, and this film also has them as a rather central part of the plot. But these elements are handled skilfully and believably, and heighten the tension that develops. One of the interesting tools used by Lemmons is to tell and retell a story from different characters' perspectives, asking the viewer to determine which is more truthful, and indeed, whether the truth is paramount. Jackson gives a sparkling performance as Dr Louis Batiste, a man of warmth and generosity who is well regarded by the local community that he serves. His family is seemingly a happy and close one, until the children begin to question some of the adult behaviour they witness. Jurnee Smollett's Eve is the main protagonist around whom much of the story is centred, and she effortlessly moves back and forth between being a precocious brat and a young woman with powerful emotions. The rest of the cast is also very good, including a voluptuous Lisa Nicole Carson as the temptress Mattie Mereaux, and Diahann Carroll as a bayou witch. This film moves along at a good pace and is a little more than you might expect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is a 90s Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesewintersundays
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer/director Kasi Lemmons and her outstanding cast have outdone themselves in the sublime "Eve's Bayou." "Eve's Bayou" is fleet but not in a hurry. The scenes are clear and lean against the richness of the setting, but they flow leisurely toward the climax, like a punt bearing two lovers languidly downstream. "Eve's Bayou" is such a great story, partly because Lemmons herself is a master storyteller who is particularly gifted at strong endings, partly because the splendid cast embodies the characters so fully that the events actually seem to be happening to them, instead of unfolding from a screenplay. What a beautiful film it is: Not an overdecorated "period" portrait, but a film in which the people move easily through town and country homes and landscapes which frame and define them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Elegant and Deeply Disquieting Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    throughtheyellowgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons ''Eve's Bayou,'' is an elegant and deeply disquieting drama that became 1997's highest grossing independent film. The tenuous bonds that hold the Batiste, a highly accomplished African-American family, together have finally come undone. Spouses cheat; secrets are held -- lies are told ; parents and children share households but have no common ground. Beautifully acted as it is, "Eve's Bayou" still elects to keep its characters and their emotions at a distance. They remain as hidden from the viewer as they are from one another, which is an essential part of the film's disturbing power. Mrs. Lemmons daringly chooses to keep her story's motivational mysteries unexplained, leaving this richly observed film open to the viewer's assessments. Yet the sense of imbalance is ever-present and strong. Films like "Eve's Bayou" are not easily summarized; they don't have that slick "high concept" one-sentence peg that makes them easy to sell. Maybe all I've said still leaves you wondering what the movie is about. But some of the best movies are like this: They show everyday life, carefully observed, and as we grow to know the people in the film, maybe we find out something about ourselves. The fact that Lemmons is able to combine these qualities with turmoil, loneliness and even tragedy make the movie very rare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding, Outstanding, Outstanding!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeofmyangels
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons has invigorated and enriched her debut film, "Eve's Bayou", through the use of a thousand details, a strong sense of time and place, outstanding characterizations and a display of energy and cinematic flair that marks an advance on any other film released in 1997. Lemmons works with such piercing fervor and intelligence that "Eve's Bayou" just about transcends its tidy moral design. "Eve's Bayou" is as good a compromise of fact and fiction as you could hope for -- and still call it a movie. Lemmons directed this with a single-mindedness and attention to detail that makes it riveting. She doesn't make the mistake of adding cornball little subplots to popularize the material; she knows she has a great story, and she tells it with such realism that feels like we're apart of the Batiste family. This is a powerful story, one of 1997's best films, told with great clarity and acted like a finely tuned powerful fire(bravo Debbi Morgan).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Sad and Yet Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    girlkeepscomingloose
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" perfectly captures the melancholia that sometimes settles on a body like the gloaming, when the dying light seems profoundly sad and yet magical. Based on the short film "Dr. Hugo" (available on the DVD), this is a gem in the debut film making crown for writer/director Kasi Lemmons. Lemmons, with customary nuance and visual brilliance, crumbles the upper crust while breaking hearts with this poignant portrait of the Batiste, a wealthy African American family dwelling on a beautiful/haunting Louisiana bayou. While virtually every scene resonates with longing, there is one that is a masterpiece of unspoken words -- and somehow calls up visions of Ingmar Bergman's great family dramas. Debbi Morgan and young Jurnee Smollet -- who provide outstanding performances -- are supported by a host of deft players, and the detailed re-creation of this small universe is in all ways remarkable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great family drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons wrote and directed "Eve's Bayou," with such precision that I'm astounded that she hasn't had anything as good since this feature. Orson Welles is still famous for "Citizen Kane" after which he never reached such heights again. Samuel L. Jackson is a doctor who has a monogamy problem, constantly cheating on his wife, played by Lynn Whitfield. They have two daughters, Eve of the title, Jurnee Smollett is awesome as the lead character of this story and her sister Cisely(Meagan Good) is also a charming child actress. The two worship their father but they eventually discover his shortcomings as a husband. The two young sisters steal this film, an absorbing, tragic family drama of Shakespearean proportions. Lemmons has created a memorable classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love Love Love It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LOVE LOVE LOVE IT!!!!! One of my ALL TIME favorite movies ever made. Brilliant acting by the whole cast. Eve's Bayou is a spectacular movie. The color and scenery is wonderful and the people are elegant and troubled. Even the character's names stir up visions of dark swamp water and sultry heat. The story is told and seen through the eyes of little Eve Batiste played by a wonderful young actress named Jurnee Smollett. Eve takes us deep into her world which is filled with colorful characters and complex personalities.Diahann Carroll is fabulous as the old fortune teller Elzora with her insane laughter. Debbi Morgan as Aunt Mozelle Batiste Delacroix is something to behold. Aunt Mozelle has promised her family that she will not use her "second sight" to tell fortunes, but neighbors won't let her keep her promise. They seek her out to find missing husbands anyway. Lynn Whitfied as the manor born wife is beautiful and poised as she tries to keep her family together in spite of her wandering husband (Samuel L. Jackson). Jackson is very sexy in this movie and his character has roving eyes as well as roving hands that don't stop even when he is caught in a compromising position by his youngest daughter, Eve. This starts a set of events that lead to the total destruction of an already deeply troubled family.Although this movie did not make history at the box office my guess is that it will become a cult classic. Years from now this movie will be viewed for what it is, a brilliantly produced film. You can literally feel the Louisiana heat from Eve's Bayou. danceability. Amsterdam
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of the '90s -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evehands
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - which i am embarrassed to admit we only went to see because of the coincidence of the name!! But this absurd 'excuse' to see a film we'd heard nothing about (no publicity or marketing - just an option among several others at our local multiplex cinema, lured in by a beautiful poster which it turned out proved to be a foretaste of a gorgeously shot movie) paid off richly. We are seldom impressed as we were with 'Eve's Bayou'; this layering of memories, filtered through the perceptions of three distinctly different women, was such an intelligent and suspenseful use of the much-abused medium of film, that I thought about and remembered it yesterday after 11 years (!) and decided to rent it again; I am confident I will like it just as much on second viewing. Now that i know it was a low budget first outing for the (female) director (whose DP was likewise female - something which is STILL an anomaly, even today, where commercially released features are concerned), I am simply blown away....Roger Ebert is absolutely right; the fact that this was not nominated for an Academy Award means they were simply not paying attention; for shame! It ought to have been a runaway success, and at very least nominated for Best Director, Best Supporting Actress(es), Best DP, Best Costumes, Best Screenplay. Unfortunately, Kasi Lemmons' follow- up to this (the gruesomely dark 'Valentine' something-or-other) was nowhere near as accomplished as this (though it was still good, by any movie standards). Perhaps she lost heart after being so overlooked? (and if so, who could blame her?!). I hope this film gets a re-release and much belated marketing 'push', with a perhaps more prominent placing at the local DVD stores, at least (I'm having to order my rented copy in 'cause it's not in the store...)!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flaaaaaaaaaaaawwwwwwwless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been a TOTAL fan of Lynn Whitfield and Debbi Morgan for YEARS, I KNEW I would be in for a treat. This overlooked film is indeed a wonder and in time will place among one of the finest movies ever made. It is multi-layered and deals with some extremely sensitive issues all the while painting a beautiful tapestry of African-American life in the Louisianna bayou. For those of you who have not seen it, it deals with the awakening of a father and his daughters one summer and the emotions that accompany this learning. The young Eve is brilliantly played by Smollett and Debbi Morgan gives a knockout performance that you crave to see over and over again. Diahann Carroll works you because her character is not at all glamorous but pivotal to the plot as Eve comes to realize the responsibility of her "gift" and learns the truth of the age-old adage, "Be careful what you wish for, for you just might get it." Samuel L. Jackson is wonderful as usual and perfectly cast. While his character is not necessarily sympathetic, he is totally understandable and for a little girl who worships her father he is perfectly cast. While some aspects of the father-daughter relationship may be somewhat uncomfortable, the director does a beautiful job bringing the complexity of these issues to the screen and I heartily applaud her. This is one that belongs in any movie collection and one where African-American life is celebrated and treated with the utmost respect and honesty. Hats off to a wonderful production!!!!!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine family drama set in 1960s Louisiana.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is the name of the small settlement along the bayou that former slave Eve gave her name to. The story is told from a young girl's point of view, Eve Batiste (Jurnee Smollett), who is narrating as an adult. It was filmed in Louisiana, in the bayou areas north of Lake Pontchartrain, north of New Orleans. I particularly like the exposition during the last scene where Eve describes our lives and memories as an intricate tapestry of all of our memories. This movie is about Eve's memories. The movie starts by saying that Eve was 11 years old when she killed her father. We don't find out what she means until the very end. Her father is small time doctor Louis Batiste (Samuel L. Jackson) who mostly makes routine house calls, dispenses aspirin, and flirts with the lonely ladies. He says he loves his wife, he appears to be a good father to his 2 daughters and son, but occasionally strays, and that is what gets him in hot water. Meagan Good is fine as the older sister Cisely Batiste. Lynn Whitfield is also good as the wife and mother Roz Batiste. SPOILERS. When Eve wanders into the storage shed during a party, and falls asleep, she awakens to find her dad and Mrs Mereaux engaged in sexual activity. This scares her, but what really gets her going is when sis tells her that dad made advances towards her, then hit her when she withdrew. Little Eve decided she needed to have her dad dead, goes to voodoo lady Elzora (Diahann Carroll) for a spell. What really gets dad is when Mrs Mereaux's husband shows up and finds him and his wife together at a bar. He tells Loius to never speak to his wife again or he will kill him. Louis smiles and yells 'good night Matty', and the jealous husband shoots and kills him. So, Eve really was responsible, because it was she in an earlier conversation that hinted to Mr Mereaux that her dad and his wife 'both seemed to come home late a lot.' Eve feels bad when she later finds out her sister's story was not true, she had been the one who made an advance by kissing dad as a mistress might, and dad rejected that which made sis mad enough to lie about it. Of interest to me, Branford Marsalis had a small role as friend Harry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich family saga with an interesting twist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prop03
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is now showing on cable here in Australia, and is a far better than average offering. Written and directed by Kasi Lemmons, the film is a powerful family drama set in the sixties in the south of the USA. It stars Samuel L Jackson as a small town doctor with a wandering eye. The story is told from the viewpoint of his middle child, Eve, wonderfully played by Jurnee Smollett, who sees her middle-class family life threatened by her father's infidelities. No tale set in a bayou village could exist without references to black magic and voodoo, and this film also has them as a rather central part of the plot. But these elements are handled skilfully and believably, and heighten the tension that develops. One of the interesting tools used by Lemmons is to tell and retell a story from different characters' perspectives, asking the viewer to determine which is more truthful, and indeed, whether the truth is paramount. Jackson gives a sparkling performance as Dr Louis Batiste, a man of warmth and generosity who is well regarded by the local community that he serves. His family is seemingly a happy and close one, until the children begin to question some of the adult behaviour they witness. Jurnee Smollett's Eve is the main protagonist around whom much of the story is centred, and she effortlessly moves back and forth between being a precocious brat and a young woman with powerful emotions. The rest of the cast is also very good, including a voluptuous Lisa Nicole Carson as the temptress Mattie Mereaux, and Diahann Carroll as a bayou witch. This film moves along at a good pace and is a little more than you might expect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is a 90s Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesewintersundays
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer/director Kasi Lemmons and her outstanding cast have outdone themselves in the sublime "Eve's Bayou." "Eve's Bayou" is fleet but not in a hurry. The scenes are clear and lean against the richness of the setting, but they flow leisurely toward the climax, like a punt bearing two lovers languidly downstream. "Eve's Bayou" is such a great story, partly because Lemmons herself is a master storyteller who is particularly gifted at strong endings, partly because the splendid cast embodies the characters so fully that the events actually seem to be happening to them, instead of unfolding from a screenplay. What a beautiful film it is: Not an overdecorated "period" portrait, but a film in which the people move easily through town and country homes and landscapes which frame and define them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Elegant and Deeply Disquieting Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    throughtheyellowgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons ''Eve's Bayou,'' is an elegant and deeply disquieting drama that became 1997's highest grossing independent film. The tenuous bonds that hold the Batiste, a highly accomplished African-American family, together have finally come undone. Spouses cheat; secrets are held -- lies are told ; parents and children share households but have no common ground. Beautifully acted as it is, "Eve's Bayou" still elects to keep its characters and their emotions at a distance. They remain as hidden from the viewer as they are from one another, which is an essential part of the film's disturbing power. Mrs. Lemmons daringly chooses to keep her story's motivational mysteries unexplained, leaving this richly observed film open to the viewer's assessments. Yet the sense of imbalance is ever-present and strong. Films like "Eve's Bayou" are not easily summarized; they don't have that slick "high concept" one-sentence peg that makes them easy to sell. Maybe all I've said still leaves you wondering what the movie is about. But some of the best movies are like this: They show everyday life, carefully observed, and as we grow to know the people in the film, maybe we find out something about ourselves. The fact that Lemmons is able to combine these qualities with turmoil, loneliness and even tragedy make the movie very rare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding, Outstanding, Outstanding!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeofmyangels
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons has invigorated and enriched her debut film, "Eve's Bayou", through the use of a thousand details, a strong sense of time and place, outstanding characterizations and a display of energy and cinematic flair that marks an advance on any other film released in 1997. Lemmons works with such piercing fervor and intelligence that "Eve's Bayou" just about transcends its tidy moral design. "Eve's Bayou" is as good a compromise of fact and fiction as you could hope for -- and still call it a movie. Lemmons directed this with a single-mindedness and attention to detail that makes it riveting. She doesn't make the mistake of adding cornball little subplots to popularize the material; she knows she has a great story, and she tells it with such realism that feels like we're apart of the Batiste family. This is a powerful story, one of 1997's best films, told with great clarity and acted like a finely tuned powerful fire(bravo Debbi Morgan).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Sad and Yet Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    girlkeepscomingloose
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" perfectly captures the melancholia that sometimes settles on a body like the gloaming, when the dying light seems profoundly sad and yet magical. Based on the short film "Dr. Hugo" (available on the DVD), this is a gem in the debut film making crown for writer/director Kasi Lemmons. Lemmons, with customary nuance and visual brilliance, crumbles the upper crust while breaking hearts with this poignant portrait of the Batiste, a wealthy African American family dwelling on a beautiful/haunting Louisiana bayou. While virtually every scene resonates with longing, there is one that is a masterpiece of unspoken words -- and somehow calls up visions of Ingmar Bergman's great family dramas. Debbi Morgan and young Jurnee Smollet -- who provide outstanding performances -- are supported by a host of deft players, and the detailed re-creation of this small universe is in all ways remarkable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great family drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons wrote and directed "Eve's Bayou," with such precision that I'm astounded that she hasn't had anything as good since this feature. Orson Welles is still famous for "Citizen Kane" after which he never reached such heights again. Samuel L. Jackson is a doctor who has a monogamy problem, constantly cheating on his wife, played by Lynn Whitfield. They have two daughters, Eve of the title, Jurnee Smollett is awesome as the lead character of this story and her sister Cisely(Meagan Good) is also a charming child actress. The two worship their father but they eventually discover his shortcomings as a husband. The two young sisters steal this film, an absorbing, tragic family drama of Shakespearean proportions. Lemmons has created a memorable classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love Love Love It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LOVE LOVE LOVE IT!!!!! One of my ALL TIME favorite movies ever made. Brilliant acting by the whole cast. Eve's Bayou is a spectacular movie. The color and scenery is wonderful and the people are elegant and troubled. Even the character's names stir up visions of dark swamp water and sultry heat. The story is told and seen through the eyes of little Eve Batiste played by a wonderful young actress named Jurnee Smollett. Eve takes us deep into her world which is filled with colorful characters and complex personalities.Diahann Carroll is fabulous as the old fortune teller Elzora with her insane laughter. Debbi Morgan as Aunt Mozelle Batiste Delacroix is something to behold. Aunt Mozelle has promised her family that she will not use her "second sight" to tell fortunes, but neighbors won't let her keep her promise. They seek her out to find missing husbands anyway. Lynn Whitfied as the manor born wife is beautiful and poised as she tries to keep her family together in spite of her wandering husband (Samuel L. Jackson). Jackson is very sexy in this movie and his character has roving eyes as well as roving hands that don't stop even when he is caught in a compromising position by his youngest daughter, Eve. This starts a set of events that lead to the total destruction of an already deeply troubled family.Although this movie did not make history at the box office my guess is that it will become a cult classic. Years from now this movie will be viewed for what it is, a brilliantly produced film. You can literally feel the Louisiana heat from Eve's Bayou. danceability. Amsterdam
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of the '90s -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evehands
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - which i am embarrassed to admit we only went to see because of the coincidence of the name!! But this absurd 'excuse' to see a film we'd heard nothing about (no publicity or marketing - just an option among several others at our local multiplex cinema, lured in by a beautiful poster which it turned out proved to be a foretaste of a gorgeously shot movie) paid off richly. We are seldom impressed as we were with 'Eve's Bayou'; this layering of memories, filtered through the perceptions of three distinctly different women, was such an intelligent and suspenseful use of the much-abused medium of film, that I thought about and remembered it yesterday after 11 years (!) and decided to rent it again; I am confident I will like it just as much on second viewing. Now that i know it was a low budget first outing for the (female) director (whose DP was likewise female - something which is STILL an anomaly, even today, where commercially released features are concerned), I am simply blown away....Roger Ebert is absolutely right; the fact that this was not nominated for an Academy Award means they were simply not paying attention; for shame! It ought to have been a runaway success, and at very least nominated for Best Director, Best Supporting Actress(es), Best DP, Best Costumes, Best Screenplay. Unfortunately, Kasi Lemmons' follow- up to this (the gruesomely dark 'Valentine' something-or-other) was nowhere near as accomplished as this (though it was still good, by any movie standards). Perhaps she lost heart after being so overlooked? (and if so, who could blame her?!). I hope this film gets a re-release and much belated marketing 'push', with a perhaps more prominent placing at the local DVD stores, at least (I'm having to order my rented copy in 'cause it's not in the store...)!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flaaaaaaaaaaaawwwwwwwless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been a TOTAL fan of Lynn Whitfield and Debbi Morgan for YEARS, I KNEW I would be in for a treat. This overlooked film is indeed a wonder and in time will place among one of the finest movies ever made. It is multi-layered and deals with some extremely sensitive issues all the while painting a beautiful tapestry of African-American life in the Louisianna bayou. For those of you who have not seen it, it deals with the awakening of a father and his daughters one summer and the emotions that accompany this learning. The young Eve is brilliantly played by Smollett and Debbi Morgan gives a knockout performance that you crave to see over and over again. Diahann Carroll works you because her character is not at all glamorous but pivotal to the plot as Eve comes to realize the responsibility of her "gift" and learns the truth of the age-old adage, "Be careful what you wish for, for you just might get it." Samuel L. Jackson is wonderful as usual and perfectly cast. While his character is not necessarily sympathetic, he is totally understandable and for a little girl who worships her father he is perfectly cast. While some aspects of the father-daughter relationship may be somewhat uncomfortable, the director does a beautiful job bringing the complexity of these issues to the screen and I heartily applaud her. This is one that belongs in any movie collection and one where African-American life is celebrated and treated with the utmost respect and honesty. Hats off to a wonderful production!!!!!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine family drama set in 1960s Louisiana.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is the name of the small settlement along the bayou that former slave Eve gave her name to. The story is told from a young girl's point of view, Eve Batiste (Jurnee Smollett), who is narrating as an adult. It was filmed in Louisiana, in the bayou areas north of Lake Pontchartrain, north of New Orleans. I particularly like the exposition during the last scene where Eve describes our lives and memories as an intricate tapestry of all of our memories. This movie is about Eve's memories. The movie starts by saying that Eve was 11 years old when she killed her father. We don't find out what she means until the very end. Her father is small time doctor Louis Batiste (Samuel L. Jackson) who mostly makes routine house calls, dispenses aspirin, and flirts with the lonely ladies. He says he loves his wife, he appears to be a good father to his 2 daughters and son, but occasionally strays, and that is what gets him in hot water. Meagan Good is fine as the older sister Cisely Batiste. Lynn Whitfield is also good as the wife and mother Roz Batiste. SPOILERS. When Eve wanders into the storage shed during a party, and falls asleep, she awakens to find her dad and Mrs Mereaux engaged in sexual activity. This scares her, but what really gets her going is when sis tells her that dad made advances towards her, then hit her when she withdrew. Little Eve decided she needed to have her dad dead, goes to voodoo lady Elzora (Diahann Carroll) for a spell. What really gets dad is when Mrs Mereaux's husband shows up and finds him and his wife together at a bar. He tells Loius to never speak to his wife again or he will kill him. Louis smiles and yells 'good night Matty', and the jealous husband shoots and kills him. So, Eve really was responsible, because it was she in an earlier conversation that hinted to Mr Mereaux that her dad and his wife 'both seemed to come home late a lot.' Eve feels bad when she later finds out her sister's story was not true, she had been the one who made an advance by kissing dad as a mistress might, and dad rejected that which made sis mad enough to lie about it. Of interest to me, Branford Marsalis had a small role as friend Harry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich family saga with an interesting twist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prop03
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is now showing on cable here in Australia, and is a far better than average offering. Written and directed by Kasi Lemmons, the film is a powerful family drama set in the sixties in the south of the USA. It stars Samuel L Jackson as a small town doctor with a wandering eye. The story is told from the viewpoint of his middle child, Eve, wonderfully played by Jurnee Smollett, who sees her middle-class family life threatened by her father's infidelities. No tale set in a bayou village could exist without references to black magic and voodoo, and this film also has them as a rather central part of the plot. But these elements are handled skilfully and believably, and heighten the tension that develops. One of the interesting tools used by Lemmons is to tell and retell a story from different characters' perspectives, asking the viewer to determine which is more truthful, and indeed, whether the truth is paramount. Jackson gives a sparkling performance as Dr Louis Batiste, a man of warmth and generosity who is well regarded by the local community that he serves. His family is seemingly a happy and close one, until the children begin to question some of the adult behaviour they witness. Jurnee Smollett's Eve is the main protagonist around whom much of the story is centred, and she effortlessly moves back and forth between being a precocious brat and a young woman with powerful emotions. The rest of the cast is also very good, including a voluptuous Lisa Nicole Carson as the temptress Mattie Mereaux, and Diahann Carroll as a bayou witch. This film moves along at a good pace and is a little more than you might expect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is a 90s Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesewintersundays
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer/director Kasi Lemmons and her outstanding cast have outdone themselves in the sublime "Eve's Bayou." "Eve's Bayou" is fleet but not in a hurry. The scenes are clear and lean against the richness of the setting, but they flow leisurely toward the climax, like a punt bearing two lovers languidly downstream. "Eve's Bayou" is such a great story, partly because Lemmons herself is a master storyteller who is particularly gifted at strong endings, partly because the splendid cast embodies the characters so fully that the events actually seem to be happening to them, instead of unfolding from a screenplay. What a beautiful film it is: Not an overdecorated "period" portrait, but a film in which the people move easily through town and country homes and landscapes which frame and define them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Elegant and Deeply Disquieting Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    throughtheyellowgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons ''Eve's Bayou,'' is an elegant and deeply disquieting drama that became 1997's highest grossing independent film. The tenuous bonds that hold the Batiste, a highly accomplished African-American family, together have finally come undone. Spouses cheat; secrets are held -- lies are told ; parents and children share households but have no common ground. Beautifully acted as it is, "Eve's Bayou" still elects to keep its characters and their emotions at a distance. They remain as hidden from the viewer as they are from one another, which is an essential part of the film's disturbing power. Mrs. Lemmons daringly chooses to keep her story's motivational mysteries unexplained, leaving this richly observed film open to the viewer's assessments. Yet the sense of imbalance is ever-present and strong. Films like "Eve's Bayou" are not easily summarized; they don't have that slick "high concept" one-sentence peg that makes them easy to sell. Maybe all I've said still leaves you wondering what the movie is about. But some of the best movies are like this: They show everyday life, carefully observed, and as we grow to know the people in the film, maybe we find out something about ourselves. The fact that Lemmons is able to combine these qualities with turmoil, loneliness and even tragedy make the movie very rare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding, Outstanding, Outstanding!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeofmyangels
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons has invigorated and enriched her debut film, "Eve's Bayou", through the use of a thousand details, a strong sense of time and place, outstanding characterizations and a display of energy and cinematic flair that marks an advance on any other film released in 1997. Lemmons works with such piercing fervor and intelligence that "Eve's Bayou" just about transcends its tidy moral design. "Eve's Bayou" is as good a compromise of fact and fiction as you could hope for -- and still call it a movie. Lemmons directed this with a single-mindedness and attention to detail that makes it riveting. She doesn't make the mistake of adding cornball little subplots to popularize the material; she knows she has a great story, and she tells it with such realism that feels like we're apart of the Batiste family. This is a powerful story, one of 1997's best films, told with great clarity and acted like a finely tuned powerful fire(bravo Debbi Morgan).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Sad and Yet Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    girlkeepscomingloose
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" perfectly captures the melancholia that sometimes settles on a body like the gloaming, when the dying light seems profoundly sad and yet magical. Based on the short film "Dr. Hugo" (available on the DVD), this is a gem in the debut film making crown for writer/director Kasi Lemmons. Lemmons, with customary nuance and visual brilliance, crumbles the upper crust while breaking hearts with this poignant portrait of the Batiste, a wealthy African American family dwelling on a beautiful/haunting Louisiana bayou. While virtually every scene resonates with longing, there is one that is a masterpiece of unspoken words -- and somehow calls up visions of Ingmar Bergman's great family dramas. Debbi Morgan and young Jurnee Smollet -- who provide outstanding performances -- are supported by a host of deft players, and the detailed re-creation of this small universe is in all ways remarkable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great family drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons wrote and directed "Eve's Bayou," with such precision that I'm astounded that she hasn't had anything as good since this feature. Orson Welles is still famous for "Citizen Kane" after which he never reached such heights again. Samuel L. Jackson is a doctor who has a monogamy problem, constantly cheating on his wife, played by Lynn Whitfield. They have two daughters, Eve of the title, Jurnee Smollett is awesome as the lead character of this story and her sister Cisely(Meagan Good) is also a charming child actress. The two worship their father but they eventually discover his shortcomings as a husband. The two young sisters steal this film, an absorbing, tragic family drama of Shakespearean proportions. Lemmons has created a memorable classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love Love Love It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LOVE LOVE LOVE IT!!!!! One of my ALL TIME favorite movies ever made. Brilliant acting by the whole cast. Eve's Bayou is a spectacular movie. The color and scenery is wonderful and the people are elegant and troubled. Even the character's names stir up visions of dark swamp water and sultry heat. The story is told and seen through the eyes of little Eve Batiste played by a wonderful young actress named Jurnee Smollett. Eve takes us deep into her world which is filled with colorful characters and complex personalities.Diahann Carroll is fabulous as the old fortune teller Elzora with her insane laughter. Debbi Morgan as Aunt Mozelle Batiste Delacroix is something to behold. Aunt Mozelle has promised her family that she will not use her "second sight" to tell fortunes, but neighbors won't let her keep her promise. They seek her out to find missing husbands anyway. Lynn Whitfied as the manor born wife is beautiful and poised as she tries to keep her family together in spite of her wandering husband (Samuel L. Jackson). Jackson is very sexy in this movie and his character has roving eyes as well as roving hands that don't stop even when he is caught in a compromising position by his youngest daughter, Eve. This starts a set of events that lead to the total destruction of an already deeply troubled family.Although this movie did not make history at the box office my guess is that it will become a cult classic. Years from now this movie will be viewed for what it is, a brilliantly produced film. You can literally feel the Louisiana heat from Eve's Bayou. danceability. Amsterdam
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of the '90s -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evehands
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - which i am embarrassed to admit we only went to see because of the coincidence of the name!! But this absurd 'excuse' to see a film we'd heard nothing about (no publicity or marketing - just an option among several others at our local multiplex cinema, lured in by a beautiful poster which it turned out proved to be a foretaste of a gorgeously shot movie) paid off richly. We are seldom impressed as we were with 'Eve's Bayou'; this layering of memories, filtered through the perceptions of three distinctly different women, was such an intelligent and suspenseful use of the much-abused medium of film, that I thought about and remembered it yesterday after 11 years (!) and decided to rent it again; I am confident I will like it just as much on second viewing. Now that i know it was a low budget first outing for the (female) director (whose DP was likewise female - something which is STILL an anomaly, even today, where commercially released features are concerned), I am simply blown away....Roger Ebert is absolutely right; the fact that this was not nominated for an Academy Award means they were simply not paying attention; for shame! It ought to have been a runaway success, and at very least nominated for Best Director, Best Supporting Actress(es), Best DP, Best Costumes, Best Screenplay. Unfortunately, Kasi Lemmons' follow- up to this (the gruesomely dark 'Valentine' something-or-other) was nowhere near as accomplished as this (though it was still good, by any movie standards). Perhaps she lost heart after being so overlooked? (and if so, who could blame her?!). I hope this film gets a re-release and much belated marketing 'push', with a perhaps more prominent placing at the local DVD stores, at least (I'm having to order my rented copy in 'cause it's not in the store...)!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flaaaaaaaaaaaawwwwwwwless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been a TOTAL fan of Lynn Whitfield and Debbi Morgan for YEARS, I KNEW I would be in for a treat. This overlooked film is indeed a wonder and in time will place among one of the finest movies ever made. It is multi-layered and deals with some extremely sensitive issues all the while painting a beautiful tapestry of African-American life in the Louisianna bayou. For those of you who have not seen it, it deals with the awakening of a father and his daughters one summer and the emotions that accompany this learning. The young Eve is brilliantly played by Smollett and Debbi Morgan gives a knockout performance that you crave to see over and over again. Diahann Carroll works you because her character is not at all glamorous but pivotal to the plot as Eve comes to realize the responsibility of her "gift" and learns the truth of the age-old adage, "Be careful what you wish for, for you just might get it." Samuel L. Jackson is wonderful as usual and perfectly cast. While his character is not necessarily sympathetic, he is totally understandable and for a little girl who worships her father he is perfectly cast. While some aspects of the father-daughter relationship may be somewhat uncomfortable, the director does a beautiful job bringing the complexity of these issues to the screen and I heartily applaud her. This is one that belongs in any movie collection and one where African-American life is celebrated and treated with the utmost respect and honesty. Hats off to a wonderful production!!!!!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine family drama set in 1960s Louisiana.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is the name of the small settlement along the bayou that former slave Eve gave her name to. The story is told from a young girl's point of view, Eve Batiste (Jurnee Smollett), who is narrating as an adult. It was filmed in Louisiana, in the bayou areas north of Lake Pontchartrain, north of New Orleans. I particularly like the exposition during the last scene where Eve describes our lives and memories as an intricate tapestry of all of our memories. This movie is about Eve's memories. The movie starts by saying that Eve was 11 years old when she killed her father. We don't find out what she means until the very end. Her father is small time doctor Louis Batiste (Samuel L. Jackson) who mostly makes routine house calls, dispenses aspirin, and flirts with the lonely ladies. He says he loves his wife, he appears to be a good father to his 2 daughters and son, but occasionally strays, and that is what gets him in hot water. Meagan Good is fine as the older sister Cisely Batiste. Lynn Whitfield is also good as the wife and mother Roz Batiste. SPOILERS. When Eve wanders into the storage shed during a party, and falls asleep, she awakens to find her dad and Mrs Mereaux engaged in sexual activity. This scares her, but what really gets her going is when sis tells her that dad made advances towards her, then hit her when she withdrew. Little Eve decided she needed to have her dad dead, goes to voodoo lady Elzora (Diahann Carroll) for a spell. What really gets dad is when Mrs Mereaux's husband shows up and finds him and his wife together at a bar. He tells Loius to never speak to his wife again or he will kill him. Louis smiles and yells 'good night Matty', and the jealous husband shoots and kills him. So, Eve really was responsible, because it was she in an earlier conversation that hinted to Mr Mereaux that her dad and his wife 'both seemed to come home late a lot.' Eve feels bad when she later finds out her sister's story was not true, she had been the one who made an advance by kissing dad as a mistress might, and dad rejected that which made sis mad enough to lie about it. Of interest to me, Branford Marsalis had a small role as friend Harry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich family saga with an interesting twist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prop03
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is now showing on cable here in Australia, and is a far better than average offering. Written and directed by Kasi Lemmons, the film is a powerful family drama set in the sixties in the south of the USA. It stars Samuel L Jackson as a small town doctor with a wandering eye. The story is told from the viewpoint of his middle child, Eve, wonderfully played by Jurnee Smollett, who sees her middle-class family life threatened by her father's infidelities. No tale set in a bayou village could exist without references to black magic and voodoo, and this film also has them as a rather central part of the plot. But these elements are handled skilfully and believably, and heighten the tension that develops. One of the interesting tools used by Lemmons is to tell and retell a story from different characters' perspectives, asking the viewer to determine which is more truthful, and indeed, whether the truth is paramount. Jackson gives a sparkling performance as Dr Louis Batiste, a man of warmth and generosity who is well regarded by the local community that he serves. His family is seemingly a happy and close one, until the children begin to question some of the adult behaviour they witness. Jurnee Smollett's Eve is the main protagonist around whom much of the story is centred, and she effortlessly moves back and forth between being a precocious brat and a young woman with powerful emotions. The rest of the cast is also very good, including a voluptuous Lisa Nicole Carson as the temptress Mattie Mereaux, and Diahann Carroll as a bayou witch. This film moves along at a good pace and is a little more than you might expect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is a 90s Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesewintersundays
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer/director Kasi Lemmons and her outstanding cast have outdone themselves in the sublime "Eve's Bayou." "Eve's Bayou" is fleet but not in a hurry. The scenes are clear and lean against the richness of the setting, but they flow leisurely toward the climax, like a punt bearing two lovers languidly downstream. "Eve's Bayou" is such a great story, partly because Lemmons herself is a master storyteller who is particularly gifted at strong endings, partly because the splendid cast embodies the characters so fully that the events actually seem to be happening to them, instead of unfolding from a screenplay. What a beautiful film it is: Not an overdecorated "period" portrait, but a film in which the people move easily through town and country homes and landscapes which frame and define them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Elegant and Deeply Disquieting Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    throughtheyellowgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons ''Eve's Bayou,'' is an elegant and deeply disquieting drama that became 1997's highest grossing independent film. The tenuous bonds that hold the Batiste, a highly accomplished African-American family, together have finally come undone. Spouses cheat; secrets are held -- lies are told ; parents and children share households but have no common ground. Beautifully acted as it is, "Eve's Bayou" still elects to keep its characters and their emotions at a distance. They remain as hidden from the viewer as they are from one another, which is an essential part of the film's disturbing power. Mrs. Lemmons daringly chooses to keep her story's motivational mysteries unexplained, leaving this richly observed film open to the viewer's assessments. Yet the sense of imbalance is ever-present and strong. Films like "Eve's Bayou" are not easily summarized; they don't have that slick "high concept" one-sentence peg that makes them easy to sell. Maybe all I've said still leaves you wondering what the movie is about. But some of the best movies are like this: They show everyday life, carefully observed, and as we grow to know the people in the film, maybe we find out something about ourselves. The fact that Lemmons is able to combine these qualities with turmoil, loneliness and even tragedy make the movie very rare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding, Outstanding, Outstanding!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeofmyangels
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons has invigorated and enriched her debut film, "Eve's Bayou", through the use of a thousand details, a strong sense of time and place, outstanding characterizations and a display of energy and cinematic flair that marks an advance on any other film released in 1997. Lemmons works with such piercing fervor and intelligence that "Eve's Bayou" just about transcends its tidy moral design. "Eve's Bayou" is as good a compromise of fact and fiction as you could hope for -- and still call it a movie. Lemmons directed this with a single-mindedness and attention to detail that makes it riveting. She doesn't make the mistake of adding cornball little subplots to popularize the material; she knows she has a great story, and she tells it with such realism that feels like we're apart of the Batiste family. This is a powerful story, one of 1997's best films, told with great clarity and acted like a finely tuned powerful fire(bravo Debbi Morgan).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Sad and Yet Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    girlkeepscomingloose
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" perfectly captures the melancholia that sometimes settles on a body like the gloaming, when the dying light seems profoundly sad and yet magical. Based on the short film "Dr. Hugo" (available on the DVD), this is a gem in the debut film making crown for writer/director Kasi Lemmons. Lemmons, with customary nuance and visual brilliance, crumbles the upper crust while breaking hearts with this poignant portrait of the Batiste, a wealthy African American family dwelling on a beautiful/haunting Louisiana bayou. While virtually every scene resonates with longing, there is one that is a masterpiece of unspoken words -- and somehow calls up visions of Ingmar Bergman's great family dramas. Debbi Morgan and young Jurnee Smollet -- who provide outstanding performances -- are supported by a host of deft players, and the detailed re-creation of this small universe is in all ways remarkable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great family drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons wrote and directed "Eve's Bayou," with such precision that I'm astounded that she hasn't had anything as good since this feature. Orson Welles is still famous for "Citizen Kane" after which he never reached such heights again. Samuel L. Jackson is a doctor who has a monogamy problem, constantly cheating on his wife, played by Lynn Whitfield. They have two daughters, Eve of the title, Jurnee Smollett is awesome as the lead character of this story and her sister Cisely(Meagan Good) is also a charming child actress. The two worship their father but they eventually discover his shortcomings as a husband. The two young sisters steal this film, an absorbing, tragic family drama of Shakespearean proportions. Lemmons has created a memorable classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Love Love Love It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    LOVE LOVE LOVE IT!!!!! One of my ALL TIME favorite movies ever made. Brilliant acting by the whole cast. Eve's Bayou is a spectacular movie. The color and scenery is wonderful and the people are elegant and troubled. Even the character's names stir up visions of dark swamp water and sultry heat. The story is told and seen through the eyes of little Eve Batiste played by a wonderful young actress named Jurnee Smollett. Eve takes us deep into her world which is filled with colorful characters and complex personalities.Diahann Carroll is fabulous as the old fortune teller Elzora with her insane laughter. Debbi Morgan as Aunt Mozelle Batiste Delacroix is something to behold. Aunt Mozelle has promised her family that she will not use her "second sight" to tell fortunes, but neighbors won't let her keep her promise. They seek her out to find missing husbands anyway. Lynn Whitfied as the manor born wife is beautiful and poised as she tries to keep her family together in spite of her wandering husband (Samuel L. Jackson). Jackson is very sexy in this movie and his character has roving eyes as well as roving hands that don't stop even when he is caught in a compromising position by his youngest daughter, Eve. This starts a set of events that lead to the total destruction of an already deeply troubled family.Although this movie did not make history at the box office my guess is that it will become a cult classic. Years from now this movie will be viewed for what it is, a brilliantly produced film. You can literally feel the Louisiana heat from Eve's Bayou. danceability. Amsterdam
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of the '90s -
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evehands
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    - which i am embarrassed to admit we only went to see because of the coincidence of the name!! But this absurd 'excuse' to see a film we'd heard nothing about (no publicity or marketing - just an option among several others at our local multiplex cinema, lured in by a beautiful poster which it turned out proved to be a foretaste of a gorgeously shot movie) paid off richly. We are seldom impressed as we were with 'Eve's Bayou'; this layering of memories, filtered through the perceptions of three distinctly different women, was such an intelligent and suspenseful use of the much-abused medium of film, that I thought about and remembered it yesterday after 11 years (!) and decided to rent it again; I am confident I will like it just as much on second viewing. Now that i know it was a low budget first outing for the (female) director (whose DP was likewise female - something which is STILL an anomaly, even today, where commercially released features are concerned), I am simply blown away....Roger Ebert is absolutely right; the fact that this was not nominated for an Academy Award means they were simply not paying attention; for shame! It ought to have been a runaway success, and at very least nominated for Best Director, Best Supporting Actress(es), Best DP, Best Costumes, Best Screenplay. Unfortunately, Kasi Lemmons' follow- up to this (the gruesomely dark 'Valentine' something-or-other) was nowhere near as accomplished as this (though it was still good, by any movie standards). Perhaps she lost heart after being so overlooked? (and if so, who could blame her?!). I hope this film gets a re-release and much belated marketing 'push', with a perhaps more prominent placing at the local DVD stores, at least (I'm having to order my rented copy in 'cause it's not in the store...)!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Flaaaaaaaaaaaawwwwwwwless!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RaiderJack
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having been a TOTAL fan of Lynn Whitfield and Debbi Morgan for YEARS, I KNEW I would be in for a treat. This overlooked film is indeed a wonder and in time will place among one of the finest movies ever made. It is multi-layered and deals with some extremely sensitive issues all the while painting a beautiful tapestry of African-American life in the Louisianna bayou. For those of you who have not seen it, it deals with the awakening of a father and his daughters one summer and the emotions that accompany this learning. The young Eve is brilliantly played by Smollett and Debbi Morgan gives a knockout performance that you crave to see over and over again. Diahann Carroll works you because her character is not at all glamorous but pivotal to the plot as Eve comes to realize the responsibility of her "gift" and learns the truth of the age-old adage, "Be careful what you wish for, for you just might get it." Samuel L. Jackson is wonderful as usual and perfectly cast. While his character is not necessarily sympathetic, he is totally understandable and for a little girl who worships her father he is perfectly cast. While some aspects of the father-daughter relationship may be somewhat uncomfortable, the director does a beautiful job bringing the complexity of these issues to the screen and I heartily applaud her. This is one that belongs in any movie collection and one where African-American life is celebrated and treated with the utmost respect and honesty. Hats off to a wonderful production!!!!!!!!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fine family drama set in 1960s Louisiana.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is the name of the small settlement along the bayou that former slave Eve gave her name to. The story is told from a young girl's point of view, Eve Batiste (Jurnee Smollett), who is narrating as an adult. It was filmed in Louisiana, in the bayou areas north of Lake Pontchartrain, north of New Orleans. I particularly like the exposition during the last scene where Eve describes our lives and memories as an intricate tapestry of all of our memories. This movie is about Eve's memories. The movie starts by saying that Eve was 11 years old when she killed her father. We don't find out what she means until the very end. Her father is small time doctor Louis Batiste (Samuel L. Jackson) who mostly makes routine house calls, dispenses aspirin, and flirts with the lonely ladies. He says he loves his wife, he appears to be a good father to his 2 daughters and son, but occasionally strays, and that is what gets him in hot water. Meagan Good is fine as the older sister Cisely Batiste. Lynn Whitfield is also good as the wife and mother Roz Batiste. SPOILERS. When Eve wanders into the storage shed during a party, and falls asleep, she awakens to find her dad and Mrs Mereaux engaged in sexual activity. This scares her, but what really gets her going is when sis tells her that dad made advances towards her, then hit her when she withdrew. Little Eve decided she needed to have her dad dead, goes to voodoo lady Elzora (Diahann Carroll) for a spell. What really gets dad is when Mrs Mereaux's husband shows up and finds him and his wife together at a bar. He tells Loius to never speak to his wife again or he will kill him. Louis smiles and yells 'good night Matty', and the jealous husband shoots and kills him. So, Eve really was responsible, because it was she in an earlier conversation that hinted to Mr Mereaux that her dad and his wife 'both seemed to come home late a lot.' Eve feels bad when she later finds out her sister's story was not true, she had been the one who made an advance by kissing dad as a mistress might, and dad rejected that which made sis mad enough to lie about it. Of interest to me, Branford Marsalis had a small role as friend Harry.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rich family saga with an interesting twist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prop03
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is now showing on cable here in Australia, and is a far better than average offering. Written and directed by Kasi Lemmons, the film is a powerful family drama set in the sixties in the south of the USA. It stars Samuel L Jackson as a small town doctor with a wandering eye. The story is told from the viewpoint of his middle child, Eve, wonderfully played by Jurnee Smollett, who sees her middle-class family life threatened by her father's infidelities. No tale set in a bayou village could exist without references to black magic and voodoo, and this film also has them as a rather central part of the plot. But these elements are handled skilfully and believably, and heighten the tension that develops. One of the interesting tools used by Lemmons is to tell and retell a story from different characters' perspectives, asking the viewer to determine which is more truthful, and indeed, whether the truth is paramount. Jackson gives a sparkling performance as Dr Louis Batiste, a man of warmth and generosity who is well regarded by the local community that he serves. His family is seemingly a happy and close one, until the children begin to question some of the adult behaviour they witness. Jurnee Smollett's Eve is the main protagonist around whom much of the story is centred, and she effortlessly moves back and forth between being a precocious brat and a young woman with powerful emotions. The rest of the cast is also very good, including a voluptuous Lisa Nicole Carson as the temptress Mattie Mereaux, and Diahann Carroll as a bayou witch. This film moves along at a good pace and is a little more than you might expect.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Eve's Bayou" is a 90s Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesewintersundays
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer/director Kasi Lemmons and her outstanding cast have outdone themselves in the sublime "Eve's Bayou." "Eve's Bayou" is fleet but not in a hurry. The scenes are clear and lean against the richness of the setting, but they flow leisurely toward the climax, like a punt bearing two lovers languidly downstream. "Eve's Bayou" is such a great story, partly because Lemmons herself is a master storyteller who is particularly gifted at strong endings, partly because the splendid cast embodies the characters so fully that the events actually seem to be happening to them, instead of unfolding from a screenplay. What a beautiful film it is: Not an overdecorated "period" portrait, but a film in which the people move easily through town and country homes and landscapes which frame and define them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Elegant and Deeply Disquieting Drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    throughtheyellowgate
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons ''Eve's Bayou,'' is an elegant and deeply disquieting drama that became 1997's highest grossing independent film. The tenuous bonds that hold the Batiste, a highly accomplished African-American family, together have finally come undone. Spouses cheat; secrets are held -- lies are told ; parents and children share households but have no common ground. Beautifully acted as it is, "Eve's Bayou" still elects to keep its characters and their emotions at a distance. They remain as hidden from the viewer as they are from one another, which is an essential part of the film's disturbing power. Mrs. Lemmons daringly chooses to keep her story's motivational mysteries unexplained, leaving this richly observed film open to the viewer's assessments. Yet the sense of imbalance is ever-present and strong. Films like "Eve's Bayou" are not easily summarized; they don't have that slick "high concept" one-sentence peg that makes them easy to sell. Maybe all I've said still leaves you wondering what the movie is about. But some of the best movies are like this: They show everyday life, carefully observed, and as we grow to know the people in the film, maybe we find out something about ourselves. The fact that Lemmons is able to combine these qualities with turmoil, loneliness and even tragedy make the movie very rare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding, Outstanding, Outstanding!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyeofmyangels
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kasi Lemmons has invigorated and enriched her debut film, "Eve's Bayou", through the use of a thousand details, a strong sense of time and place, outstanding characterizations and a display of energy and cinematic flair that marks an advance on any other film released in 1997. Lemmons works with such piercing fervor and intelligence that "Eve's Bayou" just about transcends its tidy moral design. "Eve's Bayou" is as good a compromise of fact and fiction as you could hope for -- and still call it a movie. Lemmons directed this with a single-mindedness and attention to detail that makes it riveting. She doesn't make the mistake of adding cornball little subplots to popularize the material; she knows she has a great story, and she tells it with such realism that feels like we're apart of the Batiste family. This is a powerful story, one of 1997's best films, told with great clarity and acted like a finely tuned powerful fire(bravo Debbi Morgan).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Sad and Yet Magical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    girlkeepscomingloose
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Eve's Bayou" perfectly captures the melancholia that sometimes settles on a body like the gloaming, when the dying light seems profoundly sad and yet magical. Based on the short film "Dr. Hugo" (available on the DVD), this is a gem in the debut film making crown for writer/director Kasi Lemmons. Lemmons, with customary nuance and visual brilliance, crumbles the upper crust while breaking hearts with this poignant portrait of the Batiste, a wealthy African American family dwelling on a beautiful/haunting Louisiana bayou. While virtually every scene resonates with longing, there is one that is a masterpiece of unspoken words -- and somehow calls up visions of Ingmar Bergman's great family dramas. Debbi Morgan and young Jurnee Smollet -- who provide outstanding performances -- are supported by a host of deft players, and the detailed re-creation of this small universe is in all ways remarkable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
