<filme>
 <id>
  889
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120275
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  The Tango Lesson - Uma Li&ccedil;&atilde;o de Tango
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  On a trip to Paris Sally meets Pablo, a tango dancer. He starts teaching her to dance then she returns to London to work on some "projects". She visits Buenos Aires and learns more from ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  On a trip to Paris Sally meets Pablo, a tango dancer. He starts teaching her to dance then she returns to London to work on some "projects". She visits Buenos Aires and learns more from Pablo's friends. Sally & Pablo meet again but this time their relationship changes, she realises they want different things from each other. On a trip to Buenos Aires they cement their friendship.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   dance
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tango
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dancer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   creative process
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   model
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Sally Potter
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Sally Potter
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Sally Potter
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Pablo Ver&oacute;n
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Morgane Maugran
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you love light there's lots in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drjude518
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie for its luminous black and white portraiture of Tango, Buenos Aires and Paris. There's been a few negative comments about Sally's insistence on casting herself in the lead role. A reviewer said that she looked tired; the result of multi-tasking her role as lead and director. I say she has a face that is somewhat care-worn from living a life well which is full of emotional content. It is important to juxtapose the angelic face of Pablo Veron against her much more sage face. A younger more beautiful type would not have worked. She was so smart to think of that; or perhaps it was the fortunate result of looking at the rushes that it came to her. As an art house film it works; the locations are interesting; fragments of spaces and shapes and textures with beautiful lighting. As a study of human relationships it was so painful to watch. I so related to her reluctance to interfere with yet desire to connect with Pablo. Honestly painful. There are also the familiar cast of characters that appear in Sally's other films: Heathcote Williams and Peter Eyre to name 2 that I recognized. I loved Eyre's interaction with Sally; he watched her sadly as she watched Pablo knowing exactly what was going on in her mind. Such an interesting actor with less than 5 minutes on screen time. It is interesting that Maria (one of the Hollywood execs) is an Argentinian born actress pulling off a very good interpretation of an LA beautiful person. Comfortable like a great pair of well worn dance shoes with a patina that just gets better with time. There was just enough there to whet the appetite but like good dancers; they held enough back making you beg for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect film - for certain audiences
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris_Docker
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whether you judge The Tango Lesson to be as perfect as a film can get, or a self-indulgent autohagiography with nice legs and sets, is probably about your viewpoint. There is bound to be at least one reader who will disagree with either view. So I am inclined to look at what the director was trying to achieve. Sally Potter is an established art-house filmmaker with particular interests in gender politics and dance. She also sings, writes and, in this film at least, acts. Tango is a dance drawing heavily on passion. Unlike many dances, its emotional range includes jealousy and betrayal. When sparks fly, they are not just sparks of attraction. Male power and domination, silence that bites, and doomed love and destruction (hence the metaphor of Bertolucci's Last Tango in Paris). A woman never escapes the man's embrace. The brilliance of her steps give the appearance of being entirely due to her partner's masterful guidance. At one point in our movie, Potter's partner, enraged, tells her she must 'do nothing'  he means nothing that doesn't come from him. It is a perfect dance to build dramatic metaphor around. But Potter's interest goes further. She wants to examine role reversal (this is the director who has had a hit a few years earlier with the sexual ambiguous Orlando). In The Tango Lesson, she plays opposite a top tango dancer, mentally submitting to him in order to learn the dance. Her character is a film director, disillusioned with a Hollywood deal and looking for a new project. Could it be dance? In the second half, she enlists him to play in a film. The power position is reversed. He must follow instead of lead. He must take direction. The success of this plot relies almost entirely on its real life elements. The circumstances in which the film was made mirror those depicted in the film-within-a-film. Names of principle characters are not changed. Potter does all her own dancing. Obvious commercial sell-outs are avoided. So in terms of dancing and the gender politics, how well does the film perform? The answer has to be, "Magnificently." The tango scenes are among the best of any motion picture. Tango on the stage, tango on the streets. Tango in the dancehalls, tango on the water's edge. Tango in rain, tango in snow. Potter described some of the technical challenges, saying that in the rain there were, "a limited number of takes possible due to the limited number of dry jeans." But the result is stunning. If you wanted a tango photo to hang over your fireplace, you would be spoilt for choice with stills from this film. Perfect mise-en-scene and impressive lighting make the film visually intoxicating. And when we hear Libertango  the most familiar of all tango tunes  the energy explodes as Potter bursts from the dance studio, dancing with several men at once. Cinematography is endlessly inventive. During a stage performance, the camera is positioned so that it faces the audience, dancers silhouetted by the dazzle of spotlights. "I wanted to show something of the visceral sensation of being onstage," she says, "with the lights in your eyes." Gender analysis is equally successful. Potter deals with simple male chauvinism, and in a matter-of-fact rather than an unkind way. Pablo and his friends act in a 'perfectly reasonable' manner which Potter then exposes as unreasonable. They cherish a glamorised idea of film-making. She has to exert gentle authority when they 'decide' that they've waited long enough for someone to turn up; or when Pablo might not 'want' to shed a tear in her 'little film.' She must  and does  handle their unprofessional emotions, fears and ignorance, exactly as Pablo had to handle hers when she was learning to dance. And now it is against his every instinct. He must follow and let her lead. Potter takes us beyond gender politics to the creative process. The film opens with her wiping a white table, then she sits at it with a blank sheet of paper. She starts to script, but discards one idea after another. Fast cuts to bursts of colour (in the Hollywood movie she had originally planned to make) illustrate action sequences of a movie style that makes money. They are like fragments of a finished film, waiting to be found. She hovers, waiting for the right idea to take form. "I know this moment well. It's the most precious, delicate, terrifying moment in film-making. The void beckons, seductively. But at any moment, the pencil will touch the blank page and the first, irrevocable step will have been taken. Every such step can feel like an act of treachery against abstract and infinite perfection." That state of 'becoming,' the moment before any definite action is decided, parallels the state of preparedness a follower must have in dance. It is the philosophy that an early feminist-filmmaker, Maya Deren (also a dancer), propounded in connection with films (such as her Study in Choreography for the Camera). For her, it was an essential trait of being a woman, the ability to wait, as opposed to a man's desire for immediacy. For Potter, who had focused on dancing in her earlier life, the film becomes a voyage of discovery. "I remember suddenly what I always loved about dancing  the combination of vigorous endeavour, present timidness, and dedication to process  the sure knowledge that you never 'arrive', you are instead in a constant process of arrival. It is itself, and it is a metaphor: for learning, for living, for being." On the downside, there is not a lot of story. The Tango Lesson is Strictly Ballroom stripped of make-up, witticisms, clich&eacute;s, overacting, and the pointless, predictable, but highly entertaining storyline. The Tango Lesson proudly states that the ideas (and the dancing) should be sufficient. Sadly for some people of course, it won't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Numbers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carlos
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone has mentioned this: the problem with "The Tango Lesson" is that it has Sally Potter all around. And Sally Potter doesn't dance badly, but her character, her persona, feels thin for a main character (surely because she tamed it down a lot, "forgetting" many of her "ugly" bits, so she feels like an unfinished creation), and can't carry the movie. It's interesting when the films feels sincere (loneliness, creation, and so on), but the thing that redeems this 100 minutes are the dance pieces, the musical parts, which for once they feel like a natural and optimistic part of the story that do not break the narration but feel part of it (like in the old MGM musicals and so on), and Pablo Ver&oacute;n. She has strengths; it's a pity that she didn't realize of her weaknesses.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tango lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ecuabeatinezz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Tango Lesson was a film in which one can very much see clearly the idea of feminism. Sally is a woman who wanted to learn how to dance tango. She met a man named Pablo who taught her very much on how to dance tango. He dominated her in the sense of how she had to dance, stand, look, etc. While she learned how to dance, she was writing a play that she wanted to publish. As they both practiced on dancing they start to attach feelings for each other. A little after experiencing these feelings she questions Pablo about where exactly they stand (she seemed like she wanted more than just a friendship). He replied to her that he wanted to keep distance and not confuse the professional with the personal. After learning enough to dance in a front of a stage, Sally and Pablo perform in front of an audience. She learned enough that he felt like she was taking more control than she had to. He says that she took his liberty away and he was upset. He had to be in control of the dance and let him guide her. Not the other way around. This is the turning point of the film, she starts getting in control. Her play advances, and she chose who was in her film and she regulated what happened in her film. She is the leader now in the dances, and at the end of the film she instructed them to dance and her personality gave away as a leader. This film portrays how a woman who came from not knowing anything, to a woman who became a leader of her self. Many obstacles were in her way, such as Pablo. He had an idea of a man who had to be in control and it somewhat astonished him when he saw the changes in Sally. I recall in one scene when they are arguing he states, "Let me be in control!" Even through the norms of this society, Sally managed to be in control of her self and what she wanted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feminist Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    torigemi3
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sally Potter is one of the most respected names in feminist film. The Tango Lesson, while very different from any of her earlier works, seems to be a really personal, even autobiographical film. It's about a middle-aged British filmmaker named Sally Potter. More recent productions have abandoned prudery towards women's bodies and moved to "the other side" of visual pleasure. The film shows Sally's own personal involvement with Tango. Its original purpose of something fun, new, exciting and stress relief from her routine life soon became an obsession causing several conflicts. The relevance of feminism in the film is blatantly present. A conflict scene in the film is between characters Sally and her Tango partner, teacher and love interest Pablo Veron. The back and fourth arguments are the strongest representation of a feminist point of view in a relationship. After Sally's first Tango performance with Pablo they are involved in a confrontation. Pablo's issue with Sally is that he is the leader and she was to follow which in his eyes she was not doing during the performance. The feminist thought and idea is that men lead woman. Sally replies to this by saying "you danced like a soloist". She said that no emotions were involved in the dance sequence which is extremely important in order to create a believable and interesting performance. The fact that they were involved in a personal relationship outside of the dancing did not help the situation. Pablo's character was an alpha male who fell for a woman whose strength and power intimidated him. I noticed in the film in several scenes in his house in the bathroom, on top of the fire place, and in the dressing room, Pablo was placed in front of a mirror. His obsession with himself intrigues Sally to a near jealous streak. She is envious of his confidence. He is also in control of the language spoken between the two of them. They both speak French, Spanish and English. When they are not dancing as business partners and enter their personal relationship they speak French. Pablo unable to speak very well English prefers not to while conversing with Sally. Sally Potter was not considered what society considers beautiful. She was an older woman who dressed moderately, did not wear makeup, and did not possess a voluptuous body. "The gaze" in television and movies is a serious issue for our society. Woman are considered spectacles used as objects of visual and physical pleasure. The director's gaze is present in the film because she represents and analyzes our visual culture in how men and woman perceive each other.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Tango Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kallajimon
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a different kind of film. It is based on the writer's own experience, and the main characters actually seem to be playing themselves. It is a film about the making of a film, so is a film within a film. I was bothered at first by Sally's rather stiff, and rather awkward movements as she learned the tango. Compared with her partner's fluidity and passion, her style of dancing seemed to me to match her personality (naturally), which I experienced as typically milk and toast English (limp). Though she is obviously fascinated by the tango, her passion does not translate to her dancing. At the very end, though, she seems to be beginning to get some true fluidity of movement and a teeny bit of sensuality in her dancing, so at the end of the movie, I found myself holding out hope that she one day, with practice and discovery of passion within herself, would be able to simulate something in the realm of that displayed by Carlo, her partner. It is a very good film, I think. She seems always to be thinking, while Carlo seems always to be moving, beautifully. He is a true artist of movement, and his joy of dancing comes through fabulously. He is poetry in motion. I enjoyed the extra material, too, though in one feature it was jumbled (production notes, I think it was) and in another (still photos, I believe) one couldn't use the pause, forward or reverse buttons and it was frustrating to have to play everything over from the beginning to be able to read things one hadn't time to read the first time around. And then not absolutely everything was able to be read the third time around, either, due to the pace. Anyway. The film is lovely, even though I was constantly irritated by the cerebral as opposed to emotional aspect of Sally's character. She moved like a broomstick, actually. It was annoying, especially when her partner was so fluid and sensual. But that is in fact part of the story . . . :-).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    read my comment for my summary on this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themush01
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Men are traditionally seen as the stronger sex. Men are usually portrayed as being more powerful mentally and in strength than woman. The tango is a very famous and difficult dance that has the man being the stronger of the two sexes. Within the movie The Tango Lesson, directed and written by Sally Potter in 1997, the character Sally starts taking tango lessons by a man named Pablo. During the dance lessons Sally is taught to tango. Within her lessons she is taught to follow the man's lead. While dancing with Pablo, Sally becomes a very good dancer. Pablo asks her to join him in a dance that will take place in front of a very large audience. While they are dancing Sally makes very minor mistakes. While exiting the stage Pablo stays out longer and takes more bows, this can symbolize that he feels that he is the supeiror dancer. When they are off stage Pablo yells at Sally saying that he was "messing up" his dance because she was leading and taking up his space. He said that this prevented him from dancing. That situation shows that Sally is seen as the weaker and less important sex. Sally argues with Pablo that he cant handle the fact that she can lead and will. This shows that she realizes how Pablo is thinking and sees himself when he dances with her. The Tango Dance represents the difference of roles between males and females. Overall it was a very different kind of movie, there wasn't a lot of talking, but there was a lot of very good dancing. This is a good movie to watch if you are learning how to dance the tango or interested in watching movies that show very good dance scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now I always have an answer to that worst film ever question
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterjump
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terrible acting by Potter and a flat plot with no tension what so ever. And as for the feminist polemic, it's laughable. I saw this garbage when it was first released and though I found it tedious beyond belief I'm glad I did go to see it. That's because I now have an immediate answer to the question 'what's the worst film you've ever seen?' Plus, I have the comfort of knowing that every film I see for the rest of my life will be better than The Tango Lesson. But I have to admit I was impressed with the way Potter wrote a script that would garner the maximum number of arts council grants from around the world (as is revealed in the closing credits). I only very recently saw Orlando and I can see how Potter learnt the wrong lessons from making that film. All it took was a bunch of frilly costumes, a few hard stares to camera by the leading lady, and a loose plot to seduce the cinema going public. So why shouldn't she think she could get away with the self-indulgent nothingness that is The Tango Lesson?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Tango Lesson - about power struggle between a man and woman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amybeam
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What happens when two dominant personalities fall in love? Who gets to lead? Who gets to follow? What if it doesn't suit either one to follow? Writer/director Sally Potter is also the lead actress in this dramatic love story about a film director (herself) making a movie about tango. Sally meets Pablo Veron, an authentic world-class Argentinean tango dancer, and convinces him to give her tango lessons. Pablo obliges her, in hopes of starring in one of her movies. Sally gets good enough to become his professional dance partner. The movie is divided into "Lessons." If you're a dancer, you should see this film if for no other reason than the numerous spectacular dance scenes. Half-way through, the viewer realizes that these "lessons" are not about dance after all, but about life. The tango is used as a metaphor for the power struggle between a man and a woman falling in love, but being stymied because each insists on being in control. Like the tango, the tempo starts out slowly and crescendos as Sally and Pablo's professional and personal relationship deepens and grows more volatile. Can a relationship like this survive? This movie was funded by the French government. It's in English with a few French subtitles; set in France and Argentina.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "How did you choose the tango? I didn't. The tango chose me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Galina
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Tango Lesson" is a unique and beautiful movie made by the director/ writer Sally Potter about a director/writer named Sally Potter who is fascinated by the art of Tango, meets a young dancer Pablo Ver&oacute;n (played by a dancer named Pablo Ver&oacute;n), and dances with him - and as everything Sally (well both of them) does, her dancing is graceful, elegant, delicate yet masterful, subtle, and passionate - just as the movie itself is. I don't care if it is the "Blatant narcissism", "Self-Indulgence or "Self Importance" - they don't make the movie for me any worse and I am fascinated by Sally Potter, the strong, talented, and independent woman. "The Tango Lesson" examines the mysterious connection between two people, their interest to each other, even if they were not meant to be together. At one point, Sally tells Pablo, "It doesn't suit me to follow. It suits me to lead, and you can't deal with that." The film is also about sensual passion of Tango where every dance is a fight between the partners over the control and victory and both victory and defeat are a celebration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you love light there's lots in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drjude518
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie for its luminous black and white portraiture of Tango, Buenos Aires and Paris. There's been a few negative comments about Sally's insistence on casting herself in the lead role. A reviewer said that she looked tired; the result of multi-tasking her role as lead and director. I say she has a face that is somewhat care-worn from living a life well which is full of emotional content. It is important to juxtapose the angelic face of Pablo Veron against her much more sage face. A younger more beautiful type would not have worked. She was so smart to think of that; or perhaps it was the fortunate result of looking at the rushes that it came to her. As an art house film it works; the locations are interesting; fragments of spaces and shapes and textures with beautiful lighting. As a study of human relationships it was so painful to watch. I so related to her reluctance to interfere with yet desire to connect with Pablo. Honestly painful. There are also the familiar cast of characters that appear in Sally's other films: Heathcote Williams and Peter Eyre to name 2 that I recognized. I loved Eyre's interaction with Sally; he watched her sadly as she watched Pablo knowing exactly what was going on in her mind. Such an interesting actor with less than 5 minutes on screen time. It is interesting that Maria (one of the Hollywood execs) is an Argentinian born actress pulling off a very good interpretation of an LA beautiful person. Comfortable like a great pair of well worn dance shoes with a patina that just gets better with time. There was just enough there to whet the appetite but like good dancers; they held enough back making you beg for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect film - for certain audiences
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris_Docker
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whether you judge The Tango Lesson to be as perfect as a film can get, or a self-indulgent autohagiography with nice legs and sets, is probably about your viewpoint. There is bound to be at least one reader who will disagree with either view. So I am inclined to look at what the director was trying to achieve. Sally Potter is an established art-house filmmaker with particular interests in gender politics and dance. She also sings, writes and, in this film at least, acts. Tango is a dance drawing heavily on passion. Unlike many dances, its emotional range includes jealousy and betrayal. When sparks fly, they are not just sparks of attraction. Male power and domination, silence that bites, and doomed love and destruction (hence the metaphor of Bertolucci's Last Tango in Paris). A woman never escapes the man's embrace. The brilliance of her steps give the appearance of being entirely due to her partner's masterful guidance. At one point in our movie, Potter's partner, enraged, tells her she must 'do nothing'  he means nothing that doesn't come from him. It is a perfect dance to build dramatic metaphor around. But Potter's interest goes further. She wants to examine role reversal (this is the director who has had a hit a few years earlier with the sexual ambiguous Orlando). In The Tango Lesson, she plays opposite a top tango dancer, mentally submitting to him in order to learn the dance. Her character is a film director, disillusioned with a Hollywood deal and looking for a new project. Could it be dance? In the second half, she enlists him to play in a film. The power position is reversed. He must follow instead of lead. He must take direction. The success of this plot relies almost entirely on its real life elements. The circumstances in which the film was made mirror those depicted in the film-within-a-film. Names of principle characters are not changed. Potter does all her own dancing. Obvious commercial sell-outs are avoided. So in terms of dancing and the gender politics, how well does the film perform? The answer has to be, "Magnificently." The tango scenes are among the best of any motion picture. Tango on the stage, tango on the streets. Tango in the dancehalls, tango on the water's edge. Tango in rain, tango in snow. Potter described some of the technical challenges, saying that in the rain there were, "a limited number of takes possible due to the limited number of dry jeans." But the result is stunning. If you wanted a tango photo to hang over your fireplace, you would be spoilt for choice with stills from this film. Perfect mise-en-scene and impressive lighting make the film visually intoxicating. And when we hear Libertango  the most familiar of all tango tunes  the energy explodes as Potter bursts from the dance studio, dancing with several men at once. Cinematography is endlessly inventive. During a stage performance, the camera is positioned so that it faces the audience, dancers silhouetted by the dazzle of spotlights. "I wanted to show something of the visceral sensation of being onstage," she says, "with the lights in your eyes." Gender analysis is equally successful. Potter deals with simple male chauvinism, and in a matter-of-fact rather than an unkind way. Pablo and his friends act in a 'perfectly reasonable' manner which Potter then exposes as unreasonable. They cherish a glamorised idea of film-making. She has to exert gentle authority when they 'decide' that they've waited long enough for someone to turn up; or when Pablo might not 'want' to shed a tear in her 'little film.' She must  and does  handle their unprofessional emotions, fears and ignorance, exactly as Pablo had to handle hers when she was learning to dance. And now it is against his every instinct. He must follow and let her lead. Potter takes us beyond gender politics to the creative process. The film opens with her wiping a white table, then she sits at it with a blank sheet of paper. She starts to script, but discards one idea after another. Fast cuts to bursts of colour (in the Hollywood movie she had originally planned to make) illustrate action sequences of a movie style that makes money. They are like fragments of a finished film, waiting to be found. She hovers, waiting for the right idea to take form. "I know this moment well. It's the most precious, delicate, terrifying moment in film-making. The void beckons, seductively. But at any moment, the pencil will touch the blank page and the first, irrevocable step will have been taken. Every such step can feel like an act of treachery against abstract and infinite perfection." That state of 'becoming,' the moment before any definite action is decided, parallels the state of preparedness a follower must have in dance. It is the philosophy that an early feminist-filmmaker, Maya Deren (also a dancer), propounded in connection with films (such as her Study in Choreography for the Camera). For her, it was an essential trait of being a woman, the ability to wait, as opposed to a man's desire for immediacy. For Potter, who had focused on dancing in her earlier life, the film becomes a voyage of discovery. "I remember suddenly what I always loved about dancing  the combination of vigorous endeavour, present timidness, and dedication to process  the sure knowledge that you never 'arrive', you are instead in a constant process of arrival. It is itself, and it is a metaphor: for learning, for living, for being." On the downside, there is not a lot of story. The Tango Lesson is Strictly Ballroom stripped of make-up, witticisms, clich&eacute;s, overacting, and the pointless, predictable, but highly entertaining storyline. The Tango Lesson proudly states that the ideas (and the dancing) should be sufficient. Sadly for some people of course, it won't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Numbers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carlos
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone has mentioned this: the problem with "The Tango Lesson" is that it has Sally Potter all around. And Sally Potter doesn't dance badly, but her character, her persona, feels thin for a main character (surely because she tamed it down a lot, "forgetting" many of her "ugly" bits, so she feels like an unfinished creation), and can't carry the movie. It's interesting when the films feels sincere (loneliness, creation, and so on), but the thing that redeems this 100 minutes are the dance pieces, the musical parts, which for once they feel like a natural and optimistic part of the story that do not break the narration but feel part of it (like in the old MGM musicals and so on), and Pablo Ver&oacute;n. She has strengths; it's a pity that she didn't realize of her weaknesses.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tango lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ecuabeatinezz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Tango Lesson was a film in which one can very much see clearly the idea of feminism. Sally is a woman who wanted to learn how to dance tango. She met a man named Pablo who taught her very much on how to dance tango. He dominated her in the sense of how she had to dance, stand, look, etc. While she learned how to dance, she was writing a play that she wanted to publish. As they both practiced on dancing they start to attach feelings for each other. A little after experiencing these feelings she questions Pablo about where exactly they stand (she seemed like she wanted more than just a friendship). He replied to her that he wanted to keep distance and not confuse the professional with the personal. After learning enough to dance in a front of a stage, Sally and Pablo perform in front of an audience. She learned enough that he felt like she was taking more control than she had to. He says that she took his liberty away and he was upset. He had to be in control of the dance and let him guide her. Not the other way around. This is the turning point of the film, she starts getting in control. Her play advances, and she chose who was in her film and she regulated what happened in her film. She is the leader now in the dances, and at the end of the film she instructed them to dance and her personality gave away as a leader. This film portrays how a woman who came from not knowing anything, to a woman who became a leader of her self. Many obstacles were in her way, such as Pablo. He had an idea of a man who had to be in control and it somewhat astonished him when he saw the changes in Sally. I recall in one scene when they are arguing he states, "Let me be in control!" Even through the norms of this society, Sally managed to be in control of her self and what she wanted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feminist Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    torigemi3
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sally Potter is one of the most respected names in feminist film. The Tango Lesson, while very different from any of her earlier works, seems to be a really personal, even autobiographical film. It's about a middle-aged British filmmaker named Sally Potter. More recent productions have abandoned prudery towards women's bodies and moved to "the other side" of visual pleasure. The film shows Sally's own personal involvement with Tango. Its original purpose of something fun, new, exciting and stress relief from her routine life soon became an obsession causing several conflicts. The relevance of feminism in the film is blatantly present. A conflict scene in the film is between characters Sally and her Tango partner, teacher and love interest Pablo Veron. The back and fourth arguments are the strongest representation of a feminist point of view in a relationship. After Sally's first Tango performance with Pablo they are involved in a confrontation. Pablo's issue with Sally is that he is the leader and she was to follow which in his eyes she was not doing during the performance. The feminist thought and idea is that men lead woman. Sally replies to this by saying "you danced like a soloist". She said that no emotions were involved in the dance sequence which is extremely important in order to create a believable and interesting performance. The fact that they were involved in a personal relationship outside of the dancing did not help the situation. Pablo's character was an alpha male who fell for a woman whose strength and power intimidated him. I noticed in the film in several scenes in his house in the bathroom, on top of the fire place, and in the dressing room, Pablo was placed in front of a mirror. His obsession with himself intrigues Sally to a near jealous streak. She is envious of his confidence. He is also in control of the language spoken between the two of them. They both speak French, Spanish and English. When they are not dancing as business partners and enter their personal relationship they speak French. Pablo unable to speak very well English prefers not to while conversing with Sally. Sally Potter was not considered what society considers beautiful. She was an older woman who dressed moderately, did not wear makeup, and did not possess a voluptuous body. "The gaze" in television and movies is a serious issue for our society. Woman are considered spectacles used as objects of visual and physical pleasure. The director's gaze is present in the film because she represents and analyzes our visual culture in how men and woman perceive each other.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Tango Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kallajimon
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a different kind of film. It is based on the writer's own experience, and the main characters actually seem to be playing themselves. It is a film about the making of a film, so is a film within a film. I was bothered at first by Sally's rather stiff, and rather awkward movements as she learned the tango. Compared with her partner's fluidity and passion, her style of dancing seemed to me to match her personality (naturally), which I experienced as typically milk and toast English (limp). Though she is obviously fascinated by the tango, her passion does not translate to her dancing. At the very end, though, she seems to be beginning to get some true fluidity of movement and a teeny bit of sensuality in her dancing, so at the end of the movie, I found myself holding out hope that she one day, with practice and discovery of passion within herself, would be able to simulate something in the realm of that displayed by Carlo, her partner. It is a very good film, I think. She seems always to be thinking, while Carlo seems always to be moving, beautifully. He is a true artist of movement, and his joy of dancing comes through fabulously. He is poetry in motion. I enjoyed the extra material, too, though in one feature it was jumbled (production notes, I think it was) and in another (still photos, I believe) one couldn't use the pause, forward or reverse buttons and it was frustrating to have to play everything over from the beginning to be able to read things one hadn't time to read the first time around. And then not absolutely everything was able to be read the third time around, either, due to the pace. Anyway. The film is lovely, even though I was constantly irritated by the cerebral as opposed to emotional aspect of Sally's character. She moved like a broomstick, actually. It was annoying, especially when her partner was so fluid and sensual. But that is in fact part of the story . . . :-).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    read my comment for my summary on this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themush01
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Men are traditionally seen as the stronger sex. Men are usually portrayed as being more powerful mentally and in strength than woman. The tango is a very famous and difficult dance that has the man being the stronger of the two sexes. Within the movie The Tango Lesson, directed and written by Sally Potter in 1997, the character Sally starts taking tango lessons by a man named Pablo. During the dance lessons Sally is taught to tango. Within her lessons she is taught to follow the man's lead. While dancing with Pablo, Sally becomes a very good dancer. Pablo asks her to join him in a dance that will take place in front of a very large audience. While they are dancing Sally makes very minor mistakes. While exiting the stage Pablo stays out longer and takes more bows, this can symbolize that he feels that he is the supeiror dancer. When they are off stage Pablo yells at Sally saying that he was "messing up" his dance because she was leading and taking up his space. He said that this prevented him from dancing. That situation shows that Sally is seen as the weaker and less important sex. Sally argues with Pablo that he cant handle the fact that she can lead and will. This shows that she realizes how Pablo is thinking and sees himself when he dances with her. The Tango Dance represents the difference of roles between males and females. Overall it was a very different kind of movie, there wasn't a lot of talking, but there was a lot of very good dancing. This is a good movie to watch if you are learning how to dance the tango or interested in watching movies that show very good dance scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now I always have an answer to that worst film ever question
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterjump
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terrible acting by Potter and a flat plot with no tension what so ever. And as for the feminist polemic, it's laughable. I saw this garbage when it was first released and though I found it tedious beyond belief I'm glad I did go to see it. That's because I now have an immediate answer to the question 'what's the worst film you've ever seen?' Plus, I have the comfort of knowing that every film I see for the rest of my life will be better than The Tango Lesson. But I have to admit I was impressed with the way Potter wrote a script that would garner the maximum number of arts council grants from around the world (as is revealed in the closing credits). I only very recently saw Orlando and I can see how Potter learnt the wrong lessons from making that film. All it took was a bunch of frilly costumes, a few hard stares to camera by the leading lady, and a loose plot to seduce the cinema going public. So why shouldn't she think she could get away with the self-indulgent nothingness that is The Tango Lesson?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Tango Lesson - about power struggle between a man and woman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amybeam
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What happens when two dominant personalities fall in love? Who gets to lead? Who gets to follow? What if it doesn't suit either one to follow? Writer/director Sally Potter is also the lead actress in this dramatic love story about a film director (herself) making a movie about tango. Sally meets Pablo Veron, an authentic world-class Argentinean tango dancer, and convinces him to give her tango lessons. Pablo obliges her, in hopes of starring in one of her movies. Sally gets good enough to become his professional dance partner. The movie is divided into "Lessons." If you're a dancer, you should see this film if for no other reason than the numerous spectacular dance scenes. Half-way through, the viewer realizes that these "lessons" are not about dance after all, but about life. The tango is used as a metaphor for the power struggle between a man and a woman falling in love, but being stymied because each insists on being in control. Like the tango, the tempo starts out slowly and crescendos as Sally and Pablo's professional and personal relationship deepens and grows more volatile. Can a relationship like this survive? This movie was funded by the French government. It's in English with a few French subtitles; set in France and Argentina.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "How did you choose the tango? I didn't. The tango chose me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Galina
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Tango Lesson" is a unique and beautiful movie made by the director/ writer Sally Potter about a director/writer named Sally Potter who is fascinated by the art of Tango, meets a young dancer Pablo Ver&oacute;n (played by a dancer named Pablo Ver&oacute;n), and dances with him - and as everything Sally (well both of them) does, her dancing is graceful, elegant, delicate yet masterful, subtle, and passionate - just as the movie itself is. I don't care if it is the "Blatant narcissism", "Self-Indulgence or "Self Importance" - they don't make the movie for me any worse and I am fascinated by Sally Potter, the strong, talented, and independent woman. "The Tango Lesson" examines the mysterious connection between two people, their interest to each other, even if they were not meant to be together. At one point, Sally tells Pablo, "It doesn't suit me to follow. It suits me to lead, and you can't deal with that." The film is also about sensual passion of Tango where every dance is a fight between the partners over the control and victory and both victory and defeat are a celebration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you love light there's lots in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drjude518
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie for its luminous black and white portraiture of Tango, Buenos Aires and Paris. There's been a few negative comments about Sally's insistence on casting herself in the lead role. A reviewer said that she looked tired; the result of multi-tasking her role as lead and director. I say she has a face that is somewhat care-worn from living a life well which is full of emotional content. It is important to juxtapose the angelic face of Pablo Veron against her much more sage face. A younger more beautiful type would not have worked. She was so smart to think of that; or perhaps it was the fortunate result of looking at the rushes that it came to her. As an art house film it works; the locations are interesting; fragments of spaces and shapes and textures with beautiful lighting. As a study of human relationships it was so painful to watch. I so related to her reluctance to interfere with yet desire to connect with Pablo. Honestly painful. There are also the familiar cast of characters that appear in Sally's other films: Heathcote Williams and Peter Eyre to name 2 that I recognized. I loved Eyre's interaction with Sally; he watched her sadly as she watched Pablo knowing exactly what was going on in her mind. Such an interesting actor with less than 5 minutes on screen time. It is interesting that Maria (one of the Hollywood execs) is an Argentinian born actress pulling off a very good interpretation of an LA beautiful person. Comfortable like a great pair of well worn dance shoes with a patina that just gets better with time. There was just enough there to whet the appetite but like good dancers; they held enough back making you beg for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect film - for certain audiences
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris_Docker
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whether you judge The Tango Lesson to be as perfect as a film can get, or a self-indulgent autohagiography with nice legs and sets, is probably about your viewpoint. There is bound to be at least one reader who will disagree with either view. So I am inclined to look at what the director was trying to achieve. Sally Potter is an established art-house filmmaker with particular interests in gender politics and dance. She also sings, writes and, in this film at least, acts. Tango is a dance drawing heavily on passion. Unlike many dances, its emotional range includes jealousy and betrayal. When sparks fly, they are not just sparks of attraction. Male power and domination, silence that bites, and doomed love and destruction (hence the metaphor of Bertolucci's Last Tango in Paris). A woman never escapes the man's embrace. The brilliance of her steps give the appearance of being entirely due to her partner's masterful guidance. At one point in our movie, Potter's partner, enraged, tells her she must 'do nothing'  he means nothing that doesn't come from him. It is a perfect dance to build dramatic metaphor around. But Potter's interest goes further. She wants to examine role reversal (this is the director who has had a hit a few years earlier with the sexual ambiguous Orlando). In The Tango Lesson, she plays opposite a top tango dancer, mentally submitting to him in order to learn the dance. Her character is a film director, disillusioned with a Hollywood deal and looking for a new project. Could it be dance? In the second half, she enlists him to play in a film. The power position is reversed. He must follow instead of lead. He must take direction. The success of this plot relies almost entirely on its real life elements. The circumstances in which the film was made mirror those depicted in the film-within-a-film. Names of principle characters are not changed. Potter does all her own dancing. Obvious commercial sell-outs are avoided. So in terms of dancing and the gender politics, how well does the film perform? The answer has to be, "Magnificently." The tango scenes are among the best of any motion picture. Tango on the stage, tango on the streets. Tango in the dancehalls, tango on the water's edge. Tango in rain, tango in snow. Potter described some of the technical challenges, saying that in the rain there were, "a limited number of takes possible due to the limited number of dry jeans." But the result is stunning. If you wanted a tango photo to hang over your fireplace, you would be spoilt for choice with stills from this film. Perfect mise-en-scene and impressive lighting make the film visually intoxicating. And when we hear Libertango  the most familiar of all tango tunes  the energy explodes as Potter bursts from the dance studio, dancing with several men at once. Cinematography is endlessly inventive. During a stage performance, the camera is positioned so that it faces the audience, dancers silhouetted by the dazzle of spotlights. "I wanted to show something of the visceral sensation of being onstage," she says, "with the lights in your eyes." Gender analysis is equally successful. Potter deals with simple male chauvinism, and in a matter-of-fact rather than an unkind way. Pablo and his friends act in a 'perfectly reasonable' manner which Potter then exposes as unreasonable. They cherish a glamorised idea of film-making. She has to exert gentle authority when they 'decide' that they've waited long enough for someone to turn up; or when Pablo might not 'want' to shed a tear in her 'little film.' She must  and does  handle their unprofessional emotions, fears and ignorance, exactly as Pablo had to handle hers when she was learning to dance. And now it is against his every instinct. He must follow and let her lead. Potter takes us beyond gender politics to the creative process. The film opens with her wiping a white table, then she sits at it with a blank sheet of paper. She starts to script, but discards one idea after another. Fast cuts to bursts of colour (in the Hollywood movie she had originally planned to make) illustrate action sequences of a movie style that makes money. They are like fragments of a finished film, waiting to be found. She hovers, waiting for the right idea to take form. "I know this moment well. It's the most precious, delicate, terrifying moment in film-making. The void beckons, seductively. But at any moment, the pencil will touch the blank page and the first, irrevocable step will have been taken. Every such step can feel like an act of treachery against abstract and infinite perfection." That state of 'becoming,' the moment before any definite action is decided, parallels the state of preparedness a follower must have in dance. It is the philosophy that an early feminist-filmmaker, Maya Deren (also a dancer), propounded in connection with films (such as her Study in Choreography for the Camera). For her, it was an essential trait of being a woman, the ability to wait, as opposed to a man's desire for immediacy. For Potter, who had focused on dancing in her earlier life, the film becomes a voyage of discovery. "I remember suddenly what I always loved about dancing  the combination of vigorous endeavour, present timidness, and dedication to process  the sure knowledge that you never 'arrive', you are instead in a constant process of arrival. It is itself, and it is a metaphor: for learning, for living, for being." On the downside, there is not a lot of story. The Tango Lesson is Strictly Ballroom stripped of make-up, witticisms, clich&eacute;s, overacting, and the pointless, predictable, but highly entertaining storyline. The Tango Lesson proudly states that the ideas (and the dancing) should be sufficient. Sadly for some people of course, it won't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Numbers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carlos
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone has mentioned this: the problem with "The Tango Lesson" is that it has Sally Potter all around. And Sally Potter doesn't dance badly, but her character, her persona, feels thin for a main character (surely because she tamed it down a lot, "forgetting" many of her "ugly" bits, so she feels like an unfinished creation), and can't carry the movie. It's interesting when the films feels sincere (loneliness, creation, and so on), but the thing that redeems this 100 minutes are the dance pieces, the musical parts, which for once they feel like a natural and optimistic part of the story that do not break the narration but feel part of it (like in the old MGM musicals and so on), and Pablo Ver&oacute;n. She has strengths; it's a pity that she didn't realize of her weaknesses.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tango lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ecuabeatinezz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Tango Lesson was a film in which one can very much see clearly the idea of feminism. Sally is a woman who wanted to learn how to dance tango. She met a man named Pablo who taught her very much on how to dance tango. He dominated her in the sense of how she had to dance, stand, look, etc. While she learned how to dance, she was writing a play that she wanted to publish. As they both practiced on dancing they start to attach feelings for each other. A little after experiencing these feelings she questions Pablo about where exactly they stand (she seemed like she wanted more than just a friendship). He replied to her that he wanted to keep distance and not confuse the professional with the personal. After learning enough to dance in a front of a stage, Sally and Pablo perform in front of an audience. She learned enough that he felt like she was taking more control than she had to. He says that she took his liberty away and he was upset. He had to be in control of the dance and let him guide her. Not the other way around. This is the turning point of the film, she starts getting in control. Her play advances, and she chose who was in her film and she regulated what happened in her film. She is the leader now in the dances, and at the end of the film she instructed them to dance and her personality gave away as a leader. This film portrays how a woman who came from not knowing anything, to a woman who became a leader of her self. Many obstacles were in her way, such as Pablo. He had an idea of a man who had to be in control and it somewhat astonished him when he saw the changes in Sally. I recall in one scene when they are arguing he states, "Let me be in control!" Even through the norms of this society, Sally managed to be in control of her self and what she wanted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feminist Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    torigemi3
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sally Potter is one of the most respected names in feminist film. The Tango Lesson, while very different from any of her earlier works, seems to be a really personal, even autobiographical film. It's about a middle-aged British filmmaker named Sally Potter. More recent productions have abandoned prudery towards women's bodies and moved to "the other side" of visual pleasure. The film shows Sally's own personal involvement with Tango. Its original purpose of something fun, new, exciting and stress relief from her routine life soon became an obsession causing several conflicts. The relevance of feminism in the film is blatantly present. A conflict scene in the film is between characters Sally and her Tango partner, teacher and love interest Pablo Veron. The back and fourth arguments are the strongest representation of a feminist point of view in a relationship. After Sally's first Tango performance with Pablo they are involved in a confrontation. Pablo's issue with Sally is that he is the leader and she was to follow which in his eyes she was not doing during the performance. The feminist thought and idea is that men lead woman. Sally replies to this by saying "you danced like a soloist". She said that no emotions were involved in the dance sequence which is extremely important in order to create a believable and interesting performance. The fact that they were involved in a personal relationship outside of the dancing did not help the situation. Pablo's character was an alpha male who fell for a woman whose strength and power intimidated him. I noticed in the film in several scenes in his house in the bathroom, on top of the fire place, and in the dressing room, Pablo was placed in front of a mirror. His obsession with himself intrigues Sally to a near jealous streak. She is envious of his confidence. He is also in control of the language spoken between the two of them. They both speak French, Spanish and English. When they are not dancing as business partners and enter their personal relationship they speak French. Pablo unable to speak very well English prefers not to while conversing with Sally. Sally Potter was not considered what society considers beautiful. She was an older woman who dressed moderately, did not wear makeup, and did not possess a voluptuous body. "The gaze" in television and movies is a serious issue for our society. Woman are considered spectacles used as objects of visual and physical pleasure. The director's gaze is present in the film because she represents and analyzes our visual culture in how men and woman perceive each other.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Tango Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kallajimon
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a different kind of film. It is based on the writer's own experience, and the main characters actually seem to be playing themselves. It is a film about the making of a film, so is a film within a film. I was bothered at first by Sally's rather stiff, and rather awkward movements as she learned the tango. Compared with her partner's fluidity and passion, her style of dancing seemed to me to match her personality (naturally), which I experienced as typically milk and toast English (limp). Though she is obviously fascinated by the tango, her passion does not translate to her dancing. At the very end, though, she seems to be beginning to get some true fluidity of movement and a teeny bit of sensuality in her dancing, so at the end of the movie, I found myself holding out hope that she one day, with practice and discovery of passion within herself, would be able to simulate something in the realm of that displayed by Carlo, her partner. It is a very good film, I think. She seems always to be thinking, while Carlo seems always to be moving, beautifully. He is a true artist of movement, and his joy of dancing comes through fabulously. He is poetry in motion. I enjoyed the extra material, too, though in one feature it was jumbled (production notes, I think it was) and in another (still photos, I believe) one couldn't use the pause, forward or reverse buttons and it was frustrating to have to play everything over from the beginning to be able to read things one hadn't time to read the first time around. And then not absolutely everything was able to be read the third time around, either, due to the pace. Anyway. The film is lovely, even though I was constantly irritated by the cerebral as opposed to emotional aspect of Sally's character. She moved like a broomstick, actually. It was annoying, especially when her partner was so fluid and sensual. But that is in fact part of the story . . . :-).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    read my comment for my summary on this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themush01
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Men are traditionally seen as the stronger sex. Men are usually portrayed as being more powerful mentally and in strength than woman. The tango is a very famous and difficult dance that has the man being the stronger of the two sexes. Within the movie The Tango Lesson, directed and written by Sally Potter in 1997, the character Sally starts taking tango lessons by a man named Pablo. During the dance lessons Sally is taught to tango. Within her lessons she is taught to follow the man's lead. While dancing with Pablo, Sally becomes a very good dancer. Pablo asks her to join him in a dance that will take place in front of a very large audience. While they are dancing Sally makes very minor mistakes. While exiting the stage Pablo stays out longer and takes more bows, this can symbolize that he feels that he is the supeiror dancer. When they are off stage Pablo yells at Sally saying that he was "messing up" his dance because she was leading and taking up his space. He said that this prevented him from dancing. That situation shows that Sally is seen as the weaker and less important sex. Sally argues with Pablo that he cant handle the fact that she can lead and will. This shows that she realizes how Pablo is thinking and sees himself when he dances with her. The Tango Dance represents the difference of roles between males and females. Overall it was a very different kind of movie, there wasn't a lot of talking, but there was a lot of very good dancing. This is a good movie to watch if you are learning how to dance the tango or interested in watching movies that show very good dance scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now I always have an answer to that worst film ever question
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterjump
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terrible acting by Potter and a flat plot with no tension what so ever. And as for the feminist polemic, it's laughable. I saw this garbage when it was first released and though I found it tedious beyond belief I'm glad I did go to see it. That's because I now have an immediate answer to the question 'what's the worst film you've ever seen?' Plus, I have the comfort of knowing that every film I see for the rest of my life will be better than The Tango Lesson. But I have to admit I was impressed with the way Potter wrote a script that would garner the maximum number of arts council grants from around the world (as is revealed in the closing credits). I only very recently saw Orlando and I can see how Potter learnt the wrong lessons from making that film. All it took was a bunch of frilly costumes, a few hard stares to camera by the leading lady, and a loose plot to seduce the cinema going public. So why shouldn't she think she could get away with the self-indulgent nothingness that is The Tango Lesson?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Tango Lesson - about power struggle between a man and woman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amybeam
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What happens when two dominant personalities fall in love? Who gets to lead? Who gets to follow? What if it doesn't suit either one to follow? Writer/director Sally Potter is also the lead actress in this dramatic love story about a film director (herself) making a movie about tango. Sally meets Pablo Veron, an authentic world-class Argentinean tango dancer, and convinces him to give her tango lessons. Pablo obliges her, in hopes of starring in one of her movies. Sally gets good enough to become his professional dance partner. The movie is divided into "Lessons." If you're a dancer, you should see this film if for no other reason than the numerous spectacular dance scenes. Half-way through, the viewer realizes that these "lessons" are not about dance after all, but about life. The tango is used as a metaphor for the power struggle between a man and a woman falling in love, but being stymied because each insists on being in control. Like the tango, the tempo starts out slowly and crescendos as Sally and Pablo's professional and personal relationship deepens and grows more volatile. Can a relationship like this survive? This movie was funded by the French government. It's in English with a few French subtitles; set in France and Argentina.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "How did you choose the tango? I didn't. The tango chose me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Galina
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Tango Lesson" is a unique and beautiful movie made by the director/ writer Sally Potter about a director/writer named Sally Potter who is fascinated by the art of Tango, meets a young dancer Pablo Ver&oacute;n (played by a dancer named Pablo Ver&oacute;n), and dances with him - and as everything Sally (well both of them) does, her dancing is graceful, elegant, delicate yet masterful, subtle, and passionate - just as the movie itself is. I don't care if it is the "Blatant narcissism", "Self-Indulgence or "Self Importance" - they don't make the movie for me any worse and I am fascinated by Sally Potter, the strong, talented, and independent woman. "The Tango Lesson" examines the mysterious connection between two people, their interest to each other, even if they were not meant to be together. At one point, Sally tells Pablo, "It doesn't suit me to follow. It suits me to lead, and you can't deal with that." The film is also about sensual passion of Tango where every dance is a fight between the partners over the control and victory and both victory and defeat are a celebration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you love light there's lots in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drjude518
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie for its luminous black and white portraiture of Tango, Buenos Aires and Paris. There's been a few negative comments about Sally's insistence on casting herself in the lead role. A reviewer said that she looked tired; the result of multi-tasking her role as lead and director. I say she has a face that is somewhat care-worn from living a life well which is full of emotional content. It is important to juxtapose the angelic face of Pablo Veron against her much more sage face. A younger more beautiful type would not have worked. She was so smart to think of that; or perhaps it was the fortunate result of looking at the rushes that it came to her. As an art house film it works; the locations are interesting; fragments of spaces and shapes and textures with beautiful lighting. As a study of human relationships it was so painful to watch. I so related to her reluctance to interfere with yet desire to connect with Pablo. Honestly painful. There are also the familiar cast of characters that appear in Sally's other films: Heathcote Williams and Peter Eyre to name 2 that I recognized. I loved Eyre's interaction with Sally; he watched her sadly as she watched Pablo knowing exactly what was going on in her mind. Such an interesting actor with less than 5 minutes on screen time. It is interesting that Maria (one of the Hollywood execs) is an Argentinian born actress pulling off a very good interpretation of an LA beautiful person. Comfortable like a great pair of well worn dance shoes with a patina that just gets better with time. There was just enough there to whet the appetite but like good dancers; they held enough back making you beg for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect film - for certain audiences
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris_Docker
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whether you judge The Tango Lesson to be as perfect as a film can get, or a self-indulgent autohagiography with nice legs and sets, is probably about your viewpoint. There is bound to be at least one reader who will disagree with either view. So I am inclined to look at what the director was trying to achieve. Sally Potter is an established art-house filmmaker with particular interests in gender politics and dance. She also sings, writes and, in this film at least, acts. Tango is a dance drawing heavily on passion. Unlike many dances, its emotional range includes jealousy and betrayal. When sparks fly, they are not just sparks of attraction. Male power and domination, silence that bites, and doomed love and destruction (hence the metaphor of Bertolucci's Last Tango in Paris). A woman never escapes the man's embrace. The brilliance of her steps give the appearance of being entirely due to her partner's masterful guidance. At one point in our movie, Potter's partner, enraged, tells her she must 'do nothing'  he means nothing that doesn't come from him. It is a perfect dance to build dramatic metaphor around. But Potter's interest goes further. She wants to examine role reversal (this is the director who has had a hit a few years earlier with the sexual ambiguous Orlando). In The Tango Lesson, she plays opposite a top tango dancer, mentally submitting to him in order to learn the dance. Her character is a film director, disillusioned with a Hollywood deal and looking for a new project. Could it be dance? In the second half, she enlists him to play in a film. The power position is reversed. He must follow instead of lead. He must take direction. The success of this plot relies almost entirely on its real life elements. The circumstances in which the film was made mirror those depicted in the film-within-a-film. Names of principle characters are not changed. Potter does all her own dancing. Obvious commercial sell-outs are avoided. So in terms of dancing and the gender politics, how well does the film perform? The answer has to be, "Magnificently." The tango scenes are among the best of any motion picture. Tango on the stage, tango on the streets. Tango in the dancehalls, tango on the water's edge. Tango in rain, tango in snow. Potter described some of the technical challenges, saying that in the rain there were, "a limited number of takes possible due to the limited number of dry jeans." But the result is stunning. If you wanted a tango photo to hang over your fireplace, you would be spoilt for choice with stills from this film. Perfect mise-en-scene and impressive lighting make the film visually intoxicating. And when we hear Libertango  the most familiar of all tango tunes  the energy explodes as Potter bursts from the dance studio, dancing with several men at once. Cinematography is endlessly inventive. During a stage performance, the camera is positioned so that it faces the audience, dancers silhouetted by the dazzle of spotlights. "I wanted to show something of the visceral sensation of being onstage," she says, "with the lights in your eyes." Gender analysis is equally successful. Potter deals with simple male chauvinism, and in a matter-of-fact rather than an unkind way. Pablo and his friends act in a 'perfectly reasonable' manner which Potter then exposes as unreasonable. They cherish a glamorised idea of film-making. She has to exert gentle authority when they 'decide' that they've waited long enough for someone to turn up; or when Pablo might not 'want' to shed a tear in her 'little film.' She must  and does  handle their unprofessional emotions, fears and ignorance, exactly as Pablo had to handle hers when she was learning to dance. And now it is against his every instinct. He must follow and let her lead. Potter takes us beyond gender politics to the creative process. The film opens with her wiping a white table, then she sits at it with a blank sheet of paper. She starts to script, but discards one idea after another. Fast cuts to bursts of colour (in the Hollywood movie she had originally planned to make) illustrate action sequences of a movie style that makes money. They are like fragments of a finished film, waiting to be found. She hovers, waiting for the right idea to take form. "I know this moment well. It's the most precious, delicate, terrifying moment in film-making. The void beckons, seductively. But at any moment, the pencil will touch the blank page and the first, irrevocable step will have been taken. Every such step can feel like an act of treachery against abstract and infinite perfection." That state of 'becoming,' the moment before any definite action is decided, parallels the state of preparedness a follower must have in dance. It is the philosophy that an early feminist-filmmaker, Maya Deren (also a dancer), propounded in connection with films (such as her Study in Choreography for the Camera). For her, it was an essential trait of being a woman, the ability to wait, as opposed to a man's desire for immediacy. For Potter, who had focused on dancing in her earlier life, the film becomes a voyage of discovery. "I remember suddenly what I always loved about dancing  the combination of vigorous endeavour, present timidness, and dedication to process  the sure knowledge that you never 'arrive', you are instead in a constant process of arrival. It is itself, and it is a metaphor: for learning, for living, for being." On the downside, there is not a lot of story. The Tango Lesson is Strictly Ballroom stripped of make-up, witticisms, clich&eacute;s, overacting, and the pointless, predictable, but highly entertaining storyline. The Tango Lesson proudly states that the ideas (and the dancing) should be sufficient. Sadly for some people of course, it won't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Numbers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carlos
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone has mentioned this: the problem with "The Tango Lesson" is that it has Sally Potter all around. And Sally Potter doesn't dance badly, but her character, her persona, feels thin for a main character (surely because she tamed it down a lot, "forgetting" many of her "ugly" bits, so she feels like an unfinished creation), and can't carry the movie. It's interesting when the films feels sincere (loneliness, creation, and so on), but the thing that redeems this 100 minutes are the dance pieces, the musical parts, which for once they feel like a natural and optimistic part of the story that do not break the narration but feel part of it (like in the old MGM musicals and so on), and Pablo Ver&oacute;n. She has strengths; it's a pity that she didn't realize of her weaknesses.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tango lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ecuabeatinezz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Tango Lesson was a film in which one can very much see clearly the idea of feminism. Sally is a woman who wanted to learn how to dance tango. She met a man named Pablo who taught her very much on how to dance tango. He dominated her in the sense of how she had to dance, stand, look, etc. While she learned how to dance, she was writing a play that she wanted to publish. As they both practiced on dancing they start to attach feelings for each other. A little after experiencing these feelings she questions Pablo about where exactly they stand (she seemed like she wanted more than just a friendship). He replied to her that he wanted to keep distance and not confuse the professional with the personal. After learning enough to dance in a front of a stage, Sally and Pablo perform in front of an audience. She learned enough that he felt like she was taking more control than she had to. He says that she took his liberty away and he was upset. He had to be in control of the dance and let him guide her. Not the other way around. This is the turning point of the film, she starts getting in control. Her play advances, and she chose who was in her film and she regulated what happened in her film. She is the leader now in the dances, and at the end of the film she instructed them to dance and her personality gave away as a leader. This film portrays how a woman who came from not knowing anything, to a woman who became a leader of her self. Many obstacles were in her way, such as Pablo. He had an idea of a man who had to be in control and it somewhat astonished him when he saw the changes in Sally. I recall in one scene when they are arguing he states, "Let me be in control!" Even through the norms of this society, Sally managed to be in control of her self and what she wanted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feminist Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    torigemi3
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sally Potter is one of the most respected names in feminist film. The Tango Lesson, while very different from any of her earlier works, seems to be a really personal, even autobiographical film. It's about a middle-aged British filmmaker named Sally Potter. More recent productions have abandoned prudery towards women's bodies and moved to "the other side" of visual pleasure. The film shows Sally's own personal involvement with Tango. Its original purpose of something fun, new, exciting and stress relief from her routine life soon became an obsession causing several conflicts. The relevance of feminism in the film is blatantly present. A conflict scene in the film is between characters Sally and her Tango partner, teacher and love interest Pablo Veron. The back and fourth arguments are the strongest representation of a feminist point of view in a relationship. After Sally's first Tango performance with Pablo they are involved in a confrontation. Pablo's issue with Sally is that he is the leader and she was to follow which in his eyes she was not doing during the performance. The feminist thought and idea is that men lead woman. Sally replies to this by saying "you danced like a soloist". She said that no emotions were involved in the dance sequence which is extremely important in order to create a believable and interesting performance. The fact that they were involved in a personal relationship outside of the dancing did not help the situation. Pablo's character was an alpha male who fell for a woman whose strength and power intimidated him. I noticed in the film in several scenes in his house in the bathroom, on top of the fire place, and in the dressing room, Pablo was placed in front of a mirror. His obsession with himself intrigues Sally to a near jealous streak. She is envious of his confidence. He is also in control of the language spoken between the two of them. They both speak French, Spanish and English. When they are not dancing as business partners and enter their personal relationship they speak French. Pablo unable to speak very well English prefers not to while conversing with Sally. Sally Potter was not considered what society considers beautiful. She was an older woman who dressed moderately, did not wear makeup, and did not possess a voluptuous body. "The gaze" in television and movies is a serious issue for our society. Woman are considered spectacles used as objects of visual and physical pleasure. The director's gaze is present in the film because she represents and analyzes our visual culture in how men and woman perceive each other.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Tango Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kallajimon
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a different kind of film. It is based on the writer's own experience, and the main characters actually seem to be playing themselves. It is a film about the making of a film, so is a film within a film. I was bothered at first by Sally's rather stiff, and rather awkward movements as she learned the tango. Compared with her partner's fluidity and passion, her style of dancing seemed to me to match her personality (naturally), which I experienced as typically milk and toast English (limp). Though she is obviously fascinated by the tango, her passion does not translate to her dancing. At the very end, though, she seems to be beginning to get some true fluidity of movement and a teeny bit of sensuality in her dancing, so at the end of the movie, I found myself holding out hope that she one day, with practice and discovery of passion within herself, would be able to simulate something in the realm of that displayed by Carlo, her partner. It is a very good film, I think. She seems always to be thinking, while Carlo seems always to be moving, beautifully. He is a true artist of movement, and his joy of dancing comes through fabulously. He is poetry in motion. I enjoyed the extra material, too, though in one feature it was jumbled (production notes, I think it was) and in another (still photos, I believe) one couldn't use the pause, forward or reverse buttons and it was frustrating to have to play everything over from the beginning to be able to read things one hadn't time to read the first time around. And then not absolutely everything was able to be read the third time around, either, due to the pace. Anyway. The film is lovely, even though I was constantly irritated by the cerebral as opposed to emotional aspect of Sally's character. She moved like a broomstick, actually. It was annoying, especially when her partner was so fluid and sensual. But that is in fact part of the story . . . :-).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    read my comment for my summary on this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themush01
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Men are traditionally seen as the stronger sex. Men are usually portrayed as being more powerful mentally and in strength than woman. The tango is a very famous and difficult dance that has the man being the stronger of the two sexes. Within the movie The Tango Lesson, directed and written by Sally Potter in 1997, the character Sally starts taking tango lessons by a man named Pablo. During the dance lessons Sally is taught to tango. Within her lessons she is taught to follow the man's lead. While dancing with Pablo, Sally becomes a very good dancer. Pablo asks her to join him in a dance that will take place in front of a very large audience. While they are dancing Sally makes very minor mistakes. While exiting the stage Pablo stays out longer and takes more bows, this can symbolize that he feels that he is the supeiror dancer. When they are off stage Pablo yells at Sally saying that he was "messing up" his dance because she was leading and taking up his space. He said that this prevented him from dancing. That situation shows that Sally is seen as the weaker and less important sex. Sally argues with Pablo that he cant handle the fact that she can lead and will. This shows that she realizes how Pablo is thinking and sees himself when he dances with her. The Tango Dance represents the difference of roles between males and females. Overall it was a very different kind of movie, there wasn't a lot of talking, but there was a lot of very good dancing. This is a good movie to watch if you are learning how to dance the tango or interested in watching movies that show very good dance scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now I always have an answer to that worst film ever question
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterjump
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terrible acting by Potter and a flat plot with no tension what so ever. And as for the feminist polemic, it's laughable. I saw this garbage when it was first released and though I found it tedious beyond belief I'm glad I did go to see it. That's because I now have an immediate answer to the question 'what's the worst film you've ever seen?' Plus, I have the comfort of knowing that every film I see for the rest of my life will be better than The Tango Lesson. But I have to admit I was impressed with the way Potter wrote a script that would garner the maximum number of arts council grants from around the world (as is revealed in the closing credits). I only very recently saw Orlando and I can see how Potter learnt the wrong lessons from making that film. All it took was a bunch of frilly costumes, a few hard stares to camera by the leading lady, and a loose plot to seduce the cinema going public. So why shouldn't she think she could get away with the self-indulgent nothingness that is The Tango Lesson?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Tango Lesson - about power struggle between a man and woman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amybeam
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What happens when two dominant personalities fall in love? Who gets to lead? Who gets to follow? What if it doesn't suit either one to follow? Writer/director Sally Potter is also the lead actress in this dramatic love story about a film director (herself) making a movie about tango. Sally meets Pablo Veron, an authentic world-class Argentinean tango dancer, and convinces him to give her tango lessons. Pablo obliges her, in hopes of starring in one of her movies. Sally gets good enough to become his professional dance partner. The movie is divided into "Lessons." If you're a dancer, you should see this film if for no other reason than the numerous spectacular dance scenes. Half-way through, the viewer realizes that these "lessons" are not about dance after all, but about life. The tango is used as a metaphor for the power struggle between a man and a woman falling in love, but being stymied because each insists on being in control. Like the tango, the tempo starts out slowly and crescendos as Sally and Pablo's professional and personal relationship deepens and grows more volatile. Can a relationship like this survive? This movie was funded by the French government. It's in English with a few French subtitles; set in France and Argentina.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "How did you choose the tango? I didn't. The tango chose me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Galina
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Tango Lesson" is a unique and beautiful movie made by the director/ writer Sally Potter about a director/writer named Sally Potter who is fascinated by the art of Tango, meets a young dancer Pablo Ver&oacute;n (played by a dancer named Pablo Ver&oacute;n), and dances with him - and as everything Sally (well both of them) does, her dancing is graceful, elegant, delicate yet masterful, subtle, and passionate - just as the movie itself is. I don't care if it is the "Blatant narcissism", "Self-Indulgence or "Self Importance" - they don't make the movie for me any worse and I am fascinated by Sally Potter, the strong, talented, and independent woman. "The Tango Lesson" examines the mysterious connection between two people, their interest to each other, even if they were not meant to be together. At one point, Sally tells Pablo, "It doesn't suit me to follow. It suits me to lead, and you can't deal with that." The film is also about sensual passion of Tango where every dance is a fight between the partners over the control and victory and both victory and defeat are a celebration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If you love light there's lots in this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    drjude518
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie for its luminous black and white portraiture of Tango, Buenos Aires and Paris. There's been a few negative comments about Sally's insistence on casting herself in the lead role. A reviewer said that she looked tired; the result of multi-tasking her role as lead and director. I say she has a face that is somewhat care-worn from living a life well which is full of emotional content. It is important to juxtapose the angelic face of Pablo Veron against her much more sage face. A younger more beautiful type would not have worked. She was so smart to think of that; or perhaps it was the fortunate result of looking at the rushes that it came to her. As an art house film it works; the locations are interesting; fragments of spaces and shapes and textures with beautiful lighting. As a study of human relationships it was so painful to watch. I so related to her reluctance to interfere with yet desire to connect with Pablo. Honestly painful. There are also the familiar cast of characters that appear in Sally's other films: Heathcote Williams and Peter Eyre to name 2 that I recognized. I loved Eyre's interaction with Sally; he watched her sadly as she watched Pablo knowing exactly what was going on in her mind. Such an interesting actor with less than 5 minutes on screen time. It is interesting that Maria (one of the Hollywood execs) is an Argentinian born actress pulling off a very good interpretation of an LA beautiful person. Comfortable like a great pair of well worn dance shoes with a patina that just gets better with time. There was just enough there to whet the appetite but like good dancers; they held enough back making you beg for more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A perfect film - for certain audiences
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris_Docker
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whether you judge The Tango Lesson to be as perfect as a film can get, or a self-indulgent autohagiography with nice legs and sets, is probably about your viewpoint. There is bound to be at least one reader who will disagree with either view. So I am inclined to look at what the director was trying to achieve. Sally Potter is an established art-house filmmaker with particular interests in gender politics and dance. She also sings, writes and, in this film at least, acts. Tango is a dance drawing heavily on passion. Unlike many dances, its emotional range includes jealousy and betrayal. When sparks fly, they are not just sparks of attraction. Male power and domination, silence that bites, and doomed love and destruction (hence the metaphor of Bertolucci's Last Tango in Paris). A woman never escapes the man's embrace. The brilliance of her steps give the appearance of being entirely due to her partner's masterful guidance. At one point in our movie, Potter's partner, enraged, tells her she must 'do nothing'  he means nothing that doesn't come from him. It is a perfect dance to build dramatic metaphor around. But Potter's interest goes further. She wants to examine role reversal (this is the director who has had a hit a few years earlier with the sexual ambiguous Orlando). In The Tango Lesson, she plays opposite a top tango dancer, mentally submitting to him in order to learn the dance. Her character is a film director, disillusioned with a Hollywood deal and looking for a new project. Could it be dance? In the second half, she enlists him to play in a film. The power position is reversed. He must follow instead of lead. He must take direction. The success of this plot relies almost entirely on its real life elements. The circumstances in which the film was made mirror those depicted in the film-within-a-film. Names of principle characters are not changed. Potter does all her own dancing. Obvious commercial sell-outs are avoided. So in terms of dancing and the gender politics, how well does the film perform? The answer has to be, "Magnificently." The tango scenes are among the best of any motion picture. Tango on the stage, tango on the streets. Tango in the dancehalls, tango on the water's edge. Tango in rain, tango in snow. Potter described some of the technical challenges, saying that in the rain there were, "a limited number of takes possible due to the limited number of dry jeans." But the result is stunning. If you wanted a tango photo to hang over your fireplace, you would be spoilt for choice with stills from this film. Perfect mise-en-scene and impressive lighting make the film visually intoxicating. And when we hear Libertango  the most familiar of all tango tunes  the energy explodes as Potter bursts from the dance studio, dancing with several men at once. Cinematography is endlessly inventive. During a stage performance, the camera is positioned so that it faces the audience, dancers silhouetted by the dazzle of spotlights. "I wanted to show something of the visceral sensation of being onstage," she says, "with the lights in your eyes." Gender analysis is equally successful. Potter deals with simple male chauvinism, and in a matter-of-fact rather than an unkind way. Pablo and his friends act in a 'perfectly reasonable' manner which Potter then exposes as unreasonable. They cherish a glamorised idea of film-making. She has to exert gentle authority when they 'decide' that they've waited long enough for someone to turn up; or when Pablo might not 'want' to shed a tear in her 'little film.' She must  and does  handle their unprofessional emotions, fears and ignorance, exactly as Pablo had to handle hers when she was learning to dance. And now it is against his every instinct. He must follow and let her lead. Potter takes us beyond gender politics to the creative process. The film opens with her wiping a white table, then she sits at it with a blank sheet of paper. She starts to script, but discards one idea after another. Fast cuts to bursts of colour (in the Hollywood movie she had originally planned to make) illustrate action sequences of a movie style that makes money. They are like fragments of a finished film, waiting to be found. She hovers, waiting for the right idea to take form. "I know this moment well. It's the most precious, delicate, terrifying moment in film-making. The void beckons, seductively. But at any moment, the pencil will touch the blank page and the first, irrevocable step will have been taken. Every such step can feel like an act of treachery against abstract and infinite perfection." That state of 'becoming,' the moment before any definite action is decided, parallels the state of preparedness a follower must have in dance. It is the philosophy that an early feminist-filmmaker, Maya Deren (also a dancer), propounded in connection with films (such as her Study in Choreography for the Camera). For her, it was an essential trait of being a woman, the ability to wait, as opposed to a man's desire for immediacy. For Potter, who had focused on dancing in her earlier life, the film becomes a voyage of discovery. "I remember suddenly what I always loved about dancing  the combination of vigorous endeavour, present timidness, and dedication to process  the sure knowledge that you never 'arrive', you are instead in a constant process of arrival. It is itself, and it is a metaphor: for learning, for living, for being." On the downside, there is not a lot of story. The Tango Lesson is Strictly Ballroom stripped of make-up, witticisms, clich&eacute;s, overacting, and the pointless, predictable, but highly entertaining storyline. The Tango Lesson proudly states that the ideas (and the dancing) should be sufficient. Sadly for some people of course, it won't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Musical Numbers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carlos
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everyone has mentioned this: the problem with "The Tango Lesson" is that it has Sally Potter all around. And Sally Potter doesn't dance badly, but her character, her persona, feels thin for a main character (surely because she tamed it down a lot, "forgetting" many of her "ugly" bits, so she feels like an unfinished creation), and can't carry the movie. It's interesting when the films feels sincere (loneliness, creation, and so on), but the thing that redeems this 100 minutes are the dance pieces, the musical parts, which for once they feel like a natural and optimistic part of the story that do not break the narration but feel part of it (like in the old MGM musicals and so on), and Pablo Ver&oacute;n. She has strengths; it's a pity that she didn't realize of her weaknesses.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tango lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ecuabeatinezz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Tango Lesson was a film in which one can very much see clearly the idea of feminism. Sally is a woman who wanted to learn how to dance tango. She met a man named Pablo who taught her very much on how to dance tango. He dominated her in the sense of how she had to dance, stand, look, etc. While she learned how to dance, she was writing a play that she wanted to publish. As they both practiced on dancing they start to attach feelings for each other. A little after experiencing these feelings she questions Pablo about where exactly they stand (she seemed like she wanted more than just a friendship). He replied to her that he wanted to keep distance and not confuse the professional with the personal. After learning enough to dance in a front of a stage, Sally and Pablo perform in front of an audience. She learned enough that he felt like she was taking more control than she had to. He says that she took his liberty away and he was upset. He had to be in control of the dance and let him guide her. Not the other way around. This is the turning point of the film, she starts getting in control. Her play advances, and she chose who was in her film and she regulated what happened in her film. She is the leader now in the dances, and at the end of the film she instructed them to dance and her personality gave away as a leader. This film portrays how a woman who came from not knowing anything, to a woman who became a leader of her self. Many obstacles were in her way, such as Pablo. He had an idea of a man who had to be in control and it somewhat astonished him when he saw the changes in Sally. I recall in one scene when they are arguing he states, "Let me be in control!" Even through the norms of this society, Sally managed to be in control of her self and what she wanted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feminist Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    torigemi3
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sally Potter is one of the most respected names in feminist film. The Tango Lesson, while very different from any of her earlier works, seems to be a really personal, even autobiographical film. It's about a middle-aged British filmmaker named Sally Potter. More recent productions have abandoned prudery towards women's bodies and moved to "the other side" of visual pleasure. The film shows Sally's own personal involvement with Tango. Its original purpose of something fun, new, exciting and stress relief from her routine life soon became an obsession causing several conflicts. The relevance of feminism in the film is blatantly present. A conflict scene in the film is between characters Sally and her Tango partner, teacher and love interest Pablo Veron. The back and fourth arguments are the strongest representation of a feminist point of view in a relationship. After Sally's first Tango performance with Pablo they are involved in a confrontation. Pablo's issue with Sally is that he is the leader and she was to follow which in his eyes she was not doing during the performance. The feminist thought and idea is that men lead woman. Sally replies to this by saying "you danced like a soloist". She said that no emotions were involved in the dance sequence which is extremely important in order to create a believable and interesting performance. The fact that they were involved in a personal relationship outside of the dancing did not help the situation. Pablo's character was an alpha male who fell for a woman whose strength and power intimidated him. I noticed in the film in several scenes in his house in the bathroom, on top of the fire place, and in the dressing room, Pablo was placed in front of a mirror. His obsession with himself intrigues Sally to a near jealous streak. She is envious of his confidence. He is also in control of the language spoken between the two of them. They both speak French, Spanish and English. When they are not dancing as business partners and enter their personal relationship they speak French. Pablo unable to speak very well English prefers not to while conversing with Sally. Sally Potter was not considered what society considers beautiful. She was an older woman who dressed moderately, did not wear makeup, and did not possess a voluptuous body. "The gaze" in television and movies is a serious issue for our society. Woman are considered spectacles used as objects of visual and physical pleasure. The director's gaze is present in the film because she represents and analyzes our visual culture in how men and woman perceive each other.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Tango Lesson
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kallajimon
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a different kind of film. It is based on the writer's own experience, and the main characters actually seem to be playing themselves. It is a film about the making of a film, so is a film within a film. I was bothered at first by Sally's rather stiff, and rather awkward movements as she learned the tango. Compared with her partner's fluidity and passion, her style of dancing seemed to me to match her personality (naturally), which I experienced as typically milk and toast English (limp). Though she is obviously fascinated by the tango, her passion does not translate to her dancing. At the very end, though, she seems to be beginning to get some true fluidity of movement and a teeny bit of sensuality in her dancing, so at the end of the movie, I found myself holding out hope that she one day, with practice and discovery of passion within herself, would be able to simulate something in the realm of that displayed by Carlo, her partner. It is a very good film, I think. She seems always to be thinking, while Carlo seems always to be moving, beautifully. He is a true artist of movement, and his joy of dancing comes through fabulously. He is poetry in motion. I enjoyed the extra material, too, though in one feature it was jumbled (production notes, I think it was) and in another (still photos, I believe) one couldn't use the pause, forward or reverse buttons and it was frustrating to have to play everything over from the beginning to be able to read things one hadn't time to read the first time around. And then not absolutely everything was able to be read the third time around, either, due to the pace. Anyway. The film is lovely, even though I was constantly irritated by the cerebral as opposed to emotional aspect of Sally's character. She moved like a broomstick, actually. It was annoying, especially when her partner was so fluid and sensual. But that is in fact part of the story . . . :-).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    read my comment for my summary on this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themush01
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Men are traditionally seen as the stronger sex. Men are usually portrayed as being more powerful mentally and in strength than woman. The tango is a very famous and difficult dance that has the man being the stronger of the two sexes. Within the movie The Tango Lesson, directed and written by Sally Potter in 1997, the character Sally starts taking tango lessons by a man named Pablo. During the dance lessons Sally is taught to tango. Within her lessons she is taught to follow the man's lead. While dancing with Pablo, Sally becomes a very good dancer. Pablo asks her to join him in a dance that will take place in front of a very large audience. While they are dancing Sally makes very minor mistakes. While exiting the stage Pablo stays out longer and takes more bows, this can symbolize that he feels that he is the supeiror dancer. When they are off stage Pablo yells at Sally saying that he was "messing up" his dance because she was leading and taking up his space. He said that this prevented him from dancing. That situation shows that Sally is seen as the weaker and less important sex. Sally argues with Pablo that he cant handle the fact that she can lead and will. This shows that she realizes how Pablo is thinking and sees himself when he dances with her. The Tango Dance represents the difference of roles between males and females. Overall it was a very different kind of movie, there wasn't a lot of talking, but there was a lot of very good dancing. This is a good movie to watch if you are learning how to dance the tango or interested in watching movies that show very good dance scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now I always have an answer to that worst film ever question
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peterjump
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terrible acting by Potter and a flat plot with no tension what so ever. And as for the feminist polemic, it's laughable. I saw this garbage when it was first released and though I found it tedious beyond belief I'm glad I did go to see it. That's because I now have an immediate answer to the question 'what's the worst film you've ever seen?' Plus, I have the comfort of knowing that every film I see for the rest of my life will be better than The Tango Lesson. But I have to admit I was impressed with the way Potter wrote a script that would garner the maximum number of arts council grants from around the world (as is revealed in the closing credits). I only very recently saw Orlando and I can see how Potter learnt the wrong lessons from making that film. All it took was a bunch of frilly costumes, a few hard stares to camera by the leading lady, and a loose plot to seduce the cinema going public. So why shouldn't she think she could get away with the self-indulgent nothingness that is The Tango Lesson?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Tango Lesson - about power struggle between a man and woman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amybeam
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What happens when two dominant personalities fall in love? Who gets to lead? Who gets to follow? What if it doesn't suit either one to follow? Writer/director Sally Potter is also the lead actress in this dramatic love story about a film director (herself) making a movie about tango. Sally meets Pablo Veron, an authentic world-class Argentinean tango dancer, and convinces him to give her tango lessons. Pablo obliges her, in hopes of starring in one of her movies. Sally gets good enough to become his professional dance partner. The movie is divided into "Lessons." If you're a dancer, you should see this film if for no other reason than the numerous spectacular dance scenes. Half-way through, the viewer realizes that these "lessons" are not about dance after all, but about life. The tango is used as a metaphor for the power struggle between a man and a woman falling in love, but being stymied because each insists on being in control. Like the tango, the tempo starts out slowly and crescendos as Sally and Pablo's professional and personal relationship deepens and grows more volatile. Can a relationship like this survive? This movie was funded by the French government. It's in English with a few French subtitles; set in France and Argentina.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "How did you choose the tango? I didn't. The tango chose me."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Galina
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Tango Lesson" is a unique and beautiful movie made by the director/ writer Sally Potter about a director/writer named Sally Potter who is fascinated by the art of Tango, meets a young dancer Pablo Ver&oacute;n (played by a dancer named Pablo Ver&oacute;n), and dances with him - and as everything Sally (well both of them) does, her dancing is graceful, elegant, delicate yet masterful, subtle, and passionate - just as the movie itself is. I don't care if it is the "Blatant narcissism", "Self-Indulgence or "Self Importance" - they don't make the movie for me any worse and I am fascinated by Sally Potter, the strong, talented, and independent woman. "The Tango Lesson" examines the mysterious connection between two people, their interest to each other, even if they were not meant to be together. At one point, Sally tells Pablo, "It doesn't suit me to follow. It suits me to lead, and you can't deal with that." The film is also about sensual passion of Tango where every dance is a fight between the partners over the control and victory and both victory and defeat are a celebration.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
