<filme>
 <id>
  892
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119137
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Flubber - Uma Inven&ccedil;&atilde;o Desmiolada
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An absent-minded professor discovers "flubber," a rubber-like super-bouncy substance.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Professor Phillip Brainard, an absent-minded professor, works with his assistant Weebo, trying to create a substance that's a new source of energy and that will save Medfield College where his sweetheart Sara is the president. He has missed his wedding twice, and on the afternoon of his third wedding, Professor Brainard creates flubber, which allows objects to fly through the air. It looks like rubber, so he calls it flubber. This film is based on the 1961 Disney classic, "The Absent-Minded Professor.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   professor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   college
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wedding
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   medfield college
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   flying rubber
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Les Mayfield
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Samuel W. Taylor
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   John Hughes
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Robin Williams
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Marcia Gay Harden
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Christopher McDonald
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ironically, it has no bounce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nineties variant John Hughes combines his two favourite kinds of movies - variations on the 'Home Alone' formula and remakes - to produce this rehash of 1961's 'The Absent Minded Professor' in which Robin Williams is engaging as a scientist who creates a green goo that makes his car fly and a college basketball team bounce across the court. I didn't expect this to be much good but the amount of mind-numbing tedium on display came as a bit of a surprise. The story rambles around with no real internal logic, there's too much lame slapstick, Les Mayfield directs with no flair and the movie is devoid of charm. The original was no classic but it sure beats this version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ONLY for Robin Williams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisafordeay
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this as a kid and I found it really funny.The story is about a professor who creates a rubber like substance called Flubber. But problems arise as he ends up getting late for his wedding and causes trouble with his relationship with her.Meanwhile the professor's assistant(who happens to be a robot voiced by Jodi Benson),starts to have feelings for him and in one scene she creates a hologram of a woman just to get close to him. Overall it was a really long time ago since I last seen it but it was a funny movie. Not the best of Williams career but hey if you are a fan of Robin Williams then check it out
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I want a Flubber...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    YungRapunxel212
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wish Flubber was real, because if it was, I would be playing with it right now. We watched this in Science class once because it has to do with atoms and stuff, and we were learning about that. I think we were learning about atoms. OK back to the movie. It was just a bit boring. No, it was a lot boring. Only like 5 scenes were interesting. Robin Williams acting as the professor was a bad choice, because he is like 20 years older than the woman he likes and gets married too. Well he looked like it anyways. I would love to have a house like the professor, though. It was so cool and he really did not have to do anything, just have Weebo or his master inventions do it for him. This is a very kid friendly movie. Nothing frightening or sexual, just kissing. No drugs, maybe a character smoking. Very mild profanity and some violence. 8-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A "flubbing" good film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't see what was so bad about "FLUBBER". It was rated as a 4.8 on 10, and on Internet rated as medium. I liked it myself. I thought it was a wonderful film although not best (because of the missing scenario at some parts of the film.)A wonderful performance by Robin Williams for whom I will add an Oscar for "BEST ENTERTAINING ACTOR". He seems to be one of the best comedians ever in film history as seen in his role. The special effects are just a little "bounce" of pleasure that make the film even more original. I don't really know if I'll recommend it strongly since the rating on this film was negative. Some of the scenes are perfect and originally made. It is a nice story. I really "flubbed" it. A nice try!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really all that great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmm, I was told that this movie is cute, and cute it is, but it is not the best that I have seen. I must admit that Robin Williams is a funny guy, but this is not one of his funniest movies. The best scene in the movie was when he walks into a life drawing class thinking that it is his physics class and goes ahead and teaches. Other than that this movie is rather ordinary with lots of clich&eacute;s to fill it up. I enjoyed it, a bit, but I have seen better. Basically, a college is about to be shut down and Robin Williams is an absent minded professor who has missed his wedding three times. It is interesting that he has a robot that is in love with him and is forcing him not to marry the woman who he loves. This is all very cute but I thought that it was a little silly. The professor is very smart but, as is introduced rather quickly, somebody else always steals his ideas and gets the fame for it. The guy is basically the bad guy who is milking the professor for all he is worth. Then there is the corporate boss who thinks that solving problems is done by throwing money at it. He wants his kid to get straight A's so he throws money at it. When we look at the movie we see once again the theme of the American Dream. Everybody can become happy and rich if they simply work at it. All problems can be over come by ones own ability and that the end is always happy. This is a very shallow and idealistic theme which generally annoys me. Even though, Flubber is a kids movie though it has a few interesting scenes thrown in to keep the adults interested, because it is the adults that must take their kids to see the movie. Flubber is a Walt Disney movie, and I generally don't like Disney for some unknown reason, I guess because it is reaching into the minds of children and manipulating them into clones of themselves. All of us who grew up on Disney has been forced into a Disney mindset. I am far more critical of children's movies, and those who specialise in them, because our children follow them more than adults. Adults watch movies, children believe movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review of Flubber
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jared Reabow
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie , i would say is an 8/10 it is both great for the family of all ages, and great for the lone watcher. I would have to say that anyone who hates this movie, has a dislike for a character or director as there is very little to criticize it for otherwise, it has a highish budget, which means it has potential and it delivers, so ignore haters and give it a go! The general plot is a clumsy Professor created a new life form made of flubber with strange properties, I cant really say more as it would ruin the plot. However i can say that children will love the film, adults will like the film and elderly will find it amusing, which in my books is good enough reason to buy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moronic script aimed at a 5 year old child's mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poj-man
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    O Flubber, Flubber! Wherefore art the flying rubber? Deny the original and refuse it's name And if Robin Williams could have a stupider script It is Not The Absent Minded Professor Should you know more, or should we speak of this? Tis more than thy script that is thine enemy. Robin Williams is Robin Williams and not Fred McMurray. What's Fred McMurray? He is comedic timing. His thespian ability is not buffoonish ham-handed over emoting Belonging to a paycheck. What's in a name? That we call Flubber. Blown out of a humans rectum it is not so sweet. ============================ Only a child could be entertained by this stock character story thrown around FX. Robin Williams plays a moronically brilliant professor who works in his house and forgets his wedding day...and no one can find this "known to be absent minded moronically brilliant" professor. The bride left at the altar is left to fall into the clutches of the stock evil guy becauseno one bothered to check with the Groom at all the day of his wedding. No once called the house or drove by. The Professor is such a nerd no one said "Bachelor party!" Ladies! Isn't this the man of your dreams especially if you are an ovulating female wanting to start a family? This is the stupidity passed off as a script. The video games targeted at children have more depth of character than this dreck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Williams' best role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pilsung89
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Flubber came out during the mid/late nineties. This is the time where I believe Disney began losing its magic in the movie industry. Disney movies before always had the magical feeling and good stories. Flubber does not not have either. The main good thing it has is the acting. The acting is fairly good. This is not Robin Williams' best work, but he does a good enough job. The story revolves around a naive and eccentric inventor and college professor portrayed by Robin Williams. he creates a "living" specimen of goo that can shape-shift at will and is incredibly bouncy, but his dedication to it's creation causes him to forget his wedding. He ends up using the 'Flubber' to get his fianc&eacute; back and save his college from threats of closing down. I have no idea how the movie tries to make it work. I didn't really understand as a kid and I don't get it as an adult. The plot is weird, the directing isn't very good, and many of the characters are wooden. Overall, this Disney flick can be skipped. You won't be missing much
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Technically impressive and enjoyable, but somewhat forgettable too
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie had a lot of potential. While technically impressive and very enjoyable with some genuinely funny moments, for some reason it falls short. Of course there are redeeming qualities, such as the fun music score by Danny Elfman, one of my all time favourite film composers and an amusing turn from Robin Williams. Also the special effects are greatly improved from the effects in the Absent Minded Professor, and Flubber who is so cute steals the show. The performances from Clancy Brown, Ted Levine and Marcia Gay Horden are entertaining, and Jodi Benson (who voiced Ariel in the Little Mermaid)is a delight as the voice of Weebo, whose death is absolutely heart-rending. However the story is very predictable, and offers few surprises, and the physical comedy was better than the patchy script which in places felt uninspired. That saying some of the physical comedy has strong hints of deja vu, and is rather hit and miss. Of course kids will lap it up, but adults probably won't like it as much. The second half of the movie is more meandering in quality compared to the first half, very little of interest happens and some of the situations come across as ridiculous. All in all, somewhat forgettable, but for a kids movie it is pretty entertaining. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Good as "The Absent Minded Professor" But Pretty Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tastes and times have changed drastically since 1961 when Fred MacMurray originally introduced the super-elastic stuff called 'flubber' to film audiences in Walt Disney's "The Absent Minded Professor." In the high-tech, 1990's Disney remake "Flubber" reinvents itself as an animated, gooey-green, silly putty blob of flying rubber that talks and dances. Actually, flubber resembles a combination of the Pillsbury Doughboy crossed with the shape-shifting water creature in James Cameron's 1989 fantasy thriller "The Abyss." Inventive, excessive, but tolerably entertaining, director Les Mayfield's remake of "The Absent Minded Professor" will captivate both young and absent-minded audiences. Happily, "Flubber" succeeds as a resilient special effects laden tour-de-farce. Sadly, the remake lacks the wit, warmth, subtlety, and comedic irony that distinguished its black & white predecessor. The spectacular morphing effects of George Lucas' Industrial Light & Magic Company and the visual wizardry of Peter Crosman, Tom Bertino, and Douglas Hans Smith cannot offset the film's hopelessly befuddled plot. The story by John Hughes and the late Bill Walsh follows the zany efforts of a scatterbrained university chemistry professor. Dr. Philip Brainard (Robin Williams of "Popeye") accidentally cooks up a gravity defying concoction called 'flubber.' Generating its own perpetual motion, 'flubber' has uses limited only by the imagination. Unlike the limp lump of 'flubber' in "The Absent-Minded Professor," the 'flubber' "Flubber" radiates a mischievous personality, but the filmmakers never solidify its amorphous character. Not only will Brainard 'flubber' rescue Medfield College from bankruptcy and closure, but 'flubber' will also redeem him in the eyes of the long-suffering sweetheart that he wants to wed: Medfield College President Sara Jean Reynolds (Marcia Gay Harden.) Brainard heads up Sara Jean's you-know-what list. Three times in a row he has left her stranded at the altar! If things aren't bad enough, Brainard's old academic nemesis Wilson Croft (Christopher MacDonald of "Thelma & Louise") lurks in the background. Oil and conniving, Croft plans to pilfer Brainard's fianc&eacute;e as well as take credit for his 'flubber' formula and the millions of dollars that it is sure to reap. The professor's next bigger enemy is perhaps his worst: corrupt businessman Chester Hoenicker (Raymond J. Barry of "Mad City"). Hoenicker's bratty son Bennett (Will Wheaton of TV's "Star Trek: The Next Generation") flunked Brainard's class. Consequently, Bennett got suspended from the basketball team. Initially, all that Hoenicker sought was a simple change of grade so Bennett, the top hoopster on the Medfield basketball team, could resume playing. When Hoenicker senior learns more about 'flubber,' he joins forces with the equally avaricious Croft to rip-off Braniard's discovery. Women have come a long way since the 1961 original. Disney has promoted the fianc&eacute;e from being the college president's secretary to the college president! Although Sara Jean presides over Medfield, she cannot keep it out of the red without the help of a good man. "Flubber" implies that women indeed have come a long way, but not far enough to get by on their own wits. Moreover, Sara Jean's romance with Brainard appears to occupy her every waking minute instead of the financial crisis that threatens her small, private college. Her priorities appear demeaningly misplaced. WEEBO, Brainard's flying female computer, serves as a sort of bad girl here who gets her just comeuppance for tampering with Brainard's social life. At one point, WEEBO creates a cyber-Siren image for herself to detract Brainard from Sara Jean. "Flubber" sounds like a can't-miss-hit from this description. If anything, "Flubber" proves that absent-minded audiences appreciate movies with an absence of drama. The original movie contained a richer plot with a variety of nuances that heightened its hilarity. "Flubber" smears on obvious slapstick to churn up laughs. John Hughes' script relies on his tried and true "Home Alone" routines. Hughes deserves the blame for this half-baked farce. For example, Hoenicker's henchman, Smith (Clancy Brown of "Starship Troopers") and Wesson (Ted Levine of "Silence of the Lambs") are clearly stand-ins for the Joe Pesci & Daniel Stern duo from the "Home Alone" comedies. Brainard's flubber clobbers them literally in the form of a golf ball and a bowling ball. Smith gets nailed by a non-stop golf ball, while a hard flying bowling ball wallops Wesson. When either object strikes them, these goons hit the deck like pole-axed ten pins. Director Les Mayfield of "Encino Man" and "Miracle on 34th Street") and scenarist John Hughes cannot make up their own minds about flubber. Flubber has endless possibilities, and its embryonic personality can be playful but occasionally snappish, too. WEEBO accuses Brainard of giving flubber "too much free will." Flubber never seems to live up to its potential unless it is exploding, flying through rooms, and cronking noggins. Most of the humor comes from how flubber reacts to different situations more than how Brainard applies it. Because they never define the nature of flubber, its wide open character lacks dramatic clarity. For example, the filmmakers don't set any limits to what flubber can do. Perhaps Mayfield and company chose green as flubber's lime-green color because the special effects were so expensive. Credit goes to director Les Mayfield for the get-up-and-goo pace of dizzy Disney film. He does a find job of seamlessly integrating the over-the-top special effects with live action, too. "Flubber" is aimless but predictable fun. The villains seem less villainous this time around, and Christopher MacDonald's bad guy appears simply to give flubber something through which to fly. The bowel humor here and there adds little to the humor and seems out of place in a juvenile movie. Parents may find themselves in a curious moral dilemma trying to explain to their kids why Brainard's cheating tactics should be condoned. He applies flubber to the basketball team's sneakers to help them beat their tall, merciless opponents on the court. Danny Elfman's lively music emphasizes the fast, bouncy pace of "Flubber" and helps the film scoot right along to its inevitable happy ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ironically, it has no bounce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nineties variant John Hughes combines his two favourite kinds of movies - variations on the 'Home Alone' formula and remakes - to produce this rehash of 1961's 'The Absent Minded Professor' in which Robin Williams is engaging as a scientist who creates a green goo that makes his car fly and a college basketball team bounce across the court. I didn't expect this to be much good but the amount of mind-numbing tedium on display came as a bit of a surprise. The story rambles around with no real internal logic, there's too much lame slapstick, Les Mayfield directs with no flair and the movie is devoid of charm. The original was no classic but it sure beats this version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ONLY for Robin Williams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisafordeay
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this as a kid and I found it really funny.The story is about a professor who creates a rubber like substance called Flubber. But problems arise as he ends up getting late for his wedding and causes trouble with his relationship with her.Meanwhile the professor's assistant(who happens to be a robot voiced by Jodi Benson),starts to have feelings for him and in one scene she creates a hologram of a woman just to get close to him. Overall it was a really long time ago since I last seen it but it was a funny movie. Not the best of Williams career but hey if you are a fan of Robin Williams then check it out
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I want a Flubber...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    YungRapunxel212
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wish Flubber was real, because if it was, I would be playing with it right now. We watched this in Science class once because it has to do with atoms and stuff, and we were learning about that. I think we were learning about atoms. OK back to the movie. It was just a bit boring. No, it was a lot boring. Only like 5 scenes were interesting. Robin Williams acting as the professor was a bad choice, because he is like 20 years older than the woman he likes and gets married too. Well he looked like it anyways. I would love to have a house like the professor, though. It was so cool and he really did not have to do anything, just have Weebo or his master inventions do it for him. This is a very kid friendly movie. Nothing frightening or sexual, just kissing. No drugs, maybe a character smoking. Very mild profanity and some violence. 8-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A "flubbing" good film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't see what was so bad about "FLUBBER". It was rated as a 4.8 on 10, and on Internet rated as medium. I liked it myself. I thought it was a wonderful film although not best (because of the missing scenario at some parts of the film.)A wonderful performance by Robin Williams for whom I will add an Oscar for "BEST ENTERTAINING ACTOR". He seems to be one of the best comedians ever in film history as seen in his role. The special effects are just a little "bounce" of pleasure that make the film even more original. I don't really know if I'll recommend it strongly since the rating on this film was negative. Some of the scenes are perfect and originally made. It is a nice story. I really "flubbed" it. A nice try!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really all that great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmm, I was told that this movie is cute, and cute it is, but it is not the best that I have seen. I must admit that Robin Williams is a funny guy, but this is not one of his funniest movies. The best scene in the movie was when he walks into a life drawing class thinking that it is his physics class and goes ahead and teaches. Other than that this movie is rather ordinary with lots of clich&eacute;s to fill it up. I enjoyed it, a bit, but I have seen better. Basically, a college is about to be shut down and Robin Williams is an absent minded professor who has missed his wedding three times. It is interesting that he has a robot that is in love with him and is forcing him not to marry the woman who he loves. This is all very cute but I thought that it was a little silly. The professor is very smart but, as is introduced rather quickly, somebody else always steals his ideas and gets the fame for it. The guy is basically the bad guy who is milking the professor for all he is worth. Then there is the corporate boss who thinks that solving problems is done by throwing money at it. He wants his kid to get straight A's so he throws money at it. When we look at the movie we see once again the theme of the American Dream. Everybody can become happy and rich if they simply work at it. All problems can be over come by ones own ability and that the end is always happy. This is a very shallow and idealistic theme which generally annoys me. Even though, Flubber is a kids movie though it has a few interesting scenes thrown in to keep the adults interested, because it is the adults that must take their kids to see the movie. Flubber is a Walt Disney movie, and I generally don't like Disney for some unknown reason, I guess because it is reaching into the minds of children and manipulating them into clones of themselves. All of us who grew up on Disney has been forced into a Disney mindset. I am far more critical of children's movies, and those who specialise in them, because our children follow them more than adults. Adults watch movies, children believe movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review of Flubber
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jared Reabow
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie , i would say is an 8/10 it is both great for the family of all ages, and great for the lone watcher. I would have to say that anyone who hates this movie, has a dislike for a character or director as there is very little to criticize it for otherwise, it has a highish budget, which means it has potential and it delivers, so ignore haters and give it a go! The general plot is a clumsy Professor created a new life form made of flubber with strange properties, I cant really say more as it would ruin the plot. However i can say that children will love the film, adults will like the film and elderly will find it amusing, which in my books is good enough reason to buy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moronic script aimed at a 5 year old child's mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poj-man
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    O Flubber, Flubber! Wherefore art the flying rubber? Deny the original and refuse it's name And if Robin Williams could have a stupider script It is Not The Absent Minded Professor Should you know more, or should we speak of this? Tis more than thy script that is thine enemy. Robin Williams is Robin Williams and not Fred McMurray. What's Fred McMurray? He is comedic timing. His thespian ability is not buffoonish ham-handed over emoting Belonging to a paycheck. What's in a name? That we call Flubber. Blown out of a humans rectum it is not so sweet. ============================ Only a child could be entertained by this stock character story thrown around FX. Robin Williams plays a moronically brilliant professor who works in his house and forgets his wedding day...and no one can find this "known to be absent minded moronically brilliant" professor. The bride left at the altar is left to fall into the clutches of the stock evil guy becauseno one bothered to check with the Groom at all the day of his wedding. No once called the house or drove by. The Professor is such a nerd no one said "Bachelor party!" Ladies! Isn't this the man of your dreams especially if you are an ovulating female wanting to start a family? This is the stupidity passed off as a script. The video games targeted at children have more depth of character than this dreck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Williams' best role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pilsung89
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Flubber came out during the mid/late nineties. This is the time where I believe Disney began losing its magic in the movie industry. Disney movies before always had the magical feeling and good stories. Flubber does not not have either. The main good thing it has is the acting. The acting is fairly good. This is not Robin Williams' best work, but he does a good enough job. The story revolves around a naive and eccentric inventor and college professor portrayed by Robin Williams. he creates a "living" specimen of goo that can shape-shift at will and is incredibly bouncy, but his dedication to it's creation causes him to forget his wedding. He ends up using the 'Flubber' to get his fianc&eacute; back and save his college from threats of closing down. I have no idea how the movie tries to make it work. I didn't really understand as a kid and I don't get it as an adult. The plot is weird, the directing isn't very good, and many of the characters are wooden. Overall, this Disney flick can be skipped. You won't be missing much
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Technically impressive and enjoyable, but somewhat forgettable too
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie had a lot of potential. While technically impressive and very enjoyable with some genuinely funny moments, for some reason it falls short. Of course there are redeeming qualities, such as the fun music score by Danny Elfman, one of my all time favourite film composers and an amusing turn from Robin Williams. Also the special effects are greatly improved from the effects in the Absent Minded Professor, and Flubber who is so cute steals the show. The performances from Clancy Brown, Ted Levine and Marcia Gay Horden are entertaining, and Jodi Benson (who voiced Ariel in the Little Mermaid)is a delight as the voice of Weebo, whose death is absolutely heart-rending. However the story is very predictable, and offers few surprises, and the physical comedy was better than the patchy script which in places felt uninspired. That saying some of the physical comedy has strong hints of deja vu, and is rather hit and miss. Of course kids will lap it up, but adults probably won't like it as much. The second half of the movie is more meandering in quality compared to the first half, very little of interest happens and some of the situations come across as ridiculous. All in all, somewhat forgettable, but for a kids movie it is pretty entertaining. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Good as "The Absent Minded Professor" But Pretty Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tastes and times have changed drastically since 1961 when Fred MacMurray originally introduced the super-elastic stuff called 'flubber' to film audiences in Walt Disney's "The Absent Minded Professor." In the high-tech, 1990's Disney remake "Flubber" reinvents itself as an animated, gooey-green, silly putty blob of flying rubber that talks and dances. Actually, flubber resembles a combination of the Pillsbury Doughboy crossed with the shape-shifting water creature in James Cameron's 1989 fantasy thriller "The Abyss." Inventive, excessive, but tolerably entertaining, director Les Mayfield's remake of "The Absent Minded Professor" will captivate both young and absent-minded audiences. Happily, "Flubber" succeeds as a resilient special effects laden tour-de-farce. Sadly, the remake lacks the wit, warmth, subtlety, and comedic irony that distinguished its black & white predecessor. The spectacular morphing effects of George Lucas' Industrial Light & Magic Company and the visual wizardry of Peter Crosman, Tom Bertino, and Douglas Hans Smith cannot offset the film's hopelessly befuddled plot. The story by John Hughes and the late Bill Walsh follows the zany efforts of a scatterbrained university chemistry professor. Dr. Philip Brainard (Robin Williams of "Popeye") accidentally cooks up a gravity defying concoction called 'flubber.' Generating its own perpetual motion, 'flubber' has uses limited only by the imagination. Unlike the limp lump of 'flubber' in "The Absent-Minded Professor," the 'flubber' "Flubber" radiates a mischievous personality, but the filmmakers never solidify its amorphous character. Not only will Brainard 'flubber' rescue Medfield College from bankruptcy and closure, but 'flubber' will also redeem him in the eyes of the long-suffering sweetheart that he wants to wed: Medfield College President Sara Jean Reynolds (Marcia Gay Harden.) Brainard heads up Sara Jean's you-know-what list. Three times in a row he has left her stranded at the altar! If things aren't bad enough, Brainard's old academic nemesis Wilson Croft (Christopher MacDonald of "Thelma & Louise") lurks in the background. Oil and conniving, Croft plans to pilfer Brainard's fianc&eacute;e as well as take credit for his 'flubber' formula and the millions of dollars that it is sure to reap. The professor's next bigger enemy is perhaps his worst: corrupt businessman Chester Hoenicker (Raymond J. Barry of "Mad City"). Hoenicker's bratty son Bennett (Will Wheaton of TV's "Star Trek: The Next Generation") flunked Brainard's class. Consequently, Bennett got suspended from the basketball team. Initially, all that Hoenicker sought was a simple change of grade so Bennett, the top hoopster on the Medfield basketball team, could resume playing. When Hoenicker senior learns more about 'flubber,' he joins forces with the equally avaricious Croft to rip-off Braniard's discovery. Women have come a long way since the 1961 original. Disney has promoted the fianc&eacute;e from being the college president's secretary to the college president! Although Sara Jean presides over Medfield, she cannot keep it out of the red without the help of a good man. "Flubber" implies that women indeed have come a long way, but not far enough to get by on their own wits. Moreover, Sara Jean's romance with Brainard appears to occupy her every waking minute instead of the financial crisis that threatens her small, private college. Her priorities appear demeaningly misplaced. WEEBO, Brainard's flying female computer, serves as a sort of bad girl here who gets her just comeuppance for tampering with Brainard's social life. At one point, WEEBO creates a cyber-Siren image for herself to detract Brainard from Sara Jean. "Flubber" sounds like a can't-miss-hit from this description. If anything, "Flubber" proves that absent-minded audiences appreciate movies with an absence of drama. The original movie contained a richer plot with a variety of nuances that heightened its hilarity. "Flubber" smears on obvious slapstick to churn up laughs. John Hughes' script relies on his tried and true "Home Alone" routines. Hughes deserves the blame for this half-baked farce. For example, Hoenicker's henchman, Smith (Clancy Brown of "Starship Troopers") and Wesson (Ted Levine of "Silence of the Lambs") are clearly stand-ins for the Joe Pesci & Daniel Stern duo from the "Home Alone" comedies. Brainard's flubber clobbers them literally in the form of a golf ball and a bowling ball. Smith gets nailed by a non-stop golf ball, while a hard flying bowling ball wallops Wesson. When either object strikes them, these goons hit the deck like pole-axed ten pins. Director Les Mayfield of "Encino Man" and "Miracle on 34th Street") and scenarist John Hughes cannot make up their own minds about flubber. Flubber has endless possibilities, and its embryonic personality can be playful but occasionally snappish, too. WEEBO accuses Brainard of giving flubber "too much free will." Flubber never seems to live up to its potential unless it is exploding, flying through rooms, and cronking noggins. Most of the humor comes from how flubber reacts to different situations more than how Brainard applies it. Because they never define the nature of flubber, its wide open character lacks dramatic clarity. For example, the filmmakers don't set any limits to what flubber can do. Perhaps Mayfield and company chose green as flubber's lime-green color because the special effects were so expensive. Credit goes to director Les Mayfield for the get-up-and-goo pace of dizzy Disney film. He does a find job of seamlessly integrating the over-the-top special effects with live action, too. "Flubber" is aimless but predictable fun. The villains seem less villainous this time around, and Christopher MacDonald's bad guy appears simply to give flubber something through which to fly. The bowel humor here and there adds little to the humor and seems out of place in a juvenile movie. Parents may find themselves in a curious moral dilemma trying to explain to their kids why Brainard's cheating tactics should be condoned. He applies flubber to the basketball team's sneakers to help them beat their tall, merciless opponents on the court. Danny Elfman's lively music emphasizes the fast, bouncy pace of "Flubber" and helps the film scoot right along to its inevitable happy ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ironically, it has no bounce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nineties variant John Hughes combines his two favourite kinds of movies - variations on the 'Home Alone' formula and remakes - to produce this rehash of 1961's 'The Absent Minded Professor' in which Robin Williams is engaging as a scientist who creates a green goo that makes his car fly and a college basketball team bounce across the court. I didn't expect this to be much good but the amount of mind-numbing tedium on display came as a bit of a surprise. The story rambles around with no real internal logic, there's too much lame slapstick, Les Mayfield directs with no flair and the movie is devoid of charm. The original was no classic but it sure beats this version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ONLY for Robin Williams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisafordeay
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this as a kid and I found it really funny.The story is about a professor who creates a rubber like substance called Flubber. But problems arise as he ends up getting late for his wedding and causes trouble with his relationship with her.Meanwhile the professor's assistant(who happens to be a robot voiced by Jodi Benson),starts to have feelings for him and in one scene she creates a hologram of a woman just to get close to him. Overall it was a really long time ago since I last seen it but it was a funny movie. Not the best of Williams career but hey if you are a fan of Robin Williams then check it out
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I want a Flubber...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    YungRapunxel212
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wish Flubber was real, because if it was, I would be playing with it right now. We watched this in Science class once because it has to do with atoms and stuff, and we were learning about that. I think we were learning about atoms. OK back to the movie. It was just a bit boring. No, it was a lot boring. Only like 5 scenes were interesting. Robin Williams acting as the professor was a bad choice, because he is like 20 years older than the woman he likes and gets married too. Well he looked like it anyways. I would love to have a house like the professor, though. It was so cool and he really did not have to do anything, just have Weebo or his master inventions do it for him. This is a very kid friendly movie. Nothing frightening or sexual, just kissing. No drugs, maybe a character smoking. Very mild profanity and some violence. 8-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A "flubbing" good film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't see what was so bad about "FLUBBER". It was rated as a 4.8 on 10, and on Internet rated as medium. I liked it myself. I thought it was a wonderful film although not best (because of the missing scenario at some parts of the film.)A wonderful performance by Robin Williams for whom I will add an Oscar for "BEST ENTERTAINING ACTOR". He seems to be one of the best comedians ever in film history as seen in his role. The special effects are just a little "bounce" of pleasure that make the film even more original. I don't really know if I'll recommend it strongly since the rating on this film was negative. Some of the scenes are perfect and originally made. It is a nice story. I really "flubbed" it. A nice try!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really all that great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmm, I was told that this movie is cute, and cute it is, but it is not the best that I have seen. I must admit that Robin Williams is a funny guy, but this is not one of his funniest movies. The best scene in the movie was when he walks into a life drawing class thinking that it is his physics class and goes ahead and teaches. Other than that this movie is rather ordinary with lots of clich&eacute;s to fill it up. I enjoyed it, a bit, but I have seen better. Basically, a college is about to be shut down and Robin Williams is an absent minded professor who has missed his wedding three times. It is interesting that he has a robot that is in love with him and is forcing him not to marry the woman who he loves. This is all very cute but I thought that it was a little silly. The professor is very smart but, as is introduced rather quickly, somebody else always steals his ideas and gets the fame for it. The guy is basically the bad guy who is milking the professor for all he is worth. Then there is the corporate boss who thinks that solving problems is done by throwing money at it. He wants his kid to get straight A's so he throws money at it. When we look at the movie we see once again the theme of the American Dream. Everybody can become happy and rich if they simply work at it. All problems can be over come by ones own ability and that the end is always happy. This is a very shallow and idealistic theme which generally annoys me. Even though, Flubber is a kids movie though it has a few interesting scenes thrown in to keep the adults interested, because it is the adults that must take their kids to see the movie. Flubber is a Walt Disney movie, and I generally don't like Disney for some unknown reason, I guess because it is reaching into the minds of children and manipulating them into clones of themselves. All of us who grew up on Disney has been forced into a Disney mindset. I am far more critical of children's movies, and those who specialise in them, because our children follow them more than adults. Adults watch movies, children believe movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review of Flubber
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jared Reabow
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie , i would say is an 8/10 it is both great for the family of all ages, and great for the lone watcher. I would have to say that anyone who hates this movie, has a dislike for a character or director as there is very little to criticize it for otherwise, it has a highish budget, which means it has potential and it delivers, so ignore haters and give it a go! The general plot is a clumsy Professor created a new life form made of flubber with strange properties, I cant really say more as it would ruin the plot. However i can say that children will love the film, adults will like the film and elderly will find it amusing, which in my books is good enough reason to buy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moronic script aimed at a 5 year old child's mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poj-man
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    O Flubber, Flubber! Wherefore art the flying rubber? Deny the original and refuse it's name And if Robin Williams could have a stupider script It is Not The Absent Minded Professor Should you know more, or should we speak of this? Tis more than thy script that is thine enemy. Robin Williams is Robin Williams and not Fred McMurray. What's Fred McMurray? He is comedic timing. His thespian ability is not buffoonish ham-handed over emoting Belonging to a paycheck. What's in a name? That we call Flubber. Blown out of a humans rectum it is not so sweet. ============================ Only a child could be entertained by this stock character story thrown around FX. Robin Williams plays a moronically brilliant professor who works in his house and forgets his wedding day...and no one can find this "known to be absent minded moronically brilliant" professor. The bride left at the altar is left to fall into the clutches of the stock evil guy becauseno one bothered to check with the Groom at all the day of his wedding. No once called the house or drove by. The Professor is such a nerd no one said "Bachelor party!" Ladies! Isn't this the man of your dreams especially if you are an ovulating female wanting to start a family? This is the stupidity passed off as a script. The video games targeted at children have more depth of character than this dreck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Williams' best role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pilsung89
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Flubber came out during the mid/late nineties. This is the time where I believe Disney began losing its magic in the movie industry. Disney movies before always had the magical feeling and good stories. Flubber does not not have either. The main good thing it has is the acting. The acting is fairly good. This is not Robin Williams' best work, but he does a good enough job. The story revolves around a naive and eccentric inventor and college professor portrayed by Robin Williams. he creates a "living" specimen of goo that can shape-shift at will and is incredibly bouncy, but his dedication to it's creation causes him to forget his wedding. He ends up using the 'Flubber' to get his fianc&eacute; back and save his college from threats of closing down. I have no idea how the movie tries to make it work. I didn't really understand as a kid and I don't get it as an adult. The plot is weird, the directing isn't very good, and many of the characters are wooden. Overall, this Disney flick can be skipped. You won't be missing much
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Technically impressive and enjoyable, but somewhat forgettable too
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie had a lot of potential. While technically impressive and very enjoyable with some genuinely funny moments, for some reason it falls short. Of course there are redeeming qualities, such as the fun music score by Danny Elfman, one of my all time favourite film composers and an amusing turn from Robin Williams. Also the special effects are greatly improved from the effects in the Absent Minded Professor, and Flubber who is so cute steals the show. The performances from Clancy Brown, Ted Levine and Marcia Gay Horden are entertaining, and Jodi Benson (who voiced Ariel in the Little Mermaid)is a delight as the voice of Weebo, whose death is absolutely heart-rending. However the story is very predictable, and offers few surprises, and the physical comedy was better than the patchy script which in places felt uninspired. That saying some of the physical comedy has strong hints of deja vu, and is rather hit and miss. Of course kids will lap it up, but adults probably won't like it as much. The second half of the movie is more meandering in quality compared to the first half, very little of interest happens and some of the situations come across as ridiculous. All in all, somewhat forgettable, but for a kids movie it is pretty entertaining. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Good as "The Absent Minded Professor" But Pretty Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tastes and times have changed drastically since 1961 when Fred MacMurray originally introduced the super-elastic stuff called 'flubber' to film audiences in Walt Disney's "The Absent Minded Professor." In the high-tech, 1990's Disney remake "Flubber" reinvents itself as an animated, gooey-green, silly putty blob of flying rubber that talks and dances. Actually, flubber resembles a combination of the Pillsbury Doughboy crossed with the shape-shifting water creature in James Cameron's 1989 fantasy thriller "The Abyss." Inventive, excessive, but tolerably entertaining, director Les Mayfield's remake of "The Absent Minded Professor" will captivate both young and absent-minded audiences. Happily, "Flubber" succeeds as a resilient special effects laden tour-de-farce. Sadly, the remake lacks the wit, warmth, subtlety, and comedic irony that distinguished its black & white predecessor. The spectacular morphing effects of George Lucas' Industrial Light & Magic Company and the visual wizardry of Peter Crosman, Tom Bertino, and Douglas Hans Smith cannot offset the film's hopelessly befuddled plot. The story by John Hughes and the late Bill Walsh follows the zany efforts of a scatterbrained university chemistry professor. Dr. Philip Brainard (Robin Williams of "Popeye") accidentally cooks up a gravity defying concoction called 'flubber.' Generating its own perpetual motion, 'flubber' has uses limited only by the imagination. Unlike the limp lump of 'flubber' in "The Absent-Minded Professor," the 'flubber' "Flubber" radiates a mischievous personality, but the filmmakers never solidify its amorphous character. Not only will Brainard 'flubber' rescue Medfield College from bankruptcy and closure, but 'flubber' will also redeem him in the eyes of the long-suffering sweetheart that he wants to wed: Medfield College President Sara Jean Reynolds (Marcia Gay Harden.) Brainard heads up Sara Jean's you-know-what list. Three times in a row he has left her stranded at the altar! If things aren't bad enough, Brainard's old academic nemesis Wilson Croft (Christopher MacDonald of "Thelma & Louise") lurks in the background. Oil and conniving, Croft plans to pilfer Brainard's fianc&eacute;e as well as take credit for his 'flubber' formula and the millions of dollars that it is sure to reap. The professor's next bigger enemy is perhaps his worst: corrupt businessman Chester Hoenicker (Raymond J. Barry of "Mad City"). Hoenicker's bratty son Bennett (Will Wheaton of TV's "Star Trek: The Next Generation") flunked Brainard's class. Consequently, Bennett got suspended from the basketball team. Initially, all that Hoenicker sought was a simple change of grade so Bennett, the top hoopster on the Medfield basketball team, could resume playing. When Hoenicker senior learns more about 'flubber,' he joins forces with the equally avaricious Croft to rip-off Braniard's discovery. Women have come a long way since the 1961 original. Disney has promoted the fianc&eacute;e from being the college president's secretary to the college president! Although Sara Jean presides over Medfield, she cannot keep it out of the red without the help of a good man. "Flubber" implies that women indeed have come a long way, but not far enough to get by on their own wits. Moreover, Sara Jean's romance with Brainard appears to occupy her every waking minute instead of the financial crisis that threatens her small, private college. Her priorities appear demeaningly misplaced. WEEBO, Brainard's flying female computer, serves as a sort of bad girl here who gets her just comeuppance for tampering with Brainard's social life. At one point, WEEBO creates a cyber-Siren image for herself to detract Brainard from Sara Jean. "Flubber" sounds like a can't-miss-hit from this description. If anything, "Flubber" proves that absent-minded audiences appreciate movies with an absence of drama. The original movie contained a richer plot with a variety of nuances that heightened its hilarity. "Flubber" smears on obvious slapstick to churn up laughs. John Hughes' script relies on his tried and true "Home Alone" routines. Hughes deserves the blame for this half-baked farce. For example, Hoenicker's henchman, Smith (Clancy Brown of "Starship Troopers") and Wesson (Ted Levine of "Silence of the Lambs") are clearly stand-ins for the Joe Pesci & Daniel Stern duo from the "Home Alone" comedies. Brainard's flubber clobbers them literally in the form of a golf ball and a bowling ball. Smith gets nailed by a non-stop golf ball, while a hard flying bowling ball wallops Wesson. When either object strikes them, these goons hit the deck like pole-axed ten pins. Director Les Mayfield of "Encino Man" and "Miracle on 34th Street") and scenarist John Hughes cannot make up their own minds about flubber. Flubber has endless possibilities, and its embryonic personality can be playful but occasionally snappish, too. WEEBO accuses Brainard of giving flubber "too much free will." Flubber never seems to live up to its potential unless it is exploding, flying through rooms, and cronking noggins. Most of the humor comes from how flubber reacts to different situations more than how Brainard applies it. Because they never define the nature of flubber, its wide open character lacks dramatic clarity. For example, the filmmakers don't set any limits to what flubber can do. Perhaps Mayfield and company chose green as flubber's lime-green color because the special effects were so expensive. Credit goes to director Les Mayfield for the get-up-and-goo pace of dizzy Disney film. He does a find job of seamlessly integrating the over-the-top special effects with live action, too. "Flubber" is aimless but predictable fun. The villains seem less villainous this time around, and Christopher MacDonald's bad guy appears simply to give flubber something through which to fly. The bowel humor here and there adds little to the humor and seems out of place in a juvenile movie. Parents may find themselves in a curious moral dilemma trying to explain to their kids why Brainard's cheating tactics should be condoned. He applies flubber to the basketball team's sneakers to help them beat their tall, merciless opponents on the court. Danny Elfman's lively music emphasizes the fast, bouncy pace of "Flubber" and helps the film scoot right along to its inevitable happy ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ironically, it has no bounce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nineties variant John Hughes combines his two favourite kinds of movies - variations on the 'Home Alone' formula and remakes - to produce this rehash of 1961's 'The Absent Minded Professor' in which Robin Williams is engaging as a scientist who creates a green goo that makes his car fly and a college basketball team bounce across the court. I didn't expect this to be much good but the amount of mind-numbing tedium on display came as a bit of a surprise. The story rambles around with no real internal logic, there's too much lame slapstick, Les Mayfield directs with no flair and the movie is devoid of charm. The original was no classic but it sure beats this version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ONLY for Robin Williams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisafordeay
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this as a kid and I found it really funny.The story is about a professor who creates a rubber like substance called Flubber. But problems arise as he ends up getting late for his wedding and causes trouble with his relationship with her.Meanwhile the professor's assistant(who happens to be a robot voiced by Jodi Benson),starts to have feelings for him and in one scene she creates a hologram of a woman just to get close to him. Overall it was a really long time ago since I last seen it but it was a funny movie. Not the best of Williams career but hey if you are a fan of Robin Williams then check it out
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I want a Flubber...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    YungRapunxel212
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wish Flubber was real, because if it was, I would be playing with it right now. We watched this in Science class once because it has to do with atoms and stuff, and we were learning about that. I think we were learning about atoms. OK back to the movie. It was just a bit boring. No, it was a lot boring. Only like 5 scenes were interesting. Robin Williams acting as the professor was a bad choice, because he is like 20 years older than the woman he likes and gets married too. Well he looked like it anyways. I would love to have a house like the professor, though. It was so cool and he really did not have to do anything, just have Weebo or his master inventions do it for him. This is a very kid friendly movie. Nothing frightening or sexual, just kissing. No drugs, maybe a character smoking. Very mild profanity and some violence. 8-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A "flubbing" good film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't see what was so bad about "FLUBBER". It was rated as a 4.8 on 10, and on Internet rated as medium. I liked it myself. I thought it was a wonderful film although not best (because of the missing scenario at some parts of the film.)A wonderful performance by Robin Williams for whom I will add an Oscar for "BEST ENTERTAINING ACTOR". He seems to be one of the best comedians ever in film history as seen in his role. The special effects are just a little "bounce" of pleasure that make the film even more original. I don't really know if I'll recommend it strongly since the rating on this film was negative. Some of the scenes are perfect and originally made. It is a nice story. I really "flubbed" it. A nice try!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really all that great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmm, I was told that this movie is cute, and cute it is, but it is not the best that I have seen. I must admit that Robin Williams is a funny guy, but this is not one of his funniest movies. The best scene in the movie was when he walks into a life drawing class thinking that it is his physics class and goes ahead and teaches. Other than that this movie is rather ordinary with lots of clich&eacute;s to fill it up. I enjoyed it, a bit, but I have seen better. Basically, a college is about to be shut down and Robin Williams is an absent minded professor who has missed his wedding three times. It is interesting that he has a robot that is in love with him and is forcing him not to marry the woman who he loves. This is all very cute but I thought that it was a little silly. The professor is very smart but, as is introduced rather quickly, somebody else always steals his ideas and gets the fame for it. The guy is basically the bad guy who is milking the professor for all he is worth. Then there is the corporate boss who thinks that solving problems is done by throwing money at it. He wants his kid to get straight A's so he throws money at it. When we look at the movie we see once again the theme of the American Dream. Everybody can become happy and rich if they simply work at it. All problems can be over come by ones own ability and that the end is always happy. This is a very shallow and idealistic theme which generally annoys me. Even though, Flubber is a kids movie though it has a few interesting scenes thrown in to keep the adults interested, because it is the adults that must take their kids to see the movie. Flubber is a Walt Disney movie, and I generally don't like Disney for some unknown reason, I guess because it is reaching into the minds of children and manipulating them into clones of themselves. All of us who grew up on Disney has been forced into a Disney mindset. I am far more critical of children's movies, and those who specialise in them, because our children follow them more than adults. Adults watch movies, children believe movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review of Flubber
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jared Reabow
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie , i would say is an 8/10 it is both great for the family of all ages, and great for the lone watcher. I would have to say that anyone who hates this movie, has a dislike for a character or director as there is very little to criticize it for otherwise, it has a highish budget, which means it has potential and it delivers, so ignore haters and give it a go! The general plot is a clumsy Professor created a new life form made of flubber with strange properties, I cant really say more as it would ruin the plot. However i can say that children will love the film, adults will like the film and elderly will find it amusing, which in my books is good enough reason to buy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moronic script aimed at a 5 year old child's mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poj-man
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    O Flubber, Flubber! Wherefore art the flying rubber? Deny the original and refuse it's name And if Robin Williams could have a stupider script It is Not The Absent Minded Professor Should you know more, or should we speak of this? Tis more than thy script that is thine enemy. Robin Williams is Robin Williams and not Fred McMurray. What's Fred McMurray? He is comedic timing. His thespian ability is not buffoonish ham-handed over emoting Belonging to a paycheck. What's in a name? That we call Flubber. Blown out of a humans rectum it is not so sweet. ============================ Only a child could be entertained by this stock character story thrown around FX. Robin Williams plays a moronically brilliant professor who works in his house and forgets his wedding day...and no one can find this "known to be absent minded moronically brilliant" professor. The bride left at the altar is left to fall into the clutches of the stock evil guy becauseno one bothered to check with the Groom at all the day of his wedding. No once called the house or drove by. The Professor is such a nerd no one said "Bachelor party!" Ladies! Isn't this the man of your dreams especially if you are an ovulating female wanting to start a family? This is the stupidity passed off as a script. The video games targeted at children have more depth of character than this dreck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Williams' best role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pilsung89
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Flubber came out during the mid/late nineties. This is the time where I believe Disney began losing its magic in the movie industry. Disney movies before always had the magical feeling and good stories. Flubber does not not have either. The main good thing it has is the acting. The acting is fairly good. This is not Robin Williams' best work, but he does a good enough job. The story revolves around a naive and eccentric inventor and college professor portrayed by Robin Williams. he creates a "living" specimen of goo that can shape-shift at will and is incredibly bouncy, but his dedication to it's creation causes him to forget his wedding. He ends up using the 'Flubber' to get his fianc&eacute; back and save his college from threats of closing down. I have no idea how the movie tries to make it work. I didn't really understand as a kid and I don't get it as an adult. The plot is weird, the directing isn't very good, and many of the characters are wooden. Overall, this Disney flick can be skipped. You won't be missing much
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Technically impressive and enjoyable, but somewhat forgettable too
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie had a lot of potential. While technically impressive and very enjoyable with some genuinely funny moments, for some reason it falls short. Of course there are redeeming qualities, such as the fun music score by Danny Elfman, one of my all time favourite film composers and an amusing turn from Robin Williams. Also the special effects are greatly improved from the effects in the Absent Minded Professor, and Flubber who is so cute steals the show. The performances from Clancy Brown, Ted Levine and Marcia Gay Horden are entertaining, and Jodi Benson (who voiced Ariel in the Little Mermaid)is a delight as the voice of Weebo, whose death is absolutely heart-rending. However the story is very predictable, and offers few surprises, and the physical comedy was better than the patchy script which in places felt uninspired. That saying some of the physical comedy has strong hints of deja vu, and is rather hit and miss. Of course kids will lap it up, but adults probably won't like it as much. The second half of the movie is more meandering in quality compared to the first half, very little of interest happens and some of the situations come across as ridiculous. All in all, somewhat forgettable, but for a kids movie it is pretty entertaining. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Good as "The Absent Minded Professor" But Pretty Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tastes and times have changed drastically since 1961 when Fred MacMurray originally introduced the super-elastic stuff called 'flubber' to film audiences in Walt Disney's "The Absent Minded Professor." In the high-tech, 1990's Disney remake "Flubber" reinvents itself as an animated, gooey-green, silly putty blob of flying rubber that talks and dances. Actually, flubber resembles a combination of the Pillsbury Doughboy crossed with the shape-shifting water creature in James Cameron's 1989 fantasy thriller "The Abyss." Inventive, excessive, but tolerably entertaining, director Les Mayfield's remake of "The Absent Minded Professor" will captivate both young and absent-minded audiences. Happily, "Flubber" succeeds as a resilient special effects laden tour-de-farce. Sadly, the remake lacks the wit, warmth, subtlety, and comedic irony that distinguished its black & white predecessor. The spectacular morphing effects of George Lucas' Industrial Light & Magic Company and the visual wizardry of Peter Crosman, Tom Bertino, and Douglas Hans Smith cannot offset the film's hopelessly befuddled plot. The story by John Hughes and the late Bill Walsh follows the zany efforts of a scatterbrained university chemistry professor. Dr. Philip Brainard (Robin Williams of "Popeye") accidentally cooks up a gravity defying concoction called 'flubber.' Generating its own perpetual motion, 'flubber' has uses limited only by the imagination. Unlike the limp lump of 'flubber' in "The Absent-Minded Professor," the 'flubber' "Flubber" radiates a mischievous personality, but the filmmakers never solidify its amorphous character. Not only will Brainard 'flubber' rescue Medfield College from bankruptcy and closure, but 'flubber' will also redeem him in the eyes of the long-suffering sweetheart that he wants to wed: Medfield College President Sara Jean Reynolds (Marcia Gay Harden.) Brainard heads up Sara Jean's you-know-what list. Three times in a row he has left her stranded at the altar! If things aren't bad enough, Brainard's old academic nemesis Wilson Croft (Christopher MacDonald of "Thelma & Louise") lurks in the background. Oil and conniving, Croft plans to pilfer Brainard's fianc&eacute;e as well as take credit for his 'flubber' formula and the millions of dollars that it is sure to reap. The professor's next bigger enemy is perhaps his worst: corrupt businessman Chester Hoenicker (Raymond J. Barry of "Mad City"). Hoenicker's bratty son Bennett (Will Wheaton of TV's "Star Trek: The Next Generation") flunked Brainard's class. Consequently, Bennett got suspended from the basketball team. Initially, all that Hoenicker sought was a simple change of grade so Bennett, the top hoopster on the Medfield basketball team, could resume playing. When Hoenicker senior learns more about 'flubber,' he joins forces with the equally avaricious Croft to rip-off Braniard's discovery. Women have come a long way since the 1961 original. Disney has promoted the fianc&eacute;e from being the college president's secretary to the college president! Although Sara Jean presides over Medfield, she cannot keep it out of the red without the help of a good man. "Flubber" implies that women indeed have come a long way, but not far enough to get by on their own wits. Moreover, Sara Jean's romance with Brainard appears to occupy her every waking minute instead of the financial crisis that threatens her small, private college. Her priorities appear demeaningly misplaced. WEEBO, Brainard's flying female computer, serves as a sort of bad girl here who gets her just comeuppance for tampering with Brainard's social life. At one point, WEEBO creates a cyber-Siren image for herself to detract Brainard from Sara Jean. "Flubber" sounds like a can't-miss-hit from this description. If anything, "Flubber" proves that absent-minded audiences appreciate movies with an absence of drama. The original movie contained a richer plot with a variety of nuances that heightened its hilarity. "Flubber" smears on obvious slapstick to churn up laughs. John Hughes' script relies on his tried and true "Home Alone" routines. Hughes deserves the blame for this half-baked farce. For example, Hoenicker's henchman, Smith (Clancy Brown of "Starship Troopers") and Wesson (Ted Levine of "Silence of the Lambs") are clearly stand-ins for the Joe Pesci & Daniel Stern duo from the "Home Alone" comedies. Brainard's flubber clobbers them literally in the form of a golf ball and a bowling ball. Smith gets nailed by a non-stop golf ball, while a hard flying bowling ball wallops Wesson. When either object strikes them, these goons hit the deck like pole-axed ten pins. Director Les Mayfield of "Encino Man" and "Miracle on 34th Street") and scenarist John Hughes cannot make up their own minds about flubber. Flubber has endless possibilities, and its embryonic personality can be playful but occasionally snappish, too. WEEBO accuses Brainard of giving flubber "too much free will." Flubber never seems to live up to its potential unless it is exploding, flying through rooms, and cronking noggins. Most of the humor comes from how flubber reacts to different situations more than how Brainard applies it. Because they never define the nature of flubber, its wide open character lacks dramatic clarity. For example, the filmmakers don't set any limits to what flubber can do. Perhaps Mayfield and company chose green as flubber's lime-green color because the special effects were so expensive. Credit goes to director Les Mayfield for the get-up-and-goo pace of dizzy Disney film. He does a find job of seamlessly integrating the over-the-top special effects with live action, too. "Flubber" is aimless but predictable fun. The villains seem less villainous this time around, and Christopher MacDonald's bad guy appears simply to give flubber something through which to fly. The bowel humor here and there adds little to the humor and seems out of place in a juvenile movie. Parents may find themselves in a curious moral dilemma trying to explain to their kids why Brainard's cheating tactics should be condoned. He applies flubber to the basketball team's sneakers to help them beat their tall, merciless opponents on the court. Danny Elfman's lively music emphasizes the fast, bouncy pace of "Flubber" and helps the film scoot right along to its inevitable happy ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ironically, it has no bounce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nineties variant John Hughes combines his two favourite kinds of movies - variations on the 'Home Alone' formula and remakes - to produce this rehash of 1961's 'The Absent Minded Professor' in which Robin Williams is engaging as a scientist who creates a green goo that makes his car fly and a college basketball team bounce across the court. I didn't expect this to be much good but the amount of mind-numbing tedium on display came as a bit of a surprise. The story rambles around with no real internal logic, there's too much lame slapstick, Les Mayfield directs with no flair and the movie is devoid of charm. The original was no classic but it sure beats this version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ONLY for Robin Williams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisafordeay
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this as a kid and I found it really funny.The story is about a professor who creates a rubber like substance called Flubber. But problems arise as he ends up getting late for his wedding and causes trouble with his relationship with her.Meanwhile the professor's assistant(who happens to be a robot voiced by Jodi Benson),starts to have feelings for him and in one scene she creates a hologram of a woman just to get close to him. Overall it was a really long time ago since I last seen it but it was a funny movie. Not the best of Williams career but hey if you are a fan of Robin Williams then check it out
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I want a Flubber...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    YungRapunxel212
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wish Flubber was real, because if it was, I would be playing with it right now. We watched this in Science class once because it has to do with atoms and stuff, and we were learning about that. I think we were learning about atoms. OK back to the movie. It was just a bit boring. No, it was a lot boring. Only like 5 scenes were interesting. Robin Williams acting as the professor was a bad choice, because he is like 20 years older than the woman he likes and gets married too. Well he looked like it anyways. I would love to have a house like the professor, though. It was so cool and he really did not have to do anything, just have Weebo or his master inventions do it for him. This is a very kid friendly movie. Nothing frightening or sexual, just kissing. No drugs, maybe a character smoking. Very mild profanity and some violence. 8-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A "flubbing" good film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't see what was so bad about "FLUBBER". It was rated as a 4.8 on 10, and on Internet rated as medium. I liked it myself. I thought it was a wonderful film although not best (because of the missing scenario at some parts of the film.)A wonderful performance by Robin Williams for whom I will add an Oscar for "BEST ENTERTAINING ACTOR". He seems to be one of the best comedians ever in film history as seen in his role. The special effects are just a little "bounce" of pleasure that make the film even more original. I don't really know if I'll recommend it strongly since the rating on this film was negative. Some of the scenes are perfect and originally made. It is a nice story. I really "flubbed" it. A nice try!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really all that great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmm, I was told that this movie is cute, and cute it is, but it is not the best that I have seen. I must admit that Robin Williams is a funny guy, but this is not one of his funniest movies. The best scene in the movie was when he walks into a life drawing class thinking that it is his physics class and goes ahead and teaches. Other than that this movie is rather ordinary with lots of clich&eacute;s to fill it up. I enjoyed it, a bit, but I have seen better. Basically, a college is about to be shut down and Robin Williams is an absent minded professor who has missed his wedding three times. It is interesting that he has a robot that is in love with him and is forcing him not to marry the woman who he loves. This is all very cute but I thought that it was a little silly. The professor is very smart but, as is introduced rather quickly, somebody else always steals his ideas and gets the fame for it. The guy is basically the bad guy who is milking the professor for all he is worth. Then there is the corporate boss who thinks that solving problems is done by throwing money at it. He wants his kid to get straight A's so he throws money at it. When we look at the movie we see once again the theme of the American Dream. Everybody can become happy and rich if they simply work at it. All problems can be over come by ones own ability and that the end is always happy. This is a very shallow and idealistic theme which generally annoys me. Even though, Flubber is a kids movie though it has a few interesting scenes thrown in to keep the adults interested, because it is the adults that must take their kids to see the movie. Flubber is a Walt Disney movie, and I generally don't like Disney for some unknown reason, I guess because it is reaching into the minds of children and manipulating them into clones of themselves. All of us who grew up on Disney has been forced into a Disney mindset. I am far more critical of children's movies, and those who specialise in them, because our children follow them more than adults. Adults watch movies, children believe movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review of Flubber
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jared Reabow
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie , i would say is an 8/10 it is both great for the family of all ages, and great for the lone watcher. I would have to say that anyone who hates this movie, has a dislike for a character or director as there is very little to criticize it for otherwise, it has a highish budget, which means it has potential and it delivers, so ignore haters and give it a go! The general plot is a clumsy Professor created a new life form made of flubber with strange properties, I cant really say more as it would ruin the plot. However i can say that children will love the film, adults will like the film and elderly will find it amusing, which in my books is good enough reason to buy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moronic script aimed at a 5 year old child's mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poj-man
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    O Flubber, Flubber! Wherefore art the flying rubber? Deny the original and refuse it's name And if Robin Williams could have a stupider script It is Not The Absent Minded Professor Should you know more, or should we speak of this? Tis more than thy script that is thine enemy. Robin Williams is Robin Williams and not Fred McMurray. What's Fred McMurray? He is comedic timing. His thespian ability is not buffoonish ham-handed over emoting Belonging to a paycheck. What's in a name? That we call Flubber. Blown out of a humans rectum it is not so sweet. ============================ Only a child could be entertained by this stock character story thrown around FX. Robin Williams plays a moronically brilliant professor who works in his house and forgets his wedding day...and no one can find this "known to be absent minded moronically brilliant" professor. The bride left at the altar is left to fall into the clutches of the stock evil guy becauseno one bothered to check with the Groom at all the day of his wedding. No once called the house or drove by. The Professor is such a nerd no one said "Bachelor party!" Ladies! Isn't this the man of your dreams especially if you are an ovulating female wanting to start a family? This is the stupidity passed off as a script. The video games targeted at children have more depth of character than this dreck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Williams' best role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pilsung89
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Flubber came out during the mid/late nineties. This is the time where I believe Disney began losing its magic in the movie industry. Disney movies before always had the magical feeling and good stories. Flubber does not not have either. The main good thing it has is the acting. The acting is fairly good. This is not Robin Williams' best work, but he does a good enough job. The story revolves around a naive and eccentric inventor and college professor portrayed by Robin Williams. he creates a "living" specimen of goo that can shape-shift at will and is incredibly bouncy, but his dedication to it's creation causes him to forget his wedding. He ends up using the 'Flubber' to get his fianc&eacute; back and save his college from threats of closing down. I have no idea how the movie tries to make it work. I didn't really understand as a kid and I don't get it as an adult. The plot is weird, the directing isn't very good, and many of the characters are wooden. Overall, this Disney flick can be skipped. You won't be missing much
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Technically impressive and enjoyable, but somewhat forgettable too
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie had a lot of potential. While technically impressive and very enjoyable with some genuinely funny moments, for some reason it falls short. Of course there are redeeming qualities, such as the fun music score by Danny Elfman, one of my all time favourite film composers and an amusing turn from Robin Williams. Also the special effects are greatly improved from the effects in the Absent Minded Professor, and Flubber who is so cute steals the show. The performances from Clancy Brown, Ted Levine and Marcia Gay Horden are entertaining, and Jodi Benson (who voiced Ariel in the Little Mermaid)is a delight as the voice of Weebo, whose death is absolutely heart-rending. However the story is very predictable, and offers few surprises, and the physical comedy was better than the patchy script which in places felt uninspired. That saying some of the physical comedy has strong hints of deja vu, and is rather hit and miss. Of course kids will lap it up, but adults probably won't like it as much. The second half of the movie is more meandering in quality compared to the first half, very little of interest happens and some of the situations come across as ridiculous. All in all, somewhat forgettable, but for a kids movie it is pretty entertaining. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Good as "The Absent Minded Professor" But Pretty Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tastes and times have changed drastically since 1961 when Fred MacMurray originally introduced the super-elastic stuff called 'flubber' to film audiences in Walt Disney's "The Absent Minded Professor." In the high-tech, 1990's Disney remake "Flubber" reinvents itself as an animated, gooey-green, silly putty blob of flying rubber that talks and dances. Actually, flubber resembles a combination of the Pillsbury Doughboy crossed with the shape-shifting water creature in James Cameron's 1989 fantasy thriller "The Abyss." Inventive, excessive, but tolerably entertaining, director Les Mayfield's remake of "The Absent Minded Professor" will captivate both young and absent-minded audiences. Happily, "Flubber" succeeds as a resilient special effects laden tour-de-farce. Sadly, the remake lacks the wit, warmth, subtlety, and comedic irony that distinguished its black & white predecessor. The spectacular morphing effects of George Lucas' Industrial Light & Magic Company and the visual wizardry of Peter Crosman, Tom Bertino, and Douglas Hans Smith cannot offset the film's hopelessly befuddled plot. The story by John Hughes and the late Bill Walsh follows the zany efforts of a scatterbrained university chemistry professor. Dr. Philip Brainard (Robin Williams of "Popeye") accidentally cooks up a gravity defying concoction called 'flubber.' Generating its own perpetual motion, 'flubber' has uses limited only by the imagination. Unlike the limp lump of 'flubber' in "The Absent-Minded Professor," the 'flubber' "Flubber" radiates a mischievous personality, but the filmmakers never solidify its amorphous character. Not only will Brainard 'flubber' rescue Medfield College from bankruptcy and closure, but 'flubber' will also redeem him in the eyes of the long-suffering sweetheart that he wants to wed: Medfield College President Sara Jean Reynolds (Marcia Gay Harden.) Brainard heads up Sara Jean's you-know-what list. Three times in a row he has left her stranded at the altar! If things aren't bad enough, Brainard's old academic nemesis Wilson Croft (Christopher MacDonald of "Thelma & Louise") lurks in the background. Oil and conniving, Croft plans to pilfer Brainard's fianc&eacute;e as well as take credit for his 'flubber' formula and the millions of dollars that it is sure to reap. The professor's next bigger enemy is perhaps his worst: corrupt businessman Chester Hoenicker (Raymond J. Barry of "Mad City"). Hoenicker's bratty son Bennett (Will Wheaton of TV's "Star Trek: The Next Generation") flunked Brainard's class. Consequently, Bennett got suspended from the basketball team. Initially, all that Hoenicker sought was a simple change of grade so Bennett, the top hoopster on the Medfield basketball team, could resume playing. When Hoenicker senior learns more about 'flubber,' he joins forces with the equally avaricious Croft to rip-off Braniard's discovery. Women have come a long way since the 1961 original. Disney has promoted the fianc&eacute;e from being the college president's secretary to the college president! Although Sara Jean presides over Medfield, she cannot keep it out of the red without the help of a good man. "Flubber" implies that women indeed have come a long way, but not far enough to get by on their own wits. Moreover, Sara Jean's romance with Brainard appears to occupy her every waking minute instead of the financial crisis that threatens her small, private college. Her priorities appear demeaningly misplaced. WEEBO, Brainard's flying female computer, serves as a sort of bad girl here who gets her just comeuppance for tampering with Brainard's social life. At one point, WEEBO creates a cyber-Siren image for herself to detract Brainard from Sara Jean. "Flubber" sounds like a can't-miss-hit from this description. If anything, "Flubber" proves that absent-minded audiences appreciate movies with an absence of drama. The original movie contained a richer plot with a variety of nuances that heightened its hilarity. "Flubber" smears on obvious slapstick to churn up laughs. John Hughes' script relies on his tried and true "Home Alone" routines. Hughes deserves the blame for this half-baked farce. For example, Hoenicker's henchman, Smith (Clancy Brown of "Starship Troopers") and Wesson (Ted Levine of "Silence of the Lambs") are clearly stand-ins for the Joe Pesci & Daniel Stern duo from the "Home Alone" comedies. Brainard's flubber clobbers them literally in the form of a golf ball and a bowling ball. Smith gets nailed by a non-stop golf ball, while a hard flying bowling ball wallops Wesson. When either object strikes them, these goons hit the deck like pole-axed ten pins. Director Les Mayfield of "Encino Man" and "Miracle on 34th Street") and scenarist John Hughes cannot make up their own minds about flubber. Flubber has endless possibilities, and its embryonic personality can be playful but occasionally snappish, too. WEEBO accuses Brainard of giving flubber "too much free will." Flubber never seems to live up to its potential unless it is exploding, flying through rooms, and cronking noggins. Most of the humor comes from how flubber reacts to different situations more than how Brainard applies it. Because they never define the nature of flubber, its wide open character lacks dramatic clarity. For example, the filmmakers don't set any limits to what flubber can do. Perhaps Mayfield and company chose green as flubber's lime-green color because the special effects were so expensive. Credit goes to director Les Mayfield for the get-up-and-goo pace of dizzy Disney film. He does a find job of seamlessly integrating the over-the-top special effects with live action, too. "Flubber" is aimless but predictable fun. The villains seem less villainous this time around, and Christopher MacDonald's bad guy appears simply to give flubber something through which to fly. The bowel humor here and there adds little to the humor and seems out of place in a juvenile movie. Parents may find themselves in a curious moral dilemma trying to explain to their kids why Brainard's cheating tactics should be condoned. He applies flubber to the basketball team's sneakers to help them beat their tall, merciless opponents on the court. Danny Elfman's lively music emphasizes the fast, bouncy pace of "Flubber" and helps the film scoot right along to its inevitable happy ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ironically, it has no bounce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nineties variant John Hughes combines his two favourite kinds of movies - variations on the 'Home Alone' formula and remakes - to produce this rehash of 1961's 'The Absent Minded Professor' in which Robin Williams is engaging as a scientist who creates a green goo that makes his car fly and a college basketball team bounce across the court. I didn't expect this to be much good but the amount of mind-numbing tedium on display came as a bit of a surprise. The story rambles around with no real internal logic, there's too much lame slapstick, Les Mayfield directs with no flair and the movie is devoid of charm. The original was no classic but it sure beats this version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ONLY for Robin Williams
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lisafordeay
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this as a kid and I found it really funny.The story is about a professor who creates a rubber like substance called Flubber. But problems arise as he ends up getting late for his wedding and causes trouble with his relationship with her.Meanwhile the professor's assistant(who happens to be a robot voiced by Jodi Benson),starts to have feelings for him and in one scene she creates a hologram of a woman just to get close to him. Overall it was a really long time ago since I last seen it but it was a funny movie. Not the best of Williams career but hey if you are a fan of Robin Williams then check it out
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I want a Flubber...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    YungRapunxel212
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wish Flubber was real, because if it was, I would be playing with it right now. We watched this in Science class once because it has to do with atoms and stuff, and we were learning about that. I think we were learning about atoms. OK back to the movie. It was just a bit boring. No, it was a lot boring. Only like 5 scenes were interesting. Robin Williams acting as the professor was a bad choice, because he is like 20 years older than the woman he likes and gets married too. Well he looked like it anyways. I would love to have a house like the professor, though. It was so cool and he really did not have to do anything, just have Weebo or his master inventions do it for him. This is a very kid friendly movie. Nothing frightening or sexual, just kissing. No drugs, maybe a character smoking. Very mild profanity and some violence. 8-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A "flubbing" good film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't see what was so bad about "FLUBBER". It was rated as a 4.8 on 10, and on Internet rated as medium. I liked it myself. I thought it was a wonderful film although not best (because of the missing scenario at some parts of the film.)A wonderful performance by Robin Williams for whom I will add an Oscar for "BEST ENTERTAINING ACTOR". He seems to be one of the best comedians ever in film history as seen in his role. The special effects are just a little "bounce" of pleasure that make the film even more original. I don't really know if I'll recommend it strongly since the rating on this film was negative. Some of the scenes are perfect and originally made. It is a nice story. I really "flubbed" it. A nice try!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not really all that great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hmm, I was told that this movie is cute, and cute it is, but it is not the best that I have seen. I must admit that Robin Williams is a funny guy, but this is not one of his funniest movies. The best scene in the movie was when he walks into a life drawing class thinking that it is his physics class and goes ahead and teaches. Other than that this movie is rather ordinary with lots of clich&eacute;s to fill it up. I enjoyed it, a bit, but I have seen better. Basically, a college is about to be shut down and Robin Williams is an absent minded professor who has missed his wedding three times. It is interesting that he has a robot that is in love with him and is forcing him not to marry the woman who he loves. This is all very cute but I thought that it was a little silly. The professor is very smart but, as is introduced rather quickly, somebody else always steals his ideas and gets the fame for it. The guy is basically the bad guy who is milking the professor for all he is worth. Then there is the corporate boss who thinks that solving problems is done by throwing money at it. He wants his kid to get straight A's so he throws money at it. When we look at the movie we see once again the theme of the American Dream. Everybody can become happy and rich if they simply work at it. All problems can be over come by ones own ability and that the end is always happy. This is a very shallow and idealistic theme which generally annoys me. Even though, Flubber is a kids movie though it has a few interesting scenes thrown in to keep the adults interested, because it is the adults that must take their kids to see the movie. Flubber is a Walt Disney movie, and I generally don't like Disney for some unknown reason, I guess because it is reaching into the minds of children and manipulating them into clones of themselves. All of us who grew up on Disney has been forced into a Disney mindset. I am far more critical of children's movies, and those who specialise in them, because our children follow them more than adults. Adults watch movies, children believe movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Review of Flubber
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jared Reabow
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie , i would say is an 8/10 it is both great for the family of all ages, and great for the lone watcher. I would have to say that anyone who hates this movie, has a dislike for a character or director as there is very little to criticize it for otherwise, it has a highish budget, which means it has potential and it delivers, so ignore haters and give it a go! The general plot is a clumsy Professor created a new life form made of flubber with strange properties, I cant really say more as it would ruin the plot. However i can say that children will love the film, adults will like the film and elderly will find it amusing, which in my books is good enough reason to buy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moronic script aimed at a 5 year old child's mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    poj-man
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    O Flubber, Flubber! Wherefore art the flying rubber? Deny the original and refuse it's name And if Robin Williams could have a stupider script It is Not The Absent Minded Professor Should you know more, or should we speak of this? Tis more than thy script that is thine enemy. Robin Williams is Robin Williams and not Fred McMurray. What's Fred McMurray? He is comedic timing. His thespian ability is not buffoonish ham-handed over emoting Belonging to a paycheck. What's in a name? That we call Flubber. Blown out of a humans rectum it is not so sweet. ============================ Only a child could be entertained by this stock character story thrown around FX. Robin Williams plays a moronically brilliant professor who works in his house and forgets his wedding day...and no one can find this "known to be absent minded moronically brilliant" professor. The bride left at the altar is left to fall into the clutches of the stock evil guy becauseno one bothered to check with the Groom at all the day of his wedding. No once called the house or drove by. The Professor is such a nerd no one said "Bachelor party!" Ladies! Isn't this the man of your dreams especially if you are an ovulating female wanting to start a family? This is the stupidity passed off as a script. The video games targeted at children have more depth of character than this dreck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Williams' best role
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pilsung89
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Flubber came out during the mid/late nineties. This is the time where I believe Disney began losing its magic in the movie industry. Disney movies before always had the magical feeling and good stories. Flubber does not not have either. The main good thing it has is the acting. The acting is fairly good. This is not Robin Williams' best work, but he does a good enough job. The story revolves around a naive and eccentric inventor and college professor portrayed by Robin Williams. he creates a "living" specimen of goo that can shape-shift at will and is incredibly bouncy, but his dedication to it's creation causes him to forget his wedding. He ends up using the 'Flubber' to get his fianc&eacute; back and save his college from threats of closing down. I have no idea how the movie tries to make it work. I didn't really understand as a kid and I don't get it as an adult. The plot is weird, the directing isn't very good, and many of the characters are wooden. Overall, this Disney flick can be skipped. You won't be missing much
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Technically impressive and enjoyable, but somewhat forgettable too
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie had a lot of potential. While technically impressive and very enjoyable with some genuinely funny moments, for some reason it falls short. Of course there are redeeming qualities, such as the fun music score by Danny Elfman, one of my all time favourite film composers and an amusing turn from Robin Williams. Also the special effects are greatly improved from the effects in the Absent Minded Professor, and Flubber who is so cute steals the show. The performances from Clancy Brown, Ted Levine and Marcia Gay Horden are entertaining, and Jodi Benson (who voiced Ariel in the Little Mermaid)is a delight as the voice of Weebo, whose death is absolutely heart-rending. However the story is very predictable, and offers few surprises, and the physical comedy was better than the patchy script which in places felt uninspired. That saying some of the physical comedy has strong hints of deja vu, and is rather hit and miss. Of course kids will lap it up, but adults probably won't like it as much. The second half of the movie is more meandering in quality compared to the first half, very little of interest happens and some of the situations come across as ridiculous. All in all, somewhat forgettable, but for a kids movie it is pretty entertaining. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Good as "The Absent Minded Professor" But Pretty Funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tastes and times have changed drastically since 1961 when Fred MacMurray originally introduced the super-elastic stuff called 'flubber' to film audiences in Walt Disney's "The Absent Minded Professor." In the high-tech, 1990's Disney remake "Flubber" reinvents itself as an animated, gooey-green, silly putty blob of flying rubber that talks and dances. Actually, flubber resembles a combination of the Pillsbury Doughboy crossed with the shape-shifting water creature in James Cameron's 1989 fantasy thriller "The Abyss." Inventive, excessive, but tolerably entertaining, director Les Mayfield's remake of "The Absent Minded Professor" will captivate both young and absent-minded audiences. Happily, "Flubber" succeeds as a resilient special effects laden tour-de-farce. Sadly, the remake lacks the wit, warmth, subtlety, and comedic irony that distinguished its black & white predecessor. The spectacular morphing effects of George Lucas' Industrial Light & Magic Company and the visual wizardry of Peter Crosman, Tom Bertino, and Douglas Hans Smith cannot offset the film's hopelessly befuddled plot. The story by John Hughes and the late Bill Walsh follows the zany efforts of a scatterbrained university chemistry professor. Dr. Philip Brainard (Robin Williams of "Popeye") accidentally cooks up a gravity defying concoction called 'flubber.' Generating its own perpetual motion, 'flubber' has uses limited only by the imagination. Unlike the limp lump of 'flubber' in "The Absent-Minded Professor," the 'flubber' "Flubber" radiates a mischievous personality, but the filmmakers never solidify its amorphous character. Not only will Brainard 'flubber' rescue Medfield College from bankruptcy and closure, but 'flubber' will also redeem him in the eyes of the long-suffering sweetheart that he wants to wed: Medfield College President Sara Jean Reynolds (Marcia Gay Harden.) Brainard heads up Sara Jean's you-know-what list. Three times in a row he has left her stranded at the altar! If things aren't bad enough, Brainard's old academic nemesis Wilson Croft (Christopher MacDonald of "Thelma & Louise") lurks in the background. Oil and conniving, Croft plans to pilfer Brainard's fianc&eacute;e as well as take credit for his 'flubber' formula and the millions of dollars that it is sure to reap. The professor's next bigger enemy is perhaps his worst: corrupt businessman Chester Hoenicker (Raymond J. Barry of "Mad City"). Hoenicker's bratty son Bennett (Will Wheaton of TV's "Star Trek: The Next Generation") flunked Brainard's class. Consequently, Bennett got suspended from the basketball team. Initially, all that Hoenicker sought was a simple change of grade so Bennett, the top hoopster on the Medfield basketball team, could resume playing. When Hoenicker senior learns more about 'flubber,' he joins forces with the equally avaricious Croft to rip-off Braniard's discovery. Women have come a long way since the 1961 original. Disney has promoted the fianc&eacute;e from being the college president's secretary to the college president! Although Sara Jean presides over Medfield, she cannot keep it out of the red without the help of a good man. "Flubber" implies that women indeed have come a long way, but not far enough to get by on their own wits. Moreover, Sara Jean's romance with Brainard appears to occupy her every waking minute instead of the financial crisis that threatens her small, private college. Her priorities appear demeaningly misplaced. WEEBO, Brainard's flying female computer, serves as a sort of bad girl here who gets her just comeuppance for tampering with Brainard's social life. At one point, WEEBO creates a cyber-Siren image for herself to detract Brainard from Sara Jean. "Flubber" sounds like a can't-miss-hit from this description. If anything, "Flubber" proves that absent-minded audiences appreciate movies with an absence of drama. The original movie contained a richer plot with a variety of nuances that heightened its hilarity. "Flubber" smears on obvious slapstick to churn up laughs. John Hughes' script relies on his tried and true "Home Alone" routines. Hughes deserves the blame for this half-baked farce. For example, Hoenicker's henchman, Smith (Clancy Brown of "Starship Troopers") and Wesson (Ted Levine of "Silence of the Lambs") are clearly stand-ins for the Joe Pesci & Daniel Stern duo from the "Home Alone" comedies. Brainard's flubber clobbers them literally in the form of a golf ball and a bowling ball. Smith gets nailed by a non-stop golf ball, while a hard flying bowling ball wallops Wesson. When either object strikes them, these goons hit the deck like pole-axed ten pins. Director Les Mayfield of "Encino Man" and "Miracle on 34th Street") and scenarist John Hughes cannot make up their own minds about flubber. Flubber has endless possibilities, and its embryonic personality can be playful but occasionally snappish, too. WEEBO accuses Brainard of giving flubber "too much free will." Flubber never seems to live up to its potential unless it is exploding, flying through rooms, and cronking noggins. Most of the humor comes from how flubber reacts to different situations more than how Brainard applies it. Because they never define the nature of flubber, its wide open character lacks dramatic clarity. For example, the filmmakers don't set any limits to what flubber can do. Perhaps Mayfield and company chose green as flubber's lime-green color because the special effects were so expensive. Credit goes to director Les Mayfield for the get-up-and-goo pace of dizzy Disney film. He does a find job of seamlessly integrating the over-the-top special effects with live action, too. "Flubber" is aimless but predictable fun. The villains seem less villainous this time around, and Christopher MacDonald's bad guy appears simply to give flubber something through which to fly. The bowel humor here and there adds little to the humor and seems out of place in a juvenile movie. Parents may find themselves in a curious moral dilemma trying to explain to their kids why Brainard's cheating tactics should be condoned. He applies flubber to the basketball team's sneakers to help them beat their tall, merciless opponents on the court. Danny Elfman's lively music emphasizes the fast, bouncy pace of "Flubber" and helps the film scoot right along to its inevitable happy ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
