<filme>
 <id>
  896
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120255
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Doce Amanh&atilde;
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  This film documents the effects of a tragic bus accident on the population of a small town.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A small community is torn apart by a tragic accident which kills most of the town's children. A lawyer visits the victims' parents in order to profit from the tragedy by stirring up the their anger and launching a class action suit against anyone they can blame. The community is paralyzed by its anger and cannot let go. All but one young girl, left in a wheelchair after the accident, who finds the courage to lead the way toward healing.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   bus
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   children
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   community
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   lawyer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   anger
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Atom Egoyan
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Russell Banks
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Atom Egoyan
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Ian Holm
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sarah Polley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Caerthan Banks
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Sal
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sweet Hereafter is 1997 Canadian drama movie based on a novel by Russell Banks of the same name. The screen play is written and directed by critically acclaimed director Atom Egoyon . The Film stars Ian Holm, Sarah Polly, Bruce Greenwood, AlbertaWatson, Simon Baker, Marc Donato, Broke Johnson, Maury Chaykin, Stephanie Morgenstern, Carthain Banks, Tom MeCamus, Russell Banks (cameo) and Gabrielle Rose. The Sweet Hereafter tells the story of a horrible school bus crashing accident that killed numerous local children. Their shattered and grieving parents are approached by a lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Ian Holm) who is hunted by the problems of his own, he wants them to file a class action lawsuit to sue for the damages by claiming the bus was faulty. Some of the parents at first are unwilling but they are persuaded by Mitchel Stevens that suing for damages is the right thing to do, some parents shows interest only because of the big settlement and some parents just want justice to be done. As most of the children are dead the case mainly depends only on 3 people that witnessed the accident, the bus driver Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose), Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polly) who was sitting at the front of the bus and who is now paralyzed below the waist because of the bus crashing accident and Billy (Bruce Greenwood) who was following the bus. Dolores Driscoll is willing to help to prove it wasn't her fault, Nicole Burnell is reluctant at first but agrees to help only on a condition that she wouldn't lie but Billy who lost 2 kids in the accident is against the lawsuit and tries to convince other parents to drop the lawsuit but nobody listens to him and tells him to stay out of it. In the pretrial deposition, Nicole Burnell lies and accuses the bus driver Dolores Driscoll of over speeding and thus causing the accident. After doing so all the hopes of suing the bus company with the possibility of big settlement disappears. The intention behind Nicole's lie is to punish her father who was sexually abusing her before the crash. Everybody that suffered from the accident or those who are involved in the case knows that Nicole is lying but nothing can be done and the trial never takes place. The story of the movie unfolds in non chronological order it jumps back and forth from one plot to another many times and loses the momentum. At first it was OK but after a while it was hard to watch because it never focused on the main story. In start we are introduced to several characters and each character has a story of its own. There are many different events besides the crash, which distracts the attention from the main plot. Mitchell Stevens daughter Zoe is a drug addict and she hates her father but its never explained what she hates him for also by the end of the movie Zoe tests positive for a blood test and its not explained what the test was for aids, pregnancy or something else. Also Zoe at first is shown as a homeless druggie but by the end she is well dressed. Billy has an affair with Risa (Alberta Watson) who is married to Windol (Maury Chaykin) but its never told why Risa is cheating on Windol or why can't she just leave him if she doesn't love him. Billy has also lost 2 kids in the accident but he is against the lawsuit because he knows it was just an accident and according to him it's wrong to sue for the damages but isn't it wrong to have an affair with a married woman? In the start of the movie its shown that Nicole loves her father (Sam MeCamus) and that they have a nice father daughter relationship but halfway its shown that Nicole is sexually abused by her father and by the end of the movie its shown that she hates him and therefor in order to punish him she lies and accuses an innocent person for the bus crash. Dolores Driscoll is held responsible for the accident because of over speeding but at the end of the movie she is back to driving some kind of airport passenger bus, how can she be hired just after two years for driving again when she is held responsible for the bus crash. Even the movie poster is taken from a scene that has nothing to do with the main plot of the movie. Ian Holm as Mitchel Stevens is a bit over dramatic at times but overall he plays the character nicely. Sarah Polly as Nicole Burnell does justice to her character and changes her facial expressions from a sweet to a serious bitter teen. Bruce Greenwood as Billy is convening, apart from Ion Holm, Sarah Polly and Bruce Greenwood all other actors are flat and plain and no one seems to be convincing enough in their respective characters. Atom Egoyon screenplay is too weak and confusing, he fails in directing The Sweet hereafter, he doesn't uses the right tone and right timing to introduce the characters and unfolds the story in non chronological order which only confuses the audience with all those subplots, The only good thing about his directing is choosing the beautiful locations for shoot. Cinematography is beautifully done by Paul Sarossy. Almost all of the main characters have a story, which is never explained, their personal stories are never given the depth they needed. I hardly see any place for those untold personal stories in the movie but they are introduced which drags the attention from the main plot and half way through the movie I didn't care for the accident and just wanted the movie to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    British actor Ian Holm gives a new meaning to a tale about selfishness directed by Atom Egoyan.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After an attentive viewing session,most attentive viewers would not fail at all to notice that the most recognizable feature of "The Sweet Hereafter" is its candid portrayal of selfishness. It is precisely this feeling which helps us to understand how some selfish individuals want to derive advantage from other people's suffering.This has been depicted through British actor Ian Holm whose extraordinary performance suggests that selfish people are always armed with their own ingenious explanations about their acts which in the long run bring them their fair share of misery instead of happiness.Canadian auteur Atom Egoyan whose film is an adaptation of a best selling work by Russell Banks is hardly partial when it comes to describe how ordinary people deal with guilt especially when it concerns untimely death of loved ones.No viewer would like to side with the film's characters who are full of idiosyncrasies as nobody is innocent.It is no wonder that good photography and natural setting enhance this film's viewing experience for viewers at a time when its slow pace acts as a veritable spoilsport. Finally,The Sweet Hereafter is a film to be watched at all costs if you have not seen a film which has been praised excessively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die is the book I found out about this film, it sounded like and I confirmed it as an independent film, the title obviously had some association with death, but I didn't know anything about the plot, so it would be interesting for me to try whatever. Basically a small town has been devastated by a tragic event; a school bus driven by Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose) and loaded with most of the children of the town attending the local school was driving during the snowy winter morning, when it suddenly hit an icy patch, it skids off road down the hill until it reaches the lake an crashes through the ice and sinks, drowning most victims inside. Many of the isolated village community members are mourning the deaths of their children, including Billy (Bruce Greenwood), the Walkers who lost their mentally developed and challenged son Sean (Devon Finn), and the Ottos who lost their aboriginal son Bear (Simon Baker) who was adopted. Some did survive the accident, including now wheelchair bound aspiring songstress Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polley), and Dolores, we see the accident in flashbacks while lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Sir Ian Holm) has arrived in the Canadian town wanting to take some slight advantage of the situation and get the parents of the twenty dead children to sue whatever party may be guilty for causing the incident, he will obviously represent those who agree to it. He plans to target the big companies and organisations with big amounts of money and who have some involvement with the school, most of the parents he see accept his proposal and see it as some way to get over the grieving, others are simply interested in the potential for the money, and some like Billy want nothing to do with a lawsuit. Stevens himself has demons as he suffered the death of his son and still feels grief, so he knows how the victims feel, but his son's death has also resulted in his daughter Zoe (Caerthan Banks) turning to drugs, losing respect for her father and any real relationship with him, and he knows life in the town has never been the same since this terrible event. Also starring Tom McCamus as Sam Burnell, Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian as Wanda Otto, Alberta Watson as Risa Walker, Mousehunt's Maury Chaykin as Wendell Walker, Brooke Johnson as Mary Burnell, David Hemblen as Abbott Driscoll and Peter Donaldson as Schwartz. Holm gives a pretty good glum performance as the ambulance-chasing who is trying to earn but also help those in the same grief-stricken situation he is in, Greenwood gets a reasonably good amount of time on screen, and I agree that from what I remember Polley is exceptional as the survivor paralysed by the accident. I will confess that I drifted in some of the story, particularly the parts involving a lawsuit and what have you, but it was certainly interesting to see a story about how one truly tragic incident can change the dynamics and personalities of a whole town community, it has got the right amount of intensity and atmosphere to keep you watching, a worthwhile psychological drama. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Director for Atom Egoyan (Felicia's Journey) and Best Writing, Screenplay Based on Material Previously Produced or Published. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Survivors Guilt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***SPOILERS*** We know right from the start where the film " The Sweet Hereafter" is headed in ambulance or school bus chasing shyster lawyer Mitchell Stevens, Ian Holm, on his way to this snowy little town in British Columbia Canada. Stevens is trying to get the people involved in a fatal school bus accident to help him start a class action suite against the bus company the bus driver as well as the town, Sam Dent, in what happened there. We also see that Stevens has problems of his own in that his teenage daughter Zoe,Caerthan Banks, is heavily into the drug scene and is later in the film found to be HIV or AIDS positive because of her non-stop drug use. It soon becomes obvious that Stevens in having his life screwed up, his wife also walked out on him, wants to help others like the school bus survivors and their families more then making any money for his services. It doesn't take to long for Stevens to find out that his services are no longer needed in that by him suing everyone or every thing in sight he's in fact opening up wounds in the community that have just started to begin healing. Wounds far more hurtful then what the people in Sam Dent have already suffered which in fact they were compensated for by the school bus company and despite it not being found responsible, for any shabby work on the road and guardrail,town. At first we dislike Stevens in his obsessive attempt to get the people in town to help him with his class action suit that many don't want to pursue. But later he turns out to be a victim of his own self righteousness in seeing he's going to hurt a lot of Innocent people with his suite who suffered , by surviving, even more then the victims whom he's to represent. One of them is the school bus driver Dorloes Driscoll, Gabriella Rose, who did everything to avoid her bus from skidding into a frozen lake and now has to live with the 14 children who ended up drowning in it on her conscience. There's also 15 year old Nicole Burnell, Sarah Polley, who survived the accident but ended up like the little boy in the story of "The Pide Piper of Hamlin", a favorite of hers, crippled and prevented from entering the land of "Good & Plenty" that the piper was taking the children of Hamlin to. ***SPOILERS*** Slow moving but extremely heart wrenching film that has no happy ending which in fact makes it one cut above the usual Hollywood schmaltz were used to watching about the subject matter that it presents to us. A lot like the movie released the year before in 1996 "Before and After" the film "The Sweet Hereafter" shows us how one survives a tragedy like losing a child with both dignity as well as grace instead of vengeance and self-guilt. Besides Nicole the film centers around Billy Hansel, Bruce Greenwood, the mechanic who serviced the school bus and knew that there was nothing wrong with it. Billy also lost his two children who were on the school bus that he witnessed, by driving behind it, crashing into the lake drowning them and their dozen or so classmate. For all the suffering that Billy and the rest of the people in Sam Dent went through he didn't want some shyster lawyer to make, excuse the pun, a killing off it! ***MAJOR SPOILER** In the end Stevens also lost a child, his daughter Zoe, through drug abuse and realized the only thing he can do now is try to put that tragic loss behind him like Billy as well as the crippled Nicole were doing and go on with his shattered life. It was Nicole who in her trying to put an end to the lawsuit that Stevens was pushing ended the whole affair by making up a preposterous story about the event,in Nicole being a star whiteness, that had it thrown out of court. Which allowed the healing process that Stevens tried to disrupt to continue and thus make things better for her as well as Mitchell Stevens and everyone else involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pied Piper of Hamelin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The summary will make sense once you have seen this. The Canadian film industry is one that I am now really getting into. This movie has a very disjointed structure and one that might be hard-to-follow for some people, which really is my only complaint though. The plot deals with 'tragedy', in particular losing your child. This occurs throughout the film and not just with the townsfolk that lost their kids in the bus crash, but Ian Holm's character has a drug-addicted daughter in this as well which also continues this theme outside of the townsfolk. If you want to watch a movie with good dialogue and characters with a lot of depth then I suggest watching, although to keep you in the right frame of mind then watch this movie expecting a dark, well-made period drama, that was what I was expecting and it was fulfilled in all aspects. No wonder this is considered Canada's best film, that title is deservingly so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Compassionate and reflective masterpiece..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egptian-born Canadian screenwriter, producer and director Atom Egoyan's seventh feature film, an adaptation of American writer Russel Banks' novel from 1991 which was inspired by a true story concerning a school bus accident in Alton, Texas 1989, tells the story of middle-aged attorney Mitchell Stevens who arrives in a remote rural district of Canada in December 1995 to report the circumstances surrounding a tragic school bus accident and help the parents of the victims to file an insurance-case against the bus company. A task that becomes difficult when he learns that most of the parents have numerous dark secrets. As he gets closer to the inhabitants of the small community it becomes apparent that this case has a strong personal influence on him, but his devotion brings nothing good to the parents, who begins to question his motives when they see that the case has more meaning to him than to them. The great score, the mindful dialog and the lyrical cinematography by Paul Sarossy emphasizes the emphatic and mysterious atmosphere in this resonating and realistic psychological drama which is beautifully filmed by Atom Egoyan, who creates versatile perspectives with his nuanced and subtle camera movements. His detailed and introspective screenplay examines how a bus accident affects the people in a small community and the aftermath of sorrow in a profound way, and portrays an in-depth study of character about a grieving man who has a restrained relationship to a daughter he hardly ever sees and who finds comfort and identifies with the parents who lost their children in the accident. Ian Holm's interpretation of the lawyer is outstanding in a refined and understated performance. The overall acting is good and Sarah Polley delivers a remarkable acting performance in her breakthrough role as teenager Nicole Purnell. During this brilliantly directed Canadian film, a short poem from 1842 called "The Pied Piper of Hamelin" by English poet and playwright Robert Browning (1812-1889) is read through Sarah Polley's voice-over. This fairy-tale forms a fine parallel to the story about the lawyer and the parents. With it's underlying lyrical aura and captivating narrative, this independent film stands as a poetic, compassionate and reflective masterpiece from the late 1990s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter-1997: Where time and grief just don't exist.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a simple story  simple in the sense described in the Storyline on the IMDb main page. But, it's from Russell Banks's novel that Atom Egoyan has written and directed one of the most complex plots ever put to film. For those interested, you'll find a complete analysis of this film's structure in Screen writing Updated by Linda Aronson, published in 2000. Incidentally, Russell Banks played the part of Dr Robeson. Avoiding the usual type of visual cues, Egoyan shows only two dates on screen to help orient the viewer to the time shifts (there are multiple shifts); instead, most are managed and revealed through the context of the scene and dialog. Which means the viewer must listen and watch carefully to stay on track. Some viewers might be annoyed. Adding to the complexity is the presentation of five different stories in the 112 minutes running time: the accident, the intrusive lawyer Mitchell (Ian Holm) and his daughter, Zoe (Caerthan Banks), the overly-motherly bus driver Dolores (Gabrielle Rose), the sex affair between Billy (Bruce Greenwood) and Risa (Alberta Watson) and, of course, the illicit and incestuous situation between Nicole (Sarah Polley) and her father, Sam (Tom McCamus). It takes a master film-maker to put all that together and achieve a work of art. On that basis, all serious film lovers should not miss this event, even if the story is unpalatable for many. Life, however, is full of such stories: read the daily tabloids. Ian Holm is the focus and catalyst of this narrative, for two reasons: first, he is, to some extent, the typical (or not so-typical) "ambulance chaser" after a buck, or too many; hence, much of the action involves his presence. Second, he is also after justice for the dead and lost children, spurred on because he lost Zoe to drugs, alcohol, AIDS etc  so she is effectively dead to him also. By trying to help the town folk in their loss, he hopes to achieve some sense of closure for his own loss  in other words, a self-serving attitude, much like the world in general. I think Holm gives the performance of his life in this film. For me, the greatest pleasure was listening to the voice-over of The Pied Piper of Hamelin, the narration of which is spoken by Nicole throughout the film. That poem serves to function as a metaphor of course for the fate that awaits her and her father: loneliness, sadness and despair in a cruel and indifferent world, while all the deceased children have moved on to the sweet hereafter. Not to be missed. November 27, 2011.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as exceptional as expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So this is the best rated movie of Atom Egoyan? I love his movies, and I have to say, sadly I expected a bit more. Don't get me wrong, cinematic everything is perfect. This movie is filmed beautifully. Every actor played on an extremely high level and not a single miscast was to be found in this movie! Overall it was a great watch. For me that was only destructed by the story. To me it felt, that the original novel was not suited to become a movie. The whole movie lacked a red thread. Strings didn't seem to be connected, and i failed finding a bigger meaning. All I found have been starting points, ideas. Great ideas, but in the end, the movie didn't work for me. It almost convinced me, but ultimately failed at the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ZzZzzZzZzZzzzZ
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know, to enjoy this film you have to be very patient. It runs very slowly, nothing interesting happens, there are too many names and different people coming and going, you never know what's going on; More than that, you don't get to see the accident until 60 minutes. It's like you're watching a soap opera with good actors, but with a unsatisfying development. 70 minutes was enough for me to turn it off because of it's boring scenes and conversations. I really expected much more for "Sweet Hereafter"; you know, it didn't work for me personally, don't know how it'd work with other people. IMDb wants me to write more, so I'll just repeat that I didn't like that...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great story which could be better told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shhazam2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite the director Atom Egoyan's misuse and overuse of flashbacks and flash forwards, this movie contained a great story. A terrible tragedy from which there was no emotional relief for the survivors except the chance for one to exact punishment for incest and child abuse. This story could have been told almost strictly chronologically from before the accident to after the accident without misusing the flashback technique and saving that technique for some of the background of the attorney which was still very well played by Ian Holm. Be patient with this movie and forgiving of the flash back misuse and you will have seen a gem of a story told about a tragic happening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Sal
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sweet Hereafter is 1997 Canadian drama movie based on a novel by Russell Banks of the same name. The screen play is written and directed by critically acclaimed director Atom Egoyon . The Film stars Ian Holm, Sarah Polly, Bruce Greenwood, AlbertaWatson, Simon Baker, Marc Donato, Broke Johnson, Maury Chaykin, Stephanie Morgenstern, Carthain Banks, Tom MeCamus, Russell Banks (cameo) and Gabrielle Rose. The Sweet Hereafter tells the story of a horrible school bus crashing accident that killed numerous local children. Their shattered and grieving parents are approached by a lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Ian Holm) who is hunted by the problems of his own, he wants them to file a class action lawsuit to sue for the damages by claiming the bus was faulty. Some of the parents at first are unwilling but they are persuaded by Mitchel Stevens that suing for damages is the right thing to do, some parents shows interest only because of the big settlement and some parents just want justice to be done. As most of the children are dead the case mainly depends only on 3 people that witnessed the accident, the bus driver Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose), Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polly) who was sitting at the front of the bus and who is now paralyzed below the waist because of the bus crashing accident and Billy (Bruce Greenwood) who was following the bus. Dolores Driscoll is willing to help to prove it wasn't her fault, Nicole Burnell is reluctant at first but agrees to help only on a condition that she wouldn't lie but Billy who lost 2 kids in the accident is against the lawsuit and tries to convince other parents to drop the lawsuit but nobody listens to him and tells him to stay out of it. In the pretrial deposition, Nicole Burnell lies and accuses the bus driver Dolores Driscoll of over speeding and thus causing the accident. After doing so all the hopes of suing the bus company with the possibility of big settlement disappears. The intention behind Nicole's lie is to punish her father who was sexually abusing her before the crash. Everybody that suffered from the accident or those who are involved in the case knows that Nicole is lying but nothing can be done and the trial never takes place. The story of the movie unfolds in non chronological order it jumps back and forth from one plot to another many times and loses the momentum. At first it was OK but after a while it was hard to watch because it never focused on the main story. In start we are introduced to several characters and each character has a story of its own. There are many different events besides the crash, which distracts the attention from the main plot. Mitchell Stevens daughter Zoe is a drug addict and she hates her father but its never explained what she hates him for also by the end of the movie Zoe tests positive for a blood test and its not explained what the test was for aids, pregnancy or something else. Also Zoe at first is shown as a homeless druggie but by the end she is well dressed. Billy has an affair with Risa (Alberta Watson) who is married to Windol (Maury Chaykin) but its never told why Risa is cheating on Windol or why can't she just leave him if she doesn't love him. Billy has also lost 2 kids in the accident but he is against the lawsuit because he knows it was just an accident and according to him it's wrong to sue for the damages but isn't it wrong to have an affair with a married woman? In the start of the movie its shown that Nicole loves her father (Sam MeCamus) and that they have a nice father daughter relationship but halfway its shown that Nicole is sexually abused by her father and by the end of the movie its shown that she hates him and therefor in order to punish him she lies and accuses an innocent person for the bus crash. Dolores Driscoll is held responsible for the accident because of over speeding but at the end of the movie she is back to driving some kind of airport passenger bus, how can she be hired just after two years for driving again when she is held responsible for the bus crash. Even the movie poster is taken from a scene that has nothing to do with the main plot of the movie. Ian Holm as Mitchel Stevens is a bit over dramatic at times but overall he plays the character nicely. Sarah Polly as Nicole Burnell does justice to her character and changes her facial expressions from a sweet to a serious bitter teen. Bruce Greenwood as Billy is convening, apart from Ion Holm, Sarah Polly and Bruce Greenwood all other actors are flat and plain and no one seems to be convincing enough in their respective characters. Atom Egoyon screenplay is too weak and confusing, he fails in directing The Sweet hereafter, he doesn't uses the right tone and right timing to introduce the characters and unfolds the story in non chronological order which only confuses the audience with all those subplots, The only good thing about his directing is choosing the beautiful locations for shoot. Cinematography is beautifully done by Paul Sarossy. Almost all of the main characters have a story, which is never explained, their personal stories are never given the depth they needed. I hardly see any place for those untold personal stories in the movie but they are introduced which drags the attention from the main plot and half way through the movie I didn't care for the accident and just wanted the movie to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    British actor Ian Holm gives a new meaning to a tale about selfishness directed by Atom Egoyan.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After an attentive viewing session,most attentive viewers would not fail at all to notice that the most recognizable feature of "The Sweet Hereafter" is its candid portrayal of selfishness. It is precisely this feeling which helps us to understand how some selfish individuals want to derive advantage from other people's suffering.This has been depicted through British actor Ian Holm whose extraordinary performance suggests that selfish people are always armed with their own ingenious explanations about their acts which in the long run bring them their fair share of misery instead of happiness.Canadian auteur Atom Egoyan whose film is an adaptation of a best selling work by Russell Banks is hardly partial when it comes to describe how ordinary people deal with guilt especially when it concerns untimely death of loved ones.No viewer would like to side with the film's characters who are full of idiosyncrasies as nobody is innocent.It is no wonder that good photography and natural setting enhance this film's viewing experience for viewers at a time when its slow pace acts as a veritable spoilsport. Finally,The Sweet Hereafter is a film to be watched at all costs if you have not seen a film which has been praised excessively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die is the book I found out about this film, it sounded like and I confirmed it as an independent film, the title obviously had some association with death, but I didn't know anything about the plot, so it would be interesting for me to try whatever. Basically a small town has been devastated by a tragic event; a school bus driven by Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose) and loaded with most of the children of the town attending the local school was driving during the snowy winter morning, when it suddenly hit an icy patch, it skids off road down the hill until it reaches the lake an crashes through the ice and sinks, drowning most victims inside. Many of the isolated village community members are mourning the deaths of their children, including Billy (Bruce Greenwood), the Walkers who lost their mentally developed and challenged son Sean (Devon Finn), and the Ottos who lost their aboriginal son Bear (Simon Baker) who was adopted. Some did survive the accident, including now wheelchair bound aspiring songstress Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polley), and Dolores, we see the accident in flashbacks while lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Sir Ian Holm) has arrived in the Canadian town wanting to take some slight advantage of the situation and get the parents of the twenty dead children to sue whatever party may be guilty for causing the incident, he will obviously represent those who agree to it. He plans to target the big companies and organisations with big amounts of money and who have some involvement with the school, most of the parents he see accept his proposal and see it as some way to get over the grieving, others are simply interested in the potential for the money, and some like Billy want nothing to do with a lawsuit. Stevens himself has demons as he suffered the death of his son and still feels grief, so he knows how the victims feel, but his son's death has also resulted in his daughter Zoe (Caerthan Banks) turning to drugs, losing respect for her father and any real relationship with him, and he knows life in the town has never been the same since this terrible event. Also starring Tom McCamus as Sam Burnell, Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian as Wanda Otto, Alberta Watson as Risa Walker, Mousehunt's Maury Chaykin as Wendell Walker, Brooke Johnson as Mary Burnell, David Hemblen as Abbott Driscoll and Peter Donaldson as Schwartz. Holm gives a pretty good glum performance as the ambulance-chasing who is trying to earn but also help those in the same grief-stricken situation he is in, Greenwood gets a reasonably good amount of time on screen, and I agree that from what I remember Polley is exceptional as the survivor paralysed by the accident. I will confess that I drifted in some of the story, particularly the parts involving a lawsuit and what have you, but it was certainly interesting to see a story about how one truly tragic incident can change the dynamics and personalities of a whole town community, it has got the right amount of intensity and atmosphere to keep you watching, a worthwhile psychological drama. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Director for Atom Egoyan (Felicia's Journey) and Best Writing, Screenplay Based on Material Previously Produced or Published. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Survivors Guilt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***SPOILERS*** We know right from the start where the film " The Sweet Hereafter" is headed in ambulance or school bus chasing shyster lawyer Mitchell Stevens, Ian Holm, on his way to this snowy little town in British Columbia Canada. Stevens is trying to get the people involved in a fatal school bus accident to help him start a class action suite against the bus company the bus driver as well as the town, Sam Dent, in what happened there. We also see that Stevens has problems of his own in that his teenage daughter Zoe,Caerthan Banks, is heavily into the drug scene and is later in the film found to be HIV or AIDS positive because of her non-stop drug use. It soon becomes obvious that Stevens in having his life screwed up, his wife also walked out on him, wants to help others like the school bus survivors and their families more then making any money for his services. It doesn't take to long for Stevens to find out that his services are no longer needed in that by him suing everyone or every thing in sight he's in fact opening up wounds in the community that have just started to begin healing. Wounds far more hurtful then what the people in Sam Dent have already suffered which in fact they were compensated for by the school bus company and despite it not being found responsible, for any shabby work on the road and guardrail,town. At first we dislike Stevens in his obsessive attempt to get the people in town to help him with his class action suit that many don't want to pursue. But later he turns out to be a victim of his own self righteousness in seeing he's going to hurt a lot of Innocent people with his suite who suffered , by surviving, even more then the victims whom he's to represent. One of them is the school bus driver Dorloes Driscoll, Gabriella Rose, who did everything to avoid her bus from skidding into a frozen lake and now has to live with the 14 children who ended up drowning in it on her conscience. There's also 15 year old Nicole Burnell, Sarah Polley, who survived the accident but ended up like the little boy in the story of "The Pide Piper of Hamlin", a favorite of hers, crippled and prevented from entering the land of "Good & Plenty" that the piper was taking the children of Hamlin to. ***SPOILERS*** Slow moving but extremely heart wrenching film that has no happy ending which in fact makes it one cut above the usual Hollywood schmaltz were used to watching about the subject matter that it presents to us. A lot like the movie released the year before in 1996 "Before and After" the film "The Sweet Hereafter" shows us how one survives a tragedy like losing a child with both dignity as well as grace instead of vengeance and self-guilt. Besides Nicole the film centers around Billy Hansel, Bruce Greenwood, the mechanic who serviced the school bus and knew that there was nothing wrong with it. Billy also lost his two children who were on the school bus that he witnessed, by driving behind it, crashing into the lake drowning them and their dozen or so classmate. For all the suffering that Billy and the rest of the people in Sam Dent went through he didn't want some shyster lawyer to make, excuse the pun, a killing off it! ***MAJOR SPOILER** In the end Stevens also lost a child, his daughter Zoe, through drug abuse and realized the only thing he can do now is try to put that tragic loss behind him like Billy as well as the crippled Nicole were doing and go on with his shattered life. It was Nicole who in her trying to put an end to the lawsuit that Stevens was pushing ended the whole affair by making up a preposterous story about the event,in Nicole being a star whiteness, that had it thrown out of court. Which allowed the healing process that Stevens tried to disrupt to continue and thus make things better for her as well as Mitchell Stevens and everyone else involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pied Piper of Hamelin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The summary will make sense once you have seen this. The Canadian film industry is one that I am now really getting into. This movie has a very disjointed structure and one that might be hard-to-follow for some people, which really is my only complaint though. The plot deals with 'tragedy', in particular losing your child. This occurs throughout the film and not just with the townsfolk that lost their kids in the bus crash, but Ian Holm's character has a drug-addicted daughter in this as well which also continues this theme outside of the townsfolk. If you want to watch a movie with good dialogue and characters with a lot of depth then I suggest watching, although to keep you in the right frame of mind then watch this movie expecting a dark, well-made period drama, that was what I was expecting and it was fulfilled in all aspects. No wonder this is considered Canada's best film, that title is deservingly so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Compassionate and reflective masterpiece..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egptian-born Canadian screenwriter, producer and director Atom Egoyan's seventh feature film, an adaptation of American writer Russel Banks' novel from 1991 which was inspired by a true story concerning a school bus accident in Alton, Texas 1989, tells the story of middle-aged attorney Mitchell Stevens who arrives in a remote rural district of Canada in December 1995 to report the circumstances surrounding a tragic school bus accident and help the parents of the victims to file an insurance-case against the bus company. A task that becomes difficult when he learns that most of the parents have numerous dark secrets. As he gets closer to the inhabitants of the small community it becomes apparent that this case has a strong personal influence on him, but his devotion brings nothing good to the parents, who begins to question his motives when they see that the case has more meaning to him than to them. The great score, the mindful dialog and the lyrical cinematography by Paul Sarossy emphasizes the emphatic and mysterious atmosphere in this resonating and realistic psychological drama which is beautifully filmed by Atom Egoyan, who creates versatile perspectives with his nuanced and subtle camera movements. His detailed and introspective screenplay examines how a bus accident affects the people in a small community and the aftermath of sorrow in a profound way, and portrays an in-depth study of character about a grieving man who has a restrained relationship to a daughter he hardly ever sees and who finds comfort and identifies with the parents who lost their children in the accident. Ian Holm's interpretation of the lawyer is outstanding in a refined and understated performance. The overall acting is good and Sarah Polley delivers a remarkable acting performance in her breakthrough role as teenager Nicole Purnell. During this brilliantly directed Canadian film, a short poem from 1842 called "The Pied Piper of Hamelin" by English poet and playwright Robert Browning (1812-1889) is read through Sarah Polley's voice-over. This fairy-tale forms a fine parallel to the story about the lawyer and the parents. With it's underlying lyrical aura and captivating narrative, this independent film stands as a poetic, compassionate and reflective masterpiece from the late 1990s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter-1997: Where time and grief just don't exist.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a simple story  simple in the sense described in the Storyline on the IMDb main page. But, it's from Russell Banks's novel that Atom Egoyan has written and directed one of the most complex plots ever put to film. For those interested, you'll find a complete analysis of this film's structure in Screen writing Updated by Linda Aronson, published in 2000. Incidentally, Russell Banks played the part of Dr Robeson. Avoiding the usual type of visual cues, Egoyan shows only two dates on screen to help orient the viewer to the time shifts (there are multiple shifts); instead, most are managed and revealed through the context of the scene and dialog. Which means the viewer must listen and watch carefully to stay on track. Some viewers might be annoyed. Adding to the complexity is the presentation of five different stories in the 112 minutes running time: the accident, the intrusive lawyer Mitchell (Ian Holm) and his daughter, Zoe (Caerthan Banks), the overly-motherly bus driver Dolores (Gabrielle Rose), the sex affair between Billy (Bruce Greenwood) and Risa (Alberta Watson) and, of course, the illicit and incestuous situation between Nicole (Sarah Polley) and her father, Sam (Tom McCamus). It takes a master film-maker to put all that together and achieve a work of art. On that basis, all serious film lovers should not miss this event, even if the story is unpalatable for many. Life, however, is full of such stories: read the daily tabloids. Ian Holm is the focus and catalyst of this narrative, for two reasons: first, he is, to some extent, the typical (or not so-typical) "ambulance chaser" after a buck, or too many; hence, much of the action involves his presence. Second, he is also after justice for the dead and lost children, spurred on because he lost Zoe to drugs, alcohol, AIDS etc  so she is effectively dead to him also. By trying to help the town folk in their loss, he hopes to achieve some sense of closure for his own loss  in other words, a self-serving attitude, much like the world in general. I think Holm gives the performance of his life in this film. For me, the greatest pleasure was listening to the voice-over of The Pied Piper of Hamelin, the narration of which is spoken by Nicole throughout the film. That poem serves to function as a metaphor of course for the fate that awaits her and her father: loneliness, sadness and despair in a cruel and indifferent world, while all the deceased children have moved on to the sweet hereafter. Not to be missed. November 27, 2011.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as exceptional as expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So this is the best rated movie of Atom Egoyan? I love his movies, and I have to say, sadly I expected a bit more. Don't get me wrong, cinematic everything is perfect. This movie is filmed beautifully. Every actor played on an extremely high level and not a single miscast was to be found in this movie! Overall it was a great watch. For me that was only destructed by the story. To me it felt, that the original novel was not suited to become a movie. The whole movie lacked a red thread. Strings didn't seem to be connected, and i failed finding a bigger meaning. All I found have been starting points, ideas. Great ideas, but in the end, the movie didn't work for me. It almost convinced me, but ultimately failed at the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ZzZzzZzZzZzzzZ
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know, to enjoy this film you have to be very patient. It runs very slowly, nothing interesting happens, there are too many names and different people coming and going, you never know what's going on; More than that, you don't get to see the accident until 60 minutes. It's like you're watching a soap opera with good actors, but with a unsatisfying development. 70 minutes was enough for me to turn it off because of it's boring scenes and conversations. I really expected much more for "Sweet Hereafter"; you know, it didn't work for me personally, don't know how it'd work with other people. IMDb wants me to write more, so I'll just repeat that I didn't like that...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great story which could be better told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shhazam2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite the director Atom Egoyan's misuse and overuse of flashbacks and flash forwards, this movie contained a great story. A terrible tragedy from which there was no emotional relief for the survivors except the chance for one to exact punishment for incest and child abuse. This story could have been told almost strictly chronologically from before the accident to after the accident without misusing the flashback technique and saving that technique for some of the background of the attorney which was still very well played by Ian Holm. Be patient with this movie and forgiving of the flash back misuse and you will have seen a gem of a story told about a tragic happening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Sal
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sweet Hereafter is 1997 Canadian drama movie based on a novel by Russell Banks of the same name. The screen play is written and directed by critically acclaimed director Atom Egoyon . The Film stars Ian Holm, Sarah Polly, Bruce Greenwood, AlbertaWatson, Simon Baker, Marc Donato, Broke Johnson, Maury Chaykin, Stephanie Morgenstern, Carthain Banks, Tom MeCamus, Russell Banks (cameo) and Gabrielle Rose. The Sweet Hereafter tells the story of a horrible school bus crashing accident that killed numerous local children. Their shattered and grieving parents are approached by a lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Ian Holm) who is hunted by the problems of his own, he wants them to file a class action lawsuit to sue for the damages by claiming the bus was faulty. Some of the parents at first are unwilling but they are persuaded by Mitchel Stevens that suing for damages is the right thing to do, some parents shows interest only because of the big settlement and some parents just want justice to be done. As most of the children are dead the case mainly depends only on 3 people that witnessed the accident, the bus driver Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose), Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polly) who was sitting at the front of the bus and who is now paralyzed below the waist because of the bus crashing accident and Billy (Bruce Greenwood) who was following the bus. Dolores Driscoll is willing to help to prove it wasn't her fault, Nicole Burnell is reluctant at first but agrees to help only on a condition that she wouldn't lie but Billy who lost 2 kids in the accident is against the lawsuit and tries to convince other parents to drop the lawsuit but nobody listens to him and tells him to stay out of it. In the pretrial deposition, Nicole Burnell lies and accuses the bus driver Dolores Driscoll of over speeding and thus causing the accident. After doing so all the hopes of suing the bus company with the possibility of big settlement disappears. The intention behind Nicole's lie is to punish her father who was sexually abusing her before the crash. Everybody that suffered from the accident or those who are involved in the case knows that Nicole is lying but nothing can be done and the trial never takes place. The story of the movie unfolds in non chronological order it jumps back and forth from one plot to another many times and loses the momentum. At first it was OK but after a while it was hard to watch because it never focused on the main story. In start we are introduced to several characters and each character has a story of its own. There are many different events besides the crash, which distracts the attention from the main plot. Mitchell Stevens daughter Zoe is a drug addict and she hates her father but its never explained what she hates him for also by the end of the movie Zoe tests positive for a blood test and its not explained what the test was for aids, pregnancy or something else. Also Zoe at first is shown as a homeless druggie but by the end she is well dressed. Billy has an affair with Risa (Alberta Watson) who is married to Windol (Maury Chaykin) but its never told why Risa is cheating on Windol or why can't she just leave him if she doesn't love him. Billy has also lost 2 kids in the accident but he is against the lawsuit because he knows it was just an accident and according to him it's wrong to sue for the damages but isn't it wrong to have an affair with a married woman? In the start of the movie its shown that Nicole loves her father (Sam MeCamus) and that they have a nice father daughter relationship but halfway its shown that Nicole is sexually abused by her father and by the end of the movie its shown that she hates him and therefor in order to punish him she lies and accuses an innocent person for the bus crash. Dolores Driscoll is held responsible for the accident because of over speeding but at the end of the movie she is back to driving some kind of airport passenger bus, how can she be hired just after two years for driving again when she is held responsible for the bus crash. Even the movie poster is taken from a scene that has nothing to do with the main plot of the movie. Ian Holm as Mitchel Stevens is a bit over dramatic at times but overall he plays the character nicely. Sarah Polly as Nicole Burnell does justice to her character and changes her facial expressions from a sweet to a serious bitter teen. Bruce Greenwood as Billy is convening, apart from Ion Holm, Sarah Polly and Bruce Greenwood all other actors are flat and plain and no one seems to be convincing enough in their respective characters. Atom Egoyon screenplay is too weak and confusing, he fails in directing The Sweet hereafter, he doesn't uses the right tone and right timing to introduce the characters and unfolds the story in non chronological order which only confuses the audience with all those subplots, The only good thing about his directing is choosing the beautiful locations for shoot. Cinematography is beautifully done by Paul Sarossy. Almost all of the main characters have a story, which is never explained, their personal stories are never given the depth they needed. I hardly see any place for those untold personal stories in the movie but they are introduced which drags the attention from the main plot and half way through the movie I didn't care for the accident and just wanted the movie to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    British actor Ian Holm gives a new meaning to a tale about selfishness directed by Atom Egoyan.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After an attentive viewing session,most attentive viewers would not fail at all to notice that the most recognizable feature of "The Sweet Hereafter" is its candid portrayal of selfishness. It is precisely this feeling which helps us to understand how some selfish individuals want to derive advantage from other people's suffering.This has been depicted through British actor Ian Holm whose extraordinary performance suggests that selfish people are always armed with their own ingenious explanations about their acts which in the long run bring them their fair share of misery instead of happiness.Canadian auteur Atom Egoyan whose film is an adaptation of a best selling work by Russell Banks is hardly partial when it comes to describe how ordinary people deal with guilt especially when it concerns untimely death of loved ones.No viewer would like to side with the film's characters who are full of idiosyncrasies as nobody is innocent.It is no wonder that good photography and natural setting enhance this film's viewing experience for viewers at a time when its slow pace acts as a veritable spoilsport. Finally,The Sweet Hereafter is a film to be watched at all costs if you have not seen a film which has been praised excessively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die is the book I found out about this film, it sounded like and I confirmed it as an independent film, the title obviously had some association with death, but I didn't know anything about the plot, so it would be interesting for me to try whatever. Basically a small town has been devastated by a tragic event; a school bus driven by Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose) and loaded with most of the children of the town attending the local school was driving during the snowy winter morning, when it suddenly hit an icy patch, it skids off road down the hill until it reaches the lake an crashes through the ice and sinks, drowning most victims inside. Many of the isolated village community members are mourning the deaths of their children, including Billy (Bruce Greenwood), the Walkers who lost their mentally developed and challenged son Sean (Devon Finn), and the Ottos who lost their aboriginal son Bear (Simon Baker) who was adopted. Some did survive the accident, including now wheelchair bound aspiring songstress Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polley), and Dolores, we see the accident in flashbacks while lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Sir Ian Holm) has arrived in the Canadian town wanting to take some slight advantage of the situation and get the parents of the twenty dead children to sue whatever party may be guilty for causing the incident, he will obviously represent those who agree to it. He plans to target the big companies and organisations with big amounts of money and who have some involvement with the school, most of the parents he see accept his proposal and see it as some way to get over the grieving, others are simply interested in the potential for the money, and some like Billy want nothing to do with a lawsuit. Stevens himself has demons as he suffered the death of his son and still feels grief, so he knows how the victims feel, but his son's death has also resulted in his daughter Zoe (Caerthan Banks) turning to drugs, losing respect for her father and any real relationship with him, and he knows life in the town has never been the same since this terrible event. Also starring Tom McCamus as Sam Burnell, Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian as Wanda Otto, Alberta Watson as Risa Walker, Mousehunt's Maury Chaykin as Wendell Walker, Brooke Johnson as Mary Burnell, David Hemblen as Abbott Driscoll and Peter Donaldson as Schwartz. Holm gives a pretty good glum performance as the ambulance-chasing who is trying to earn but also help those in the same grief-stricken situation he is in, Greenwood gets a reasonably good amount of time on screen, and I agree that from what I remember Polley is exceptional as the survivor paralysed by the accident. I will confess that I drifted in some of the story, particularly the parts involving a lawsuit and what have you, but it was certainly interesting to see a story about how one truly tragic incident can change the dynamics and personalities of a whole town community, it has got the right amount of intensity and atmosphere to keep you watching, a worthwhile psychological drama. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Director for Atom Egoyan (Felicia's Journey) and Best Writing, Screenplay Based on Material Previously Produced or Published. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Survivors Guilt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***SPOILERS*** We know right from the start where the film " The Sweet Hereafter" is headed in ambulance or school bus chasing shyster lawyer Mitchell Stevens, Ian Holm, on his way to this snowy little town in British Columbia Canada. Stevens is trying to get the people involved in a fatal school bus accident to help him start a class action suite against the bus company the bus driver as well as the town, Sam Dent, in what happened there. We also see that Stevens has problems of his own in that his teenage daughter Zoe,Caerthan Banks, is heavily into the drug scene and is later in the film found to be HIV or AIDS positive because of her non-stop drug use. It soon becomes obvious that Stevens in having his life screwed up, his wife also walked out on him, wants to help others like the school bus survivors and their families more then making any money for his services. It doesn't take to long for Stevens to find out that his services are no longer needed in that by him suing everyone or every thing in sight he's in fact opening up wounds in the community that have just started to begin healing. Wounds far more hurtful then what the people in Sam Dent have already suffered which in fact they were compensated for by the school bus company and despite it not being found responsible, for any shabby work on the road and guardrail,town. At first we dislike Stevens in his obsessive attempt to get the people in town to help him with his class action suit that many don't want to pursue. But later he turns out to be a victim of his own self righteousness in seeing he's going to hurt a lot of Innocent people with his suite who suffered , by surviving, even more then the victims whom he's to represent. One of them is the school bus driver Dorloes Driscoll, Gabriella Rose, who did everything to avoid her bus from skidding into a frozen lake and now has to live with the 14 children who ended up drowning in it on her conscience. There's also 15 year old Nicole Burnell, Sarah Polley, who survived the accident but ended up like the little boy in the story of "The Pide Piper of Hamlin", a favorite of hers, crippled and prevented from entering the land of "Good & Plenty" that the piper was taking the children of Hamlin to. ***SPOILERS*** Slow moving but extremely heart wrenching film that has no happy ending which in fact makes it one cut above the usual Hollywood schmaltz were used to watching about the subject matter that it presents to us. A lot like the movie released the year before in 1996 "Before and After" the film "The Sweet Hereafter" shows us how one survives a tragedy like losing a child with both dignity as well as grace instead of vengeance and self-guilt. Besides Nicole the film centers around Billy Hansel, Bruce Greenwood, the mechanic who serviced the school bus and knew that there was nothing wrong with it. Billy also lost his two children who were on the school bus that he witnessed, by driving behind it, crashing into the lake drowning them and their dozen or so classmate. For all the suffering that Billy and the rest of the people in Sam Dent went through he didn't want some shyster lawyer to make, excuse the pun, a killing off it! ***MAJOR SPOILER** In the end Stevens also lost a child, his daughter Zoe, through drug abuse and realized the only thing he can do now is try to put that tragic loss behind him like Billy as well as the crippled Nicole were doing and go on with his shattered life. It was Nicole who in her trying to put an end to the lawsuit that Stevens was pushing ended the whole affair by making up a preposterous story about the event,in Nicole being a star whiteness, that had it thrown out of court. Which allowed the healing process that Stevens tried to disrupt to continue and thus make things better for her as well as Mitchell Stevens and everyone else involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pied Piper of Hamelin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The summary will make sense once you have seen this. The Canadian film industry is one that I am now really getting into. This movie has a very disjointed structure and one that might be hard-to-follow for some people, which really is my only complaint though. The plot deals with 'tragedy', in particular losing your child. This occurs throughout the film and not just with the townsfolk that lost their kids in the bus crash, but Ian Holm's character has a drug-addicted daughter in this as well which also continues this theme outside of the townsfolk. If you want to watch a movie with good dialogue and characters with a lot of depth then I suggest watching, although to keep you in the right frame of mind then watch this movie expecting a dark, well-made period drama, that was what I was expecting and it was fulfilled in all aspects. No wonder this is considered Canada's best film, that title is deservingly so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Compassionate and reflective masterpiece..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egptian-born Canadian screenwriter, producer and director Atom Egoyan's seventh feature film, an adaptation of American writer Russel Banks' novel from 1991 which was inspired by a true story concerning a school bus accident in Alton, Texas 1989, tells the story of middle-aged attorney Mitchell Stevens who arrives in a remote rural district of Canada in December 1995 to report the circumstances surrounding a tragic school bus accident and help the parents of the victims to file an insurance-case against the bus company. A task that becomes difficult when he learns that most of the parents have numerous dark secrets. As he gets closer to the inhabitants of the small community it becomes apparent that this case has a strong personal influence on him, but his devotion brings nothing good to the parents, who begins to question his motives when they see that the case has more meaning to him than to them. The great score, the mindful dialog and the lyrical cinematography by Paul Sarossy emphasizes the emphatic and mysterious atmosphere in this resonating and realistic psychological drama which is beautifully filmed by Atom Egoyan, who creates versatile perspectives with his nuanced and subtle camera movements. His detailed and introspective screenplay examines how a bus accident affects the people in a small community and the aftermath of sorrow in a profound way, and portrays an in-depth study of character about a grieving man who has a restrained relationship to a daughter he hardly ever sees and who finds comfort and identifies with the parents who lost their children in the accident. Ian Holm's interpretation of the lawyer is outstanding in a refined and understated performance. The overall acting is good and Sarah Polley delivers a remarkable acting performance in her breakthrough role as teenager Nicole Purnell. During this brilliantly directed Canadian film, a short poem from 1842 called "The Pied Piper of Hamelin" by English poet and playwright Robert Browning (1812-1889) is read through Sarah Polley's voice-over. This fairy-tale forms a fine parallel to the story about the lawyer and the parents. With it's underlying lyrical aura and captivating narrative, this independent film stands as a poetic, compassionate and reflective masterpiece from the late 1990s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter-1997: Where time and grief just don't exist.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a simple story  simple in the sense described in the Storyline on the IMDb main page. But, it's from Russell Banks's novel that Atom Egoyan has written and directed one of the most complex plots ever put to film. For those interested, you'll find a complete analysis of this film's structure in Screen writing Updated by Linda Aronson, published in 2000. Incidentally, Russell Banks played the part of Dr Robeson. Avoiding the usual type of visual cues, Egoyan shows only two dates on screen to help orient the viewer to the time shifts (there are multiple shifts); instead, most are managed and revealed through the context of the scene and dialog. Which means the viewer must listen and watch carefully to stay on track. Some viewers might be annoyed. Adding to the complexity is the presentation of five different stories in the 112 minutes running time: the accident, the intrusive lawyer Mitchell (Ian Holm) and his daughter, Zoe (Caerthan Banks), the overly-motherly bus driver Dolores (Gabrielle Rose), the sex affair between Billy (Bruce Greenwood) and Risa (Alberta Watson) and, of course, the illicit and incestuous situation between Nicole (Sarah Polley) and her father, Sam (Tom McCamus). It takes a master film-maker to put all that together and achieve a work of art. On that basis, all serious film lovers should not miss this event, even if the story is unpalatable for many. Life, however, is full of such stories: read the daily tabloids. Ian Holm is the focus and catalyst of this narrative, for two reasons: first, he is, to some extent, the typical (or not so-typical) "ambulance chaser" after a buck, or too many; hence, much of the action involves his presence. Second, he is also after justice for the dead and lost children, spurred on because he lost Zoe to drugs, alcohol, AIDS etc  so she is effectively dead to him also. By trying to help the town folk in their loss, he hopes to achieve some sense of closure for his own loss  in other words, a self-serving attitude, much like the world in general. I think Holm gives the performance of his life in this film. For me, the greatest pleasure was listening to the voice-over of The Pied Piper of Hamelin, the narration of which is spoken by Nicole throughout the film. That poem serves to function as a metaphor of course for the fate that awaits her and her father: loneliness, sadness and despair in a cruel and indifferent world, while all the deceased children have moved on to the sweet hereafter. Not to be missed. November 27, 2011.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as exceptional as expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So this is the best rated movie of Atom Egoyan? I love his movies, and I have to say, sadly I expected a bit more. Don't get me wrong, cinematic everything is perfect. This movie is filmed beautifully. Every actor played on an extremely high level and not a single miscast was to be found in this movie! Overall it was a great watch. For me that was only destructed by the story. To me it felt, that the original novel was not suited to become a movie. The whole movie lacked a red thread. Strings didn't seem to be connected, and i failed finding a bigger meaning. All I found have been starting points, ideas. Great ideas, but in the end, the movie didn't work for me. It almost convinced me, but ultimately failed at the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ZzZzzZzZzZzzzZ
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know, to enjoy this film you have to be very patient. It runs very slowly, nothing interesting happens, there are too many names and different people coming and going, you never know what's going on; More than that, you don't get to see the accident until 60 minutes. It's like you're watching a soap opera with good actors, but with a unsatisfying development. 70 minutes was enough for me to turn it off because of it's boring scenes and conversations. I really expected much more for "Sweet Hereafter"; you know, it didn't work for me personally, don't know how it'd work with other people. IMDb wants me to write more, so I'll just repeat that I didn't like that...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great story which could be better told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shhazam2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite the director Atom Egoyan's misuse and overuse of flashbacks and flash forwards, this movie contained a great story. A terrible tragedy from which there was no emotional relief for the survivors except the chance for one to exact punishment for incest and child abuse. This story could have been told almost strictly chronologically from before the accident to after the accident without misusing the flashback technique and saving that technique for some of the background of the attorney which was still very well played by Ian Holm. Be patient with this movie and forgiving of the flash back misuse and you will have seen a gem of a story told about a tragic happening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Sal
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sweet Hereafter is 1997 Canadian drama movie based on a novel by Russell Banks of the same name. The screen play is written and directed by critically acclaimed director Atom Egoyon . The Film stars Ian Holm, Sarah Polly, Bruce Greenwood, AlbertaWatson, Simon Baker, Marc Donato, Broke Johnson, Maury Chaykin, Stephanie Morgenstern, Carthain Banks, Tom MeCamus, Russell Banks (cameo) and Gabrielle Rose. The Sweet Hereafter tells the story of a horrible school bus crashing accident that killed numerous local children. Their shattered and grieving parents are approached by a lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Ian Holm) who is hunted by the problems of his own, he wants them to file a class action lawsuit to sue for the damages by claiming the bus was faulty. Some of the parents at first are unwilling but they are persuaded by Mitchel Stevens that suing for damages is the right thing to do, some parents shows interest only because of the big settlement and some parents just want justice to be done. As most of the children are dead the case mainly depends only on 3 people that witnessed the accident, the bus driver Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose), Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polly) who was sitting at the front of the bus and who is now paralyzed below the waist because of the bus crashing accident and Billy (Bruce Greenwood) who was following the bus. Dolores Driscoll is willing to help to prove it wasn't her fault, Nicole Burnell is reluctant at first but agrees to help only on a condition that she wouldn't lie but Billy who lost 2 kids in the accident is against the lawsuit and tries to convince other parents to drop the lawsuit but nobody listens to him and tells him to stay out of it. In the pretrial deposition, Nicole Burnell lies and accuses the bus driver Dolores Driscoll of over speeding and thus causing the accident. After doing so all the hopes of suing the bus company with the possibility of big settlement disappears. The intention behind Nicole's lie is to punish her father who was sexually abusing her before the crash. Everybody that suffered from the accident or those who are involved in the case knows that Nicole is lying but nothing can be done and the trial never takes place. The story of the movie unfolds in non chronological order it jumps back and forth from one plot to another many times and loses the momentum. At first it was OK but after a while it was hard to watch because it never focused on the main story. In start we are introduced to several characters and each character has a story of its own. There are many different events besides the crash, which distracts the attention from the main plot. Mitchell Stevens daughter Zoe is a drug addict and she hates her father but its never explained what she hates him for also by the end of the movie Zoe tests positive for a blood test and its not explained what the test was for aids, pregnancy or something else. Also Zoe at first is shown as a homeless druggie but by the end she is well dressed. Billy has an affair with Risa (Alberta Watson) who is married to Windol (Maury Chaykin) but its never told why Risa is cheating on Windol or why can't she just leave him if she doesn't love him. Billy has also lost 2 kids in the accident but he is against the lawsuit because he knows it was just an accident and according to him it's wrong to sue for the damages but isn't it wrong to have an affair with a married woman? In the start of the movie its shown that Nicole loves her father (Sam MeCamus) and that they have a nice father daughter relationship but halfway its shown that Nicole is sexually abused by her father and by the end of the movie its shown that she hates him and therefor in order to punish him she lies and accuses an innocent person for the bus crash. Dolores Driscoll is held responsible for the accident because of over speeding but at the end of the movie she is back to driving some kind of airport passenger bus, how can she be hired just after two years for driving again when she is held responsible for the bus crash. Even the movie poster is taken from a scene that has nothing to do with the main plot of the movie. Ian Holm as Mitchel Stevens is a bit over dramatic at times but overall he plays the character nicely. Sarah Polly as Nicole Burnell does justice to her character and changes her facial expressions from a sweet to a serious bitter teen. Bruce Greenwood as Billy is convening, apart from Ion Holm, Sarah Polly and Bruce Greenwood all other actors are flat and plain and no one seems to be convincing enough in their respective characters. Atom Egoyon screenplay is too weak and confusing, he fails in directing The Sweet hereafter, he doesn't uses the right tone and right timing to introduce the characters and unfolds the story in non chronological order which only confuses the audience with all those subplots, The only good thing about his directing is choosing the beautiful locations for shoot. Cinematography is beautifully done by Paul Sarossy. Almost all of the main characters have a story, which is never explained, their personal stories are never given the depth they needed. I hardly see any place for those untold personal stories in the movie but they are introduced which drags the attention from the main plot and half way through the movie I didn't care for the accident and just wanted the movie to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    British actor Ian Holm gives a new meaning to a tale about selfishness directed by Atom Egoyan.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After an attentive viewing session,most attentive viewers would not fail at all to notice that the most recognizable feature of "The Sweet Hereafter" is its candid portrayal of selfishness. It is precisely this feeling which helps us to understand how some selfish individuals want to derive advantage from other people's suffering.This has been depicted through British actor Ian Holm whose extraordinary performance suggests that selfish people are always armed with their own ingenious explanations about their acts which in the long run bring them their fair share of misery instead of happiness.Canadian auteur Atom Egoyan whose film is an adaptation of a best selling work by Russell Banks is hardly partial when it comes to describe how ordinary people deal with guilt especially when it concerns untimely death of loved ones.No viewer would like to side with the film's characters who are full of idiosyncrasies as nobody is innocent.It is no wonder that good photography and natural setting enhance this film's viewing experience for viewers at a time when its slow pace acts as a veritable spoilsport. Finally,The Sweet Hereafter is a film to be watched at all costs if you have not seen a film which has been praised excessively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die is the book I found out about this film, it sounded like and I confirmed it as an independent film, the title obviously had some association with death, but I didn't know anything about the plot, so it would be interesting for me to try whatever. Basically a small town has been devastated by a tragic event; a school bus driven by Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose) and loaded with most of the children of the town attending the local school was driving during the snowy winter morning, when it suddenly hit an icy patch, it skids off road down the hill until it reaches the lake an crashes through the ice and sinks, drowning most victims inside. Many of the isolated village community members are mourning the deaths of their children, including Billy (Bruce Greenwood), the Walkers who lost their mentally developed and challenged son Sean (Devon Finn), and the Ottos who lost their aboriginal son Bear (Simon Baker) who was adopted. Some did survive the accident, including now wheelchair bound aspiring songstress Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polley), and Dolores, we see the accident in flashbacks while lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Sir Ian Holm) has arrived in the Canadian town wanting to take some slight advantage of the situation and get the parents of the twenty dead children to sue whatever party may be guilty for causing the incident, he will obviously represent those who agree to it. He plans to target the big companies and organisations with big amounts of money and who have some involvement with the school, most of the parents he see accept his proposal and see it as some way to get over the grieving, others are simply interested in the potential for the money, and some like Billy want nothing to do with a lawsuit. Stevens himself has demons as he suffered the death of his son and still feels grief, so he knows how the victims feel, but his son's death has also resulted in his daughter Zoe (Caerthan Banks) turning to drugs, losing respect for her father and any real relationship with him, and he knows life in the town has never been the same since this terrible event. Also starring Tom McCamus as Sam Burnell, Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian as Wanda Otto, Alberta Watson as Risa Walker, Mousehunt's Maury Chaykin as Wendell Walker, Brooke Johnson as Mary Burnell, David Hemblen as Abbott Driscoll and Peter Donaldson as Schwartz. Holm gives a pretty good glum performance as the ambulance-chasing who is trying to earn but also help those in the same grief-stricken situation he is in, Greenwood gets a reasonably good amount of time on screen, and I agree that from what I remember Polley is exceptional as the survivor paralysed by the accident. I will confess that I drifted in some of the story, particularly the parts involving a lawsuit and what have you, but it was certainly interesting to see a story about how one truly tragic incident can change the dynamics and personalities of a whole town community, it has got the right amount of intensity and atmosphere to keep you watching, a worthwhile psychological drama. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Director for Atom Egoyan (Felicia's Journey) and Best Writing, Screenplay Based on Material Previously Produced or Published. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Survivors Guilt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***SPOILERS*** We know right from the start where the film " The Sweet Hereafter" is headed in ambulance or school bus chasing shyster lawyer Mitchell Stevens, Ian Holm, on his way to this snowy little town in British Columbia Canada. Stevens is trying to get the people involved in a fatal school bus accident to help him start a class action suite against the bus company the bus driver as well as the town, Sam Dent, in what happened there. We also see that Stevens has problems of his own in that his teenage daughter Zoe,Caerthan Banks, is heavily into the drug scene and is later in the film found to be HIV or AIDS positive because of her non-stop drug use. It soon becomes obvious that Stevens in having his life screwed up, his wife also walked out on him, wants to help others like the school bus survivors and their families more then making any money for his services. It doesn't take to long for Stevens to find out that his services are no longer needed in that by him suing everyone or every thing in sight he's in fact opening up wounds in the community that have just started to begin healing. Wounds far more hurtful then what the people in Sam Dent have already suffered which in fact they were compensated for by the school bus company and despite it not being found responsible, for any shabby work on the road and guardrail,town. At first we dislike Stevens in his obsessive attempt to get the people in town to help him with his class action suit that many don't want to pursue. But later he turns out to be a victim of his own self righteousness in seeing he's going to hurt a lot of Innocent people with his suite who suffered , by surviving, even more then the victims whom he's to represent. One of them is the school bus driver Dorloes Driscoll, Gabriella Rose, who did everything to avoid her bus from skidding into a frozen lake and now has to live with the 14 children who ended up drowning in it on her conscience. There's also 15 year old Nicole Burnell, Sarah Polley, who survived the accident but ended up like the little boy in the story of "The Pide Piper of Hamlin", a favorite of hers, crippled and prevented from entering the land of "Good & Plenty" that the piper was taking the children of Hamlin to. ***SPOILERS*** Slow moving but extremely heart wrenching film that has no happy ending which in fact makes it one cut above the usual Hollywood schmaltz were used to watching about the subject matter that it presents to us. A lot like the movie released the year before in 1996 "Before and After" the film "The Sweet Hereafter" shows us how one survives a tragedy like losing a child with both dignity as well as grace instead of vengeance and self-guilt. Besides Nicole the film centers around Billy Hansel, Bruce Greenwood, the mechanic who serviced the school bus and knew that there was nothing wrong with it. Billy also lost his two children who were on the school bus that he witnessed, by driving behind it, crashing into the lake drowning them and their dozen or so classmate. For all the suffering that Billy and the rest of the people in Sam Dent went through he didn't want some shyster lawyer to make, excuse the pun, a killing off it! ***MAJOR SPOILER** In the end Stevens also lost a child, his daughter Zoe, through drug abuse and realized the only thing he can do now is try to put that tragic loss behind him like Billy as well as the crippled Nicole were doing and go on with his shattered life. It was Nicole who in her trying to put an end to the lawsuit that Stevens was pushing ended the whole affair by making up a preposterous story about the event,in Nicole being a star whiteness, that had it thrown out of court. Which allowed the healing process that Stevens tried to disrupt to continue and thus make things better for her as well as Mitchell Stevens and everyone else involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pied Piper of Hamelin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The summary will make sense once you have seen this. The Canadian film industry is one that I am now really getting into. This movie has a very disjointed structure and one that might be hard-to-follow for some people, which really is my only complaint though. The plot deals with 'tragedy', in particular losing your child. This occurs throughout the film and not just with the townsfolk that lost their kids in the bus crash, but Ian Holm's character has a drug-addicted daughter in this as well which also continues this theme outside of the townsfolk. If you want to watch a movie with good dialogue and characters with a lot of depth then I suggest watching, although to keep you in the right frame of mind then watch this movie expecting a dark, well-made period drama, that was what I was expecting and it was fulfilled in all aspects. No wonder this is considered Canada's best film, that title is deservingly so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Compassionate and reflective masterpiece..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egptian-born Canadian screenwriter, producer and director Atom Egoyan's seventh feature film, an adaptation of American writer Russel Banks' novel from 1991 which was inspired by a true story concerning a school bus accident in Alton, Texas 1989, tells the story of middle-aged attorney Mitchell Stevens who arrives in a remote rural district of Canada in December 1995 to report the circumstances surrounding a tragic school bus accident and help the parents of the victims to file an insurance-case against the bus company. A task that becomes difficult when he learns that most of the parents have numerous dark secrets. As he gets closer to the inhabitants of the small community it becomes apparent that this case has a strong personal influence on him, but his devotion brings nothing good to the parents, who begins to question his motives when they see that the case has more meaning to him than to them. The great score, the mindful dialog and the lyrical cinematography by Paul Sarossy emphasizes the emphatic and mysterious atmosphere in this resonating and realistic psychological drama which is beautifully filmed by Atom Egoyan, who creates versatile perspectives with his nuanced and subtle camera movements. His detailed and introspective screenplay examines how a bus accident affects the people in a small community and the aftermath of sorrow in a profound way, and portrays an in-depth study of character about a grieving man who has a restrained relationship to a daughter he hardly ever sees and who finds comfort and identifies with the parents who lost their children in the accident. Ian Holm's interpretation of the lawyer is outstanding in a refined and understated performance. The overall acting is good and Sarah Polley delivers a remarkable acting performance in her breakthrough role as teenager Nicole Purnell. During this brilliantly directed Canadian film, a short poem from 1842 called "The Pied Piper of Hamelin" by English poet and playwright Robert Browning (1812-1889) is read through Sarah Polley's voice-over. This fairy-tale forms a fine parallel to the story about the lawyer and the parents. With it's underlying lyrical aura and captivating narrative, this independent film stands as a poetic, compassionate and reflective masterpiece from the late 1990s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter-1997: Where time and grief just don't exist.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a simple story  simple in the sense described in the Storyline on the IMDb main page. But, it's from Russell Banks's novel that Atom Egoyan has written and directed one of the most complex plots ever put to film. For those interested, you'll find a complete analysis of this film's structure in Screen writing Updated by Linda Aronson, published in 2000. Incidentally, Russell Banks played the part of Dr Robeson. Avoiding the usual type of visual cues, Egoyan shows only two dates on screen to help orient the viewer to the time shifts (there are multiple shifts); instead, most are managed and revealed through the context of the scene and dialog. Which means the viewer must listen and watch carefully to stay on track. Some viewers might be annoyed. Adding to the complexity is the presentation of five different stories in the 112 minutes running time: the accident, the intrusive lawyer Mitchell (Ian Holm) and his daughter, Zoe (Caerthan Banks), the overly-motherly bus driver Dolores (Gabrielle Rose), the sex affair between Billy (Bruce Greenwood) and Risa (Alberta Watson) and, of course, the illicit and incestuous situation between Nicole (Sarah Polley) and her father, Sam (Tom McCamus). It takes a master film-maker to put all that together and achieve a work of art. On that basis, all serious film lovers should not miss this event, even if the story is unpalatable for many. Life, however, is full of such stories: read the daily tabloids. Ian Holm is the focus and catalyst of this narrative, for two reasons: first, he is, to some extent, the typical (or not so-typical) "ambulance chaser" after a buck, or too many; hence, much of the action involves his presence. Second, he is also after justice for the dead and lost children, spurred on because he lost Zoe to drugs, alcohol, AIDS etc  so she is effectively dead to him also. By trying to help the town folk in their loss, he hopes to achieve some sense of closure for his own loss  in other words, a self-serving attitude, much like the world in general. I think Holm gives the performance of his life in this film. For me, the greatest pleasure was listening to the voice-over of The Pied Piper of Hamelin, the narration of which is spoken by Nicole throughout the film. That poem serves to function as a metaphor of course for the fate that awaits her and her father: loneliness, sadness and despair in a cruel and indifferent world, while all the deceased children have moved on to the sweet hereafter. Not to be missed. November 27, 2011.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as exceptional as expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So this is the best rated movie of Atom Egoyan? I love his movies, and I have to say, sadly I expected a bit more. Don't get me wrong, cinematic everything is perfect. This movie is filmed beautifully. Every actor played on an extremely high level and not a single miscast was to be found in this movie! Overall it was a great watch. For me that was only destructed by the story. To me it felt, that the original novel was not suited to become a movie. The whole movie lacked a red thread. Strings didn't seem to be connected, and i failed finding a bigger meaning. All I found have been starting points, ideas. Great ideas, but in the end, the movie didn't work for me. It almost convinced me, but ultimately failed at the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ZzZzzZzZzZzzzZ
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know, to enjoy this film you have to be very patient. It runs very slowly, nothing interesting happens, there are too many names and different people coming and going, you never know what's going on; More than that, you don't get to see the accident until 60 minutes. It's like you're watching a soap opera with good actors, but with a unsatisfying development. 70 minutes was enough for me to turn it off because of it's boring scenes and conversations. I really expected much more for "Sweet Hereafter"; you know, it didn't work for me personally, don't know how it'd work with other people. IMDb wants me to write more, so I'll just repeat that I didn't like that...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great story which could be better told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shhazam2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite the director Atom Egoyan's misuse and overuse of flashbacks and flash forwards, this movie contained a great story. A terrible tragedy from which there was no emotional relief for the survivors except the chance for one to exact punishment for incest and child abuse. This story could have been told almost strictly chronologically from before the accident to after the accident without misusing the flashback technique and saving that technique for some of the background of the attorney which was still very well played by Ian Holm. Be patient with this movie and forgiving of the flash back misuse and you will have seen a gem of a story told about a tragic happening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Sal
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sweet Hereafter is 1997 Canadian drama movie based on a novel by Russell Banks of the same name. The screen play is written and directed by critically acclaimed director Atom Egoyon . The Film stars Ian Holm, Sarah Polly, Bruce Greenwood, AlbertaWatson, Simon Baker, Marc Donato, Broke Johnson, Maury Chaykin, Stephanie Morgenstern, Carthain Banks, Tom MeCamus, Russell Banks (cameo) and Gabrielle Rose. The Sweet Hereafter tells the story of a horrible school bus crashing accident that killed numerous local children. Their shattered and grieving parents are approached by a lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Ian Holm) who is hunted by the problems of his own, he wants them to file a class action lawsuit to sue for the damages by claiming the bus was faulty. Some of the parents at first are unwilling but they are persuaded by Mitchel Stevens that suing for damages is the right thing to do, some parents shows interest only because of the big settlement and some parents just want justice to be done. As most of the children are dead the case mainly depends only on 3 people that witnessed the accident, the bus driver Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose), Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polly) who was sitting at the front of the bus and who is now paralyzed below the waist because of the bus crashing accident and Billy (Bruce Greenwood) who was following the bus. Dolores Driscoll is willing to help to prove it wasn't her fault, Nicole Burnell is reluctant at first but agrees to help only on a condition that she wouldn't lie but Billy who lost 2 kids in the accident is against the lawsuit and tries to convince other parents to drop the lawsuit but nobody listens to him and tells him to stay out of it. In the pretrial deposition, Nicole Burnell lies and accuses the bus driver Dolores Driscoll of over speeding and thus causing the accident. After doing so all the hopes of suing the bus company with the possibility of big settlement disappears. The intention behind Nicole's lie is to punish her father who was sexually abusing her before the crash. Everybody that suffered from the accident or those who are involved in the case knows that Nicole is lying but nothing can be done and the trial never takes place. The story of the movie unfolds in non chronological order it jumps back and forth from one plot to another many times and loses the momentum. At first it was OK but after a while it was hard to watch because it never focused on the main story. In start we are introduced to several characters and each character has a story of its own. There are many different events besides the crash, which distracts the attention from the main plot. Mitchell Stevens daughter Zoe is a drug addict and she hates her father but its never explained what she hates him for also by the end of the movie Zoe tests positive for a blood test and its not explained what the test was for aids, pregnancy or something else. Also Zoe at first is shown as a homeless druggie but by the end she is well dressed. Billy has an affair with Risa (Alberta Watson) who is married to Windol (Maury Chaykin) but its never told why Risa is cheating on Windol or why can't she just leave him if she doesn't love him. Billy has also lost 2 kids in the accident but he is against the lawsuit because he knows it was just an accident and according to him it's wrong to sue for the damages but isn't it wrong to have an affair with a married woman? In the start of the movie its shown that Nicole loves her father (Sam MeCamus) and that they have a nice father daughter relationship but halfway its shown that Nicole is sexually abused by her father and by the end of the movie its shown that she hates him and therefor in order to punish him she lies and accuses an innocent person for the bus crash. Dolores Driscoll is held responsible for the accident because of over speeding but at the end of the movie she is back to driving some kind of airport passenger bus, how can she be hired just after two years for driving again when she is held responsible for the bus crash. Even the movie poster is taken from a scene that has nothing to do with the main plot of the movie. Ian Holm as Mitchel Stevens is a bit over dramatic at times but overall he plays the character nicely. Sarah Polly as Nicole Burnell does justice to her character and changes her facial expressions from a sweet to a serious bitter teen. Bruce Greenwood as Billy is convening, apart from Ion Holm, Sarah Polly and Bruce Greenwood all other actors are flat and plain and no one seems to be convincing enough in their respective characters. Atom Egoyon screenplay is too weak and confusing, he fails in directing The Sweet hereafter, he doesn't uses the right tone and right timing to introduce the characters and unfolds the story in non chronological order which only confuses the audience with all those subplots, The only good thing about his directing is choosing the beautiful locations for shoot. Cinematography is beautifully done by Paul Sarossy. Almost all of the main characters have a story, which is never explained, their personal stories are never given the depth they needed. I hardly see any place for those untold personal stories in the movie but they are introduced which drags the attention from the main plot and half way through the movie I didn't care for the accident and just wanted the movie to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    British actor Ian Holm gives a new meaning to a tale about selfishness directed by Atom Egoyan.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After an attentive viewing session,most attentive viewers would not fail at all to notice that the most recognizable feature of "The Sweet Hereafter" is its candid portrayal of selfishness. It is precisely this feeling which helps us to understand how some selfish individuals want to derive advantage from other people's suffering.This has been depicted through British actor Ian Holm whose extraordinary performance suggests that selfish people are always armed with their own ingenious explanations about their acts which in the long run bring them their fair share of misery instead of happiness.Canadian auteur Atom Egoyan whose film is an adaptation of a best selling work by Russell Banks is hardly partial when it comes to describe how ordinary people deal with guilt especially when it concerns untimely death of loved ones.No viewer would like to side with the film's characters who are full of idiosyncrasies as nobody is innocent.It is no wonder that good photography and natural setting enhance this film's viewing experience for viewers at a time when its slow pace acts as a veritable spoilsport. Finally,The Sweet Hereafter is a film to be watched at all costs if you have not seen a film which has been praised excessively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die is the book I found out about this film, it sounded like and I confirmed it as an independent film, the title obviously had some association with death, but I didn't know anything about the plot, so it would be interesting for me to try whatever. Basically a small town has been devastated by a tragic event; a school bus driven by Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose) and loaded with most of the children of the town attending the local school was driving during the snowy winter morning, when it suddenly hit an icy patch, it skids off road down the hill until it reaches the lake an crashes through the ice and sinks, drowning most victims inside. Many of the isolated village community members are mourning the deaths of their children, including Billy (Bruce Greenwood), the Walkers who lost their mentally developed and challenged son Sean (Devon Finn), and the Ottos who lost their aboriginal son Bear (Simon Baker) who was adopted. Some did survive the accident, including now wheelchair bound aspiring songstress Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polley), and Dolores, we see the accident in flashbacks while lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Sir Ian Holm) has arrived in the Canadian town wanting to take some slight advantage of the situation and get the parents of the twenty dead children to sue whatever party may be guilty for causing the incident, he will obviously represent those who agree to it. He plans to target the big companies and organisations with big amounts of money and who have some involvement with the school, most of the parents he see accept his proposal and see it as some way to get over the grieving, others are simply interested in the potential for the money, and some like Billy want nothing to do with a lawsuit. Stevens himself has demons as he suffered the death of his son and still feels grief, so he knows how the victims feel, but his son's death has also resulted in his daughter Zoe (Caerthan Banks) turning to drugs, losing respect for her father and any real relationship with him, and he knows life in the town has never been the same since this terrible event. Also starring Tom McCamus as Sam Burnell, Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian as Wanda Otto, Alberta Watson as Risa Walker, Mousehunt's Maury Chaykin as Wendell Walker, Brooke Johnson as Mary Burnell, David Hemblen as Abbott Driscoll and Peter Donaldson as Schwartz. Holm gives a pretty good glum performance as the ambulance-chasing who is trying to earn but also help those in the same grief-stricken situation he is in, Greenwood gets a reasonably good amount of time on screen, and I agree that from what I remember Polley is exceptional as the survivor paralysed by the accident. I will confess that I drifted in some of the story, particularly the parts involving a lawsuit and what have you, but it was certainly interesting to see a story about how one truly tragic incident can change the dynamics and personalities of a whole town community, it has got the right amount of intensity and atmosphere to keep you watching, a worthwhile psychological drama. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Director for Atom Egoyan (Felicia's Journey) and Best Writing, Screenplay Based on Material Previously Produced or Published. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Survivors Guilt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***SPOILERS*** We know right from the start where the film " The Sweet Hereafter" is headed in ambulance or school bus chasing shyster lawyer Mitchell Stevens, Ian Holm, on his way to this snowy little town in British Columbia Canada. Stevens is trying to get the people involved in a fatal school bus accident to help him start a class action suite against the bus company the bus driver as well as the town, Sam Dent, in what happened there. We also see that Stevens has problems of his own in that his teenage daughter Zoe,Caerthan Banks, is heavily into the drug scene and is later in the film found to be HIV or AIDS positive because of her non-stop drug use. It soon becomes obvious that Stevens in having his life screwed up, his wife also walked out on him, wants to help others like the school bus survivors and their families more then making any money for his services. It doesn't take to long for Stevens to find out that his services are no longer needed in that by him suing everyone or every thing in sight he's in fact opening up wounds in the community that have just started to begin healing. Wounds far more hurtful then what the people in Sam Dent have already suffered which in fact they were compensated for by the school bus company and despite it not being found responsible, for any shabby work on the road and guardrail,town. At first we dislike Stevens in his obsessive attempt to get the people in town to help him with his class action suit that many don't want to pursue. But later he turns out to be a victim of his own self righteousness in seeing he's going to hurt a lot of Innocent people with his suite who suffered , by surviving, even more then the victims whom he's to represent. One of them is the school bus driver Dorloes Driscoll, Gabriella Rose, who did everything to avoid her bus from skidding into a frozen lake and now has to live with the 14 children who ended up drowning in it on her conscience. There's also 15 year old Nicole Burnell, Sarah Polley, who survived the accident but ended up like the little boy in the story of "The Pide Piper of Hamlin", a favorite of hers, crippled and prevented from entering the land of "Good & Plenty" that the piper was taking the children of Hamlin to. ***SPOILERS*** Slow moving but extremely heart wrenching film that has no happy ending which in fact makes it one cut above the usual Hollywood schmaltz were used to watching about the subject matter that it presents to us. A lot like the movie released the year before in 1996 "Before and After" the film "The Sweet Hereafter" shows us how one survives a tragedy like losing a child with both dignity as well as grace instead of vengeance and self-guilt. Besides Nicole the film centers around Billy Hansel, Bruce Greenwood, the mechanic who serviced the school bus and knew that there was nothing wrong with it. Billy also lost his two children who were on the school bus that he witnessed, by driving behind it, crashing into the lake drowning them and their dozen or so classmate. For all the suffering that Billy and the rest of the people in Sam Dent went through he didn't want some shyster lawyer to make, excuse the pun, a killing off it! ***MAJOR SPOILER** In the end Stevens also lost a child, his daughter Zoe, through drug abuse and realized the only thing he can do now is try to put that tragic loss behind him like Billy as well as the crippled Nicole were doing and go on with his shattered life. It was Nicole who in her trying to put an end to the lawsuit that Stevens was pushing ended the whole affair by making up a preposterous story about the event,in Nicole being a star whiteness, that had it thrown out of court. Which allowed the healing process that Stevens tried to disrupt to continue and thus make things better for her as well as Mitchell Stevens and everyone else involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pied Piper of Hamelin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The summary will make sense once you have seen this. The Canadian film industry is one that I am now really getting into. This movie has a very disjointed structure and one that might be hard-to-follow for some people, which really is my only complaint though. The plot deals with 'tragedy', in particular losing your child. This occurs throughout the film and not just with the townsfolk that lost their kids in the bus crash, but Ian Holm's character has a drug-addicted daughter in this as well which also continues this theme outside of the townsfolk. If you want to watch a movie with good dialogue and characters with a lot of depth then I suggest watching, although to keep you in the right frame of mind then watch this movie expecting a dark, well-made period drama, that was what I was expecting and it was fulfilled in all aspects. No wonder this is considered Canada's best film, that title is deservingly so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Compassionate and reflective masterpiece..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egptian-born Canadian screenwriter, producer and director Atom Egoyan's seventh feature film, an adaptation of American writer Russel Banks' novel from 1991 which was inspired by a true story concerning a school bus accident in Alton, Texas 1989, tells the story of middle-aged attorney Mitchell Stevens who arrives in a remote rural district of Canada in December 1995 to report the circumstances surrounding a tragic school bus accident and help the parents of the victims to file an insurance-case against the bus company. A task that becomes difficult when he learns that most of the parents have numerous dark secrets. As he gets closer to the inhabitants of the small community it becomes apparent that this case has a strong personal influence on him, but his devotion brings nothing good to the parents, who begins to question his motives when they see that the case has more meaning to him than to them. The great score, the mindful dialog and the lyrical cinematography by Paul Sarossy emphasizes the emphatic and mysterious atmosphere in this resonating and realistic psychological drama which is beautifully filmed by Atom Egoyan, who creates versatile perspectives with his nuanced and subtle camera movements. His detailed and introspective screenplay examines how a bus accident affects the people in a small community and the aftermath of sorrow in a profound way, and portrays an in-depth study of character about a grieving man who has a restrained relationship to a daughter he hardly ever sees and who finds comfort and identifies with the parents who lost their children in the accident. Ian Holm's interpretation of the lawyer is outstanding in a refined and understated performance. The overall acting is good and Sarah Polley delivers a remarkable acting performance in her breakthrough role as teenager Nicole Purnell. During this brilliantly directed Canadian film, a short poem from 1842 called "The Pied Piper of Hamelin" by English poet and playwright Robert Browning (1812-1889) is read through Sarah Polley's voice-over. This fairy-tale forms a fine parallel to the story about the lawyer and the parents. With it's underlying lyrical aura and captivating narrative, this independent film stands as a poetic, compassionate and reflective masterpiece from the late 1990s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter-1997: Where time and grief just don't exist.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a simple story  simple in the sense described in the Storyline on the IMDb main page. But, it's from Russell Banks's novel that Atom Egoyan has written and directed one of the most complex plots ever put to film. For those interested, you'll find a complete analysis of this film's structure in Screen writing Updated by Linda Aronson, published in 2000. Incidentally, Russell Banks played the part of Dr Robeson. Avoiding the usual type of visual cues, Egoyan shows only two dates on screen to help orient the viewer to the time shifts (there are multiple shifts); instead, most are managed and revealed through the context of the scene and dialog. Which means the viewer must listen and watch carefully to stay on track. Some viewers might be annoyed. Adding to the complexity is the presentation of five different stories in the 112 minutes running time: the accident, the intrusive lawyer Mitchell (Ian Holm) and his daughter, Zoe (Caerthan Banks), the overly-motherly bus driver Dolores (Gabrielle Rose), the sex affair between Billy (Bruce Greenwood) and Risa (Alberta Watson) and, of course, the illicit and incestuous situation between Nicole (Sarah Polley) and her father, Sam (Tom McCamus). It takes a master film-maker to put all that together and achieve a work of art. On that basis, all serious film lovers should not miss this event, even if the story is unpalatable for many. Life, however, is full of such stories: read the daily tabloids. Ian Holm is the focus and catalyst of this narrative, for two reasons: first, he is, to some extent, the typical (or not so-typical) "ambulance chaser" after a buck, or too many; hence, much of the action involves his presence. Second, he is also after justice for the dead and lost children, spurred on because he lost Zoe to drugs, alcohol, AIDS etc  so she is effectively dead to him also. By trying to help the town folk in their loss, he hopes to achieve some sense of closure for his own loss  in other words, a self-serving attitude, much like the world in general. I think Holm gives the performance of his life in this film. For me, the greatest pleasure was listening to the voice-over of The Pied Piper of Hamelin, the narration of which is spoken by Nicole throughout the film. That poem serves to function as a metaphor of course for the fate that awaits her and her father: loneliness, sadness and despair in a cruel and indifferent world, while all the deceased children have moved on to the sweet hereafter. Not to be missed. November 27, 2011.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as exceptional as expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So this is the best rated movie of Atom Egoyan? I love his movies, and I have to say, sadly I expected a bit more. Don't get me wrong, cinematic everything is perfect. This movie is filmed beautifully. Every actor played on an extremely high level and not a single miscast was to be found in this movie! Overall it was a great watch. For me that was only destructed by the story. To me it felt, that the original novel was not suited to become a movie. The whole movie lacked a red thread. Strings didn't seem to be connected, and i failed finding a bigger meaning. All I found have been starting points, ideas. Great ideas, but in the end, the movie didn't work for me. It almost convinced me, but ultimately failed at the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ZzZzzZzZzZzzzZ
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know, to enjoy this film you have to be very patient. It runs very slowly, nothing interesting happens, there are too many names and different people coming and going, you never know what's going on; More than that, you don't get to see the accident until 60 minutes. It's like you're watching a soap opera with good actors, but with a unsatisfying development. 70 minutes was enough for me to turn it off because of it's boring scenes and conversations. I really expected much more for "Sweet Hereafter"; you know, it didn't work for me personally, don't know how it'd work with other people. IMDb wants me to write more, so I'll just repeat that I didn't like that...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great story which could be better told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shhazam2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite the director Atom Egoyan's misuse and overuse of flashbacks and flash forwards, this movie contained a great story. A terrible tragedy from which there was no emotional relief for the survivors except the chance for one to exact punishment for incest and child abuse. This story could have been told almost strictly chronologically from before the accident to after the accident without misusing the flashback technique and saving that technique for some of the background of the attorney which was still very well played by Ian Holm. Be patient with this movie and forgiving of the flash back misuse and you will have seen a gem of a story told about a tragic happening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Sal
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sweet Hereafter is 1997 Canadian drama movie based on a novel by Russell Banks of the same name. The screen play is written and directed by critically acclaimed director Atom Egoyon . The Film stars Ian Holm, Sarah Polly, Bruce Greenwood, AlbertaWatson, Simon Baker, Marc Donato, Broke Johnson, Maury Chaykin, Stephanie Morgenstern, Carthain Banks, Tom MeCamus, Russell Banks (cameo) and Gabrielle Rose. The Sweet Hereafter tells the story of a horrible school bus crashing accident that killed numerous local children. Their shattered and grieving parents are approached by a lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Ian Holm) who is hunted by the problems of his own, he wants them to file a class action lawsuit to sue for the damages by claiming the bus was faulty. Some of the parents at first are unwilling but they are persuaded by Mitchel Stevens that suing for damages is the right thing to do, some parents shows interest only because of the big settlement and some parents just want justice to be done. As most of the children are dead the case mainly depends only on 3 people that witnessed the accident, the bus driver Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose), Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polly) who was sitting at the front of the bus and who is now paralyzed below the waist because of the bus crashing accident and Billy (Bruce Greenwood) who was following the bus. Dolores Driscoll is willing to help to prove it wasn't her fault, Nicole Burnell is reluctant at first but agrees to help only on a condition that she wouldn't lie but Billy who lost 2 kids in the accident is against the lawsuit and tries to convince other parents to drop the lawsuit but nobody listens to him and tells him to stay out of it. In the pretrial deposition, Nicole Burnell lies and accuses the bus driver Dolores Driscoll of over speeding and thus causing the accident. After doing so all the hopes of suing the bus company with the possibility of big settlement disappears. The intention behind Nicole's lie is to punish her father who was sexually abusing her before the crash. Everybody that suffered from the accident or those who are involved in the case knows that Nicole is lying but nothing can be done and the trial never takes place. The story of the movie unfolds in non chronological order it jumps back and forth from one plot to another many times and loses the momentum. At first it was OK but after a while it was hard to watch because it never focused on the main story. In start we are introduced to several characters and each character has a story of its own. There are many different events besides the crash, which distracts the attention from the main plot. Mitchell Stevens daughter Zoe is a drug addict and she hates her father but its never explained what she hates him for also by the end of the movie Zoe tests positive for a blood test and its not explained what the test was for aids, pregnancy or something else. Also Zoe at first is shown as a homeless druggie but by the end she is well dressed. Billy has an affair with Risa (Alberta Watson) who is married to Windol (Maury Chaykin) but its never told why Risa is cheating on Windol or why can't she just leave him if she doesn't love him. Billy has also lost 2 kids in the accident but he is against the lawsuit because he knows it was just an accident and according to him it's wrong to sue for the damages but isn't it wrong to have an affair with a married woman? In the start of the movie its shown that Nicole loves her father (Sam MeCamus) and that they have a nice father daughter relationship but halfway its shown that Nicole is sexually abused by her father and by the end of the movie its shown that she hates him and therefor in order to punish him she lies and accuses an innocent person for the bus crash. Dolores Driscoll is held responsible for the accident because of over speeding but at the end of the movie she is back to driving some kind of airport passenger bus, how can she be hired just after two years for driving again when she is held responsible for the bus crash. Even the movie poster is taken from a scene that has nothing to do with the main plot of the movie. Ian Holm as Mitchel Stevens is a bit over dramatic at times but overall he plays the character nicely. Sarah Polly as Nicole Burnell does justice to her character and changes her facial expressions from a sweet to a serious bitter teen. Bruce Greenwood as Billy is convening, apart from Ion Holm, Sarah Polly and Bruce Greenwood all other actors are flat and plain and no one seems to be convincing enough in their respective characters. Atom Egoyon screenplay is too weak and confusing, he fails in directing The Sweet hereafter, he doesn't uses the right tone and right timing to introduce the characters and unfolds the story in non chronological order which only confuses the audience with all those subplots, The only good thing about his directing is choosing the beautiful locations for shoot. Cinematography is beautifully done by Paul Sarossy. Almost all of the main characters have a story, which is never explained, their personal stories are never given the depth they needed. I hardly see any place for those untold personal stories in the movie but they are introduced which drags the attention from the main plot and half way through the movie I didn't care for the accident and just wanted the movie to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    British actor Ian Holm gives a new meaning to a tale about selfishness directed by Atom Egoyan.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After an attentive viewing session,most attentive viewers would not fail at all to notice that the most recognizable feature of "The Sweet Hereafter" is its candid portrayal of selfishness. It is precisely this feeling which helps us to understand how some selfish individuals want to derive advantage from other people's suffering.This has been depicted through British actor Ian Holm whose extraordinary performance suggests that selfish people are always armed with their own ingenious explanations about their acts which in the long run bring them their fair share of misery instead of happiness.Canadian auteur Atom Egoyan whose film is an adaptation of a best selling work by Russell Banks is hardly partial when it comes to describe how ordinary people deal with guilt especially when it concerns untimely death of loved ones.No viewer would like to side with the film's characters who are full of idiosyncrasies as nobody is innocent.It is no wonder that good photography and natural setting enhance this film's viewing experience for viewers at a time when its slow pace acts as a veritable spoilsport. Finally,The Sweet Hereafter is a film to be watched at all costs if you have not seen a film which has been praised excessively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die is the book I found out about this film, it sounded like and I confirmed it as an independent film, the title obviously had some association with death, but I didn't know anything about the plot, so it would be interesting for me to try whatever. Basically a small town has been devastated by a tragic event; a school bus driven by Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose) and loaded with most of the children of the town attending the local school was driving during the snowy winter morning, when it suddenly hit an icy patch, it skids off road down the hill until it reaches the lake an crashes through the ice and sinks, drowning most victims inside. Many of the isolated village community members are mourning the deaths of their children, including Billy (Bruce Greenwood), the Walkers who lost their mentally developed and challenged son Sean (Devon Finn), and the Ottos who lost their aboriginal son Bear (Simon Baker) who was adopted. Some did survive the accident, including now wheelchair bound aspiring songstress Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polley), and Dolores, we see the accident in flashbacks while lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Sir Ian Holm) has arrived in the Canadian town wanting to take some slight advantage of the situation and get the parents of the twenty dead children to sue whatever party may be guilty for causing the incident, he will obviously represent those who agree to it. He plans to target the big companies and organisations with big amounts of money and who have some involvement with the school, most of the parents he see accept his proposal and see it as some way to get over the grieving, others are simply interested in the potential for the money, and some like Billy want nothing to do with a lawsuit. Stevens himself has demons as he suffered the death of his son and still feels grief, so he knows how the victims feel, but his son's death has also resulted in his daughter Zoe (Caerthan Banks) turning to drugs, losing respect for her father and any real relationship with him, and he knows life in the town has never been the same since this terrible event. Also starring Tom McCamus as Sam Burnell, Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian as Wanda Otto, Alberta Watson as Risa Walker, Mousehunt's Maury Chaykin as Wendell Walker, Brooke Johnson as Mary Burnell, David Hemblen as Abbott Driscoll and Peter Donaldson as Schwartz. Holm gives a pretty good glum performance as the ambulance-chasing who is trying to earn but also help those in the same grief-stricken situation he is in, Greenwood gets a reasonably good amount of time on screen, and I agree that from what I remember Polley is exceptional as the survivor paralysed by the accident. I will confess that I drifted in some of the story, particularly the parts involving a lawsuit and what have you, but it was certainly interesting to see a story about how one truly tragic incident can change the dynamics and personalities of a whole town community, it has got the right amount of intensity and atmosphere to keep you watching, a worthwhile psychological drama. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Director for Atom Egoyan (Felicia's Journey) and Best Writing, Screenplay Based on Material Previously Produced or Published. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Survivors Guilt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***SPOILERS*** We know right from the start where the film " The Sweet Hereafter" is headed in ambulance or school bus chasing shyster lawyer Mitchell Stevens, Ian Holm, on his way to this snowy little town in British Columbia Canada. Stevens is trying to get the people involved in a fatal school bus accident to help him start a class action suite against the bus company the bus driver as well as the town, Sam Dent, in what happened there. We also see that Stevens has problems of his own in that his teenage daughter Zoe,Caerthan Banks, is heavily into the drug scene and is later in the film found to be HIV or AIDS positive because of her non-stop drug use. It soon becomes obvious that Stevens in having his life screwed up, his wife also walked out on him, wants to help others like the school bus survivors and their families more then making any money for his services. It doesn't take to long for Stevens to find out that his services are no longer needed in that by him suing everyone or every thing in sight he's in fact opening up wounds in the community that have just started to begin healing. Wounds far more hurtful then what the people in Sam Dent have already suffered which in fact they were compensated for by the school bus company and despite it not being found responsible, for any shabby work on the road and guardrail,town. At first we dislike Stevens in his obsessive attempt to get the people in town to help him with his class action suit that many don't want to pursue. But later he turns out to be a victim of his own self righteousness in seeing he's going to hurt a lot of Innocent people with his suite who suffered , by surviving, even more then the victims whom he's to represent. One of them is the school bus driver Dorloes Driscoll, Gabriella Rose, who did everything to avoid her bus from skidding into a frozen lake and now has to live with the 14 children who ended up drowning in it on her conscience. There's also 15 year old Nicole Burnell, Sarah Polley, who survived the accident but ended up like the little boy in the story of "The Pide Piper of Hamlin", a favorite of hers, crippled and prevented from entering the land of "Good & Plenty" that the piper was taking the children of Hamlin to. ***SPOILERS*** Slow moving but extremely heart wrenching film that has no happy ending which in fact makes it one cut above the usual Hollywood schmaltz were used to watching about the subject matter that it presents to us. A lot like the movie released the year before in 1996 "Before and After" the film "The Sweet Hereafter" shows us how one survives a tragedy like losing a child with both dignity as well as grace instead of vengeance and self-guilt. Besides Nicole the film centers around Billy Hansel, Bruce Greenwood, the mechanic who serviced the school bus and knew that there was nothing wrong with it. Billy also lost his two children who were on the school bus that he witnessed, by driving behind it, crashing into the lake drowning them and their dozen or so classmate. For all the suffering that Billy and the rest of the people in Sam Dent went through he didn't want some shyster lawyer to make, excuse the pun, a killing off it! ***MAJOR SPOILER** In the end Stevens also lost a child, his daughter Zoe, through drug abuse and realized the only thing he can do now is try to put that tragic loss behind him like Billy as well as the crippled Nicole were doing and go on with his shattered life. It was Nicole who in her trying to put an end to the lawsuit that Stevens was pushing ended the whole affair by making up a preposterous story about the event,in Nicole being a star whiteness, that had it thrown out of court. Which allowed the healing process that Stevens tried to disrupt to continue and thus make things better for her as well as Mitchell Stevens and everyone else involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pied Piper of Hamelin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The summary will make sense once you have seen this. The Canadian film industry is one that I am now really getting into. This movie has a very disjointed structure and one that might be hard-to-follow for some people, which really is my only complaint though. The plot deals with 'tragedy', in particular losing your child. This occurs throughout the film and not just with the townsfolk that lost their kids in the bus crash, but Ian Holm's character has a drug-addicted daughter in this as well which also continues this theme outside of the townsfolk. If you want to watch a movie with good dialogue and characters with a lot of depth then I suggest watching, although to keep you in the right frame of mind then watch this movie expecting a dark, well-made period drama, that was what I was expecting and it was fulfilled in all aspects. No wonder this is considered Canada's best film, that title is deservingly so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Compassionate and reflective masterpiece..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egptian-born Canadian screenwriter, producer and director Atom Egoyan's seventh feature film, an adaptation of American writer Russel Banks' novel from 1991 which was inspired by a true story concerning a school bus accident in Alton, Texas 1989, tells the story of middle-aged attorney Mitchell Stevens who arrives in a remote rural district of Canada in December 1995 to report the circumstances surrounding a tragic school bus accident and help the parents of the victims to file an insurance-case against the bus company. A task that becomes difficult when he learns that most of the parents have numerous dark secrets. As he gets closer to the inhabitants of the small community it becomes apparent that this case has a strong personal influence on him, but his devotion brings nothing good to the parents, who begins to question his motives when they see that the case has more meaning to him than to them. The great score, the mindful dialog and the lyrical cinematography by Paul Sarossy emphasizes the emphatic and mysterious atmosphere in this resonating and realistic psychological drama which is beautifully filmed by Atom Egoyan, who creates versatile perspectives with his nuanced and subtle camera movements. His detailed and introspective screenplay examines how a bus accident affects the people in a small community and the aftermath of sorrow in a profound way, and portrays an in-depth study of character about a grieving man who has a restrained relationship to a daughter he hardly ever sees and who finds comfort and identifies with the parents who lost their children in the accident. Ian Holm's interpretation of the lawyer is outstanding in a refined and understated performance. The overall acting is good and Sarah Polley delivers a remarkable acting performance in her breakthrough role as teenager Nicole Purnell. During this brilliantly directed Canadian film, a short poem from 1842 called "The Pied Piper of Hamelin" by English poet and playwright Robert Browning (1812-1889) is read through Sarah Polley's voice-over. This fairy-tale forms a fine parallel to the story about the lawyer and the parents. With it's underlying lyrical aura and captivating narrative, this independent film stands as a poetic, compassionate and reflective masterpiece from the late 1990s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter-1997: Where time and grief just don't exist.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a simple story  simple in the sense described in the Storyline on the IMDb main page. But, it's from Russell Banks's novel that Atom Egoyan has written and directed one of the most complex plots ever put to film. For those interested, you'll find a complete analysis of this film's structure in Screen writing Updated by Linda Aronson, published in 2000. Incidentally, Russell Banks played the part of Dr Robeson. Avoiding the usual type of visual cues, Egoyan shows only two dates on screen to help orient the viewer to the time shifts (there are multiple shifts); instead, most are managed and revealed through the context of the scene and dialog. Which means the viewer must listen and watch carefully to stay on track. Some viewers might be annoyed. Adding to the complexity is the presentation of five different stories in the 112 minutes running time: the accident, the intrusive lawyer Mitchell (Ian Holm) and his daughter, Zoe (Caerthan Banks), the overly-motherly bus driver Dolores (Gabrielle Rose), the sex affair between Billy (Bruce Greenwood) and Risa (Alberta Watson) and, of course, the illicit and incestuous situation between Nicole (Sarah Polley) and her father, Sam (Tom McCamus). It takes a master film-maker to put all that together and achieve a work of art. On that basis, all serious film lovers should not miss this event, even if the story is unpalatable for many. Life, however, is full of such stories: read the daily tabloids. Ian Holm is the focus and catalyst of this narrative, for two reasons: first, he is, to some extent, the typical (or not so-typical) "ambulance chaser" after a buck, or too many; hence, much of the action involves his presence. Second, he is also after justice for the dead and lost children, spurred on because he lost Zoe to drugs, alcohol, AIDS etc  so she is effectively dead to him also. By trying to help the town folk in their loss, he hopes to achieve some sense of closure for his own loss  in other words, a self-serving attitude, much like the world in general. I think Holm gives the performance of his life in this film. For me, the greatest pleasure was listening to the voice-over of The Pied Piper of Hamelin, the narration of which is spoken by Nicole throughout the film. That poem serves to function as a metaphor of course for the fate that awaits her and her father: loneliness, sadness and despair in a cruel and indifferent world, while all the deceased children have moved on to the sweet hereafter. Not to be missed. November 27, 2011.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as exceptional as expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So this is the best rated movie of Atom Egoyan? I love his movies, and I have to say, sadly I expected a bit more. Don't get me wrong, cinematic everything is perfect. This movie is filmed beautifully. Every actor played on an extremely high level and not a single miscast was to be found in this movie! Overall it was a great watch. For me that was only destructed by the story. To me it felt, that the original novel was not suited to become a movie. The whole movie lacked a red thread. Strings didn't seem to be connected, and i failed finding a bigger meaning. All I found have been starting points, ideas. Great ideas, but in the end, the movie didn't work for me. It almost convinced me, but ultimately failed at the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ZzZzzZzZzZzzzZ
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know, to enjoy this film you have to be very patient. It runs very slowly, nothing interesting happens, there are too many names and different people coming and going, you never know what's going on; More than that, you don't get to see the accident until 60 minutes. It's like you're watching a soap opera with good actors, but with a unsatisfying development. 70 minutes was enough for me to turn it off because of it's boring scenes and conversations. I really expected much more for "Sweet Hereafter"; you know, it didn't work for me personally, don't know how it'd work with other people. IMDb wants me to write more, so I'll just repeat that I didn't like that...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great story which could be better told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shhazam2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite the director Atom Egoyan's misuse and overuse of flashbacks and flash forwards, this movie contained a great story. A terrible tragedy from which there was no emotional relief for the survivors except the chance for one to exact punishment for incest and child abuse. This story could have been told almost strictly chronologically from before the accident to after the accident without misusing the flashback technique and saving that technique for some of the background of the attorney which was still very well played by Ian Holm. Be patient with this movie and forgiving of the flash back misuse and you will have seen a gem of a story told about a tragic happening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Sal
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sweet Hereafter is 1997 Canadian drama movie based on a novel by Russell Banks of the same name. The screen play is written and directed by critically acclaimed director Atom Egoyon . The Film stars Ian Holm, Sarah Polly, Bruce Greenwood, AlbertaWatson, Simon Baker, Marc Donato, Broke Johnson, Maury Chaykin, Stephanie Morgenstern, Carthain Banks, Tom MeCamus, Russell Banks (cameo) and Gabrielle Rose. The Sweet Hereafter tells the story of a horrible school bus crashing accident that killed numerous local children. Their shattered and grieving parents are approached by a lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Ian Holm) who is hunted by the problems of his own, he wants them to file a class action lawsuit to sue for the damages by claiming the bus was faulty. Some of the parents at first are unwilling but they are persuaded by Mitchel Stevens that suing for damages is the right thing to do, some parents shows interest only because of the big settlement and some parents just want justice to be done. As most of the children are dead the case mainly depends only on 3 people that witnessed the accident, the bus driver Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose), Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polly) who was sitting at the front of the bus and who is now paralyzed below the waist because of the bus crashing accident and Billy (Bruce Greenwood) who was following the bus. Dolores Driscoll is willing to help to prove it wasn't her fault, Nicole Burnell is reluctant at first but agrees to help only on a condition that she wouldn't lie but Billy who lost 2 kids in the accident is against the lawsuit and tries to convince other parents to drop the lawsuit but nobody listens to him and tells him to stay out of it. In the pretrial deposition, Nicole Burnell lies and accuses the bus driver Dolores Driscoll of over speeding and thus causing the accident. After doing so all the hopes of suing the bus company with the possibility of big settlement disappears. The intention behind Nicole's lie is to punish her father who was sexually abusing her before the crash. Everybody that suffered from the accident or those who are involved in the case knows that Nicole is lying but nothing can be done and the trial never takes place. The story of the movie unfolds in non chronological order it jumps back and forth from one plot to another many times and loses the momentum. At first it was OK but after a while it was hard to watch because it never focused on the main story. In start we are introduced to several characters and each character has a story of its own. There are many different events besides the crash, which distracts the attention from the main plot. Mitchell Stevens daughter Zoe is a drug addict and she hates her father but its never explained what she hates him for also by the end of the movie Zoe tests positive for a blood test and its not explained what the test was for aids, pregnancy or something else. Also Zoe at first is shown as a homeless druggie but by the end she is well dressed. Billy has an affair with Risa (Alberta Watson) who is married to Windol (Maury Chaykin) but its never told why Risa is cheating on Windol or why can't she just leave him if she doesn't love him. Billy has also lost 2 kids in the accident but he is against the lawsuit because he knows it was just an accident and according to him it's wrong to sue for the damages but isn't it wrong to have an affair with a married woman? In the start of the movie its shown that Nicole loves her father (Sam MeCamus) and that they have a nice father daughter relationship but halfway its shown that Nicole is sexually abused by her father and by the end of the movie its shown that she hates him and therefor in order to punish him she lies and accuses an innocent person for the bus crash. Dolores Driscoll is held responsible for the accident because of over speeding but at the end of the movie she is back to driving some kind of airport passenger bus, how can she be hired just after two years for driving again when she is held responsible for the bus crash. Even the movie poster is taken from a scene that has nothing to do with the main plot of the movie. Ian Holm as Mitchel Stevens is a bit over dramatic at times but overall he plays the character nicely. Sarah Polly as Nicole Burnell does justice to her character and changes her facial expressions from a sweet to a serious bitter teen. Bruce Greenwood as Billy is convening, apart from Ion Holm, Sarah Polly and Bruce Greenwood all other actors are flat and plain and no one seems to be convincing enough in their respective characters. Atom Egoyon screenplay is too weak and confusing, he fails in directing The Sweet hereafter, he doesn't uses the right tone and right timing to introduce the characters and unfolds the story in non chronological order which only confuses the audience with all those subplots, The only good thing about his directing is choosing the beautiful locations for shoot. Cinematography is beautifully done by Paul Sarossy. Almost all of the main characters have a story, which is never explained, their personal stories are never given the depth they needed. I hardly see any place for those untold personal stories in the movie but they are introduced which drags the attention from the main plot and half way through the movie I didn't care for the accident and just wanted the movie to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    British actor Ian Holm gives a new meaning to a tale about selfishness directed by Atom Egoyan.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After an attentive viewing session,most attentive viewers would not fail at all to notice that the most recognizable feature of "The Sweet Hereafter" is its candid portrayal of selfishness. It is precisely this feeling which helps us to understand how some selfish individuals want to derive advantage from other people's suffering.This has been depicted through British actor Ian Holm whose extraordinary performance suggests that selfish people are always armed with their own ingenious explanations about their acts which in the long run bring them their fair share of misery instead of happiness.Canadian auteur Atom Egoyan whose film is an adaptation of a best selling work by Russell Banks is hardly partial when it comes to describe how ordinary people deal with guilt especially when it concerns untimely death of loved ones.No viewer would like to side with the film's characters who are full of idiosyncrasies as nobody is innocent.It is no wonder that good photography and natural setting enhance this film's viewing experience for viewers at a time when its slow pace acts as a veritable spoilsport. Finally,The Sweet Hereafter is a film to be watched at all costs if you have not seen a film which has been praised excessively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die is the book I found out about this film, it sounded like and I confirmed it as an independent film, the title obviously had some association with death, but I didn't know anything about the plot, so it would be interesting for me to try whatever. Basically a small town has been devastated by a tragic event; a school bus driven by Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose) and loaded with most of the children of the town attending the local school was driving during the snowy winter morning, when it suddenly hit an icy patch, it skids off road down the hill until it reaches the lake an crashes through the ice and sinks, drowning most victims inside. Many of the isolated village community members are mourning the deaths of their children, including Billy (Bruce Greenwood), the Walkers who lost their mentally developed and challenged son Sean (Devon Finn), and the Ottos who lost their aboriginal son Bear (Simon Baker) who was adopted. Some did survive the accident, including now wheelchair bound aspiring songstress Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polley), and Dolores, we see the accident in flashbacks while lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Sir Ian Holm) has arrived in the Canadian town wanting to take some slight advantage of the situation and get the parents of the twenty dead children to sue whatever party may be guilty for causing the incident, he will obviously represent those who agree to it. He plans to target the big companies and organisations with big amounts of money and who have some involvement with the school, most of the parents he see accept his proposal and see it as some way to get over the grieving, others are simply interested in the potential for the money, and some like Billy want nothing to do with a lawsuit. Stevens himself has demons as he suffered the death of his son and still feels grief, so he knows how the victims feel, but his son's death has also resulted in his daughter Zoe (Caerthan Banks) turning to drugs, losing respect for her father and any real relationship with him, and he knows life in the town has never been the same since this terrible event. Also starring Tom McCamus as Sam Burnell, Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian as Wanda Otto, Alberta Watson as Risa Walker, Mousehunt's Maury Chaykin as Wendell Walker, Brooke Johnson as Mary Burnell, David Hemblen as Abbott Driscoll and Peter Donaldson as Schwartz. Holm gives a pretty good glum performance as the ambulance-chasing who is trying to earn but also help those in the same grief-stricken situation he is in, Greenwood gets a reasonably good amount of time on screen, and I agree that from what I remember Polley is exceptional as the survivor paralysed by the accident. I will confess that I drifted in some of the story, particularly the parts involving a lawsuit and what have you, but it was certainly interesting to see a story about how one truly tragic incident can change the dynamics and personalities of a whole town community, it has got the right amount of intensity and atmosphere to keep you watching, a worthwhile psychological drama. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Director for Atom Egoyan (Felicia's Journey) and Best Writing, Screenplay Based on Material Previously Produced or Published. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Survivors Guilt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***SPOILERS*** We know right from the start where the film " The Sweet Hereafter" is headed in ambulance or school bus chasing shyster lawyer Mitchell Stevens, Ian Holm, on his way to this snowy little town in British Columbia Canada. Stevens is trying to get the people involved in a fatal school bus accident to help him start a class action suite against the bus company the bus driver as well as the town, Sam Dent, in what happened there. We also see that Stevens has problems of his own in that his teenage daughter Zoe,Caerthan Banks, is heavily into the drug scene and is later in the film found to be HIV or AIDS positive because of her non-stop drug use. It soon becomes obvious that Stevens in having his life screwed up, his wife also walked out on him, wants to help others like the school bus survivors and their families more then making any money for his services. It doesn't take to long for Stevens to find out that his services are no longer needed in that by him suing everyone or every thing in sight he's in fact opening up wounds in the community that have just started to begin healing. Wounds far more hurtful then what the people in Sam Dent have already suffered which in fact they were compensated for by the school bus company and despite it not being found responsible, for any shabby work on the road and guardrail,town. At first we dislike Stevens in his obsessive attempt to get the people in town to help him with his class action suit that many don't want to pursue. But later he turns out to be a victim of his own self righteousness in seeing he's going to hurt a lot of Innocent people with his suite who suffered , by surviving, even more then the victims whom he's to represent. One of them is the school bus driver Dorloes Driscoll, Gabriella Rose, who did everything to avoid her bus from skidding into a frozen lake and now has to live with the 14 children who ended up drowning in it on her conscience. There's also 15 year old Nicole Burnell, Sarah Polley, who survived the accident but ended up like the little boy in the story of "The Pide Piper of Hamlin", a favorite of hers, crippled and prevented from entering the land of "Good & Plenty" that the piper was taking the children of Hamlin to. ***SPOILERS*** Slow moving but extremely heart wrenching film that has no happy ending which in fact makes it one cut above the usual Hollywood schmaltz were used to watching about the subject matter that it presents to us. A lot like the movie released the year before in 1996 "Before and After" the film "The Sweet Hereafter" shows us how one survives a tragedy like losing a child with both dignity as well as grace instead of vengeance and self-guilt. Besides Nicole the film centers around Billy Hansel, Bruce Greenwood, the mechanic who serviced the school bus and knew that there was nothing wrong with it. Billy also lost his two children who were on the school bus that he witnessed, by driving behind it, crashing into the lake drowning them and their dozen or so classmate. For all the suffering that Billy and the rest of the people in Sam Dent went through he didn't want some shyster lawyer to make, excuse the pun, a killing off it! ***MAJOR SPOILER** In the end Stevens also lost a child, his daughter Zoe, through drug abuse and realized the only thing he can do now is try to put that tragic loss behind him like Billy as well as the crippled Nicole were doing and go on with his shattered life. It was Nicole who in her trying to put an end to the lawsuit that Stevens was pushing ended the whole affair by making up a preposterous story about the event,in Nicole being a star whiteness, that had it thrown out of court. Which allowed the healing process that Stevens tried to disrupt to continue and thus make things better for her as well as Mitchell Stevens and everyone else involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pied Piper of Hamelin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The summary will make sense once you have seen this. The Canadian film industry is one that I am now really getting into. This movie has a very disjointed structure and one that might be hard-to-follow for some people, which really is my only complaint though. The plot deals with 'tragedy', in particular losing your child. This occurs throughout the film and not just with the townsfolk that lost their kids in the bus crash, but Ian Holm's character has a drug-addicted daughter in this as well which also continues this theme outside of the townsfolk. If you want to watch a movie with good dialogue and characters with a lot of depth then I suggest watching, although to keep you in the right frame of mind then watch this movie expecting a dark, well-made period drama, that was what I was expecting and it was fulfilled in all aspects. No wonder this is considered Canada's best film, that title is deservingly so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Compassionate and reflective masterpiece..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egptian-born Canadian screenwriter, producer and director Atom Egoyan's seventh feature film, an adaptation of American writer Russel Banks' novel from 1991 which was inspired by a true story concerning a school bus accident in Alton, Texas 1989, tells the story of middle-aged attorney Mitchell Stevens who arrives in a remote rural district of Canada in December 1995 to report the circumstances surrounding a tragic school bus accident and help the parents of the victims to file an insurance-case against the bus company. A task that becomes difficult when he learns that most of the parents have numerous dark secrets. As he gets closer to the inhabitants of the small community it becomes apparent that this case has a strong personal influence on him, but his devotion brings nothing good to the parents, who begins to question his motives when they see that the case has more meaning to him than to them. The great score, the mindful dialog and the lyrical cinematography by Paul Sarossy emphasizes the emphatic and mysterious atmosphere in this resonating and realistic psychological drama which is beautifully filmed by Atom Egoyan, who creates versatile perspectives with his nuanced and subtle camera movements. His detailed and introspective screenplay examines how a bus accident affects the people in a small community and the aftermath of sorrow in a profound way, and portrays an in-depth study of character about a grieving man who has a restrained relationship to a daughter he hardly ever sees and who finds comfort and identifies with the parents who lost their children in the accident. Ian Holm's interpretation of the lawyer is outstanding in a refined and understated performance. The overall acting is good and Sarah Polley delivers a remarkable acting performance in her breakthrough role as teenager Nicole Purnell. During this brilliantly directed Canadian film, a short poem from 1842 called "The Pied Piper of Hamelin" by English poet and playwright Robert Browning (1812-1889) is read through Sarah Polley's voice-over. This fairy-tale forms a fine parallel to the story about the lawyer and the parents. With it's underlying lyrical aura and captivating narrative, this independent film stands as a poetic, compassionate and reflective masterpiece from the late 1990s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter-1997: Where time and grief just don't exist.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a simple story  simple in the sense described in the Storyline on the IMDb main page. But, it's from Russell Banks's novel that Atom Egoyan has written and directed one of the most complex plots ever put to film. For those interested, you'll find a complete analysis of this film's structure in Screen writing Updated by Linda Aronson, published in 2000. Incidentally, Russell Banks played the part of Dr Robeson. Avoiding the usual type of visual cues, Egoyan shows only two dates on screen to help orient the viewer to the time shifts (there are multiple shifts); instead, most are managed and revealed through the context of the scene and dialog. Which means the viewer must listen and watch carefully to stay on track. Some viewers might be annoyed. Adding to the complexity is the presentation of five different stories in the 112 minutes running time: the accident, the intrusive lawyer Mitchell (Ian Holm) and his daughter, Zoe (Caerthan Banks), the overly-motherly bus driver Dolores (Gabrielle Rose), the sex affair between Billy (Bruce Greenwood) and Risa (Alberta Watson) and, of course, the illicit and incestuous situation between Nicole (Sarah Polley) and her father, Sam (Tom McCamus). It takes a master film-maker to put all that together and achieve a work of art. On that basis, all serious film lovers should not miss this event, even if the story is unpalatable for many. Life, however, is full of such stories: read the daily tabloids. Ian Holm is the focus and catalyst of this narrative, for two reasons: first, he is, to some extent, the typical (or not so-typical) "ambulance chaser" after a buck, or too many; hence, much of the action involves his presence. Second, he is also after justice for the dead and lost children, spurred on because he lost Zoe to drugs, alcohol, AIDS etc  so she is effectively dead to him also. By trying to help the town folk in their loss, he hopes to achieve some sense of closure for his own loss  in other words, a self-serving attitude, much like the world in general. I think Holm gives the performance of his life in this film. For me, the greatest pleasure was listening to the voice-over of The Pied Piper of Hamelin, the narration of which is spoken by Nicole throughout the film. That poem serves to function as a metaphor of course for the fate that awaits her and her father: loneliness, sadness and despair in a cruel and indifferent world, while all the deceased children have moved on to the sweet hereafter. Not to be missed. November 27, 2011.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as exceptional as expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So this is the best rated movie of Atom Egoyan? I love his movies, and I have to say, sadly I expected a bit more. Don't get me wrong, cinematic everything is perfect. This movie is filmed beautifully. Every actor played on an extremely high level and not a single miscast was to be found in this movie! Overall it was a great watch. For me that was only destructed by the story. To me it felt, that the original novel was not suited to become a movie. The whole movie lacked a red thread. Strings didn't seem to be connected, and i failed finding a bigger meaning. All I found have been starting points, ideas. Great ideas, but in the end, the movie didn't work for me. It almost convinced me, but ultimately failed at the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ZzZzzZzZzZzzzZ
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know, to enjoy this film you have to be very patient. It runs very slowly, nothing interesting happens, there are too many names and different people coming and going, you never know what's going on; More than that, you don't get to see the accident until 60 minutes. It's like you're watching a soap opera with good actors, but with a unsatisfying development. 70 minutes was enough for me to turn it off because of it's boring scenes and conversations. I really expected much more for "Sweet Hereafter"; you know, it didn't work for me personally, don't know how it'd work with other people. IMDb wants me to write more, so I'll just repeat that I didn't like that...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great story which could be better told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shhazam2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite the director Atom Egoyan's misuse and overuse of flashbacks and flash forwards, this movie contained a great story. A terrible tragedy from which there was no emotional relief for the survivors except the chance for one to exact punishment for incest and child abuse. This story could have been told almost strictly chronologically from before the accident to after the accident without misusing the flashback technique and saving that technique for some of the background of the attorney which was still very well played by Ian Holm. Be patient with this movie and forgiving of the flash back misuse and you will have seen a gem of a story told about a tragic happening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Sal
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sweet Hereafter is 1997 Canadian drama movie based on a novel by Russell Banks of the same name. The screen play is written and directed by critically acclaimed director Atom Egoyon . The Film stars Ian Holm, Sarah Polly, Bruce Greenwood, AlbertaWatson, Simon Baker, Marc Donato, Broke Johnson, Maury Chaykin, Stephanie Morgenstern, Carthain Banks, Tom MeCamus, Russell Banks (cameo) and Gabrielle Rose. The Sweet Hereafter tells the story of a horrible school bus crashing accident that killed numerous local children. Their shattered and grieving parents are approached by a lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Ian Holm) who is hunted by the problems of his own, he wants them to file a class action lawsuit to sue for the damages by claiming the bus was faulty. Some of the parents at first are unwilling but they are persuaded by Mitchel Stevens that suing for damages is the right thing to do, some parents shows interest only because of the big settlement and some parents just want justice to be done. As most of the children are dead the case mainly depends only on 3 people that witnessed the accident, the bus driver Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose), Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polly) who was sitting at the front of the bus and who is now paralyzed below the waist because of the bus crashing accident and Billy (Bruce Greenwood) who was following the bus. Dolores Driscoll is willing to help to prove it wasn't her fault, Nicole Burnell is reluctant at first but agrees to help only on a condition that she wouldn't lie but Billy who lost 2 kids in the accident is against the lawsuit and tries to convince other parents to drop the lawsuit but nobody listens to him and tells him to stay out of it. In the pretrial deposition, Nicole Burnell lies and accuses the bus driver Dolores Driscoll of over speeding and thus causing the accident. After doing so all the hopes of suing the bus company with the possibility of big settlement disappears. The intention behind Nicole's lie is to punish her father who was sexually abusing her before the crash. Everybody that suffered from the accident or those who are involved in the case knows that Nicole is lying but nothing can be done and the trial never takes place. The story of the movie unfolds in non chronological order it jumps back and forth from one plot to another many times and loses the momentum. At first it was OK but after a while it was hard to watch because it never focused on the main story. In start we are introduced to several characters and each character has a story of its own. There are many different events besides the crash, which distracts the attention from the main plot. Mitchell Stevens daughter Zoe is a drug addict and she hates her father but its never explained what she hates him for also by the end of the movie Zoe tests positive for a blood test and its not explained what the test was for aids, pregnancy or something else. Also Zoe at first is shown as a homeless druggie but by the end she is well dressed. Billy has an affair with Risa (Alberta Watson) who is married to Windol (Maury Chaykin) but its never told why Risa is cheating on Windol or why can't she just leave him if she doesn't love him. Billy has also lost 2 kids in the accident but he is against the lawsuit because he knows it was just an accident and according to him it's wrong to sue for the damages but isn't it wrong to have an affair with a married woman? In the start of the movie its shown that Nicole loves her father (Sam MeCamus) and that they have a nice father daughter relationship but halfway its shown that Nicole is sexually abused by her father and by the end of the movie its shown that she hates him and therefor in order to punish him she lies and accuses an innocent person for the bus crash. Dolores Driscoll is held responsible for the accident because of over speeding but at the end of the movie she is back to driving some kind of airport passenger bus, how can she be hired just after two years for driving again when she is held responsible for the bus crash. Even the movie poster is taken from a scene that has nothing to do with the main plot of the movie. Ian Holm as Mitchel Stevens is a bit over dramatic at times but overall he plays the character nicely. Sarah Polly as Nicole Burnell does justice to her character and changes her facial expressions from a sweet to a serious bitter teen. Bruce Greenwood as Billy is convening, apart from Ion Holm, Sarah Polly and Bruce Greenwood all other actors are flat and plain and no one seems to be convincing enough in their respective characters. Atom Egoyon screenplay is too weak and confusing, he fails in directing The Sweet hereafter, he doesn't uses the right tone and right timing to introduce the characters and unfolds the story in non chronological order which only confuses the audience with all those subplots, The only good thing about his directing is choosing the beautiful locations for shoot. Cinematography is beautifully done by Paul Sarossy. Almost all of the main characters have a story, which is never explained, their personal stories are never given the depth they needed. I hardly see any place for those untold personal stories in the movie but they are introduced which drags the attention from the main plot and half way through the movie I didn't care for the accident and just wanted the movie to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    British actor Ian Holm gives a new meaning to a tale about selfishness directed by Atom Egoyan.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After an attentive viewing session,most attentive viewers would not fail at all to notice that the most recognizable feature of "The Sweet Hereafter" is its candid portrayal of selfishness. It is precisely this feeling which helps us to understand how some selfish individuals want to derive advantage from other people's suffering.This has been depicted through British actor Ian Holm whose extraordinary performance suggests that selfish people are always armed with their own ingenious explanations about their acts which in the long run bring them their fair share of misery instead of happiness.Canadian auteur Atom Egoyan whose film is an adaptation of a best selling work by Russell Banks is hardly partial when it comes to describe how ordinary people deal with guilt especially when it concerns untimely death of loved ones.No viewer would like to side with the film's characters who are full of idiosyncrasies as nobody is innocent.It is no wonder that good photography and natural setting enhance this film's viewing experience for viewers at a time when its slow pace acts as a veritable spoilsport. Finally,The Sweet Hereafter is a film to be watched at all costs if you have not seen a film which has been praised excessively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die is the book I found out about this film, it sounded like and I confirmed it as an independent film, the title obviously had some association with death, but I didn't know anything about the plot, so it would be interesting for me to try whatever. Basically a small town has been devastated by a tragic event; a school bus driven by Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose) and loaded with most of the children of the town attending the local school was driving during the snowy winter morning, when it suddenly hit an icy patch, it skids off road down the hill until it reaches the lake an crashes through the ice and sinks, drowning most victims inside. Many of the isolated village community members are mourning the deaths of their children, including Billy (Bruce Greenwood), the Walkers who lost their mentally developed and challenged son Sean (Devon Finn), and the Ottos who lost their aboriginal son Bear (Simon Baker) who was adopted. Some did survive the accident, including now wheelchair bound aspiring songstress Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polley), and Dolores, we see the accident in flashbacks while lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Sir Ian Holm) has arrived in the Canadian town wanting to take some slight advantage of the situation and get the parents of the twenty dead children to sue whatever party may be guilty for causing the incident, he will obviously represent those who agree to it. He plans to target the big companies and organisations with big amounts of money and who have some involvement with the school, most of the parents he see accept his proposal and see it as some way to get over the grieving, others are simply interested in the potential for the money, and some like Billy want nothing to do with a lawsuit. Stevens himself has demons as he suffered the death of his son and still feels grief, so he knows how the victims feel, but his son's death has also resulted in his daughter Zoe (Caerthan Banks) turning to drugs, losing respect for her father and any real relationship with him, and he knows life in the town has never been the same since this terrible event. Also starring Tom McCamus as Sam Burnell, Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian as Wanda Otto, Alberta Watson as Risa Walker, Mousehunt's Maury Chaykin as Wendell Walker, Brooke Johnson as Mary Burnell, David Hemblen as Abbott Driscoll and Peter Donaldson as Schwartz. Holm gives a pretty good glum performance as the ambulance-chasing who is trying to earn but also help those in the same grief-stricken situation he is in, Greenwood gets a reasonably good amount of time on screen, and I agree that from what I remember Polley is exceptional as the survivor paralysed by the accident. I will confess that I drifted in some of the story, particularly the parts involving a lawsuit and what have you, but it was certainly interesting to see a story about how one truly tragic incident can change the dynamics and personalities of a whole town community, it has got the right amount of intensity and atmosphere to keep you watching, a worthwhile psychological drama. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Director for Atom Egoyan (Felicia's Journey) and Best Writing, Screenplay Based on Material Previously Produced or Published. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Survivors Guilt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***SPOILERS*** We know right from the start where the film " The Sweet Hereafter" is headed in ambulance or school bus chasing shyster lawyer Mitchell Stevens, Ian Holm, on his way to this snowy little town in British Columbia Canada. Stevens is trying to get the people involved in a fatal school bus accident to help him start a class action suite against the bus company the bus driver as well as the town, Sam Dent, in what happened there. We also see that Stevens has problems of his own in that his teenage daughter Zoe,Caerthan Banks, is heavily into the drug scene and is later in the film found to be HIV or AIDS positive because of her non-stop drug use. It soon becomes obvious that Stevens in having his life screwed up, his wife also walked out on him, wants to help others like the school bus survivors and their families more then making any money for his services. It doesn't take to long for Stevens to find out that his services are no longer needed in that by him suing everyone or every thing in sight he's in fact opening up wounds in the community that have just started to begin healing. Wounds far more hurtful then what the people in Sam Dent have already suffered which in fact they were compensated for by the school bus company and despite it not being found responsible, for any shabby work on the road and guardrail,town. At first we dislike Stevens in his obsessive attempt to get the people in town to help him with his class action suit that many don't want to pursue. But later he turns out to be a victim of his own self righteousness in seeing he's going to hurt a lot of Innocent people with his suite who suffered , by surviving, even more then the victims whom he's to represent. One of them is the school bus driver Dorloes Driscoll, Gabriella Rose, who did everything to avoid her bus from skidding into a frozen lake and now has to live with the 14 children who ended up drowning in it on her conscience. There's also 15 year old Nicole Burnell, Sarah Polley, who survived the accident but ended up like the little boy in the story of "The Pide Piper of Hamlin", a favorite of hers, crippled and prevented from entering the land of "Good & Plenty" that the piper was taking the children of Hamlin to. ***SPOILERS*** Slow moving but extremely heart wrenching film that has no happy ending which in fact makes it one cut above the usual Hollywood schmaltz were used to watching about the subject matter that it presents to us. A lot like the movie released the year before in 1996 "Before and After" the film "The Sweet Hereafter" shows us how one survives a tragedy like losing a child with both dignity as well as grace instead of vengeance and self-guilt. Besides Nicole the film centers around Billy Hansel, Bruce Greenwood, the mechanic who serviced the school bus and knew that there was nothing wrong with it. Billy also lost his two children who were on the school bus that he witnessed, by driving behind it, crashing into the lake drowning them and their dozen or so classmate. For all the suffering that Billy and the rest of the people in Sam Dent went through he didn't want some shyster lawyer to make, excuse the pun, a killing off it! ***MAJOR SPOILER** In the end Stevens also lost a child, his daughter Zoe, through drug abuse and realized the only thing he can do now is try to put that tragic loss behind him like Billy as well as the crippled Nicole were doing and go on with his shattered life. It was Nicole who in her trying to put an end to the lawsuit that Stevens was pushing ended the whole affair by making up a preposterous story about the event,in Nicole being a star whiteness, that had it thrown out of court. Which allowed the healing process that Stevens tried to disrupt to continue and thus make things better for her as well as Mitchell Stevens and everyone else involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pied Piper of Hamelin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The summary will make sense once you have seen this. The Canadian film industry is one that I am now really getting into. This movie has a very disjointed structure and one that might be hard-to-follow for some people, which really is my only complaint though. The plot deals with 'tragedy', in particular losing your child. This occurs throughout the film and not just with the townsfolk that lost their kids in the bus crash, but Ian Holm's character has a drug-addicted daughter in this as well which also continues this theme outside of the townsfolk. If you want to watch a movie with good dialogue and characters with a lot of depth then I suggest watching, although to keep you in the right frame of mind then watch this movie expecting a dark, well-made period drama, that was what I was expecting and it was fulfilled in all aspects. No wonder this is considered Canada's best film, that title is deservingly so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Compassionate and reflective masterpiece..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egptian-born Canadian screenwriter, producer and director Atom Egoyan's seventh feature film, an adaptation of American writer Russel Banks' novel from 1991 which was inspired by a true story concerning a school bus accident in Alton, Texas 1989, tells the story of middle-aged attorney Mitchell Stevens who arrives in a remote rural district of Canada in December 1995 to report the circumstances surrounding a tragic school bus accident and help the parents of the victims to file an insurance-case against the bus company. A task that becomes difficult when he learns that most of the parents have numerous dark secrets. As he gets closer to the inhabitants of the small community it becomes apparent that this case has a strong personal influence on him, but his devotion brings nothing good to the parents, who begins to question his motives when they see that the case has more meaning to him than to them. The great score, the mindful dialog and the lyrical cinematography by Paul Sarossy emphasizes the emphatic and mysterious atmosphere in this resonating and realistic psychological drama which is beautifully filmed by Atom Egoyan, who creates versatile perspectives with his nuanced and subtle camera movements. His detailed and introspective screenplay examines how a bus accident affects the people in a small community and the aftermath of sorrow in a profound way, and portrays an in-depth study of character about a grieving man who has a restrained relationship to a daughter he hardly ever sees and who finds comfort and identifies with the parents who lost their children in the accident. Ian Holm's interpretation of the lawyer is outstanding in a refined and understated performance. The overall acting is good and Sarah Polley delivers a remarkable acting performance in her breakthrough role as teenager Nicole Purnell. During this brilliantly directed Canadian film, a short poem from 1842 called "The Pied Piper of Hamelin" by English poet and playwright Robert Browning (1812-1889) is read through Sarah Polley's voice-over. This fairy-tale forms a fine parallel to the story about the lawyer and the parents. With it's underlying lyrical aura and captivating narrative, this independent film stands as a poetic, compassionate and reflective masterpiece from the late 1990s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter-1997: Where time and grief just don't exist.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a simple story  simple in the sense described in the Storyline on the IMDb main page. But, it's from Russell Banks's novel that Atom Egoyan has written and directed one of the most complex plots ever put to film. For those interested, you'll find a complete analysis of this film's structure in Screen writing Updated by Linda Aronson, published in 2000. Incidentally, Russell Banks played the part of Dr Robeson. Avoiding the usual type of visual cues, Egoyan shows only two dates on screen to help orient the viewer to the time shifts (there are multiple shifts); instead, most are managed and revealed through the context of the scene and dialog. Which means the viewer must listen and watch carefully to stay on track. Some viewers might be annoyed. Adding to the complexity is the presentation of five different stories in the 112 minutes running time: the accident, the intrusive lawyer Mitchell (Ian Holm) and his daughter, Zoe (Caerthan Banks), the overly-motherly bus driver Dolores (Gabrielle Rose), the sex affair between Billy (Bruce Greenwood) and Risa (Alberta Watson) and, of course, the illicit and incestuous situation between Nicole (Sarah Polley) and her father, Sam (Tom McCamus). It takes a master film-maker to put all that together and achieve a work of art. On that basis, all serious film lovers should not miss this event, even if the story is unpalatable for many. Life, however, is full of such stories: read the daily tabloids. Ian Holm is the focus and catalyst of this narrative, for two reasons: first, he is, to some extent, the typical (or not so-typical) "ambulance chaser" after a buck, or too many; hence, much of the action involves his presence. Second, he is also after justice for the dead and lost children, spurred on because he lost Zoe to drugs, alcohol, AIDS etc  so she is effectively dead to him also. By trying to help the town folk in their loss, he hopes to achieve some sense of closure for his own loss  in other words, a self-serving attitude, much like the world in general. I think Holm gives the performance of his life in this film. For me, the greatest pleasure was listening to the voice-over of The Pied Piper of Hamelin, the narration of which is spoken by Nicole throughout the film. That poem serves to function as a metaphor of course for the fate that awaits her and her father: loneliness, sadness and despair in a cruel and indifferent world, while all the deceased children have moved on to the sweet hereafter. Not to be missed. November 27, 2011.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as exceptional as expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So this is the best rated movie of Atom Egoyan? I love his movies, and I have to say, sadly I expected a bit more. Don't get me wrong, cinematic everything is perfect. This movie is filmed beautifully. Every actor played on an extremely high level and not a single miscast was to be found in this movie! Overall it was a great watch. For me that was only destructed by the story. To me it felt, that the original novel was not suited to become a movie. The whole movie lacked a red thread. Strings didn't seem to be connected, and i failed finding a bigger meaning. All I found have been starting points, ideas. Great ideas, but in the end, the movie didn't work for me. It almost convinced me, but ultimately failed at the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ZzZzzZzZzZzzzZ
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know, to enjoy this film you have to be very patient. It runs very slowly, nothing interesting happens, there are too many names and different people coming and going, you never know what's going on; More than that, you don't get to see the accident until 60 minutes. It's like you're watching a soap opera with good actors, but with a unsatisfying development. 70 minutes was enough for me to turn it off because of it's boring scenes and conversations. I really expected much more for "Sweet Hereafter"; you know, it didn't work for me personally, don't know how it'd work with other people. IMDb wants me to write more, so I'll just repeat that I didn't like that...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great story which could be better told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shhazam2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite the director Atom Egoyan's misuse and overuse of flashbacks and flash forwards, this movie contained a great story. A terrible tragedy from which there was no emotional relief for the survivors except the chance for one to exact punishment for incest and child abuse. This story could have been told almost strictly chronologically from before the accident to after the accident without misusing the flashback technique and saving that technique for some of the background of the attorney which was still very well played by Ian Holm. Be patient with this movie and forgiving of the flash back misuse and you will have seen a gem of a story told about a tragic happening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Sal
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sweet Hereafter is 1997 Canadian drama movie based on a novel by Russell Banks of the same name. The screen play is written and directed by critically acclaimed director Atom Egoyon . The Film stars Ian Holm, Sarah Polly, Bruce Greenwood, AlbertaWatson, Simon Baker, Marc Donato, Broke Johnson, Maury Chaykin, Stephanie Morgenstern, Carthain Banks, Tom MeCamus, Russell Banks (cameo) and Gabrielle Rose. The Sweet Hereafter tells the story of a horrible school bus crashing accident that killed numerous local children. Their shattered and grieving parents are approached by a lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Ian Holm) who is hunted by the problems of his own, he wants them to file a class action lawsuit to sue for the damages by claiming the bus was faulty. Some of the parents at first are unwilling but they are persuaded by Mitchel Stevens that suing for damages is the right thing to do, some parents shows interest only because of the big settlement and some parents just want justice to be done. As most of the children are dead the case mainly depends only on 3 people that witnessed the accident, the bus driver Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose), Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polly) who was sitting at the front of the bus and who is now paralyzed below the waist because of the bus crashing accident and Billy (Bruce Greenwood) who was following the bus. Dolores Driscoll is willing to help to prove it wasn't her fault, Nicole Burnell is reluctant at first but agrees to help only on a condition that she wouldn't lie but Billy who lost 2 kids in the accident is against the lawsuit and tries to convince other parents to drop the lawsuit but nobody listens to him and tells him to stay out of it. In the pretrial deposition, Nicole Burnell lies and accuses the bus driver Dolores Driscoll of over speeding and thus causing the accident. After doing so all the hopes of suing the bus company with the possibility of big settlement disappears. The intention behind Nicole's lie is to punish her father who was sexually abusing her before the crash. Everybody that suffered from the accident or those who are involved in the case knows that Nicole is lying but nothing can be done and the trial never takes place. The story of the movie unfolds in non chronological order it jumps back and forth from one plot to another many times and loses the momentum. At first it was OK but after a while it was hard to watch because it never focused on the main story. In start we are introduced to several characters and each character has a story of its own. There are many different events besides the crash, which distracts the attention from the main plot. Mitchell Stevens daughter Zoe is a drug addict and she hates her father but its never explained what she hates him for also by the end of the movie Zoe tests positive for a blood test and its not explained what the test was for aids, pregnancy or something else. Also Zoe at first is shown as a homeless druggie but by the end she is well dressed. Billy has an affair with Risa (Alberta Watson) who is married to Windol (Maury Chaykin) but its never told why Risa is cheating on Windol or why can't she just leave him if she doesn't love him. Billy has also lost 2 kids in the accident but he is against the lawsuit because he knows it was just an accident and according to him it's wrong to sue for the damages but isn't it wrong to have an affair with a married woman? In the start of the movie its shown that Nicole loves her father (Sam MeCamus) and that they have a nice father daughter relationship but halfway its shown that Nicole is sexually abused by her father and by the end of the movie its shown that she hates him and therefor in order to punish him she lies and accuses an innocent person for the bus crash. Dolores Driscoll is held responsible for the accident because of over speeding but at the end of the movie she is back to driving some kind of airport passenger bus, how can she be hired just after two years for driving again when she is held responsible for the bus crash. Even the movie poster is taken from a scene that has nothing to do with the main plot of the movie. Ian Holm as Mitchel Stevens is a bit over dramatic at times but overall he plays the character nicely. Sarah Polly as Nicole Burnell does justice to her character and changes her facial expressions from a sweet to a serious bitter teen. Bruce Greenwood as Billy is convening, apart from Ion Holm, Sarah Polly and Bruce Greenwood all other actors are flat and plain and no one seems to be convincing enough in their respective characters. Atom Egoyon screenplay is too weak and confusing, he fails in directing The Sweet hereafter, he doesn't uses the right tone and right timing to introduce the characters and unfolds the story in non chronological order which only confuses the audience with all those subplots, The only good thing about his directing is choosing the beautiful locations for shoot. Cinematography is beautifully done by Paul Sarossy. Almost all of the main characters have a story, which is never explained, their personal stories are never given the depth they needed. I hardly see any place for those untold personal stories in the movie but they are introduced which drags the attention from the main plot and half way through the movie I didn't care for the accident and just wanted the movie to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    British actor Ian Holm gives a new meaning to a tale about selfishness directed by Atom Egoyan.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After an attentive viewing session,most attentive viewers would not fail at all to notice that the most recognizable feature of "The Sweet Hereafter" is its candid portrayal of selfishness. It is precisely this feeling which helps us to understand how some selfish individuals want to derive advantage from other people's suffering.This has been depicted through British actor Ian Holm whose extraordinary performance suggests that selfish people are always armed with their own ingenious explanations about their acts which in the long run bring them their fair share of misery instead of happiness.Canadian auteur Atom Egoyan whose film is an adaptation of a best selling work by Russell Banks is hardly partial when it comes to describe how ordinary people deal with guilt especially when it concerns untimely death of loved ones.No viewer would like to side with the film's characters who are full of idiosyncrasies as nobody is innocent.It is no wonder that good photography and natural setting enhance this film's viewing experience for viewers at a time when its slow pace acts as a veritable spoilsport. Finally,The Sweet Hereafter is a film to be watched at all costs if you have not seen a film which has been praised excessively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die is the book I found out about this film, it sounded like and I confirmed it as an independent film, the title obviously had some association with death, but I didn't know anything about the plot, so it would be interesting for me to try whatever. Basically a small town has been devastated by a tragic event; a school bus driven by Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose) and loaded with most of the children of the town attending the local school was driving during the snowy winter morning, when it suddenly hit an icy patch, it skids off road down the hill until it reaches the lake an crashes through the ice and sinks, drowning most victims inside. Many of the isolated village community members are mourning the deaths of their children, including Billy (Bruce Greenwood), the Walkers who lost their mentally developed and challenged son Sean (Devon Finn), and the Ottos who lost their aboriginal son Bear (Simon Baker) who was adopted. Some did survive the accident, including now wheelchair bound aspiring songstress Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polley), and Dolores, we see the accident in flashbacks while lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Sir Ian Holm) has arrived in the Canadian town wanting to take some slight advantage of the situation and get the parents of the twenty dead children to sue whatever party may be guilty for causing the incident, he will obviously represent those who agree to it. He plans to target the big companies and organisations with big amounts of money and who have some involvement with the school, most of the parents he see accept his proposal and see it as some way to get over the grieving, others are simply interested in the potential for the money, and some like Billy want nothing to do with a lawsuit. Stevens himself has demons as he suffered the death of his son and still feels grief, so he knows how the victims feel, but his son's death has also resulted in his daughter Zoe (Caerthan Banks) turning to drugs, losing respect for her father and any real relationship with him, and he knows life in the town has never been the same since this terrible event. Also starring Tom McCamus as Sam Burnell, Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian as Wanda Otto, Alberta Watson as Risa Walker, Mousehunt's Maury Chaykin as Wendell Walker, Brooke Johnson as Mary Burnell, David Hemblen as Abbott Driscoll and Peter Donaldson as Schwartz. Holm gives a pretty good glum performance as the ambulance-chasing who is trying to earn but also help those in the same grief-stricken situation he is in, Greenwood gets a reasonably good amount of time on screen, and I agree that from what I remember Polley is exceptional as the survivor paralysed by the accident. I will confess that I drifted in some of the story, particularly the parts involving a lawsuit and what have you, but it was certainly interesting to see a story about how one truly tragic incident can change the dynamics and personalities of a whole town community, it has got the right amount of intensity and atmosphere to keep you watching, a worthwhile psychological drama. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Director for Atom Egoyan (Felicia's Journey) and Best Writing, Screenplay Based on Material Previously Produced or Published. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Survivors Guilt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***SPOILERS*** We know right from the start where the film " The Sweet Hereafter" is headed in ambulance or school bus chasing shyster lawyer Mitchell Stevens, Ian Holm, on his way to this snowy little town in British Columbia Canada. Stevens is trying to get the people involved in a fatal school bus accident to help him start a class action suite against the bus company the bus driver as well as the town, Sam Dent, in what happened there. We also see that Stevens has problems of his own in that his teenage daughter Zoe,Caerthan Banks, is heavily into the drug scene and is later in the film found to be HIV or AIDS positive because of her non-stop drug use. It soon becomes obvious that Stevens in having his life screwed up, his wife also walked out on him, wants to help others like the school bus survivors and their families more then making any money for his services. It doesn't take to long for Stevens to find out that his services are no longer needed in that by him suing everyone or every thing in sight he's in fact opening up wounds in the community that have just started to begin healing. Wounds far more hurtful then what the people in Sam Dent have already suffered which in fact they were compensated for by the school bus company and despite it not being found responsible, for any shabby work on the road and guardrail,town. At first we dislike Stevens in his obsessive attempt to get the people in town to help him with his class action suit that many don't want to pursue. But later he turns out to be a victim of his own self righteousness in seeing he's going to hurt a lot of Innocent people with his suite who suffered , by surviving, even more then the victims whom he's to represent. One of them is the school bus driver Dorloes Driscoll, Gabriella Rose, who did everything to avoid her bus from skidding into a frozen lake and now has to live with the 14 children who ended up drowning in it on her conscience. There's also 15 year old Nicole Burnell, Sarah Polley, who survived the accident but ended up like the little boy in the story of "The Pide Piper of Hamlin", a favorite of hers, crippled and prevented from entering the land of "Good & Plenty" that the piper was taking the children of Hamlin to. ***SPOILERS*** Slow moving but extremely heart wrenching film that has no happy ending which in fact makes it one cut above the usual Hollywood schmaltz were used to watching about the subject matter that it presents to us. A lot like the movie released the year before in 1996 "Before and After" the film "The Sweet Hereafter" shows us how one survives a tragedy like losing a child with both dignity as well as grace instead of vengeance and self-guilt. Besides Nicole the film centers around Billy Hansel, Bruce Greenwood, the mechanic who serviced the school bus and knew that there was nothing wrong with it. Billy also lost his two children who were on the school bus that he witnessed, by driving behind it, crashing into the lake drowning them and their dozen or so classmate. For all the suffering that Billy and the rest of the people in Sam Dent went through he didn't want some shyster lawyer to make, excuse the pun, a killing off it! ***MAJOR SPOILER** In the end Stevens also lost a child, his daughter Zoe, through drug abuse and realized the only thing he can do now is try to put that tragic loss behind him like Billy as well as the crippled Nicole were doing and go on with his shattered life. It was Nicole who in her trying to put an end to the lawsuit that Stevens was pushing ended the whole affair by making up a preposterous story about the event,in Nicole being a star whiteness, that had it thrown out of court. Which allowed the healing process that Stevens tried to disrupt to continue and thus make things better for her as well as Mitchell Stevens and everyone else involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pied Piper of Hamelin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The summary will make sense once you have seen this. The Canadian film industry is one that I am now really getting into. This movie has a very disjointed structure and one that might be hard-to-follow for some people, which really is my only complaint though. The plot deals with 'tragedy', in particular losing your child. This occurs throughout the film and not just with the townsfolk that lost their kids in the bus crash, but Ian Holm's character has a drug-addicted daughter in this as well which also continues this theme outside of the townsfolk. If you want to watch a movie with good dialogue and characters with a lot of depth then I suggest watching, although to keep you in the right frame of mind then watch this movie expecting a dark, well-made period drama, that was what I was expecting and it was fulfilled in all aspects. No wonder this is considered Canada's best film, that title is deservingly so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Compassionate and reflective masterpiece..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egptian-born Canadian screenwriter, producer and director Atom Egoyan's seventh feature film, an adaptation of American writer Russel Banks' novel from 1991 which was inspired by a true story concerning a school bus accident in Alton, Texas 1989, tells the story of middle-aged attorney Mitchell Stevens who arrives in a remote rural district of Canada in December 1995 to report the circumstances surrounding a tragic school bus accident and help the parents of the victims to file an insurance-case against the bus company. A task that becomes difficult when he learns that most of the parents have numerous dark secrets. As he gets closer to the inhabitants of the small community it becomes apparent that this case has a strong personal influence on him, but his devotion brings nothing good to the parents, who begins to question his motives when they see that the case has more meaning to him than to them. The great score, the mindful dialog and the lyrical cinematography by Paul Sarossy emphasizes the emphatic and mysterious atmosphere in this resonating and realistic psychological drama which is beautifully filmed by Atom Egoyan, who creates versatile perspectives with his nuanced and subtle camera movements. His detailed and introspective screenplay examines how a bus accident affects the people in a small community and the aftermath of sorrow in a profound way, and portrays an in-depth study of character about a grieving man who has a restrained relationship to a daughter he hardly ever sees and who finds comfort and identifies with the parents who lost their children in the accident. Ian Holm's interpretation of the lawyer is outstanding in a refined and understated performance. The overall acting is good and Sarah Polley delivers a remarkable acting performance in her breakthrough role as teenager Nicole Purnell. During this brilliantly directed Canadian film, a short poem from 1842 called "The Pied Piper of Hamelin" by English poet and playwright Robert Browning (1812-1889) is read through Sarah Polley's voice-over. This fairy-tale forms a fine parallel to the story about the lawyer and the parents. With it's underlying lyrical aura and captivating narrative, this independent film stands as a poetic, compassionate and reflective masterpiece from the late 1990s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter-1997: Where time and grief just don't exist.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a simple story  simple in the sense described in the Storyline on the IMDb main page. But, it's from Russell Banks's novel that Atom Egoyan has written and directed one of the most complex plots ever put to film. For those interested, you'll find a complete analysis of this film's structure in Screen writing Updated by Linda Aronson, published in 2000. Incidentally, Russell Banks played the part of Dr Robeson. Avoiding the usual type of visual cues, Egoyan shows only two dates on screen to help orient the viewer to the time shifts (there are multiple shifts); instead, most are managed and revealed through the context of the scene and dialog. Which means the viewer must listen and watch carefully to stay on track. Some viewers might be annoyed. Adding to the complexity is the presentation of five different stories in the 112 minutes running time: the accident, the intrusive lawyer Mitchell (Ian Holm) and his daughter, Zoe (Caerthan Banks), the overly-motherly bus driver Dolores (Gabrielle Rose), the sex affair between Billy (Bruce Greenwood) and Risa (Alberta Watson) and, of course, the illicit and incestuous situation between Nicole (Sarah Polley) and her father, Sam (Tom McCamus). It takes a master film-maker to put all that together and achieve a work of art. On that basis, all serious film lovers should not miss this event, even if the story is unpalatable for many. Life, however, is full of such stories: read the daily tabloids. Ian Holm is the focus and catalyst of this narrative, for two reasons: first, he is, to some extent, the typical (or not so-typical) "ambulance chaser" after a buck, or too many; hence, much of the action involves his presence. Second, he is also after justice for the dead and lost children, spurred on because he lost Zoe to drugs, alcohol, AIDS etc  so she is effectively dead to him also. By trying to help the town folk in their loss, he hopes to achieve some sense of closure for his own loss  in other words, a self-serving attitude, much like the world in general. I think Holm gives the performance of his life in this film. For me, the greatest pleasure was listening to the voice-over of The Pied Piper of Hamelin, the narration of which is spoken by Nicole throughout the film. That poem serves to function as a metaphor of course for the fate that awaits her and her father: loneliness, sadness and despair in a cruel and indifferent world, while all the deceased children have moved on to the sweet hereafter. Not to be missed. November 27, 2011.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as exceptional as expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So this is the best rated movie of Atom Egoyan? I love his movies, and I have to say, sadly I expected a bit more. Don't get me wrong, cinematic everything is perfect. This movie is filmed beautifully. Every actor played on an extremely high level and not a single miscast was to be found in this movie! Overall it was a great watch. For me that was only destructed by the story. To me it felt, that the original novel was not suited to become a movie. The whole movie lacked a red thread. Strings didn't seem to be connected, and i failed finding a bigger meaning. All I found have been starting points, ideas. Great ideas, but in the end, the movie didn't work for me. It almost convinced me, but ultimately failed at the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ZzZzzZzZzZzzzZ
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know, to enjoy this film you have to be very patient. It runs very slowly, nothing interesting happens, there are too many names and different people coming and going, you never know what's going on; More than that, you don't get to see the accident until 60 minutes. It's like you're watching a soap opera with good actors, but with a unsatisfying development. 70 minutes was enough for me to turn it off because of it's boring scenes and conversations. I really expected much more for "Sweet Hereafter"; you know, it didn't work for me personally, don't know how it'd work with other people. IMDb wants me to write more, so I'll just repeat that I didn't like that...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great story which could be better told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shhazam2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite the director Atom Egoyan's misuse and overuse of flashbacks and flash forwards, this movie contained a great story. A terrible tragedy from which there was no emotional relief for the survivors except the chance for one to exact punishment for incest and child abuse. This story could have been told almost strictly chronologically from before the accident to after the accident without misusing the flashback technique and saving that technique for some of the background of the attorney which was still very well played by Ian Holm. Be patient with this movie and forgiving of the flash back misuse and you will have seen a gem of a story told about a tragic happening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoiler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Sal
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sweet Hereafter is 1997 Canadian drama movie based on a novel by Russell Banks of the same name. The screen play is written and directed by critically acclaimed director Atom Egoyon . The Film stars Ian Holm, Sarah Polly, Bruce Greenwood, AlbertaWatson, Simon Baker, Marc Donato, Broke Johnson, Maury Chaykin, Stephanie Morgenstern, Carthain Banks, Tom MeCamus, Russell Banks (cameo) and Gabrielle Rose. The Sweet Hereafter tells the story of a horrible school bus crashing accident that killed numerous local children. Their shattered and grieving parents are approached by a lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Ian Holm) who is hunted by the problems of his own, he wants them to file a class action lawsuit to sue for the damages by claiming the bus was faulty. Some of the parents at first are unwilling but they are persuaded by Mitchel Stevens that suing for damages is the right thing to do, some parents shows interest only because of the big settlement and some parents just want justice to be done. As most of the children are dead the case mainly depends only on 3 people that witnessed the accident, the bus driver Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose), Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polly) who was sitting at the front of the bus and who is now paralyzed below the waist because of the bus crashing accident and Billy (Bruce Greenwood) who was following the bus. Dolores Driscoll is willing to help to prove it wasn't her fault, Nicole Burnell is reluctant at first but agrees to help only on a condition that she wouldn't lie but Billy who lost 2 kids in the accident is against the lawsuit and tries to convince other parents to drop the lawsuit but nobody listens to him and tells him to stay out of it. In the pretrial deposition, Nicole Burnell lies and accuses the bus driver Dolores Driscoll of over speeding and thus causing the accident. After doing so all the hopes of suing the bus company with the possibility of big settlement disappears. The intention behind Nicole's lie is to punish her father who was sexually abusing her before the crash. Everybody that suffered from the accident or those who are involved in the case knows that Nicole is lying but nothing can be done and the trial never takes place. The story of the movie unfolds in non chronological order it jumps back and forth from one plot to another many times and loses the momentum. At first it was OK but after a while it was hard to watch because it never focused on the main story. In start we are introduced to several characters and each character has a story of its own. There are many different events besides the crash, which distracts the attention from the main plot. Mitchell Stevens daughter Zoe is a drug addict and she hates her father but its never explained what she hates him for also by the end of the movie Zoe tests positive for a blood test and its not explained what the test was for aids, pregnancy or something else. Also Zoe at first is shown as a homeless druggie but by the end she is well dressed. Billy has an affair with Risa (Alberta Watson) who is married to Windol (Maury Chaykin) but its never told why Risa is cheating on Windol or why can't she just leave him if she doesn't love him. Billy has also lost 2 kids in the accident but he is against the lawsuit because he knows it was just an accident and according to him it's wrong to sue for the damages but isn't it wrong to have an affair with a married woman? In the start of the movie its shown that Nicole loves her father (Sam MeCamus) and that they have a nice father daughter relationship but halfway its shown that Nicole is sexually abused by her father and by the end of the movie its shown that she hates him and therefor in order to punish him she lies and accuses an innocent person for the bus crash. Dolores Driscoll is held responsible for the accident because of over speeding but at the end of the movie she is back to driving some kind of airport passenger bus, how can she be hired just after two years for driving again when she is held responsible for the bus crash. Even the movie poster is taken from a scene that has nothing to do with the main plot of the movie. Ian Holm as Mitchel Stevens is a bit over dramatic at times but overall he plays the character nicely. Sarah Polly as Nicole Burnell does justice to her character and changes her facial expressions from a sweet to a serious bitter teen. Bruce Greenwood as Billy is convening, apart from Ion Holm, Sarah Polly and Bruce Greenwood all other actors are flat and plain and no one seems to be convincing enough in their respective characters. Atom Egoyon screenplay is too weak and confusing, he fails in directing The Sweet hereafter, he doesn't uses the right tone and right timing to introduce the characters and unfolds the story in non chronological order which only confuses the audience with all those subplots, The only good thing about his directing is choosing the beautiful locations for shoot. Cinematography is beautifully done by Paul Sarossy. Almost all of the main characters have a story, which is never explained, their personal stories are never given the depth they needed. I hardly see any place for those untold personal stories in the movie but they are introduced which drags the attention from the main plot and half way through the movie I didn't care for the accident and just wanted the movie to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    British actor Ian Holm gives a new meaning to a tale about selfishness directed by Atom Egoyan.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After an attentive viewing session,most attentive viewers would not fail at all to notice that the most recognizable feature of "The Sweet Hereafter" is its candid portrayal of selfishness. It is precisely this feeling which helps us to understand how some selfish individuals want to derive advantage from other people's suffering.This has been depicted through British actor Ian Holm whose extraordinary performance suggests that selfish people are always armed with their own ingenious explanations about their acts which in the long run bring them their fair share of misery instead of happiness.Canadian auteur Atom Egoyan whose film is an adaptation of a best selling work by Russell Banks is hardly partial when it comes to describe how ordinary people deal with guilt especially when it concerns untimely death of loved ones.No viewer would like to side with the film's characters who are full of idiosyncrasies as nobody is innocent.It is no wonder that good photography and natural setting enhance this film's viewing experience for viewers at a time when its slow pace acts as a veritable spoilsport. Finally,The Sweet Hereafter is a film to be watched at all costs if you have not seen a film which has been praised excessively.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die is the book I found out about this film, it sounded like and I confirmed it as an independent film, the title obviously had some association with death, but I didn't know anything about the plot, so it would be interesting for me to try whatever. Basically a small town has been devastated by a tragic event; a school bus driven by Dolores Driscoll (Gabrielle Rose) and loaded with most of the children of the town attending the local school was driving during the snowy winter morning, when it suddenly hit an icy patch, it skids off road down the hill until it reaches the lake an crashes through the ice and sinks, drowning most victims inside. Many of the isolated village community members are mourning the deaths of their children, including Billy (Bruce Greenwood), the Walkers who lost their mentally developed and challenged son Sean (Devon Finn), and the Ottos who lost their aboriginal son Bear (Simon Baker) who was adopted. Some did survive the accident, including now wheelchair bound aspiring songstress Nicole Burnell (Sarah Polley), and Dolores, we see the accident in flashbacks while lawyer Mitchell Stevens (Sir Ian Holm) has arrived in the Canadian town wanting to take some slight advantage of the situation and get the parents of the twenty dead children to sue whatever party may be guilty for causing the incident, he will obviously represent those who agree to it. He plans to target the big companies and organisations with big amounts of money and who have some involvement with the school, most of the parents he see accept his proposal and see it as some way to get over the grieving, others are simply interested in the potential for the money, and some like Billy want nothing to do with a lawsuit. Stevens himself has demons as he suffered the death of his son and still feels grief, so he knows how the victims feel, but his son's death has also resulted in his daughter Zoe (Caerthan Banks) turning to drugs, losing respect for her father and any real relationship with him, and he knows life in the town has never been the same since this terrible event. Also starring Tom McCamus as Sam Burnell, Arsin&eacute;e Khanjian as Wanda Otto, Alberta Watson as Risa Walker, Mousehunt's Maury Chaykin as Wendell Walker, Brooke Johnson as Mary Burnell, David Hemblen as Abbott Driscoll and Peter Donaldson as Schwartz. Holm gives a pretty good glum performance as the ambulance-chasing who is trying to earn but also help those in the same grief-stricken situation he is in, Greenwood gets a reasonably good amount of time on screen, and I agree that from what I remember Polley is exceptional as the survivor paralysed by the accident. I will confess that I drifted in some of the story, particularly the parts involving a lawsuit and what have you, but it was certainly interesting to see a story about how one truly tragic incident can change the dynamics and personalities of a whole town community, it has got the right amount of intensity and atmosphere to keep you watching, a worthwhile psychological drama. It was nominated the Oscar for Best Director for Atom Egoyan (Felicia's Journey) and Best Writing, Screenplay Based on Material Previously Produced or Published. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Survivors Guilt
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sol
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ***SPOILERS*** We know right from the start where the film " The Sweet Hereafter" is headed in ambulance or school bus chasing shyster lawyer Mitchell Stevens, Ian Holm, on his way to this snowy little town in British Columbia Canada. Stevens is trying to get the people involved in a fatal school bus accident to help him start a class action suite against the bus company the bus driver as well as the town, Sam Dent, in what happened there. We also see that Stevens has problems of his own in that his teenage daughter Zoe,Caerthan Banks, is heavily into the drug scene and is later in the film found to be HIV or AIDS positive because of her non-stop drug use. It soon becomes obvious that Stevens in having his life screwed up, his wife also walked out on him, wants to help others like the school bus survivors and their families more then making any money for his services. It doesn't take to long for Stevens to find out that his services are no longer needed in that by him suing everyone or every thing in sight he's in fact opening up wounds in the community that have just started to begin healing. Wounds far more hurtful then what the people in Sam Dent have already suffered which in fact they were compensated for by the school bus company and despite it not being found responsible, for any shabby work on the road and guardrail,town. At first we dislike Stevens in his obsessive attempt to get the people in town to help him with his class action suit that many don't want to pursue. But later he turns out to be a victim of his own self righteousness in seeing he's going to hurt a lot of Innocent people with his suite who suffered , by surviving, even more then the victims whom he's to represent. One of them is the school bus driver Dorloes Driscoll, Gabriella Rose, who did everything to avoid her bus from skidding into a frozen lake and now has to live with the 14 children who ended up drowning in it on her conscience. There's also 15 year old Nicole Burnell, Sarah Polley, who survived the accident but ended up like the little boy in the story of "The Pide Piper of Hamlin", a favorite of hers, crippled and prevented from entering the land of "Good & Plenty" that the piper was taking the children of Hamlin to. ***SPOILERS*** Slow moving but extremely heart wrenching film that has no happy ending which in fact makes it one cut above the usual Hollywood schmaltz were used to watching about the subject matter that it presents to us. A lot like the movie released the year before in 1996 "Before and After" the film "The Sweet Hereafter" shows us how one survives a tragedy like losing a child with both dignity as well as grace instead of vengeance and self-guilt. Besides Nicole the film centers around Billy Hansel, Bruce Greenwood, the mechanic who serviced the school bus and knew that there was nothing wrong with it. Billy also lost his two children who were on the school bus that he witnessed, by driving behind it, crashing into the lake drowning them and their dozen or so classmate. For all the suffering that Billy and the rest of the people in Sam Dent went through he didn't want some shyster lawyer to make, excuse the pun, a killing off it! ***MAJOR SPOILER** In the end Stevens also lost a child, his daughter Zoe, through drug abuse and realized the only thing he can do now is try to put that tragic loss behind him like Billy as well as the crippled Nicole were doing and go on with his shattered life. It was Nicole who in her trying to put an end to the lawsuit that Stevens was pushing ended the whole affair by making up a preposterous story about the event,in Nicole being a star whiteness, that had it thrown out of court. Which allowed the healing process that Stevens tried to disrupt to continue and thus make things better for her as well as Mitchell Stevens and everyone else involved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pied Piper of Hamelin
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    WakenPayne
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The summary will make sense once you have seen this. The Canadian film industry is one that I am now really getting into. This movie has a very disjointed structure and one that might be hard-to-follow for some people, which really is my only complaint though. The plot deals with 'tragedy', in particular losing your child. This occurs throughout the film and not just with the townsfolk that lost their kids in the bus crash, but Ian Holm's character has a drug-addicted daughter in this as well which also continues this theme outside of the townsfolk. If you want to watch a movie with good dialogue and characters with a lot of depth then I suggest watching, although to keep you in the right frame of mind then watch this movie expecting a dark, well-made period drama, that was what I was expecting and it was fulfilled in all aspects. No wonder this is considered Canada's best film, that title is deservingly so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Compassionate and reflective masterpiece..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Egptian-born Canadian screenwriter, producer and director Atom Egoyan's seventh feature film, an adaptation of American writer Russel Banks' novel from 1991 which was inspired by a true story concerning a school bus accident in Alton, Texas 1989, tells the story of middle-aged attorney Mitchell Stevens who arrives in a remote rural district of Canada in December 1995 to report the circumstances surrounding a tragic school bus accident and help the parents of the victims to file an insurance-case against the bus company. A task that becomes difficult when he learns that most of the parents have numerous dark secrets. As he gets closer to the inhabitants of the small community it becomes apparent that this case has a strong personal influence on him, but his devotion brings nothing good to the parents, who begins to question his motives when they see that the case has more meaning to him than to them. The great score, the mindful dialog and the lyrical cinematography by Paul Sarossy emphasizes the emphatic and mysterious atmosphere in this resonating and realistic psychological drama which is beautifully filmed by Atom Egoyan, who creates versatile perspectives with his nuanced and subtle camera movements. His detailed and introspective screenplay examines how a bus accident affects the people in a small community and the aftermath of sorrow in a profound way, and portrays an in-depth study of character about a grieving man who has a restrained relationship to a daughter he hardly ever sees and who finds comfort and identifies with the parents who lost their children in the accident. Ian Holm's interpretation of the lawyer is outstanding in a refined and understated performance. The overall acting is good and Sarah Polley delivers a remarkable acting performance in her breakthrough role as teenager Nicole Purnell. During this brilliantly directed Canadian film, a short poem from 1842 called "The Pied Piper of Hamelin" by English poet and playwright Robert Browning (1812-1889) is read through Sarah Polley's voice-over. This fairy-tale forms a fine parallel to the story about the lawyer and the parents. With it's underlying lyrical aura and captivating narrative, this independent film stands as a poetic, compassionate and reflective masterpiece from the late 1990s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sweet Hereafter-1997: Where time and grief just don't exist.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Roger Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a simple story  simple in the sense described in the Storyline on the IMDb main page. But, it's from Russell Banks's novel that Atom Egoyan has written and directed one of the most complex plots ever put to film. For those interested, you'll find a complete analysis of this film's structure in Screen writing Updated by Linda Aronson, published in 2000. Incidentally, Russell Banks played the part of Dr Robeson. Avoiding the usual type of visual cues, Egoyan shows only two dates on screen to help orient the viewer to the time shifts (there are multiple shifts); instead, most are managed and revealed through the context of the scene and dialog. Which means the viewer must listen and watch carefully to stay on track. Some viewers might be annoyed. Adding to the complexity is the presentation of five different stories in the 112 minutes running time: the accident, the intrusive lawyer Mitchell (Ian Holm) and his daughter, Zoe (Caerthan Banks), the overly-motherly bus driver Dolores (Gabrielle Rose), the sex affair between Billy (Bruce Greenwood) and Risa (Alberta Watson) and, of course, the illicit and incestuous situation between Nicole (Sarah Polley) and her father, Sam (Tom McCamus). It takes a master film-maker to put all that together and achieve a work of art. On that basis, all serious film lovers should not miss this event, even if the story is unpalatable for many. Life, however, is full of such stories: read the daily tabloids. Ian Holm is the focus and catalyst of this narrative, for two reasons: first, he is, to some extent, the typical (or not so-typical) "ambulance chaser" after a buck, or too many; hence, much of the action involves his presence. Second, he is also after justice for the dead and lost children, spurred on because he lost Zoe to drugs, alcohol, AIDS etc  so she is effectively dead to him also. By trying to help the town folk in their loss, he hopes to achieve some sense of closure for his own loss  in other words, a self-serving attitude, much like the world in general. I think Holm gives the performance of his life in this film. For me, the greatest pleasure was listening to the voice-over of The Pied Piper of Hamelin, the narration of which is spoken by Nicole throughout the film. That poem serves to function as a metaphor of course for the fate that awaits her and her father: loneliness, sadness and despair in a cruel and indifferent world, while all the deceased children have moved on to the sweet hereafter. Not to be missed. November 27, 2011.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as exceptional as expected
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kneiss1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So this is the best rated movie of Atom Egoyan? I love his movies, and I have to say, sadly I expected a bit more. Don't get me wrong, cinematic everything is perfect. This movie is filmed beautifully. Every actor played on an extremely high level and not a single miscast was to be found in this movie! Overall it was a great watch. For me that was only destructed by the story. To me it felt, that the original novel was not suited to become a movie. The whole movie lacked a red thread. Strings didn't seem to be connected, and i failed finding a bigger meaning. All I found have been starting points, ideas. Great ideas, but in the end, the movie didn't work for me. It almost convinced me, but ultimately failed at the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ZzZzzZzZzZzzzZ
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Raul Faust
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know, to enjoy this film you have to be very patient. It runs very slowly, nothing interesting happens, there are too many names and different people coming and going, you never know what's going on; More than that, you don't get to see the accident until 60 minutes. It's like you're watching a soap opera with good actors, but with a unsatisfying development. 70 minutes was enough for me to turn it off because of it's boring scenes and conversations. I really expected much more for "Sweet Hereafter"; you know, it didn't work for me personally, don't know how it'd work with other people. IMDb wants me to write more, so I'll just repeat that I didn't like that...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great story which could be better told
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shhazam2
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite the director Atom Egoyan's misuse and overuse of flashbacks and flash forwards, this movie contained a great story. A terrible tragedy from which there was no emotional relief for the survivors except the chance for one to exact punishment for incest and child abuse. This story could have been told almost strictly chronologically from before the accident to after the accident without misusing the flashback technique and saving that technique for some of the background of the attorney which was still very well played by Ian Holm. Be patient with this movie and forgiving of the flash back misuse and you will have seen a gem of a story told about a tragic happening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
