<filme>
 <id>
  898
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119925
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Mensageiro
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A drifter with no name finds a jeep with the skeleton of a postman and a bag of mail and dons the postman's uniform and bag of mail as he begins a quest to inspire hope to the survivors living in the post apocalyptic America.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In the year 2013 civilization has all but destroyed itself. After a war that decimated the government and most of the population of the United States (possibly the world) people struggle to survive against starvation and rogue groups of armed men. One such group is called the Holnists. This group is bigger than any other and their leader, General Bethlehem, has delusions of ruling the country. A drifter is captured by the group and forced to join. He escapes at the first chance and happens on a mail jeep with a skeleton in it. The skeleton is wearing a postal uniform and the drifter takes it to keep him warm. He also finds a mailbag and starts conning people with old letters. The hope he sees in the people he delivers to changes his plans and he decides that he must help bring the Holnists down.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   postman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drifter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   escape
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   leader
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   letter
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Kevin Costner
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   David Brin
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Eric Roth
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kevin Costner
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Will Patton
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Larenz Tate
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Postman  After destroying itself how can society get back up on its feet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman is a post-apocalypse survival movie geared toward society and what it means to be a society. The good. The settings are well chosen and built. Great main characters with nicely developing personas. Interesting story. Good pace. The intro is solid and really puts us in the right mood. The actors. Kevin Costner is a great fit for his role as a loner surviving on his wits. Olivia Williams is disarmingly charming as the sweet girl with a budding iron determination. Will Patton makes us hate his egocentric character right away. You can't help but get attached to Larenz Tate as the over eager young man looking for meaning to his life. Daniel von Bargen as the suspicious sheriff is just right. And finally, Giovanni Ribisi in the small role of an almost psychotic blind follower is astounding. The bad. Just a few things. Galloping horses before the siege. Really? You needed to do that to build the tension before the attack? The cable ride. A horse would have been just as good. The ugly. The 30 years later ending. F*ck that! It ruined the movie. Cut it out and it's an additional star, easy. The result. The length of the movie is not for everybody, but it's good entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Post Apocalypse Movie I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Raskin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that 15 out of the last 20 reviewers over the last two years have given this movie 6 stars or above. As the wicked hatchet job the professional critics did on the movie when it first came out in 1997 gets forgotten, I believe more and more people will discover just how brilliant and classic this film is and 3/4ths of people who see it will enjoy it. In the year 2013, after an apocalypse, only small bands of isolated, frightened humans are still alive in the western United States. Apparently all electricity and electrical communication is gone. People are suspicious of each other and live in fortress-like towns. Loner Costner discovers an old mail truck with a dead mailman inside. He takes the clothes of the mailman and carries his mailbag filled with mail. Desperately needing food, he approaches the guards at the gate of a nearby town and tells them that he is a postman appointed by the new President of the United States, Richard Starkey, from Minnesota to deliver mail. The people of the town believe his story and are excited that civilization is starting again. One of the town's young men demands that Costner tell him how he can become a postman like him. Costner appoints him the postman for the town. The town's sheriff discovers Costner's deception and kicks him out of town. The following year, Costner returns again. He is astonished to find a fully functioning post office with dozens of new postmen and women delivering mail to different towns in the region. Costner gets welcomed back as a hero and nearly a God. Everyone now believes Costner's fable about the United States starting up again and the new president living in Minnesota. Costner's great lies about a new country starting are ironically actually causing a new country to be started. Why did the movie get such bad reviews? It believe it was because of the movie's ideology. I think the extreme negative reaction was only because the movie presented the idea that total lies can be believed and start new movements. It is an offensive thought for many true believers. The hero, Kevin Costner, makes up a fabulous lie. It leads to a new cult centered around him. The movie at one point makes the connection to Christian ideology transparent. Costner asks his companion Abbey why everybody believes the nonsense he made up. She answers, "You made Mrs. March feel like she could see again. You made Ford believe he was part of something. You give out hope like it was candy in your pocket." If you like Westerns or Science Fiction or just thoughtful movies, you'll probably enjoy this movie. I am sorry that I listened to the critics and did not see it for 15 years after it came out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorta like vampires, huh?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lost in Film UK
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story/Plot  We have arrived in the year 2013. The United States of America are no longer united. A war has since passed and the civilization of the world has near enough destroyed itself. A lone wanderer (Costner) drifts along with his beloved donkey until he is captured by a savage militia led by the notorious General Bethlehem (Patton). The drifter manages to escape and by chance falls upon a Jeep. Inside this Jeep he finds a skeleton donning a postman's outfit. Desperate for dry clothes he takes the uniform and mailbag. He goes from town to town delivering the mail in an elaborate con to gain food and shelter. Soon though the postal service is revived and the legend of the postman ensues. Bethlehem is determined to put a stop to the revolution caused by the postman. In reply the postman rallies support and takes on the general in a bid for leadership of the militia. A fight that could turn civilization back to the ways of old. My verdict  A brilliant epic tale of one man's quest to put the right back into the world that has long since gone. A must watch for everyone. I now rate this film in my top 5 all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Self Indulgent trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not until this was released on blu ray did i manage to catch The Postman.What have i been missing all these years - absolutely nothing apart from the best part of three hours i wont get back. Its interesting watching this in light of more recent post apocalyptic flops but The Postman takes the biscuit. The script is totally overloaded with schmaltz - a pure glucose overdose. The cast seem to be taking the whole thing so seriously when they are participating in a joke. The only good thing about the movie is Will Pattons performance as the bad guy but his eyesight is failing as he cannot recognise Costner without his facial hair. It also is annoying that Ribisi (playing a loon again) and Russo (playing a bad ass again) are offed in the first half hour as they were entertaining. But hey great looking blu ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is WAY under rated!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mojave_jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a much better post apocalyptic film than almost any others out there. WAY UNDER RATED. It holds your attention all the way through and is almost a post apocalypse version of Dances With Wolves. As such, it should be rated between 7 and 8. Don't know what those low voters were thinking. The Postman never explains what the cause of the breakdown of society is, it leaves it up to the view to decide if it was a nuclear war, a pandemic, or some other catastrophe. The cause is not important. It chronicles the adventure of an actor/conman who starts a con to get food and supplies and comes to believe in his cause. He starts out as a minor villain and ends up being the hero.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A much better film than people give it credit for.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Piggy6756
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I also think this film is far better than its reviews suggest. The photography, for one thing, is beautiful, showcasing as it does the North West American wilderness. More than this, and the reason why I cut the film a great deal of slack, is its moral core. Costner's character, at a difficult point in his life in this dystopian future, discovers a wrecked mail van, puts on the dead driver's jacket, and decides to deliver the mail to the nearest community as a way to scrounge a meal and a bed for the night. Quite against his expectations he strikes a chord with the community he visits, and they give him mail to deliver to their loved ones whom they have not spoken to in years. So he starts a mail service for his own benefit, but as he brings people messages from people they thought were dead he also brings them hope that life will get better and in the process he becomes a better man. There is a violent conclusion to the movie, but it is not the violence that revives the community but someone bringing people closer together via the mail. For that reason in particular I look kindly on this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wholly Underrated - Would've Been A Huge Hit In 2002
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman suffered from its release date. Had it come out the first couple years post-9/11, it would've been seen as an uplifting epic and been a huge hit. Instead, it came out in the middle of a period of relative discontent with the US, where there was no threat of anything to be lost, where therewas no threat of stability lost, where there was no greatness to see, as people were absorbed in their own lives and oblivious to the wonders of having such a great country. (Yes, the movie is very focused on the US.) As a national epic, it just came out at the wrong time. There are plenty of bad elements to the film, and the reason why it's a good film and not a great film. The theme is sometimes missing and then returning in a heavy handed way that makes for inconsistency that could've been done better, but it's still a good film. There are cheesy lines, there are characters or their actions that sometimes seem to be a bit forced, but there are others who are completely within the realm of possibility, and some that are very, very believable. Larenz Tate as Ford Lincoln Mercury is one of the most uplifting, motivating, idealistic characters on film in a long time - his spirit by itself is inspiring. There are several scenes in which he really shines, as his character takes responsibility for his actions. Will Patton does a truly outstanding job as General Bethlehem. The character is portrayed every bit as you'd expect a character with his backstory to be - done well, and a character whose occasional seeming overacting would be consistent with how the character - a megalomaniac - would really act. Some small touches towards the beginning really set down who the character is. Kevin Costner is just pretty good. His low-key attitude sometimes comes off as disinterested and not terribly into the role. Costner does have the physical presence to carry off the role, but on occasion he seems just out of it. Sometimes the movie sometimes seems to dwell on Costner too much, even though he is the main character, the changes in the world that he sets in motion are fascinating. He's not bad, he's just good, not great. The other options for leads that were considered would've been far worse. Costner does pull it off well, but he could've put more effort into his own role. Once in a while his own stated motivations (notably at the end) don't seem to have been developed, and it's possible there was something left on the cutting room floor. This goes to the theme as mentioned above and below as well - there may be some scenes that just didn't make the cut that would've expounded on how the theme developed better. Olivia Williams is excellent through most of the movie, though her role becomes a bit conventional at the end, limiting what she can do. (Incidentally, she's great in "Below", which I highly recommend as a WWII sub movie - but it's best watched without any reviews, and even without looking at the box - it's best viewed totally fresh, with zero foreknowledge. Seriously, don't go look it up, just cue it on Netflix or order it online and don't read about it. It's really, really, really good.) Tom Petty's role is fantastic. His first few lines, "I was..." are rather haunting, when you sit down to think about it; they convey a lot of the atmosphere of the film, and go far towards reminding you the world of the Postman is very different. Daniel von Bargen is excellent, and provides a very good foil for Costner to play off towards the beginning of the film. Almost every scene he's in he manages to convey a seriousness and depth that helps ground the film. Ron McLarty is fantastic. His character is great, and the way he plays into it is great. He's another of the supporting cast that provides atmosphere to the film, conveying the setting even more; he also sets up some great lines that foreshadow a lot of action in a way that is just subtle enough that it's not cheesy at all, but clear enough that the audience can see something big and satisfying is on the way. The scenery is majestic, the setting is made to be truly epic - often it is, the score is fantastic (though sometimes a bit heavy-handed, but that's okay), editing is good, lighting is used well, and there's some subtle symbolism tossed in every so often to go along with the overt themes. Some of the costuming stands out positively (especially the improvised uniformity of the Holnists and the carriers), while the costuming for pretty much everybody else is slightly overdone - you can tell there was work put into it, but sometimes almost too much. Overall, the theme is one that may be lost on many folks, and was especially lost at the time. It's a wonderful, patriotic flick that was released at the wrong time. Just remember it's good, not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly under-rated, way better than Waterworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctardis
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know if this movie ever came out in the theaters. If it did, then it must have been for only a brief period. I saw this movie on cable, and I was shocked to find a Kevin Costner movie that I have never heard of. I also was shocked to find it is really a good movie. I suppose the problem is that it came out after Waterworld, and that movie was so bad nobody want to risk money on another Costner post-apocalypse movie. However this is a much better movie than Waterworld. It is more like Dances with Wolves set in a post - apocalyptic era. The performances are all strong. Costner's character evolves through the movie. This one is worth a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Post Apocalyptic Blast!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emina Zeleski
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Postman" is a great movie, regardless of what you "critics" think of it. I think it tries to be as accurate in it's portrayal of the future as any movie I've ever seen. I know that some of you just can't stand the fact that there's no futuristic army battles, no 600 horsepower car chases, and "Iron armored costumes" I honestly think that's how the world would go if all government and basic infrastructure were brought down. Think about it. What would you do? Drive a 600 horsepower, supercharged dune buggy that gets 3 mpg or ride a horse. Gasoline supplies would deplete after about a month. Hoarding gas will not work. (it goes bad after about a year of storage) Most people raised in big cities would starve within a couple of months due to lack of survival education or tyranny by people with guns. Secondly, In the film, Costner ends up being the hero in the way that real hero's do. Hero's aren't the people who are tough and beautiful. They're people who are forced into a situation and do the best they can. He starts the new government purely by accident. The only real mistake I see in this movie is that in the beginning, Costner is portrayed as being weak and unable to defend himself. In reality he would be in extremely good shape strong as an ox and very wily. (he's been dragging a mule around for years. Try that sometime. It'll make you strong as an ox or kill you) I give it 9 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than its rating!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pnorris
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm always a little surprised when I see an IMDb rating that's unusually low compared to my take..then again, I often forget that the average poster on this site is now a 20-something who thinks Pulp Fiction is the best movie ever made..sorry; it's not.that distinction still goes to Godfather I & II although not a personal favorite of mine.along with PF, too violent for my taste.. This film has much to offer for fans of the apocalyptic genre (Road Warrior, Red Dawn, etc.): an intriguing storyline; very good pacing even at its near epic length; good acting; good dialogue; excellent cinematography and a lively score & soundtrack, especially the Pinewood Band tunes. The main cast is appealing with Kevin Costner, Will Patton (in an over-the-top role similar to his "Falling Skies" Capt. Weaver), Olivia Williams, Larenz Tate and Tom Petty in more than a just a cameo..add in some recognizable character actors like Ron McLarty, Rex Linn, Daniel Barger, Joe Santos, George Wyner, Giovani Ribisi and Brain Anthony Wilson..a pretty good crew.. Watching this always makes me feel patriotic like when I watch "Red Dawn".and despite the almost universal bashing Costner receives, he is often very endearing in his roles (For the Love of the Game, Tin Cup, Wyatt Earp, JFK, Field of Dreams, Bull Durham, No Way Out and Dances with Wolves).if you've ever seen the creepy Mr. Brooks, you know he can actually act.and he does deliver some very funny lines; my favorite: "So much for the uniform theory".. 8 stars.watch it for yourself and choose
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Postman  After destroying itself how can society get back up on its feet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman is a post-apocalypse survival movie geared toward society and what it means to be a society. The good. The settings are well chosen and built. Great main characters with nicely developing personas. Interesting story. Good pace. The intro is solid and really puts us in the right mood. The actors. Kevin Costner is a great fit for his role as a loner surviving on his wits. Olivia Williams is disarmingly charming as the sweet girl with a budding iron determination. Will Patton makes us hate his egocentric character right away. You can't help but get attached to Larenz Tate as the over eager young man looking for meaning to his life. Daniel von Bargen as the suspicious sheriff is just right. And finally, Giovanni Ribisi in the small role of an almost psychotic blind follower is astounding. The bad. Just a few things. Galloping horses before the siege. Really? You needed to do that to build the tension before the attack? The cable ride. A horse would have been just as good. The ugly. The 30 years later ending. F*ck that! It ruined the movie. Cut it out and it's an additional star, easy. The result. The length of the movie is not for everybody, but it's good entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Post Apocalypse Movie I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Raskin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that 15 out of the last 20 reviewers over the last two years have given this movie 6 stars or above. As the wicked hatchet job the professional critics did on the movie when it first came out in 1997 gets forgotten, I believe more and more people will discover just how brilliant and classic this film is and 3/4ths of people who see it will enjoy it. In the year 2013, after an apocalypse, only small bands of isolated, frightened humans are still alive in the western United States. Apparently all electricity and electrical communication is gone. People are suspicious of each other and live in fortress-like towns. Loner Costner discovers an old mail truck with a dead mailman inside. He takes the clothes of the mailman and carries his mailbag filled with mail. Desperately needing food, he approaches the guards at the gate of a nearby town and tells them that he is a postman appointed by the new President of the United States, Richard Starkey, from Minnesota to deliver mail. The people of the town believe his story and are excited that civilization is starting again. One of the town's young men demands that Costner tell him how he can become a postman like him. Costner appoints him the postman for the town. The town's sheriff discovers Costner's deception and kicks him out of town. The following year, Costner returns again. He is astonished to find a fully functioning post office with dozens of new postmen and women delivering mail to different towns in the region. Costner gets welcomed back as a hero and nearly a God. Everyone now believes Costner's fable about the United States starting up again and the new president living in Minnesota. Costner's great lies about a new country starting are ironically actually causing a new country to be started. Why did the movie get such bad reviews? It believe it was because of the movie's ideology. I think the extreme negative reaction was only because the movie presented the idea that total lies can be believed and start new movements. It is an offensive thought for many true believers. The hero, Kevin Costner, makes up a fabulous lie. It leads to a new cult centered around him. The movie at one point makes the connection to Christian ideology transparent. Costner asks his companion Abbey why everybody believes the nonsense he made up. She answers, "You made Mrs. March feel like she could see again. You made Ford believe he was part of something. You give out hope like it was candy in your pocket." If you like Westerns or Science Fiction or just thoughtful movies, you'll probably enjoy this movie. I am sorry that I listened to the critics and did not see it for 15 years after it came out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorta like vampires, huh?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lost in Film UK
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story/Plot  We have arrived in the year 2013. The United States of America are no longer united. A war has since passed and the civilization of the world has near enough destroyed itself. A lone wanderer (Costner) drifts along with his beloved donkey until he is captured by a savage militia led by the notorious General Bethlehem (Patton). The drifter manages to escape and by chance falls upon a Jeep. Inside this Jeep he finds a skeleton donning a postman's outfit. Desperate for dry clothes he takes the uniform and mailbag. He goes from town to town delivering the mail in an elaborate con to gain food and shelter. Soon though the postal service is revived and the legend of the postman ensues. Bethlehem is determined to put a stop to the revolution caused by the postman. In reply the postman rallies support and takes on the general in a bid for leadership of the militia. A fight that could turn civilization back to the ways of old. My verdict  A brilliant epic tale of one man's quest to put the right back into the world that has long since gone. A must watch for everyone. I now rate this film in my top 5 all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Self Indulgent trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not until this was released on blu ray did i manage to catch The Postman.What have i been missing all these years - absolutely nothing apart from the best part of three hours i wont get back. Its interesting watching this in light of more recent post apocalyptic flops but The Postman takes the biscuit. The script is totally overloaded with schmaltz - a pure glucose overdose. The cast seem to be taking the whole thing so seriously when they are participating in a joke. The only good thing about the movie is Will Pattons performance as the bad guy but his eyesight is failing as he cannot recognise Costner without his facial hair. It also is annoying that Ribisi (playing a loon again) and Russo (playing a bad ass again) are offed in the first half hour as they were entertaining. But hey great looking blu ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is WAY under rated!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mojave_jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a much better post apocalyptic film than almost any others out there. WAY UNDER RATED. It holds your attention all the way through and is almost a post apocalypse version of Dances With Wolves. As such, it should be rated between 7 and 8. Don't know what those low voters were thinking. The Postman never explains what the cause of the breakdown of society is, it leaves it up to the view to decide if it was a nuclear war, a pandemic, or some other catastrophe. The cause is not important. It chronicles the adventure of an actor/conman who starts a con to get food and supplies and comes to believe in his cause. He starts out as a minor villain and ends up being the hero.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A much better film than people give it credit for.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Piggy6756
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I also think this film is far better than its reviews suggest. The photography, for one thing, is beautiful, showcasing as it does the North West American wilderness. More than this, and the reason why I cut the film a great deal of slack, is its moral core. Costner's character, at a difficult point in his life in this dystopian future, discovers a wrecked mail van, puts on the dead driver's jacket, and decides to deliver the mail to the nearest community as a way to scrounge a meal and a bed for the night. Quite against his expectations he strikes a chord with the community he visits, and they give him mail to deliver to their loved ones whom they have not spoken to in years. So he starts a mail service for his own benefit, but as he brings people messages from people they thought were dead he also brings them hope that life will get better and in the process he becomes a better man. There is a violent conclusion to the movie, but it is not the violence that revives the community but someone bringing people closer together via the mail. For that reason in particular I look kindly on this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wholly Underrated - Would've Been A Huge Hit In 2002
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman suffered from its release date. Had it come out the first couple years post-9/11, it would've been seen as an uplifting epic and been a huge hit. Instead, it came out in the middle of a period of relative discontent with the US, where there was no threat of anything to be lost, where therewas no threat of stability lost, where there was no greatness to see, as people were absorbed in their own lives and oblivious to the wonders of having such a great country. (Yes, the movie is very focused on the US.) As a national epic, it just came out at the wrong time. There are plenty of bad elements to the film, and the reason why it's a good film and not a great film. The theme is sometimes missing and then returning in a heavy handed way that makes for inconsistency that could've been done better, but it's still a good film. There are cheesy lines, there are characters or their actions that sometimes seem to be a bit forced, but there are others who are completely within the realm of possibility, and some that are very, very believable. Larenz Tate as Ford Lincoln Mercury is one of the most uplifting, motivating, idealistic characters on film in a long time - his spirit by itself is inspiring. There are several scenes in which he really shines, as his character takes responsibility for his actions. Will Patton does a truly outstanding job as General Bethlehem. The character is portrayed every bit as you'd expect a character with his backstory to be - done well, and a character whose occasional seeming overacting would be consistent with how the character - a megalomaniac - would really act. Some small touches towards the beginning really set down who the character is. Kevin Costner is just pretty good. His low-key attitude sometimes comes off as disinterested and not terribly into the role. Costner does have the physical presence to carry off the role, but on occasion he seems just out of it. Sometimes the movie sometimes seems to dwell on Costner too much, even though he is the main character, the changes in the world that he sets in motion are fascinating. He's not bad, he's just good, not great. The other options for leads that were considered would've been far worse. Costner does pull it off well, but he could've put more effort into his own role. Once in a while his own stated motivations (notably at the end) don't seem to have been developed, and it's possible there was something left on the cutting room floor. This goes to the theme as mentioned above and below as well - there may be some scenes that just didn't make the cut that would've expounded on how the theme developed better. Olivia Williams is excellent through most of the movie, though her role becomes a bit conventional at the end, limiting what she can do. (Incidentally, she's great in "Below", which I highly recommend as a WWII sub movie - but it's best watched without any reviews, and even without looking at the box - it's best viewed totally fresh, with zero foreknowledge. Seriously, don't go look it up, just cue it on Netflix or order it online and don't read about it. It's really, really, really good.) Tom Petty's role is fantastic. His first few lines, "I was..." are rather haunting, when you sit down to think about it; they convey a lot of the atmosphere of the film, and go far towards reminding you the world of the Postman is very different. Daniel von Bargen is excellent, and provides a very good foil for Costner to play off towards the beginning of the film. Almost every scene he's in he manages to convey a seriousness and depth that helps ground the film. Ron McLarty is fantastic. His character is great, and the way he plays into it is great. He's another of the supporting cast that provides atmosphere to the film, conveying the setting even more; he also sets up some great lines that foreshadow a lot of action in a way that is just subtle enough that it's not cheesy at all, but clear enough that the audience can see something big and satisfying is on the way. The scenery is majestic, the setting is made to be truly epic - often it is, the score is fantastic (though sometimes a bit heavy-handed, but that's okay), editing is good, lighting is used well, and there's some subtle symbolism tossed in every so often to go along with the overt themes. Some of the costuming stands out positively (especially the improvised uniformity of the Holnists and the carriers), while the costuming for pretty much everybody else is slightly overdone - you can tell there was work put into it, but sometimes almost too much. Overall, the theme is one that may be lost on many folks, and was especially lost at the time. It's a wonderful, patriotic flick that was released at the wrong time. Just remember it's good, not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly under-rated, way better than Waterworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctardis
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know if this movie ever came out in the theaters. If it did, then it must have been for only a brief period. I saw this movie on cable, and I was shocked to find a Kevin Costner movie that I have never heard of. I also was shocked to find it is really a good movie. I suppose the problem is that it came out after Waterworld, and that movie was so bad nobody want to risk money on another Costner post-apocalypse movie. However this is a much better movie than Waterworld. It is more like Dances with Wolves set in a post - apocalyptic era. The performances are all strong. Costner's character evolves through the movie. This one is worth a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Post Apocalyptic Blast!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emina Zeleski
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Postman" is a great movie, regardless of what you "critics" think of it. I think it tries to be as accurate in it's portrayal of the future as any movie I've ever seen. I know that some of you just can't stand the fact that there's no futuristic army battles, no 600 horsepower car chases, and "Iron armored costumes" I honestly think that's how the world would go if all government and basic infrastructure were brought down. Think about it. What would you do? Drive a 600 horsepower, supercharged dune buggy that gets 3 mpg or ride a horse. Gasoline supplies would deplete after about a month. Hoarding gas will not work. (it goes bad after about a year of storage) Most people raised in big cities would starve within a couple of months due to lack of survival education or tyranny by people with guns. Secondly, In the film, Costner ends up being the hero in the way that real hero's do. Hero's aren't the people who are tough and beautiful. They're people who are forced into a situation and do the best they can. He starts the new government purely by accident. The only real mistake I see in this movie is that in the beginning, Costner is portrayed as being weak and unable to defend himself. In reality he would be in extremely good shape strong as an ox and very wily. (he's been dragging a mule around for years. Try that sometime. It'll make you strong as an ox or kill you) I give it 9 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than its rating!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pnorris
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm always a little surprised when I see an IMDb rating that's unusually low compared to my take..then again, I often forget that the average poster on this site is now a 20-something who thinks Pulp Fiction is the best movie ever made..sorry; it's not.that distinction still goes to Godfather I & II although not a personal favorite of mine.along with PF, too violent for my taste.. This film has much to offer for fans of the apocalyptic genre (Road Warrior, Red Dawn, etc.): an intriguing storyline; very good pacing even at its near epic length; good acting; good dialogue; excellent cinematography and a lively score & soundtrack, especially the Pinewood Band tunes. The main cast is appealing with Kevin Costner, Will Patton (in an over-the-top role similar to his "Falling Skies" Capt. Weaver), Olivia Williams, Larenz Tate and Tom Petty in more than a just a cameo..add in some recognizable character actors like Ron McLarty, Rex Linn, Daniel Barger, Joe Santos, George Wyner, Giovani Ribisi and Brain Anthony Wilson..a pretty good crew.. Watching this always makes me feel patriotic like when I watch "Red Dawn".and despite the almost universal bashing Costner receives, he is often very endearing in his roles (For the Love of the Game, Tin Cup, Wyatt Earp, JFK, Field of Dreams, Bull Durham, No Way Out and Dances with Wolves).if you've ever seen the creepy Mr. Brooks, you know he can actually act.and he does deliver some very funny lines; my favorite: "So much for the uniform theory".. 8 stars.watch it for yourself and choose
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Postman  After destroying itself how can society get back up on its feet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman is a post-apocalypse survival movie geared toward society and what it means to be a society. The good. The settings are well chosen and built. Great main characters with nicely developing personas. Interesting story. Good pace. The intro is solid and really puts us in the right mood. The actors. Kevin Costner is a great fit for his role as a loner surviving on his wits. Olivia Williams is disarmingly charming as the sweet girl with a budding iron determination. Will Patton makes us hate his egocentric character right away. You can't help but get attached to Larenz Tate as the over eager young man looking for meaning to his life. Daniel von Bargen as the suspicious sheriff is just right. And finally, Giovanni Ribisi in the small role of an almost psychotic blind follower is astounding. The bad. Just a few things. Galloping horses before the siege. Really? You needed to do that to build the tension before the attack? The cable ride. A horse would have been just as good. The ugly. The 30 years later ending. F*ck that! It ruined the movie. Cut it out and it's an additional star, easy. The result. The length of the movie is not for everybody, but it's good entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Post Apocalypse Movie I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Raskin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that 15 out of the last 20 reviewers over the last two years have given this movie 6 stars or above. As the wicked hatchet job the professional critics did on the movie when it first came out in 1997 gets forgotten, I believe more and more people will discover just how brilliant and classic this film is and 3/4ths of people who see it will enjoy it. In the year 2013, after an apocalypse, only small bands of isolated, frightened humans are still alive in the western United States. Apparently all electricity and electrical communication is gone. People are suspicious of each other and live in fortress-like towns. Loner Costner discovers an old mail truck with a dead mailman inside. He takes the clothes of the mailman and carries his mailbag filled with mail. Desperately needing food, he approaches the guards at the gate of a nearby town and tells them that he is a postman appointed by the new President of the United States, Richard Starkey, from Minnesota to deliver mail. The people of the town believe his story and are excited that civilization is starting again. One of the town's young men demands that Costner tell him how he can become a postman like him. Costner appoints him the postman for the town. The town's sheriff discovers Costner's deception and kicks him out of town. The following year, Costner returns again. He is astonished to find a fully functioning post office with dozens of new postmen and women delivering mail to different towns in the region. Costner gets welcomed back as a hero and nearly a God. Everyone now believes Costner's fable about the United States starting up again and the new president living in Minnesota. Costner's great lies about a new country starting are ironically actually causing a new country to be started. Why did the movie get such bad reviews? It believe it was because of the movie's ideology. I think the extreme negative reaction was only because the movie presented the idea that total lies can be believed and start new movements. It is an offensive thought for many true believers. The hero, Kevin Costner, makes up a fabulous lie. It leads to a new cult centered around him. The movie at one point makes the connection to Christian ideology transparent. Costner asks his companion Abbey why everybody believes the nonsense he made up. She answers, "You made Mrs. March feel like she could see again. You made Ford believe he was part of something. You give out hope like it was candy in your pocket." If you like Westerns or Science Fiction or just thoughtful movies, you'll probably enjoy this movie. I am sorry that I listened to the critics and did not see it for 15 years after it came out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorta like vampires, huh?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lost in Film UK
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story/Plot  We have arrived in the year 2013. The United States of America are no longer united. A war has since passed and the civilization of the world has near enough destroyed itself. A lone wanderer (Costner) drifts along with his beloved donkey until he is captured by a savage militia led by the notorious General Bethlehem (Patton). The drifter manages to escape and by chance falls upon a Jeep. Inside this Jeep he finds a skeleton donning a postman's outfit. Desperate for dry clothes he takes the uniform and mailbag. He goes from town to town delivering the mail in an elaborate con to gain food and shelter. Soon though the postal service is revived and the legend of the postman ensues. Bethlehem is determined to put a stop to the revolution caused by the postman. In reply the postman rallies support and takes on the general in a bid for leadership of the militia. A fight that could turn civilization back to the ways of old. My verdict  A brilliant epic tale of one man's quest to put the right back into the world that has long since gone. A must watch for everyone. I now rate this film in my top 5 all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Self Indulgent trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not until this was released on blu ray did i manage to catch The Postman.What have i been missing all these years - absolutely nothing apart from the best part of three hours i wont get back. Its interesting watching this in light of more recent post apocalyptic flops but The Postman takes the biscuit. The script is totally overloaded with schmaltz - a pure glucose overdose. The cast seem to be taking the whole thing so seriously when they are participating in a joke. The only good thing about the movie is Will Pattons performance as the bad guy but his eyesight is failing as he cannot recognise Costner without his facial hair. It also is annoying that Ribisi (playing a loon again) and Russo (playing a bad ass again) are offed in the first half hour as they were entertaining. But hey great looking blu ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is WAY under rated!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mojave_jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a much better post apocalyptic film than almost any others out there. WAY UNDER RATED. It holds your attention all the way through and is almost a post apocalypse version of Dances With Wolves. As such, it should be rated between 7 and 8. Don't know what those low voters were thinking. The Postman never explains what the cause of the breakdown of society is, it leaves it up to the view to decide if it was a nuclear war, a pandemic, or some other catastrophe. The cause is not important. It chronicles the adventure of an actor/conman who starts a con to get food and supplies and comes to believe in his cause. He starts out as a minor villain and ends up being the hero.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A much better film than people give it credit for.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Piggy6756
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I also think this film is far better than its reviews suggest. The photography, for one thing, is beautiful, showcasing as it does the North West American wilderness. More than this, and the reason why I cut the film a great deal of slack, is its moral core. Costner's character, at a difficult point in his life in this dystopian future, discovers a wrecked mail van, puts on the dead driver's jacket, and decides to deliver the mail to the nearest community as a way to scrounge a meal and a bed for the night. Quite against his expectations he strikes a chord with the community he visits, and they give him mail to deliver to their loved ones whom they have not spoken to in years. So he starts a mail service for his own benefit, but as he brings people messages from people they thought were dead he also brings them hope that life will get better and in the process he becomes a better man. There is a violent conclusion to the movie, but it is not the violence that revives the community but someone bringing people closer together via the mail. For that reason in particular I look kindly on this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wholly Underrated - Would've Been A Huge Hit In 2002
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman suffered from its release date. Had it come out the first couple years post-9/11, it would've been seen as an uplifting epic and been a huge hit. Instead, it came out in the middle of a period of relative discontent with the US, where there was no threat of anything to be lost, where therewas no threat of stability lost, where there was no greatness to see, as people were absorbed in their own lives and oblivious to the wonders of having such a great country. (Yes, the movie is very focused on the US.) As a national epic, it just came out at the wrong time. There are plenty of bad elements to the film, and the reason why it's a good film and not a great film. The theme is sometimes missing and then returning in a heavy handed way that makes for inconsistency that could've been done better, but it's still a good film. There are cheesy lines, there are characters or their actions that sometimes seem to be a bit forced, but there are others who are completely within the realm of possibility, and some that are very, very believable. Larenz Tate as Ford Lincoln Mercury is one of the most uplifting, motivating, idealistic characters on film in a long time - his spirit by itself is inspiring. There are several scenes in which he really shines, as his character takes responsibility for his actions. Will Patton does a truly outstanding job as General Bethlehem. The character is portrayed every bit as you'd expect a character with his backstory to be - done well, and a character whose occasional seeming overacting would be consistent with how the character - a megalomaniac - would really act. Some small touches towards the beginning really set down who the character is. Kevin Costner is just pretty good. His low-key attitude sometimes comes off as disinterested and not terribly into the role. Costner does have the physical presence to carry off the role, but on occasion he seems just out of it. Sometimes the movie sometimes seems to dwell on Costner too much, even though he is the main character, the changes in the world that he sets in motion are fascinating. He's not bad, he's just good, not great. The other options for leads that were considered would've been far worse. Costner does pull it off well, but he could've put more effort into his own role. Once in a while his own stated motivations (notably at the end) don't seem to have been developed, and it's possible there was something left on the cutting room floor. This goes to the theme as mentioned above and below as well - there may be some scenes that just didn't make the cut that would've expounded on how the theme developed better. Olivia Williams is excellent through most of the movie, though her role becomes a bit conventional at the end, limiting what she can do. (Incidentally, she's great in "Below", which I highly recommend as a WWII sub movie - but it's best watched without any reviews, and even without looking at the box - it's best viewed totally fresh, with zero foreknowledge. Seriously, don't go look it up, just cue it on Netflix or order it online and don't read about it. It's really, really, really good.) Tom Petty's role is fantastic. His first few lines, "I was..." are rather haunting, when you sit down to think about it; they convey a lot of the atmosphere of the film, and go far towards reminding you the world of the Postman is very different. Daniel von Bargen is excellent, and provides a very good foil for Costner to play off towards the beginning of the film. Almost every scene he's in he manages to convey a seriousness and depth that helps ground the film. Ron McLarty is fantastic. His character is great, and the way he plays into it is great. He's another of the supporting cast that provides atmosphere to the film, conveying the setting even more; he also sets up some great lines that foreshadow a lot of action in a way that is just subtle enough that it's not cheesy at all, but clear enough that the audience can see something big and satisfying is on the way. The scenery is majestic, the setting is made to be truly epic - often it is, the score is fantastic (though sometimes a bit heavy-handed, but that's okay), editing is good, lighting is used well, and there's some subtle symbolism tossed in every so often to go along with the overt themes. Some of the costuming stands out positively (especially the improvised uniformity of the Holnists and the carriers), while the costuming for pretty much everybody else is slightly overdone - you can tell there was work put into it, but sometimes almost too much. Overall, the theme is one that may be lost on many folks, and was especially lost at the time. It's a wonderful, patriotic flick that was released at the wrong time. Just remember it's good, not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly under-rated, way better than Waterworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctardis
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know if this movie ever came out in the theaters. If it did, then it must have been for only a brief period. I saw this movie on cable, and I was shocked to find a Kevin Costner movie that I have never heard of. I also was shocked to find it is really a good movie. I suppose the problem is that it came out after Waterworld, and that movie was so bad nobody want to risk money on another Costner post-apocalypse movie. However this is a much better movie than Waterworld. It is more like Dances with Wolves set in a post - apocalyptic era. The performances are all strong. Costner's character evolves through the movie. This one is worth a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Post Apocalyptic Blast!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emina Zeleski
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Postman" is a great movie, regardless of what you "critics" think of it. I think it tries to be as accurate in it's portrayal of the future as any movie I've ever seen. I know that some of you just can't stand the fact that there's no futuristic army battles, no 600 horsepower car chases, and "Iron armored costumes" I honestly think that's how the world would go if all government and basic infrastructure were brought down. Think about it. What would you do? Drive a 600 horsepower, supercharged dune buggy that gets 3 mpg or ride a horse. Gasoline supplies would deplete after about a month. Hoarding gas will not work. (it goes bad after about a year of storage) Most people raised in big cities would starve within a couple of months due to lack of survival education or tyranny by people with guns. Secondly, In the film, Costner ends up being the hero in the way that real hero's do. Hero's aren't the people who are tough and beautiful. They're people who are forced into a situation and do the best they can. He starts the new government purely by accident. The only real mistake I see in this movie is that in the beginning, Costner is portrayed as being weak and unable to defend himself. In reality he would be in extremely good shape strong as an ox and very wily. (he's been dragging a mule around for years. Try that sometime. It'll make you strong as an ox or kill you) I give it 9 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than its rating!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pnorris
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm always a little surprised when I see an IMDb rating that's unusually low compared to my take..then again, I often forget that the average poster on this site is now a 20-something who thinks Pulp Fiction is the best movie ever made..sorry; it's not.that distinction still goes to Godfather I & II although not a personal favorite of mine.along with PF, too violent for my taste.. This film has much to offer for fans of the apocalyptic genre (Road Warrior, Red Dawn, etc.): an intriguing storyline; very good pacing even at its near epic length; good acting; good dialogue; excellent cinematography and a lively score & soundtrack, especially the Pinewood Band tunes. The main cast is appealing with Kevin Costner, Will Patton (in an over-the-top role similar to his "Falling Skies" Capt. Weaver), Olivia Williams, Larenz Tate and Tom Petty in more than a just a cameo..add in some recognizable character actors like Ron McLarty, Rex Linn, Daniel Barger, Joe Santos, George Wyner, Giovani Ribisi and Brain Anthony Wilson..a pretty good crew.. Watching this always makes me feel patriotic like when I watch "Red Dawn".and despite the almost universal bashing Costner receives, he is often very endearing in his roles (For the Love of the Game, Tin Cup, Wyatt Earp, JFK, Field of Dreams, Bull Durham, No Way Out and Dances with Wolves).if you've ever seen the creepy Mr. Brooks, you know he can actually act.and he does deliver some very funny lines; my favorite: "So much for the uniform theory".. 8 stars.watch it for yourself and choose
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Postman  After destroying itself how can society get back up on its feet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman is a post-apocalypse survival movie geared toward society and what it means to be a society. The good. The settings are well chosen and built. Great main characters with nicely developing personas. Interesting story. Good pace. The intro is solid and really puts us in the right mood. The actors. Kevin Costner is a great fit for his role as a loner surviving on his wits. Olivia Williams is disarmingly charming as the sweet girl with a budding iron determination. Will Patton makes us hate his egocentric character right away. You can't help but get attached to Larenz Tate as the over eager young man looking for meaning to his life. Daniel von Bargen as the suspicious sheriff is just right. And finally, Giovanni Ribisi in the small role of an almost psychotic blind follower is astounding. The bad. Just a few things. Galloping horses before the siege. Really? You needed to do that to build the tension before the attack? The cable ride. A horse would have been just as good. The ugly. The 30 years later ending. F*ck that! It ruined the movie. Cut it out and it's an additional star, easy. The result. The length of the movie is not for everybody, but it's good entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Post Apocalypse Movie I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Raskin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that 15 out of the last 20 reviewers over the last two years have given this movie 6 stars or above. As the wicked hatchet job the professional critics did on the movie when it first came out in 1997 gets forgotten, I believe more and more people will discover just how brilliant and classic this film is and 3/4ths of people who see it will enjoy it. In the year 2013, after an apocalypse, only small bands of isolated, frightened humans are still alive in the western United States. Apparently all electricity and electrical communication is gone. People are suspicious of each other and live in fortress-like towns. Loner Costner discovers an old mail truck with a dead mailman inside. He takes the clothes of the mailman and carries his mailbag filled with mail. Desperately needing food, he approaches the guards at the gate of a nearby town and tells them that he is a postman appointed by the new President of the United States, Richard Starkey, from Minnesota to deliver mail. The people of the town believe his story and are excited that civilization is starting again. One of the town's young men demands that Costner tell him how he can become a postman like him. Costner appoints him the postman for the town. The town's sheriff discovers Costner's deception and kicks him out of town. The following year, Costner returns again. He is astonished to find a fully functioning post office with dozens of new postmen and women delivering mail to different towns in the region. Costner gets welcomed back as a hero and nearly a God. Everyone now believes Costner's fable about the United States starting up again and the new president living in Minnesota. Costner's great lies about a new country starting are ironically actually causing a new country to be started. Why did the movie get such bad reviews? It believe it was because of the movie's ideology. I think the extreme negative reaction was only because the movie presented the idea that total lies can be believed and start new movements. It is an offensive thought for many true believers. The hero, Kevin Costner, makes up a fabulous lie. It leads to a new cult centered around him. The movie at one point makes the connection to Christian ideology transparent. Costner asks his companion Abbey why everybody believes the nonsense he made up. She answers, "You made Mrs. March feel like she could see again. You made Ford believe he was part of something. You give out hope like it was candy in your pocket." If you like Westerns or Science Fiction or just thoughtful movies, you'll probably enjoy this movie. I am sorry that I listened to the critics and did not see it for 15 years after it came out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorta like vampires, huh?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lost in Film UK
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story/Plot  We have arrived in the year 2013. The United States of America are no longer united. A war has since passed and the civilization of the world has near enough destroyed itself. A lone wanderer (Costner) drifts along with his beloved donkey until he is captured by a savage militia led by the notorious General Bethlehem (Patton). The drifter manages to escape and by chance falls upon a Jeep. Inside this Jeep he finds a skeleton donning a postman's outfit. Desperate for dry clothes he takes the uniform and mailbag. He goes from town to town delivering the mail in an elaborate con to gain food and shelter. Soon though the postal service is revived and the legend of the postman ensues. Bethlehem is determined to put a stop to the revolution caused by the postman. In reply the postman rallies support and takes on the general in a bid for leadership of the militia. A fight that could turn civilization back to the ways of old. My verdict  A brilliant epic tale of one man's quest to put the right back into the world that has long since gone. A must watch for everyone. I now rate this film in my top 5 all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Self Indulgent trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not until this was released on blu ray did i manage to catch The Postman.What have i been missing all these years - absolutely nothing apart from the best part of three hours i wont get back. Its interesting watching this in light of more recent post apocalyptic flops but The Postman takes the biscuit. The script is totally overloaded with schmaltz - a pure glucose overdose. The cast seem to be taking the whole thing so seriously when they are participating in a joke. The only good thing about the movie is Will Pattons performance as the bad guy but his eyesight is failing as he cannot recognise Costner without his facial hair. It also is annoying that Ribisi (playing a loon again) and Russo (playing a bad ass again) are offed in the first half hour as they were entertaining. But hey great looking blu ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is WAY under rated!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mojave_jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a much better post apocalyptic film than almost any others out there. WAY UNDER RATED. It holds your attention all the way through and is almost a post apocalypse version of Dances With Wolves. As such, it should be rated between 7 and 8. Don't know what those low voters were thinking. The Postman never explains what the cause of the breakdown of society is, it leaves it up to the view to decide if it was a nuclear war, a pandemic, or some other catastrophe. The cause is not important. It chronicles the adventure of an actor/conman who starts a con to get food and supplies and comes to believe in his cause. He starts out as a minor villain and ends up being the hero.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A much better film than people give it credit for.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Piggy6756
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I also think this film is far better than its reviews suggest. The photography, for one thing, is beautiful, showcasing as it does the North West American wilderness. More than this, and the reason why I cut the film a great deal of slack, is its moral core. Costner's character, at a difficult point in his life in this dystopian future, discovers a wrecked mail van, puts on the dead driver's jacket, and decides to deliver the mail to the nearest community as a way to scrounge a meal and a bed for the night. Quite against his expectations he strikes a chord with the community he visits, and they give him mail to deliver to their loved ones whom they have not spoken to in years. So he starts a mail service for his own benefit, but as he brings people messages from people they thought were dead he also brings them hope that life will get better and in the process he becomes a better man. There is a violent conclusion to the movie, but it is not the violence that revives the community but someone bringing people closer together via the mail. For that reason in particular I look kindly on this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wholly Underrated - Would've Been A Huge Hit In 2002
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman suffered from its release date. Had it come out the first couple years post-9/11, it would've been seen as an uplifting epic and been a huge hit. Instead, it came out in the middle of a period of relative discontent with the US, where there was no threat of anything to be lost, where therewas no threat of stability lost, where there was no greatness to see, as people were absorbed in their own lives and oblivious to the wonders of having such a great country. (Yes, the movie is very focused on the US.) As a national epic, it just came out at the wrong time. There are plenty of bad elements to the film, and the reason why it's a good film and not a great film. The theme is sometimes missing and then returning in a heavy handed way that makes for inconsistency that could've been done better, but it's still a good film. There are cheesy lines, there are characters or their actions that sometimes seem to be a bit forced, but there are others who are completely within the realm of possibility, and some that are very, very believable. Larenz Tate as Ford Lincoln Mercury is one of the most uplifting, motivating, idealistic characters on film in a long time - his spirit by itself is inspiring. There are several scenes in which he really shines, as his character takes responsibility for his actions. Will Patton does a truly outstanding job as General Bethlehem. The character is portrayed every bit as you'd expect a character with his backstory to be - done well, and a character whose occasional seeming overacting would be consistent with how the character - a megalomaniac - would really act. Some small touches towards the beginning really set down who the character is. Kevin Costner is just pretty good. His low-key attitude sometimes comes off as disinterested and not terribly into the role. Costner does have the physical presence to carry off the role, but on occasion he seems just out of it. Sometimes the movie sometimes seems to dwell on Costner too much, even though he is the main character, the changes in the world that he sets in motion are fascinating. He's not bad, he's just good, not great. The other options for leads that were considered would've been far worse. Costner does pull it off well, but he could've put more effort into his own role. Once in a while his own stated motivations (notably at the end) don't seem to have been developed, and it's possible there was something left on the cutting room floor. This goes to the theme as mentioned above and below as well - there may be some scenes that just didn't make the cut that would've expounded on how the theme developed better. Olivia Williams is excellent through most of the movie, though her role becomes a bit conventional at the end, limiting what she can do. (Incidentally, she's great in "Below", which I highly recommend as a WWII sub movie - but it's best watched without any reviews, and even without looking at the box - it's best viewed totally fresh, with zero foreknowledge. Seriously, don't go look it up, just cue it on Netflix or order it online and don't read about it. It's really, really, really good.) Tom Petty's role is fantastic. His first few lines, "I was..." are rather haunting, when you sit down to think about it; they convey a lot of the atmosphere of the film, and go far towards reminding you the world of the Postman is very different. Daniel von Bargen is excellent, and provides a very good foil for Costner to play off towards the beginning of the film. Almost every scene he's in he manages to convey a seriousness and depth that helps ground the film. Ron McLarty is fantastic. His character is great, and the way he plays into it is great. He's another of the supporting cast that provides atmosphere to the film, conveying the setting even more; he also sets up some great lines that foreshadow a lot of action in a way that is just subtle enough that it's not cheesy at all, but clear enough that the audience can see something big and satisfying is on the way. The scenery is majestic, the setting is made to be truly epic - often it is, the score is fantastic (though sometimes a bit heavy-handed, but that's okay), editing is good, lighting is used well, and there's some subtle symbolism tossed in every so often to go along with the overt themes. Some of the costuming stands out positively (especially the improvised uniformity of the Holnists and the carriers), while the costuming for pretty much everybody else is slightly overdone - you can tell there was work put into it, but sometimes almost too much. Overall, the theme is one that may be lost on many folks, and was especially lost at the time. It's a wonderful, patriotic flick that was released at the wrong time. Just remember it's good, not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly under-rated, way better than Waterworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctardis
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know if this movie ever came out in the theaters. If it did, then it must have been for only a brief period. I saw this movie on cable, and I was shocked to find a Kevin Costner movie that I have never heard of. I also was shocked to find it is really a good movie. I suppose the problem is that it came out after Waterworld, and that movie was so bad nobody want to risk money on another Costner post-apocalypse movie. However this is a much better movie than Waterworld. It is more like Dances with Wolves set in a post - apocalyptic era. The performances are all strong. Costner's character evolves through the movie. This one is worth a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Post Apocalyptic Blast!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emina Zeleski
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Postman" is a great movie, regardless of what you "critics" think of it. I think it tries to be as accurate in it's portrayal of the future as any movie I've ever seen. I know that some of you just can't stand the fact that there's no futuristic army battles, no 600 horsepower car chases, and "Iron armored costumes" I honestly think that's how the world would go if all government and basic infrastructure were brought down. Think about it. What would you do? Drive a 600 horsepower, supercharged dune buggy that gets 3 mpg or ride a horse. Gasoline supplies would deplete after about a month. Hoarding gas will not work. (it goes bad after about a year of storage) Most people raised in big cities would starve within a couple of months due to lack of survival education or tyranny by people with guns. Secondly, In the film, Costner ends up being the hero in the way that real hero's do. Hero's aren't the people who are tough and beautiful. They're people who are forced into a situation and do the best they can. He starts the new government purely by accident. The only real mistake I see in this movie is that in the beginning, Costner is portrayed as being weak and unable to defend himself. In reality he would be in extremely good shape strong as an ox and very wily. (he's been dragging a mule around for years. Try that sometime. It'll make you strong as an ox or kill you) I give it 9 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than its rating!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pnorris
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm always a little surprised when I see an IMDb rating that's unusually low compared to my take..then again, I often forget that the average poster on this site is now a 20-something who thinks Pulp Fiction is the best movie ever made..sorry; it's not.that distinction still goes to Godfather I & II although not a personal favorite of mine.along with PF, too violent for my taste.. This film has much to offer for fans of the apocalyptic genre (Road Warrior, Red Dawn, etc.): an intriguing storyline; very good pacing even at its near epic length; good acting; good dialogue; excellent cinematography and a lively score & soundtrack, especially the Pinewood Band tunes. The main cast is appealing with Kevin Costner, Will Patton (in an over-the-top role similar to his "Falling Skies" Capt. Weaver), Olivia Williams, Larenz Tate and Tom Petty in more than a just a cameo..add in some recognizable character actors like Ron McLarty, Rex Linn, Daniel Barger, Joe Santos, George Wyner, Giovani Ribisi and Brain Anthony Wilson..a pretty good crew.. Watching this always makes me feel patriotic like when I watch "Red Dawn".and despite the almost universal bashing Costner receives, he is often very endearing in his roles (For the Love of the Game, Tin Cup, Wyatt Earp, JFK, Field of Dreams, Bull Durham, No Way Out and Dances with Wolves).if you've ever seen the creepy Mr. Brooks, you know he can actually act.and he does deliver some very funny lines; my favorite: "So much for the uniform theory".. 8 stars.watch it for yourself and choose
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Postman  After destroying itself how can society get back up on its feet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman is a post-apocalypse survival movie geared toward society and what it means to be a society. The good. The settings are well chosen and built. Great main characters with nicely developing personas. Interesting story. Good pace. The intro is solid and really puts us in the right mood. The actors. Kevin Costner is a great fit for his role as a loner surviving on his wits. Olivia Williams is disarmingly charming as the sweet girl with a budding iron determination. Will Patton makes us hate his egocentric character right away. You can't help but get attached to Larenz Tate as the over eager young man looking for meaning to his life. Daniel von Bargen as the suspicious sheriff is just right. And finally, Giovanni Ribisi in the small role of an almost psychotic blind follower is astounding. The bad. Just a few things. Galloping horses before the siege. Really? You needed to do that to build the tension before the attack? The cable ride. A horse would have been just as good. The ugly. The 30 years later ending. F*ck that! It ruined the movie. Cut it out and it's an additional star, easy. The result. The length of the movie is not for everybody, but it's good entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Post Apocalypse Movie I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Raskin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that 15 out of the last 20 reviewers over the last two years have given this movie 6 stars or above. As the wicked hatchet job the professional critics did on the movie when it first came out in 1997 gets forgotten, I believe more and more people will discover just how brilliant and classic this film is and 3/4ths of people who see it will enjoy it. In the year 2013, after an apocalypse, only small bands of isolated, frightened humans are still alive in the western United States. Apparently all electricity and electrical communication is gone. People are suspicious of each other and live in fortress-like towns. Loner Costner discovers an old mail truck with a dead mailman inside. He takes the clothes of the mailman and carries his mailbag filled with mail. Desperately needing food, he approaches the guards at the gate of a nearby town and tells them that he is a postman appointed by the new President of the United States, Richard Starkey, from Minnesota to deliver mail. The people of the town believe his story and are excited that civilization is starting again. One of the town's young men demands that Costner tell him how he can become a postman like him. Costner appoints him the postman for the town. The town's sheriff discovers Costner's deception and kicks him out of town. The following year, Costner returns again. He is astonished to find a fully functioning post office with dozens of new postmen and women delivering mail to different towns in the region. Costner gets welcomed back as a hero and nearly a God. Everyone now believes Costner's fable about the United States starting up again and the new president living in Minnesota. Costner's great lies about a new country starting are ironically actually causing a new country to be started. Why did the movie get such bad reviews? It believe it was because of the movie's ideology. I think the extreme negative reaction was only because the movie presented the idea that total lies can be believed and start new movements. It is an offensive thought for many true believers. The hero, Kevin Costner, makes up a fabulous lie. It leads to a new cult centered around him. The movie at one point makes the connection to Christian ideology transparent. Costner asks his companion Abbey why everybody believes the nonsense he made up. She answers, "You made Mrs. March feel like she could see again. You made Ford believe he was part of something. You give out hope like it was candy in your pocket." If you like Westerns or Science Fiction or just thoughtful movies, you'll probably enjoy this movie. I am sorry that I listened to the critics and did not see it for 15 years after it came out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorta like vampires, huh?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lost in Film UK
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story/Plot  We have arrived in the year 2013. The United States of America are no longer united. A war has since passed and the civilization of the world has near enough destroyed itself. A lone wanderer (Costner) drifts along with his beloved donkey until he is captured by a savage militia led by the notorious General Bethlehem (Patton). The drifter manages to escape and by chance falls upon a Jeep. Inside this Jeep he finds a skeleton donning a postman's outfit. Desperate for dry clothes he takes the uniform and mailbag. He goes from town to town delivering the mail in an elaborate con to gain food and shelter. Soon though the postal service is revived and the legend of the postman ensues. Bethlehem is determined to put a stop to the revolution caused by the postman. In reply the postman rallies support and takes on the general in a bid for leadership of the militia. A fight that could turn civilization back to the ways of old. My verdict  A brilliant epic tale of one man's quest to put the right back into the world that has long since gone. A must watch for everyone. I now rate this film in my top 5 all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Self Indulgent trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not until this was released on blu ray did i manage to catch The Postman.What have i been missing all these years - absolutely nothing apart from the best part of three hours i wont get back. Its interesting watching this in light of more recent post apocalyptic flops but The Postman takes the biscuit. The script is totally overloaded with schmaltz - a pure glucose overdose. The cast seem to be taking the whole thing so seriously when they are participating in a joke. The only good thing about the movie is Will Pattons performance as the bad guy but his eyesight is failing as he cannot recognise Costner without his facial hair. It also is annoying that Ribisi (playing a loon again) and Russo (playing a bad ass again) are offed in the first half hour as they were entertaining. But hey great looking blu ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is WAY under rated!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mojave_jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a much better post apocalyptic film than almost any others out there. WAY UNDER RATED. It holds your attention all the way through and is almost a post apocalypse version of Dances With Wolves. As such, it should be rated between 7 and 8. Don't know what those low voters were thinking. The Postman never explains what the cause of the breakdown of society is, it leaves it up to the view to decide if it was a nuclear war, a pandemic, or some other catastrophe. The cause is not important. It chronicles the adventure of an actor/conman who starts a con to get food and supplies and comes to believe in his cause. He starts out as a minor villain and ends up being the hero.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A much better film than people give it credit for.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Piggy6756
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I also think this film is far better than its reviews suggest. The photography, for one thing, is beautiful, showcasing as it does the North West American wilderness. More than this, and the reason why I cut the film a great deal of slack, is its moral core. Costner's character, at a difficult point in his life in this dystopian future, discovers a wrecked mail van, puts on the dead driver's jacket, and decides to deliver the mail to the nearest community as a way to scrounge a meal and a bed for the night. Quite against his expectations he strikes a chord with the community he visits, and they give him mail to deliver to their loved ones whom they have not spoken to in years. So he starts a mail service for his own benefit, but as he brings people messages from people they thought were dead he also brings them hope that life will get better and in the process he becomes a better man. There is a violent conclusion to the movie, but it is not the violence that revives the community but someone bringing people closer together via the mail. For that reason in particular I look kindly on this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wholly Underrated - Would've Been A Huge Hit In 2002
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman suffered from its release date. Had it come out the first couple years post-9/11, it would've been seen as an uplifting epic and been a huge hit. Instead, it came out in the middle of a period of relative discontent with the US, where there was no threat of anything to be lost, where therewas no threat of stability lost, where there was no greatness to see, as people were absorbed in their own lives and oblivious to the wonders of having such a great country. (Yes, the movie is very focused on the US.) As a national epic, it just came out at the wrong time. There are plenty of bad elements to the film, and the reason why it's a good film and not a great film. The theme is sometimes missing and then returning in a heavy handed way that makes for inconsistency that could've been done better, but it's still a good film. There are cheesy lines, there are characters or their actions that sometimes seem to be a bit forced, but there are others who are completely within the realm of possibility, and some that are very, very believable. Larenz Tate as Ford Lincoln Mercury is one of the most uplifting, motivating, idealistic characters on film in a long time - his spirit by itself is inspiring. There are several scenes in which he really shines, as his character takes responsibility for his actions. Will Patton does a truly outstanding job as General Bethlehem. The character is portrayed every bit as you'd expect a character with his backstory to be - done well, and a character whose occasional seeming overacting would be consistent with how the character - a megalomaniac - would really act. Some small touches towards the beginning really set down who the character is. Kevin Costner is just pretty good. His low-key attitude sometimes comes off as disinterested and not terribly into the role. Costner does have the physical presence to carry off the role, but on occasion he seems just out of it. Sometimes the movie sometimes seems to dwell on Costner too much, even though he is the main character, the changes in the world that he sets in motion are fascinating. He's not bad, he's just good, not great. The other options for leads that were considered would've been far worse. Costner does pull it off well, but he could've put more effort into his own role. Once in a while his own stated motivations (notably at the end) don't seem to have been developed, and it's possible there was something left on the cutting room floor. This goes to the theme as mentioned above and below as well - there may be some scenes that just didn't make the cut that would've expounded on how the theme developed better. Olivia Williams is excellent through most of the movie, though her role becomes a bit conventional at the end, limiting what she can do. (Incidentally, she's great in "Below", which I highly recommend as a WWII sub movie - but it's best watched without any reviews, and even without looking at the box - it's best viewed totally fresh, with zero foreknowledge. Seriously, don't go look it up, just cue it on Netflix or order it online and don't read about it. It's really, really, really good.) Tom Petty's role is fantastic. His first few lines, "I was..." are rather haunting, when you sit down to think about it; they convey a lot of the atmosphere of the film, and go far towards reminding you the world of the Postman is very different. Daniel von Bargen is excellent, and provides a very good foil for Costner to play off towards the beginning of the film. Almost every scene he's in he manages to convey a seriousness and depth that helps ground the film. Ron McLarty is fantastic. His character is great, and the way he plays into it is great. He's another of the supporting cast that provides atmosphere to the film, conveying the setting even more; he also sets up some great lines that foreshadow a lot of action in a way that is just subtle enough that it's not cheesy at all, but clear enough that the audience can see something big and satisfying is on the way. The scenery is majestic, the setting is made to be truly epic - often it is, the score is fantastic (though sometimes a bit heavy-handed, but that's okay), editing is good, lighting is used well, and there's some subtle symbolism tossed in every so often to go along with the overt themes. Some of the costuming stands out positively (especially the improvised uniformity of the Holnists and the carriers), while the costuming for pretty much everybody else is slightly overdone - you can tell there was work put into it, but sometimes almost too much. Overall, the theme is one that may be lost on many folks, and was especially lost at the time. It's a wonderful, patriotic flick that was released at the wrong time. Just remember it's good, not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly under-rated, way better than Waterworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctardis
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know if this movie ever came out in the theaters. If it did, then it must have been for only a brief period. I saw this movie on cable, and I was shocked to find a Kevin Costner movie that I have never heard of. I also was shocked to find it is really a good movie. I suppose the problem is that it came out after Waterworld, and that movie was so bad nobody want to risk money on another Costner post-apocalypse movie. However this is a much better movie than Waterworld. It is more like Dances with Wolves set in a post - apocalyptic era. The performances are all strong. Costner's character evolves through the movie. This one is worth a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Post Apocalyptic Blast!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emina Zeleski
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Postman" is a great movie, regardless of what you "critics" think of it. I think it tries to be as accurate in it's portrayal of the future as any movie I've ever seen. I know that some of you just can't stand the fact that there's no futuristic army battles, no 600 horsepower car chases, and "Iron armored costumes" I honestly think that's how the world would go if all government and basic infrastructure were brought down. Think about it. What would you do? Drive a 600 horsepower, supercharged dune buggy that gets 3 mpg or ride a horse. Gasoline supplies would deplete after about a month. Hoarding gas will not work. (it goes bad after about a year of storage) Most people raised in big cities would starve within a couple of months due to lack of survival education or tyranny by people with guns. Secondly, In the film, Costner ends up being the hero in the way that real hero's do. Hero's aren't the people who are tough and beautiful. They're people who are forced into a situation and do the best they can. He starts the new government purely by accident. The only real mistake I see in this movie is that in the beginning, Costner is portrayed as being weak and unable to defend himself. In reality he would be in extremely good shape strong as an ox and very wily. (he's been dragging a mule around for years. Try that sometime. It'll make you strong as an ox or kill you) I give it 9 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than its rating!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pnorris
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm always a little surprised when I see an IMDb rating that's unusually low compared to my take..then again, I often forget that the average poster on this site is now a 20-something who thinks Pulp Fiction is the best movie ever made..sorry; it's not.that distinction still goes to Godfather I & II although not a personal favorite of mine.along with PF, too violent for my taste.. This film has much to offer for fans of the apocalyptic genre (Road Warrior, Red Dawn, etc.): an intriguing storyline; very good pacing even at its near epic length; good acting; good dialogue; excellent cinematography and a lively score & soundtrack, especially the Pinewood Band tunes. The main cast is appealing with Kevin Costner, Will Patton (in an over-the-top role similar to his "Falling Skies" Capt. Weaver), Olivia Williams, Larenz Tate and Tom Petty in more than a just a cameo..add in some recognizable character actors like Ron McLarty, Rex Linn, Daniel Barger, Joe Santos, George Wyner, Giovani Ribisi and Brain Anthony Wilson..a pretty good crew.. Watching this always makes me feel patriotic like when I watch "Red Dawn".and despite the almost universal bashing Costner receives, he is often very endearing in his roles (For the Love of the Game, Tin Cup, Wyatt Earp, JFK, Field of Dreams, Bull Durham, No Way Out and Dances with Wolves).if you've ever seen the creepy Mr. Brooks, you know he can actually act.and he does deliver some very funny lines; my favorite: "So much for the uniform theory".. 8 stars.watch it for yourself and choose
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Postman  After destroying itself how can society get back up on its feet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman is a post-apocalypse survival movie geared toward society and what it means to be a society. The good. The settings are well chosen and built. Great main characters with nicely developing personas. Interesting story. Good pace. The intro is solid and really puts us in the right mood. The actors. Kevin Costner is a great fit for his role as a loner surviving on his wits. Olivia Williams is disarmingly charming as the sweet girl with a budding iron determination. Will Patton makes us hate his egocentric character right away. You can't help but get attached to Larenz Tate as the over eager young man looking for meaning to his life. Daniel von Bargen as the suspicious sheriff is just right. And finally, Giovanni Ribisi in the small role of an almost psychotic blind follower is astounding. The bad. Just a few things. Galloping horses before the siege. Really? You needed to do that to build the tension before the attack? The cable ride. A horse would have been just as good. The ugly. The 30 years later ending. F*ck that! It ruined the movie. Cut it out and it's an additional star, easy. The result. The length of the movie is not for everybody, but it's good entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Post Apocalypse Movie I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Raskin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that 15 out of the last 20 reviewers over the last two years have given this movie 6 stars or above. As the wicked hatchet job the professional critics did on the movie when it first came out in 1997 gets forgotten, I believe more and more people will discover just how brilliant and classic this film is and 3/4ths of people who see it will enjoy it. In the year 2013, after an apocalypse, only small bands of isolated, frightened humans are still alive in the western United States. Apparently all electricity and electrical communication is gone. People are suspicious of each other and live in fortress-like towns. Loner Costner discovers an old mail truck with a dead mailman inside. He takes the clothes of the mailman and carries his mailbag filled with mail. Desperately needing food, he approaches the guards at the gate of a nearby town and tells them that he is a postman appointed by the new President of the United States, Richard Starkey, from Minnesota to deliver mail. The people of the town believe his story and are excited that civilization is starting again. One of the town's young men demands that Costner tell him how he can become a postman like him. Costner appoints him the postman for the town. The town's sheriff discovers Costner's deception and kicks him out of town. The following year, Costner returns again. He is astonished to find a fully functioning post office with dozens of new postmen and women delivering mail to different towns in the region. Costner gets welcomed back as a hero and nearly a God. Everyone now believes Costner's fable about the United States starting up again and the new president living in Minnesota. Costner's great lies about a new country starting are ironically actually causing a new country to be started. Why did the movie get such bad reviews? It believe it was because of the movie's ideology. I think the extreme negative reaction was only because the movie presented the idea that total lies can be believed and start new movements. It is an offensive thought for many true believers. The hero, Kevin Costner, makes up a fabulous lie. It leads to a new cult centered around him. The movie at one point makes the connection to Christian ideology transparent. Costner asks his companion Abbey why everybody believes the nonsense he made up. She answers, "You made Mrs. March feel like she could see again. You made Ford believe he was part of something. You give out hope like it was candy in your pocket." If you like Westerns or Science Fiction or just thoughtful movies, you'll probably enjoy this movie. I am sorry that I listened to the critics and did not see it for 15 years after it came out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorta like vampires, huh?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lost in Film UK
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story/Plot  We have arrived in the year 2013. The United States of America are no longer united. A war has since passed and the civilization of the world has near enough destroyed itself. A lone wanderer (Costner) drifts along with his beloved donkey until he is captured by a savage militia led by the notorious General Bethlehem (Patton). The drifter manages to escape and by chance falls upon a Jeep. Inside this Jeep he finds a skeleton donning a postman's outfit. Desperate for dry clothes he takes the uniform and mailbag. He goes from town to town delivering the mail in an elaborate con to gain food and shelter. Soon though the postal service is revived and the legend of the postman ensues. Bethlehem is determined to put a stop to the revolution caused by the postman. In reply the postman rallies support and takes on the general in a bid for leadership of the militia. A fight that could turn civilization back to the ways of old. My verdict  A brilliant epic tale of one man's quest to put the right back into the world that has long since gone. A must watch for everyone. I now rate this film in my top 5 all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Self Indulgent trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not until this was released on blu ray did i manage to catch The Postman.What have i been missing all these years - absolutely nothing apart from the best part of three hours i wont get back. Its interesting watching this in light of more recent post apocalyptic flops but The Postman takes the biscuit. The script is totally overloaded with schmaltz - a pure glucose overdose. The cast seem to be taking the whole thing so seriously when they are participating in a joke. The only good thing about the movie is Will Pattons performance as the bad guy but his eyesight is failing as he cannot recognise Costner without his facial hair. It also is annoying that Ribisi (playing a loon again) and Russo (playing a bad ass again) are offed in the first half hour as they were entertaining. But hey great looking blu ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is WAY under rated!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mojave_jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a much better post apocalyptic film than almost any others out there. WAY UNDER RATED. It holds your attention all the way through and is almost a post apocalypse version of Dances With Wolves. As such, it should be rated between 7 and 8. Don't know what those low voters were thinking. The Postman never explains what the cause of the breakdown of society is, it leaves it up to the view to decide if it was a nuclear war, a pandemic, or some other catastrophe. The cause is not important. It chronicles the adventure of an actor/conman who starts a con to get food and supplies and comes to believe in his cause. He starts out as a minor villain and ends up being the hero.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A much better film than people give it credit for.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Piggy6756
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I also think this film is far better than its reviews suggest. The photography, for one thing, is beautiful, showcasing as it does the North West American wilderness. More than this, and the reason why I cut the film a great deal of slack, is its moral core. Costner's character, at a difficult point in his life in this dystopian future, discovers a wrecked mail van, puts on the dead driver's jacket, and decides to deliver the mail to the nearest community as a way to scrounge a meal and a bed for the night. Quite against his expectations he strikes a chord with the community he visits, and they give him mail to deliver to their loved ones whom they have not spoken to in years. So he starts a mail service for his own benefit, but as he brings people messages from people they thought were dead he also brings them hope that life will get better and in the process he becomes a better man. There is a violent conclusion to the movie, but it is not the violence that revives the community but someone bringing people closer together via the mail. For that reason in particular I look kindly on this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wholly Underrated - Would've Been A Huge Hit In 2002
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman suffered from its release date. Had it come out the first couple years post-9/11, it would've been seen as an uplifting epic and been a huge hit. Instead, it came out in the middle of a period of relative discontent with the US, where there was no threat of anything to be lost, where therewas no threat of stability lost, where there was no greatness to see, as people were absorbed in their own lives and oblivious to the wonders of having such a great country. (Yes, the movie is very focused on the US.) As a national epic, it just came out at the wrong time. There are plenty of bad elements to the film, and the reason why it's a good film and not a great film. The theme is sometimes missing and then returning in a heavy handed way that makes for inconsistency that could've been done better, but it's still a good film. There are cheesy lines, there are characters or their actions that sometimes seem to be a bit forced, but there are others who are completely within the realm of possibility, and some that are very, very believable. Larenz Tate as Ford Lincoln Mercury is one of the most uplifting, motivating, idealistic characters on film in a long time - his spirit by itself is inspiring. There are several scenes in which he really shines, as his character takes responsibility for his actions. Will Patton does a truly outstanding job as General Bethlehem. The character is portrayed every bit as you'd expect a character with his backstory to be - done well, and a character whose occasional seeming overacting would be consistent with how the character - a megalomaniac - would really act. Some small touches towards the beginning really set down who the character is. Kevin Costner is just pretty good. His low-key attitude sometimes comes off as disinterested and not terribly into the role. Costner does have the physical presence to carry off the role, but on occasion he seems just out of it. Sometimes the movie sometimes seems to dwell on Costner too much, even though he is the main character, the changes in the world that he sets in motion are fascinating. He's not bad, he's just good, not great. The other options for leads that were considered would've been far worse. Costner does pull it off well, but he could've put more effort into his own role. Once in a while his own stated motivations (notably at the end) don't seem to have been developed, and it's possible there was something left on the cutting room floor. This goes to the theme as mentioned above and below as well - there may be some scenes that just didn't make the cut that would've expounded on how the theme developed better. Olivia Williams is excellent through most of the movie, though her role becomes a bit conventional at the end, limiting what she can do. (Incidentally, she's great in "Below", which I highly recommend as a WWII sub movie - but it's best watched without any reviews, and even without looking at the box - it's best viewed totally fresh, with zero foreknowledge. Seriously, don't go look it up, just cue it on Netflix or order it online and don't read about it. It's really, really, really good.) Tom Petty's role is fantastic. His first few lines, "I was..." are rather haunting, when you sit down to think about it; they convey a lot of the atmosphere of the film, and go far towards reminding you the world of the Postman is very different. Daniel von Bargen is excellent, and provides a very good foil for Costner to play off towards the beginning of the film. Almost every scene he's in he manages to convey a seriousness and depth that helps ground the film. Ron McLarty is fantastic. His character is great, and the way he plays into it is great. He's another of the supporting cast that provides atmosphere to the film, conveying the setting even more; he also sets up some great lines that foreshadow a lot of action in a way that is just subtle enough that it's not cheesy at all, but clear enough that the audience can see something big and satisfying is on the way. The scenery is majestic, the setting is made to be truly epic - often it is, the score is fantastic (though sometimes a bit heavy-handed, but that's okay), editing is good, lighting is used well, and there's some subtle symbolism tossed in every so often to go along with the overt themes. Some of the costuming stands out positively (especially the improvised uniformity of the Holnists and the carriers), while the costuming for pretty much everybody else is slightly overdone - you can tell there was work put into it, but sometimes almost too much. Overall, the theme is one that may be lost on many folks, and was especially lost at the time. It's a wonderful, patriotic flick that was released at the wrong time. Just remember it's good, not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly under-rated, way better than Waterworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctardis
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know if this movie ever came out in the theaters. If it did, then it must have been for only a brief period. I saw this movie on cable, and I was shocked to find a Kevin Costner movie that I have never heard of. I also was shocked to find it is really a good movie. I suppose the problem is that it came out after Waterworld, and that movie was so bad nobody want to risk money on another Costner post-apocalypse movie. However this is a much better movie than Waterworld. It is more like Dances with Wolves set in a post - apocalyptic era. The performances are all strong. Costner's character evolves through the movie. This one is worth a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Post Apocalyptic Blast!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emina Zeleski
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Postman" is a great movie, regardless of what you "critics" think of it. I think it tries to be as accurate in it's portrayal of the future as any movie I've ever seen. I know that some of you just can't stand the fact that there's no futuristic army battles, no 600 horsepower car chases, and "Iron armored costumes" I honestly think that's how the world would go if all government and basic infrastructure were brought down. Think about it. What would you do? Drive a 600 horsepower, supercharged dune buggy that gets 3 mpg or ride a horse. Gasoline supplies would deplete after about a month. Hoarding gas will not work. (it goes bad after about a year of storage) Most people raised in big cities would starve within a couple of months due to lack of survival education or tyranny by people with guns. Secondly, In the film, Costner ends up being the hero in the way that real hero's do. Hero's aren't the people who are tough and beautiful. They're people who are forced into a situation and do the best they can. He starts the new government purely by accident. The only real mistake I see in this movie is that in the beginning, Costner is portrayed as being weak and unable to defend himself. In reality he would be in extremely good shape strong as an ox and very wily. (he's been dragging a mule around for years. Try that sometime. It'll make you strong as an ox or kill you) I give it 9 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than its rating!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pnorris
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm always a little surprised when I see an IMDb rating that's unusually low compared to my take..then again, I often forget that the average poster on this site is now a 20-something who thinks Pulp Fiction is the best movie ever made..sorry; it's not.that distinction still goes to Godfather I & II although not a personal favorite of mine.along with PF, too violent for my taste.. This film has much to offer for fans of the apocalyptic genre (Road Warrior, Red Dawn, etc.): an intriguing storyline; very good pacing even at its near epic length; good acting; good dialogue; excellent cinematography and a lively score & soundtrack, especially the Pinewood Band tunes. The main cast is appealing with Kevin Costner, Will Patton (in an over-the-top role similar to his "Falling Skies" Capt. Weaver), Olivia Williams, Larenz Tate and Tom Petty in more than a just a cameo..add in some recognizable character actors like Ron McLarty, Rex Linn, Daniel Barger, Joe Santos, George Wyner, Giovani Ribisi and Brain Anthony Wilson..a pretty good crew.. Watching this always makes me feel patriotic like when I watch "Red Dawn".and despite the almost universal bashing Costner receives, he is often very endearing in his roles (For the Love of the Game, Tin Cup, Wyatt Earp, JFK, Field of Dreams, Bull Durham, No Way Out and Dances with Wolves).if you've ever seen the creepy Mr. Brooks, you know he can actually act.and he does deliver some very funny lines; my favorite: "So much for the uniform theory".. 8 stars.watch it for yourself and choose
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Postman  After destroying itself how can society get back up on its feet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman is a post-apocalypse survival movie geared toward society and what it means to be a society. The good. The settings are well chosen and built. Great main characters with nicely developing personas. Interesting story. Good pace. The intro is solid and really puts us in the right mood. The actors. Kevin Costner is a great fit for his role as a loner surviving on his wits. Olivia Williams is disarmingly charming as the sweet girl with a budding iron determination. Will Patton makes us hate his egocentric character right away. You can't help but get attached to Larenz Tate as the over eager young man looking for meaning to his life. Daniel von Bargen as the suspicious sheriff is just right. And finally, Giovanni Ribisi in the small role of an almost psychotic blind follower is astounding. The bad. Just a few things. Galloping horses before the siege. Really? You needed to do that to build the tension before the attack? The cable ride. A horse would have been just as good. The ugly. The 30 years later ending. F*ck that! It ruined the movie. Cut it out and it's an additional star, easy. The result. The length of the movie is not for everybody, but it's good entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Post Apocalypse Movie I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Raskin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that 15 out of the last 20 reviewers over the last two years have given this movie 6 stars or above. As the wicked hatchet job the professional critics did on the movie when it first came out in 1997 gets forgotten, I believe more and more people will discover just how brilliant and classic this film is and 3/4ths of people who see it will enjoy it. In the year 2013, after an apocalypse, only small bands of isolated, frightened humans are still alive in the western United States. Apparently all electricity and electrical communication is gone. People are suspicious of each other and live in fortress-like towns. Loner Costner discovers an old mail truck with a dead mailman inside. He takes the clothes of the mailman and carries his mailbag filled with mail. Desperately needing food, he approaches the guards at the gate of a nearby town and tells them that he is a postman appointed by the new President of the United States, Richard Starkey, from Minnesota to deliver mail. The people of the town believe his story and are excited that civilization is starting again. One of the town's young men demands that Costner tell him how he can become a postman like him. Costner appoints him the postman for the town. The town's sheriff discovers Costner's deception and kicks him out of town. The following year, Costner returns again. He is astonished to find a fully functioning post office with dozens of new postmen and women delivering mail to different towns in the region. Costner gets welcomed back as a hero and nearly a God. Everyone now believes Costner's fable about the United States starting up again and the new president living in Minnesota. Costner's great lies about a new country starting are ironically actually causing a new country to be started. Why did the movie get such bad reviews? It believe it was because of the movie's ideology. I think the extreme negative reaction was only because the movie presented the idea that total lies can be believed and start new movements. It is an offensive thought for many true believers. The hero, Kevin Costner, makes up a fabulous lie. It leads to a new cult centered around him. The movie at one point makes the connection to Christian ideology transparent. Costner asks his companion Abbey why everybody believes the nonsense he made up. She answers, "You made Mrs. March feel like she could see again. You made Ford believe he was part of something. You give out hope like it was candy in your pocket." If you like Westerns or Science Fiction or just thoughtful movies, you'll probably enjoy this movie. I am sorry that I listened to the critics and did not see it for 15 years after it came out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorta like vampires, huh?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lost in Film UK
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story/Plot  We have arrived in the year 2013. The United States of America are no longer united. A war has since passed and the civilization of the world has near enough destroyed itself. A lone wanderer (Costner) drifts along with his beloved donkey until he is captured by a savage militia led by the notorious General Bethlehem (Patton). The drifter manages to escape and by chance falls upon a Jeep. Inside this Jeep he finds a skeleton donning a postman's outfit. Desperate for dry clothes he takes the uniform and mailbag. He goes from town to town delivering the mail in an elaborate con to gain food and shelter. Soon though the postal service is revived and the legend of the postman ensues. Bethlehem is determined to put a stop to the revolution caused by the postman. In reply the postman rallies support and takes on the general in a bid for leadership of the militia. A fight that could turn civilization back to the ways of old. My verdict  A brilliant epic tale of one man's quest to put the right back into the world that has long since gone. A must watch for everyone. I now rate this film in my top 5 all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Self Indulgent trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not until this was released on blu ray did i manage to catch The Postman.What have i been missing all these years - absolutely nothing apart from the best part of three hours i wont get back. Its interesting watching this in light of more recent post apocalyptic flops but The Postman takes the biscuit. The script is totally overloaded with schmaltz - a pure glucose overdose. The cast seem to be taking the whole thing so seriously when they are participating in a joke. The only good thing about the movie is Will Pattons performance as the bad guy but his eyesight is failing as he cannot recognise Costner without his facial hair. It also is annoying that Ribisi (playing a loon again) and Russo (playing a bad ass again) are offed in the first half hour as they were entertaining. But hey great looking blu ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is WAY under rated!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mojave_jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a much better post apocalyptic film than almost any others out there. WAY UNDER RATED. It holds your attention all the way through and is almost a post apocalypse version of Dances With Wolves. As such, it should be rated between 7 and 8. Don't know what those low voters were thinking. The Postman never explains what the cause of the breakdown of society is, it leaves it up to the view to decide if it was a nuclear war, a pandemic, or some other catastrophe. The cause is not important. It chronicles the adventure of an actor/conman who starts a con to get food and supplies and comes to believe in his cause. He starts out as a minor villain and ends up being the hero.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A much better film than people give it credit for.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Piggy6756
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I also think this film is far better than its reviews suggest. The photography, for one thing, is beautiful, showcasing as it does the North West American wilderness. More than this, and the reason why I cut the film a great deal of slack, is its moral core. Costner's character, at a difficult point in his life in this dystopian future, discovers a wrecked mail van, puts on the dead driver's jacket, and decides to deliver the mail to the nearest community as a way to scrounge a meal and a bed for the night. Quite against his expectations he strikes a chord with the community he visits, and they give him mail to deliver to their loved ones whom they have not spoken to in years. So he starts a mail service for his own benefit, but as he brings people messages from people they thought were dead he also brings them hope that life will get better and in the process he becomes a better man. There is a violent conclusion to the movie, but it is not the violence that revives the community but someone bringing people closer together via the mail. For that reason in particular I look kindly on this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wholly Underrated - Would've Been A Huge Hit In 2002
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman suffered from its release date. Had it come out the first couple years post-9/11, it would've been seen as an uplifting epic and been a huge hit. Instead, it came out in the middle of a period of relative discontent with the US, where there was no threat of anything to be lost, where therewas no threat of stability lost, where there was no greatness to see, as people were absorbed in their own lives and oblivious to the wonders of having such a great country. (Yes, the movie is very focused on the US.) As a national epic, it just came out at the wrong time. There are plenty of bad elements to the film, and the reason why it's a good film and not a great film. The theme is sometimes missing and then returning in a heavy handed way that makes for inconsistency that could've been done better, but it's still a good film. There are cheesy lines, there are characters or their actions that sometimes seem to be a bit forced, but there are others who are completely within the realm of possibility, and some that are very, very believable. Larenz Tate as Ford Lincoln Mercury is one of the most uplifting, motivating, idealistic characters on film in a long time - his spirit by itself is inspiring. There are several scenes in which he really shines, as his character takes responsibility for his actions. Will Patton does a truly outstanding job as General Bethlehem. The character is portrayed every bit as you'd expect a character with his backstory to be - done well, and a character whose occasional seeming overacting would be consistent with how the character - a megalomaniac - would really act. Some small touches towards the beginning really set down who the character is. Kevin Costner is just pretty good. His low-key attitude sometimes comes off as disinterested and not terribly into the role. Costner does have the physical presence to carry off the role, but on occasion he seems just out of it. Sometimes the movie sometimes seems to dwell on Costner too much, even though he is the main character, the changes in the world that he sets in motion are fascinating. He's not bad, he's just good, not great. The other options for leads that were considered would've been far worse. Costner does pull it off well, but he could've put more effort into his own role. Once in a while his own stated motivations (notably at the end) don't seem to have been developed, and it's possible there was something left on the cutting room floor. This goes to the theme as mentioned above and below as well - there may be some scenes that just didn't make the cut that would've expounded on how the theme developed better. Olivia Williams is excellent through most of the movie, though her role becomes a bit conventional at the end, limiting what she can do. (Incidentally, she's great in "Below", which I highly recommend as a WWII sub movie - but it's best watched without any reviews, and even without looking at the box - it's best viewed totally fresh, with zero foreknowledge. Seriously, don't go look it up, just cue it on Netflix or order it online and don't read about it. It's really, really, really good.) Tom Petty's role is fantastic. His first few lines, "I was..." are rather haunting, when you sit down to think about it; they convey a lot of the atmosphere of the film, and go far towards reminding you the world of the Postman is very different. Daniel von Bargen is excellent, and provides a very good foil for Costner to play off towards the beginning of the film. Almost every scene he's in he manages to convey a seriousness and depth that helps ground the film. Ron McLarty is fantastic. His character is great, and the way he plays into it is great. He's another of the supporting cast that provides atmosphere to the film, conveying the setting even more; he also sets up some great lines that foreshadow a lot of action in a way that is just subtle enough that it's not cheesy at all, but clear enough that the audience can see something big and satisfying is on the way. The scenery is majestic, the setting is made to be truly epic - often it is, the score is fantastic (though sometimes a bit heavy-handed, but that's okay), editing is good, lighting is used well, and there's some subtle symbolism tossed in every so often to go along with the overt themes. Some of the costuming stands out positively (especially the improvised uniformity of the Holnists and the carriers), while the costuming for pretty much everybody else is slightly overdone - you can tell there was work put into it, but sometimes almost too much. Overall, the theme is one that may be lost on many folks, and was especially lost at the time. It's a wonderful, patriotic flick that was released at the wrong time. Just remember it's good, not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly under-rated, way better than Waterworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctardis
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know if this movie ever came out in the theaters. If it did, then it must have been for only a brief period. I saw this movie on cable, and I was shocked to find a Kevin Costner movie that I have never heard of. I also was shocked to find it is really a good movie. I suppose the problem is that it came out after Waterworld, and that movie was so bad nobody want to risk money on another Costner post-apocalypse movie. However this is a much better movie than Waterworld. It is more like Dances with Wolves set in a post - apocalyptic era. The performances are all strong. Costner's character evolves through the movie. This one is worth a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Post Apocalyptic Blast!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emina Zeleski
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Postman" is a great movie, regardless of what you "critics" think of it. I think it tries to be as accurate in it's portrayal of the future as any movie I've ever seen. I know that some of you just can't stand the fact that there's no futuristic army battles, no 600 horsepower car chases, and "Iron armored costumes" I honestly think that's how the world would go if all government and basic infrastructure were brought down. Think about it. What would you do? Drive a 600 horsepower, supercharged dune buggy that gets 3 mpg or ride a horse. Gasoline supplies would deplete after about a month. Hoarding gas will not work. (it goes bad after about a year of storage) Most people raised in big cities would starve within a couple of months due to lack of survival education or tyranny by people with guns. Secondly, In the film, Costner ends up being the hero in the way that real hero's do. Hero's aren't the people who are tough and beautiful. They're people who are forced into a situation and do the best they can. He starts the new government purely by accident. The only real mistake I see in this movie is that in the beginning, Costner is portrayed as being weak and unable to defend himself. In reality he would be in extremely good shape strong as an ox and very wily. (he's been dragging a mule around for years. Try that sometime. It'll make you strong as an ox or kill you) I give it 9 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than its rating!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pnorris
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm always a little surprised when I see an IMDb rating that's unusually low compared to my take..then again, I often forget that the average poster on this site is now a 20-something who thinks Pulp Fiction is the best movie ever made..sorry; it's not.that distinction still goes to Godfather I & II although not a personal favorite of mine.along with PF, too violent for my taste.. This film has much to offer for fans of the apocalyptic genre (Road Warrior, Red Dawn, etc.): an intriguing storyline; very good pacing even at its near epic length; good acting; good dialogue; excellent cinematography and a lively score & soundtrack, especially the Pinewood Band tunes. The main cast is appealing with Kevin Costner, Will Patton (in an over-the-top role similar to his "Falling Skies" Capt. Weaver), Olivia Williams, Larenz Tate and Tom Petty in more than a just a cameo..add in some recognizable character actors like Ron McLarty, Rex Linn, Daniel Barger, Joe Santos, George Wyner, Giovani Ribisi and Brain Anthony Wilson..a pretty good crew.. Watching this always makes me feel patriotic like when I watch "Red Dawn".and despite the almost universal bashing Costner receives, he is often very endearing in his roles (For the Love of the Game, Tin Cup, Wyatt Earp, JFK, Field of Dreams, Bull Durham, No Way Out and Dances with Wolves).if you've ever seen the creepy Mr. Brooks, you know he can actually act.and he does deliver some very funny lines; my favorite: "So much for the uniform theory".. 8 stars.watch it for yourself and choose
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Postman  After destroying itself how can society get back up on its feet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman is a post-apocalypse survival movie geared toward society and what it means to be a society. The good. The settings are well chosen and built. Great main characters with nicely developing personas. Interesting story. Good pace. The intro is solid and really puts us in the right mood. The actors. Kevin Costner is a great fit for his role as a loner surviving on his wits. Olivia Williams is disarmingly charming as the sweet girl with a budding iron determination. Will Patton makes us hate his egocentric character right away. You can't help but get attached to Larenz Tate as the over eager young man looking for meaning to his life. Daniel von Bargen as the suspicious sheriff is just right. And finally, Giovanni Ribisi in the small role of an almost psychotic blind follower is astounding. The bad. Just a few things. Galloping horses before the siege. Really? You needed to do that to build the tension before the attack? The cable ride. A horse would have been just as good. The ugly. The 30 years later ending. F*ck that! It ruined the movie. Cut it out and it's an additional star, easy. The result. The length of the movie is not for everybody, but it's good entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Post Apocalypse Movie I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Raskin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that 15 out of the last 20 reviewers over the last two years have given this movie 6 stars or above. As the wicked hatchet job the professional critics did on the movie when it first came out in 1997 gets forgotten, I believe more and more people will discover just how brilliant and classic this film is and 3/4ths of people who see it will enjoy it. In the year 2013, after an apocalypse, only small bands of isolated, frightened humans are still alive in the western United States. Apparently all electricity and electrical communication is gone. People are suspicious of each other and live in fortress-like towns. Loner Costner discovers an old mail truck with a dead mailman inside. He takes the clothes of the mailman and carries his mailbag filled with mail. Desperately needing food, he approaches the guards at the gate of a nearby town and tells them that he is a postman appointed by the new President of the United States, Richard Starkey, from Minnesota to deliver mail. The people of the town believe his story and are excited that civilization is starting again. One of the town's young men demands that Costner tell him how he can become a postman like him. Costner appoints him the postman for the town. The town's sheriff discovers Costner's deception and kicks him out of town. The following year, Costner returns again. He is astonished to find a fully functioning post office with dozens of new postmen and women delivering mail to different towns in the region. Costner gets welcomed back as a hero and nearly a God. Everyone now believes Costner's fable about the United States starting up again and the new president living in Minnesota. Costner's great lies about a new country starting are ironically actually causing a new country to be started. Why did the movie get such bad reviews? It believe it was because of the movie's ideology. I think the extreme negative reaction was only because the movie presented the idea that total lies can be believed and start new movements. It is an offensive thought for many true believers. The hero, Kevin Costner, makes up a fabulous lie. It leads to a new cult centered around him. The movie at one point makes the connection to Christian ideology transparent. Costner asks his companion Abbey why everybody believes the nonsense he made up. She answers, "You made Mrs. March feel like she could see again. You made Ford believe he was part of something. You give out hope like it was candy in your pocket." If you like Westerns or Science Fiction or just thoughtful movies, you'll probably enjoy this movie. I am sorry that I listened to the critics and did not see it for 15 years after it came out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorta like vampires, huh?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lost in Film UK
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story/Plot  We have arrived in the year 2013. The United States of America are no longer united. A war has since passed and the civilization of the world has near enough destroyed itself. A lone wanderer (Costner) drifts along with his beloved donkey until he is captured by a savage militia led by the notorious General Bethlehem (Patton). The drifter manages to escape and by chance falls upon a Jeep. Inside this Jeep he finds a skeleton donning a postman's outfit. Desperate for dry clothes he takes the uniform and mailbag. He goes from town to town delivering the mail in an elaborate con to gain food and shelter. Soon though the postal service is revived and the legend of the postman ensues. Bethlehem is determined to put a stop to the revolution caused by the postman. In reply the postman rallies support and takes on the general in a bid for leadership of the militia. A fight that could turn civilization back to the ways of old. My verdict  A brilliant epic tale of one man's quest to put the right back into the world that has long since gone. A must watch for everyone. I now rate this film in my top 5 all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Self Indulgent trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not until this was released on blu ray did i manage to catch The Postman.What have i been missing all these years - absolutely nothing apart from the best part of three hours i wont get back. Its interesting watching this in light of more recent post apocalyptic flops but The Postman takes the biscuit. The script is totally overloaded with schmaltz - a pure glucose overdose. The cast seem to be taking the whole thing so seriously when they are participating in a joke. The only good thing about the movie is Will Pattons performance as the bad guy but his eyesight is failing as he cannot recognise Costner without his facial hair. It also is annoying that Ribisi (playing a loon again) and Russo (playing a bad ass again) are offed in the first half hour as they were entertaining. But hey great looking blu ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is WAY under rated!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mojave_jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a much better post apocalyptic film than almost any others out there. WAY UNDER RATED. It holds your attention all the way through and is almost a post apocalypse version of Dances With Wolves. As such, it should be rated between 7 and 8. Don't know what those low voters were thinking. The Postman never explains what the cause of the breakdown of society is, it leaves it up to the view to decide if it was a nuclear war, a pandemic, or some other catastrophe. The cause is not important. It chronicles the adventure of an actor/conman who starts a con to get food and supplies and comes to believe in his cause. He starts out as a minor villain and ends up being the hero.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A much better film than people give it credit for.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Piggy6756
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I also think this film is far better than its reviews suggest. The photography, for one thing, is beautiful, showcasing as it does the North West American wilderness. More than this, and the reason why I cut the film a great deal of slack, is its moral core. Costner's character, at a difficult point in his life in this dystopian future, discovers a wrecked mail van, puts on the dead driver's jacket, and decides to deliver the mail to the nearest community as a way to scrounge a meal and a bed for the night. Quite against his expectations he strikes a chord with the community he visits, and they give him mail to deliver to their loved ones whom they have not spoken to in years. So he starts a mail service for his own benefit, but as he brings people messages from people they thought were dead he also brings them hope that life will get better and in the process he becomes a better man. There is a violent conclusion to the movie, but it is not the violence that revives the community but someone bringing people closer together via the mail. For that reason in particular I look kindly on this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wholly Underrated - Would've Been A Huge Hit In 2002
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman suffered from its release date. Had it come out the first couple years post-9/11, it would've been seen as an uplifting epic and been a huge hit. Instead, it came out in the middle of a period of relative discontent with the US, where there was no threat of anything to be lost, where therewas no threat of stability lost, where there was no greatness to see, as people were absorbed in their own lives and oblivious to the wonders of having such a great country. (Yes, the movie is very focused on the US.) As a national epic, it just came out at the wrong time. There are plenty of bad elements to the film, and the reason why it's a good film and not a great film. The theme is sometimes missing and then returning in a heavy handed way that makes for inconsistency that could've been done better, but it's still a good film. There are cheesy lines, there are characters or their actions that sometimes seem to be a bit forced, but there are others who are completely within the realm of possibility, and some that are very, very believable. Larenz Tate as Ford Lincoln Mercury is one of the most uplifting, motivating, idealistic characters on film in a long time - his spirit by itself is inspiring. There are several scenes in which he really shines, as his character takes responsibility for his actions. Will Patton does a truly outstanding job as General Bethlehem. The character is portrayed every bit as you'd expect a character with his backstory to be - done well, and a character whose occasional seeming overacting would be consistent with how the character - a megalomaniac - would really act. Some small touches towards the beginning really set down who the character is. Kevin Costner is just pretty good. His low-key attitude sometimes comes off as disinterested and not terribly into the role. Costner does have the physical presence to carry off the role, but on occasion he seems just out of it. Sometimes the movie sometimes seems to dwell on Costner too much, even though he is the main character, the changes in the world that he sets in motion are fascinating. He's not bad, he's just good, not great. The other options for leads that were considered would've been far worse. Costner does pull it off well, but he could've put more effort into his own role. Once in a while his own stated motivations (notably at the end) don't seem to have been developed, and it's possible there was something left on the cutting room floor. This goes to the theme as mentioned above and below as well - there may be some scenes that just didn't make the cut that would've expounded on how the theme developed better. Olivia Williams is excellent through most of the movie, though her role becomes a bit conventional at the end, limiting what she can do. (Incidentally, she's great in "Below", which I highly recommend as a WWII sub movie - but it's best watched without any reviews, and even without looking at the box - it's best viewed totally fresh, with zero foreknowledge. Seriously, don't go look it up, just cue it on Netflix or order it online and don't read about it. It's really, really, really good.) Tom Petty's role is fantastic. His first few lines, "I was..." are rather haunting, when you sit down to think about it; they convey a lot of the atmosphere of the film, and go far towards reminding you the world of the Postman is very different. Daniel von Bargen is excellent, and provides a very good foil for Costner to play off towards the beginning of the film. Almost every scene he's in he manages to convey a seriousness and depth that helps ground the film. Ron McLarty is fantastic. His character is great, and the way he plays into it is great. He's another of the supporting cast that provides atmosphere to the film, conveying the setting even more; he also sets up some great lines that foreshadow a lot of action in a way that is just subtle enough that it's not cheesy at all, but clear enough that the audience can see something big and satisfying is on the way. The scenery is majestic, the setting is made to be truly epic - often it is, the score is fantastic (though sometimes a bit heavy-handed, but that's okay), editing is good, lighting is used well, and there's some subtle symbolism tossed in every so often to go along with the overt themes. Some of the costuming stands out positively (especially the improvised uniformity of the Holnists and the carriers), while the costuming for pretty much everybody else is slightly overdone - you can tell there was work put into it, but sometimes almost too much. Overall, the theme is one that may be lost on many folks, and was especially lost at the time. It's a wonderful, patriotic flick that was released at the wrong time. Just remember it's good, not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly under-rated, way better than Waterworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctardis
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know if this movie ever came out in the theaters. If it did, then it must have been for only a brief period. I saw this movie on cable, and I was shocked to find a Kevin Costner movie that I have never heard of. I also was shocked to find it is really a good movie. I suppose the problem is that it came out after Waterworld, and that movie was so bad nobody want to risk money on another Costner post-apocalypse movie. However this is a much better movie than Waterworld. It is more like Dances with Wolves set in a post - apocalyptic era. The performances are all strong. Costner's character evolves through the movie. This one is worth a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Post Apocalyptic Blast!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emina Zeleski
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Postman" is a great movie, regardless of what you "critics" think of it. I think it tries to be as accurate in it's portrayal of the future as any movie I've ever seen. I know that some of you just can't stand the fact that there's no futuristic army battles, no 600 horsepower car chases, and "Iron armored costumes" I honestly think that's how the world would go if all government and basic infrastructure were brought down. Think about it. What would you do? Drive a 600 horsepower, supercharged dune buggy that gets 3 mpg or ride a horse. Gasoline supplies would deplete after about a month. Hoarding gas will not work. (it goes bad after about a year of storage) Most people raised in big cities would starve within a couple of months due to lack of survival education or tyranny by people with guns. Secondly, In the film, Costner ends up being the hero in the way that real hero's do. Hero's aren't the people who are tough and beautiful. They're people who are forced into a situation and do the best they can. He starts the new government purely by accident. The only real mistake I see in this movie is that in the beginning, Costner is portrayed as being weak and unable to defend himself. In reality he would be in extremely good shape strong as an ox and very wily. (he's been dragging a mule around for years. Try that sometime. It'll make you strong as an ox or kill you) I give it 9 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than its rating!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pnorris
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm always a little surprised when I see an IMDb rating that's unusually low compared to my take..then again, I often forget that the average poster on this site is now a 20-something who thinks Pulp Fiction is the best movie ever made..sorry; it's not.that distinction still goes to Godfather I & II although not a personal favorite of mine.along with PF, too violent for my taste.. This film has much to offer for fans of the apocalyptic genre (Road Warrior, Red Dawn, etc.): an intriguing storyline; very good pacing even at its near epic length; good acting; good dialogue; excellent cinematography and a lively score & soundtrack, especially the Pinewood Band tunes. The main cast is appealing with Kevin Costner, Will Patton (in an over-the-top role similar to his "Falling Skies" Capt. Weaver), Olivia Williams, Larenz Tate and Tom Petty in more than a just a cameo..add in some recognizable character actors like Ron McLarty, Rex Linn, Daniel Barger, Joe Santos, George Wyner, Giovani Ribisi and Brain Anthony Wilson..a pretty good crew.. Watching this always makes me feel patriotic like when I watch "Red Dawn".and despite the almost universal bashing Costner receives, he is often very endearing in his roles (For the Love of the Game, Tin Cup, Wyatt Earp, JFK, Field of Dreams, Bull Durham, No Way Out and Dances with Wolves).if you've ever seen the creepy Mr. Brooks, you know he can actually act.and he does deliver some very funny lines; my favorite: "So much for the uniform theory".. 8 stars.watch it for yourself and choose
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Postman  After destroying itself how can society get back up on its feet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman is a post-apocalypse survival movie geared toward society and what it means to be a society. The good. The settings are well chosen and built. Great main characters with nicely developing personas. Interesting story. Good pace. The intro is solid and really puts us in the right mood. The actors. Kevin Costner is a great fit for his role as a loner surviving on his wits. Olivia Williams is disarmingly charming as the sweet girl with a budding iron determination. Will Patton makes us hate his egocentric character right away. You can't help but get attached to Larenz Tate as the over eager young man looking for meaning to his life. Daniel von Bargen as the suspicious sheriff is just right. And finally, Giovanni Ribisi in the small role of an almost psychotic blind follower is astounding. The bad. Just a few things. Galloping horses before the siege. Really? You needed to do that to build the tension before the attack? The cable ride. A horse would have been just as good. The ugly. The 30 years later ending. F*ck that! It ruined the movie. Cut it out and it's an additional star, easy. The result. The length of the movie is not for everybody, but it's good entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Post Apocalypse Movie I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Raskin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that 15 out of the last 20 reviewers over the last two years have given this movie 6 stars or above. As the wicked hatchet job the professional critics did on the movie when it first came out in 1997 gets forgotten, I believe more and more people will discover just how brilliant and classic this film is and 3/4ths of people who see it will enjoy it. In the year 2013, after an apocalypse, only small bands of isolated, frightened humans are still alive in the western United States. Apparently all electricity and electrical communication is gone. People are suspicious of each other and live in fortress-like towns. Loner Costner discovers an old mail truck with a dead mailman inside. He takes the clothes of the mailman and carries his mailbag filled with mail. Desperately needing food, he approaches the guards at the gate of a nearby town and tells them that he is a postman appointed by the new President of the United States, Richard Starkey, from Minnesota to deliver mail. The people of the town believe his story and are excited that civilization is starting again. One of the town's young men demands that Costner tell him how he can become a postman like him. Costner appoints him the postman for the town. The town's sheriff discovers Costner's deception and kicks him out of town. The following year, Costner returns again. He is astonished to find a fully functioning post office with dozens of new postmen and women delivering mail to different towns in the region. Costner gets welcomed back as a hero and nearly a God. Everyone now believes Costner's fable about the United States starting up again and the new president living in Minnesota. Costner's great lies about a new country starting are ironically actually causing a new country to be started. Why did the movie get such bad reviews? It believe it was because of the movie's ideology. I think the extreme negative reaction was only because the movie presented the idea that total lies can be believed and start new movements. It is an offensive thought for many true believers. The hero, Kevin Costner, makes up a fabulous lie. It leads to a new cult centered around him. The movie at one point makes the connection to Christian ideology transparent. Costner asks his companion Abbey why everybody believes the nonsense he made up. She answers, "You made Mrs. March feel like she could see again. You made Ford believe he was part of something. You give out hope like it was candy in your pocket." If you like Westerns or Science Fiction or just thoughtful movies, you'll probably enjoy this movie. I am sorry that I listened to the critics and did not see it for 15 years after it came out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorta like vampires, huh?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lost in Film UK
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story/Plot  We have arrived in the year 2013. The United States of America are no longer united. A war has since passed and the civilization of the world has near enough destroyed itself. A lone wanderer (Costner) drifts along with his beloved donkey until he is captured by a savage militia led by the notorious General Bethlehem (Patton). The drifter manages to escape and by chance falls upon a Jeep. Inside this Jeep he finds a skeleton donning a postman's outfit. Desperate for dry clothes he takes the uniform and mailbag. He goes from town to town delivering the mail in an elaborate con to gain food and shelter. Soon though the postal service is revived and the legend of the postman ensues. Bethlehem is determined to put a stop to the revolution caused by the postman. In reply the postman rallies support and takes on the general in a bid for leadership of the militia. A fight that could turn civilization back to the ways of old. My verdict  A brilliant epic tale of one man's quest to put the right back into the world that has long since gone. A must watch for everyone. I now rate this film in my top 5 all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Self Indulgent trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not until this was released on blu ray did i manage to catch The Postman.What have i been missing all these years - absolutely nothing apart from the best part of three hours i wont get back. Its interesting watching this in light of more recent post apocalyptic flops but The Postman takes the biscuit. The script is totally overloaded with schmaltz - a pure glucose overdose. The cast seem to be taking the whole thing so seriously when they are participating in a joke. The only good thing about the movie is Will Pattons performance as the bad guy but his eyesight is failing as he cannot recognise Costner without his facial hair. It also is annoying that Ribisi (playing a loon again) and Russo (playing a bad ass again) are offed in the first half hour as they were entertaining. But hey great looking blu ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is WAY under rated!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mojave_jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a much better post apocalyptic film than almost any others out there. WAY UNDER RATED. It holds your attention all the way through and is almost a post apocalypse version of Dances With Wolves. As such, it should be rated between 7 and 8. Don't know what those low voters were thinking. The Postman never explains what the cause of the breakdown of society is, it leaves it up to the view to decide if it was a nuclear war, a pandemic, or some other catastrophe. The cause is not important. It chronicles the adventure of an actor/conman who starts a con to get food and supplies and comes to believe in his cause. He starts out as a minor villain and ends up being the hero.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A much better film than people give it credit for.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Piggy6756
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I also think this film is far better than its reviews suggest. The photography, for one thing, is beautiful, showcasing as it does the North West American wilderness. More than this, and the reason why I cut the film a great deal of slack, is its moral core. Costner's character, at a difficult point in his life in this dystopian future, discovers a wrecked mail van, puts on the dead driver's jacket, and decides to deliver the mail to the nearest community as a way to scrounge a meal and a bed for the night. Quite against his expectations he strikes a chord with the community he visits, and they give him mail to deliver to their loved ones whom they have not spoken to in years. So he starts a mail service for his own benefit, but as he brings people messages from people they thought were dead he also brings them hope that life will get better and in the process he becomes a better man. There is a violent conclusion to the movie, but it is not the violence that revives the community but someone bringing people closer together via the mail. For that reason in particular I look kindly on this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wholly Underrated - Would've Been A Huge Hit In 2002
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman suffered from its release date. Had it come out the first couple years post-9/11, it would've been seen as an uplifting epic and been a huge hit. Instead, it came out in the middle of a period of relative discontent with the US, where there was no threat of anything to be lost, where therewas no threat of stability lost, where there was no greatness to see, as people were absorbed in their own lives and oblivious to the wonders of having such a great country. (Yes, the movie is very focused on the US.) As a national epic, it just came out at the wrong time. There are plenty of bad elements to the film, and the reason why it's a good film and not a great film. The theme is sometimes missing and then returning in a heavy handed way that makes for inconsistency that could've been done better, but it's still a good film. There are cheesy lines, there are characters or their actions that sometimes seem to be a bit forced, but there are others who are completely within the realm of possibility, and some that are very, very believable. Larenz Tate as Ford Lincoln Mercury is one of the most uplifting, motivating, idealistic characters on film in a long time - his spirit by itself is inspiring. There are several scenes in which he really shines, as his character takes responsibility for his actions. Will Patton does a truly outstanding job as General Bethlehem. The character is portrayed every bit as you'd expect a character with his backstory to be - done well, and a character whose occasional seeming overacting would be consistent with how the character - a megalomaniac - would really act. Some small touches towards the beginning really set down who the character is. Kevin Costner is just pretty good. His low-key attitude sometimes comes off as disinterested and not terribly into the role. Costner does have the physical presence to carry off the role, but on occasion he seems just out of it. Sometimes the movie sometimes seems to dwell on Costner too much, even though he is the main character, the changes in the world that he sets in motion are fascinating. He's not bad, he's just good, not great. The other options for leads that were considered would've been far worse. Costner does pull it off well, but he could've put more effort into his own role. Once in a while his own stated motivations (notably at the end) don't seem to have been developed, and it's possible there was something left on the cutting room floor. This goes to the theme as mentioned above and below as well - there may be some scenes that just didn't make the cut that would've expounded on how the theme developed better. Olivia Williams is excellent through most of the movie, though her role becomes a bit conventional at the end, limiting what she can do. (Incidentally, she's great in "Below", which I highly recommend as a WWII sub movie - but it's best watched without any reviews, and even without looking at the box - it's best viewed totally fresh, with zero foreknowledge. Seriously, don't go look it up, just cue it on Netflix or order it online and don't read about it. It's really, really, really good.) Tom Petty's role is fantastic. His first few lines, "I was..." are rather haunting, when you sit down to think about it; they convey a lot of the atmosphere of the film, and go far towards reminding you the world of the Postman is very different. Daniel von Bargen is excellent, and provides a very good foil for Costner to play off towards the beginning of the film. Almost every scene he's in he manages to convey a seriousness and depth that helps ground the film. Ron McLarty is fantastic. His character is great, and the way he plays into it is great. He's another of the supporting cast that provides atmosphere to the film, conveying the setting even more; he also sets up some great lines that foreshadow a lot of action in a way that is just subtle enough that it's not cheesy at all, but clear enough that the audience can see something big and satisfying is on the way. The scenery is majestic, the setting is made to be truly epic - often it is, the score is fantastic (though sometimes a bit heavy-handed, but that's okay), editing is good, lighting is used well, and there's some subtle symbolism tossed in every so often to go along with the overt themes. Some of the costuming stands out positively (especially the improvised uniformity of the Holnists and the carriers), while the costuming for pretty much everybody else is slightly overdone - you can tell there was work put into it, but sometimes almost too much. Overall, the theme is one that may be lost on many folks, and was especially lost at the time. It's a wonderful, patriotic flick that was released at the wrong time. Just remember it's good, not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly under-rated, way better than Waterworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctardis
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know if this movie ever came out in the theaters. If it did, then it must have been for only a brief period. I saw this movie on cable, and I was shocked to find a Kevin Costner movie that I have never heard of. I also was shocked to find it is really a good movie. I suppose the problem is that it came out after Waterworld, and that movie was so bad nobody want to risk money on another Costner post-apocalypse movie. However this is a much better movie than Waterworld. It is more like Dances with Wolves set in a post - apocalyptic era. The performances are all strong. Costner's character evolves through the movie. This one is worth a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Post Apocalyptic Blast!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emina Zeleski
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Postman" is a great movie, regardless of what you "critics" think of it. I think it tries to be as accurate in it's portrayal of the future as any movie I've ever seen. I know that some of you just can't stand the fact that there's no futuristic army battles, no 600 horsepower car chases, and "Iron armored costumes" I honestly think that's how the world would go if all government and basic infrastructure were brought down. Think about it. What would you do? Drive a 600 horsepower, supercharged dune buggy that gets 3 mpg or ride a horse. Gasoline supplies would deplete after about a month. Hoarding gas will not work. (it goes bad after about a year of storage) Most people raised in big cities would starve within a couple of months due to lack of survival education or tyranny by people with guns. Secondly, In the film, Costner ends up being the hero in the way that real hero's do. Hero's aren't the people who are tough and beautiful. They're people who are forced into a situation and do the best they can. He starts the new government purely by accident. The only real mistake I see in this movie is that in the beginning, Costner is portrayed as being weak and unable to defend himself. In reality he would be in extremely good shape strong as an ox and very wily. (he's been dragging a mule around for years. Try that sometime. It'll make you strong as an ox or kill you) I give it 9 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than its rating!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pnorris
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm always a little surprised when I see an IMDb rating that's unusually low compared to my take..then again, I often forget that the average poster on this site is now a 20-something who thinks Pulp Fiction is the best movie ever made..sorry; it's not.that distinction still goes to Godfather I & II although not a personal favorite of mine.along with PF, too violent for my taste.. This film has much to offer for fans of the apocalyptic genre (Road Warrior, Red Dawn, etc.): an intriguing storyline; very good pacing even at its near epic length; good acting; good dialogue; excellent cinematography and a lively score & soundtrack, especially the Pinewood Band tunes. The main cast is appealing with Kevin Costner, Will Patton (in an over-the-top role similar to his "Falling Skies" Capt. Weaver), Olivia Williams, Larenz Tate and Tom Petty in more than a just a cameo..add in some recognizable character actors like Ron McLarty, Rex Linn, Daniel Barger, Joe Santos, George Wyner, Giovani Ribisi and Brain Anthony Wilson..a pretty good crew.. Watching this always makes me feel patriotic like when I watch "Red Dawn".and despite the almost universal bashing Costner receives, he is often very endearing in his roles (For the Love of the Game, Tin Cup, Wyatt Earp, JFK, Field of Dreams, Bull Durham, No Way Out and Dances with Wolves).if you've ever seen the creepy Mr. Brooks, you know he can actually act.and he does deliver some very funny lines; my favorite: "So much for the uniform theory".. 8 stars.watch it for yourself and choose
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Postman  After destroying itself how can society get back up on its feet
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman is a post-apocalypse survival movie geared toward society and what it means to be a society. The good. The settings are well chosen and built. Great main characters with nicely developing personas. Interesting story. Good pace. The intro is solid and really puts us in the right mood. The actors. Kevin Costner is a great fit for his role as a loner surviving on his wits. Olivia Williams is disarmingly charming as the sweet girl with a budding iron determination. Will Patton makes us hate his egocentric character right away. You can't help but get attached to Larenz Tate as the over eager young man looking for meaning to his life. Daniel von Bargen as the suspicious sheriff is just right. And finally, Giovanni Ribisi in the small role of an almost psychotic blind follower is astounding. The bad. Just a few things. Galloping horses before the siege. Really? You needed to do that to build the tension before the attack? The cable ride. A horse would have been just as good. The ugly. The 30 years later ending. F*ck that! It ruined the movie. Cut it out and it's an additional star, easy. The result. The length of the movie is not for everybody, but it's good entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Post Apocalypse Movie I Have Ever Seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jay Raskin
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am glad that 15 out of the last 20 reviewers over the last two years have given this movie 6 stars or above. As the wicked hatchet job the professional critics did on the movie when it first came out in 1997 gets forgotten, I believe more and more people will discover just how brilliant and classic this film is and 3/4ths of people who see it will enjoy it. In the year 2013, after an apocalypse, only small bands of isolated, frightened humans are still alive in the western United States. Apparently all electricity and electrical communication is gone. People are suspicious of each other and live in fortress-like towns. Loner Costner discovers an old mail truck with a dead mailman inside. He takes the clothes of the mailman and carries his mailbag filled with mail. Desperately needing food, he approaches the guards at the gate of a nearby town and tells them that he is a postman appointed by the new President of the United States, Richard Starkey, from Minnesota to deliver mail. The people of the town believe his story and are excited that civilization is starting again. One of the town's young men demands that Costner tell him how he can become a postman like him. Costner appoints him the postman for the town. The town's sheriff discovers Costner's deception and kicks him out of town. The following year, Costner returns again. He is astonished to find a fully functioning post office with dozens of new postmen and women delivering mail to different towns in the region. Costner gets welcomed back as a hero and nearly a God. Everyone now believes Costner's fable about the United States starting up again and the new president living in Minnesota. Costner's great lies about a new country starting are ironically actually causing a new country to be started. Why did the movie get such bad reviews? It believe it was because of the movie's ideology. I think the extreme negative reaction was only because the movie presented the idea that total lies can be believed and start new movements. It is an offensive thought for many true believers. The hero, Kevin Costner, makes up a fabulous lie. It leads to a new cult centered around him. The movie at one point makes the connection to Christian ideology transparent. Costner asks his companion Abbey why everybody believes the nonsense he made up. She answers, "You made Mrs. March feel like she could see again. You made Ford believe he was part of something. You give out hope like it was candy in your pocket." If you like Westerns or Science Fiction or just thoughtful movies, you'll probably enjoy this movie. I am sorry that I listened to the critics and did not see it for 15 years after it came out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sorta like vampires, huh?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lost in Film UK
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Story/Plot  We have arrived in the year 2013. The United States of America are no longer united. A war has since passed and the civilization of the world has near enough destroyed itself. A lone wanderer (Costner) drifts along with his beloved donkey until he is captured by a savage militia led by the notorious General Bethlehem (Patton). The drifter manages to escape and by chance falls upon a Jeep. Inside this Jeep he finds a skeleton donning a postman's outfit. Desperate for dry clothes he takes the uniform and mailbag. He goes from town to town delivering the mail in an elaborate con to gain food and shelter. Soon though the postal service is revived and the legend of the postman ensues. Bethlehem is determined to put a stop to the revolution caused by the postman. In reply the postman rallies support and takes on the general in a bid for leadership of the militia. A fight that could turn civilization back to the ways of old. My verdict  A brilliant epic tale of one man's quest to put the right back into the world that has long since gone. A must watch for everyone. I now rate this film in my top 5 all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Self Indulgent trash
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cmoyton
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not until this was released on blu ray did i manage to catch The Postman.What have i been missing all these years - absolutely nothing apart from the best part of three hours i wont get back. Its interesting watching this in light of more recent post apocalyptic flops but The Postman takes the biscuit. The script is totally overloaded with schmaltz - a pure glucose overdose. The cast seem to be taking the whole thing so seriously when they are participating in a joke. The only good thing about the movie is Will Pattons performance as the bad guy but his eyesight is failing as he cannot recognise Costner without his facial hair. It also is annoying that Ribisi (playing a loon again) and Russo (playing a bad ass again) are offed in the first half hour as they were entertaining. But hey great looking blu ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is WAY under rated!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mojave_jack
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a much better post apocalyptic film than almost any others out there. WAY UNDER RATED. It holds your attention all the way through and is almost a post apocalypse version of Dances With Wolves. As such, it should be rated between 7 and 8. Don't know what those low voters were thinking. The Postman never explains what the cause of the breakdown of society is, it leaves it up to the view to decide if it was a nuclear war, a pandemic, or some other catastrophe. The cause is not important. It chronicles the adventure of an actor/conman who starts a con to get food and supplies and comes to believe in his cause. He starts out as a minor villain and ends up being the hero.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A much better film than people give it credit for.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Piggy6756
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I also think this film is far better than its reviews suggest. The photography, for one thing, is beautiful, showcasing as it does the North West American wilderness. More than this, and the reason why I cut the film a great deal of slack, is its moral core. Costner's character, at a difficult point in his life in this dystopian future, discovers a wrecked mail van, puts on the dead driver's jacket, and decides to deliver the mail to the nearest community as a way to scrounge a meal and a bed for the night. Quite against his expectations he strikes a chord with the community he visits, and they give him mail to deliver to their loved ones whom they have not spoken to in years. So he starts a mail service for his own benefit, but as he brings people messages from people they thought were dead he also brings them hope that life will get better and in the process he becomes a better man. There is a violent conclusion to the movie, but it is not the violence that revives the community but someone bringing people closer together via the mail. For that reason in particular I look kindly on this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wholly Underrated - Would've Been A Huge Hit In 2002
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Postman suffered from its release date. Had it come out the first couple years post-9/11, it would've been seen as an uplifting epic and been a huge hit. Instead, it came out in the middle of a period of relative discontent with the US, where there was no threat of anything to be lost, where therewas no threat of stability lost, where there was no greatness to see, as people were absorbed in their own lives and oblivious to the wonders of having such a great country. (Yes, the movie is very focused on the US.) As a national epic, it just came out at the wrong time. There are plenty of bad elements to the film, and the reason why it's a good film and not a great film. The theme is sometimes missing and then returning in a heavy handed way that makes for inconsistency that could've been done better, but it's still a good film. There are cheesy lines, there are characters or their actions that sometimes seem to be a bit forced, but there are others who are completely within the realm of possibility, and some that are very, very believable. Larenz Tate as Ford Lincoln Mercury is one of the most uplifting, motivating, idealistic characters on film in a long time - his spirit by itself is inspiring. There are several scenes in which he really shines, as his character takes responsibility for his actions. Will Patton does a truly outstanding job as General Bethlehem. The character is portrayed every bit as you'd expect a character with his backstory to be - done well, and a character whose occasional seeming overacting would be consistent with how the character - a megalomaniac - would really act. Some small touches towards the beginning really set down who the character is. Kevin Costner is just pretty good. His low-key attitude sometimes comes off as disinterested and not terribly into the role. Costner does have the physical presence to carry off the role, but on occasion he seems just out of it. Sometimes the movie sometimes seems to dwell on Costner too much, even though he is the main character, the changes in the world that he sets in motion are fascinating. He's not bad, he's just good, not great. The other options for leads that were considered would've been far worse. Costner does pull it off well, but he could've put more effort into his own role. Once in a while his own stated motivations (notably at the end) don't seem to have been developed, and it's possible there was something left on the cutting room floor. This goes to the theme as mentioned above and below as well - there may be some scenes that just didn't make the cut that would've expounded on how the theme developed better. Olivia Williams is excellent through most of the movie, though her role becomes a bit conventional at the end, limiting what she can do. (Incidentally, she's great in "Below", which I highly recommend as a WWII sub movie - but it's best watched without any reviews, and even without looking at the box - it's best viewed totally fresh, with zero foreknowledge. Seriously, don't go look it up, just cue it on Netflix or order it online and don't read about it. It's really, really, really good.) Tom Petty's role is fantastic. His first few lines, "I was..." are rather haunting, when you sit down to think about it; they convey a lot of the atmosphere of the film, and go far towards reminding you the world of the Postman is very different. Daniel von Bargen is excellent, and provides a very good foil for Costner to play off towards the beginning of the film. Almost every scene he's in he manages to convey a seriousness and depth that helps ground the film. Ron McLarty is fantastic. His character is great, and the way he plays into it is great. He's another of the supporting cast that provides atmosphere to the film, conveying the setting even more; he also sets up some great lines that foreshadow a lot of action in a way that is just subtle enough that it's not cheesy at all, but clear enough that the audience can see something big and satisfying is on the way. The scenery is majestic, the setting is made to be truly epic - often it is, the score is fantastic (though sometimes a bit heavy-handed, but that's okay), editing is good, lighting is used well, and there's some subtle symbolism tossed in every so often to go along with the overt themes. Some of the costuming stands out positively (especially the improvised uniformity of the Holnists and the carriers), while the costuming for pretty much everybody else is slightly overdone - you can tell there was work put into it, but sometimes almost too much. Overall, the theme is one that may be lost on many folks, and was especially lost at the time. It's a wonderful, patriotic flick that was released at the wrong time. Just remember it's good, not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly under-rated, way better than Waterworld
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doctardis
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I did not know if this movie ever came out in the theaters. If it did, then it must have been for only a brief period. I saw this movie on cable, and I was shocked to find a Kevin Costner movie that I have never heard of. I also was shocked to find it is really a good movie. I suppose the problem is that it came out after Waterworld, and that movie was so bad nobody want to risk money on another Costner post-apocalypse movie. However this is a much better movie than Waterworld. It is more like Dances with Wolves set in a post - apocalyptic era. The performances are all strong. Costner's character evolves through the movie. This one is worth a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Post Apocalyptic Blast!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Emina Zeleski
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Postman" is a great movie, regardless of what you "critics" think of it. I think it tries to be as accurate in it's portrayal of the future as any movie I've ever seen. I know that some of you just can't stand the fact that there's no futuristic army battles, no 600 horsepower car chases, and "Iron armored costumes" I honestly think that's how the world would go if all government and basic infrastructure were brought down. Think about it. What would you do? Drive a 600 horsepower, supercharged dune buggy that gets 3 mpg or ride a horse. Gasoline supplies would deplete after about a month. Hoarding gas will not work. (it goes bad after about a year of storage) Most people raised in big cities would starve within a couple of months due to lack of survival education or tyranny by people with guns. Secondly, In the film, Costner ends up being the hero in the way that real hero's do. Hero's aren't the people who are tough and beautiful. They're people who are forced into a situation and do the best they can. He starts the new government purely by accident. The only real mistake I see in this movie is that in the beginning, Costner is portrayed as being weak and unable to defend himself. In reality he would be in extremely good shape strong as an ox and very wily. (he's been dragging a mule around for years. Try that sometime. It'll make you strong as an ox or kill you) I give it 9 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Much better than its rating!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pnorris
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm always a little surprised when I see an IMDb rating that's unusually low compared to my take..then again, I often forget that the average poster on this site is now a 20-something who thinks Pulp Fiction is the best movie ever made..sorry; it's not.that distinction still goes to Godfather I & II although not a personal favorite of mine.along with PF, too violent for my taste.. This film has much to offer for fans of the apocalyptic genre (Road Warrior, Red Dawn, etc.): an intriguing storyline; very good pacing even at its near epic length; good acting; good dialogue; excellent cinematography and a lively score & soundtrack, especially the Pinewood Band tunes. The main cast is appealing with Kevin Costner, Will Patton (in an over-the-top role similar to his "Falling Skies" Capt. Weaver), Olivia Williams, Larenz Tate and Tom Petty in more than a just a cameo..add in some recognizable character actors like Ron McLarty, Rex Linn, Daniel Barger, Joe Santos, George Wyner, Giovani Ribisi and Brain Anthony Wilson..a pretty good crew.. Watching this always makes me feel patriotic like when I watch "Red Dawn".and despite the almost universal bashing Costner receives, he is often very endearing in his roles (For the Love of the Game, Tin Cup, Wyatt Earp, JFK, Field of Dreams, Bull Durham, No Way Out and Dances with Wolves).if you've ever seen the creepy Mr. Brooks, you know he can actually act.and he does deliver some very funny lines; my favorite: "So much for the uniform theory".. 8 stars.watch it for yourself and choose
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
