<filme>
 <id>
  902
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118715
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1998
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Grande Lebowski
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  "Dude" Lebowski, mistaken for a millionaire Lebowski, seeks restitution for his ruined rug and enlists his bowling buddies to help get it.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  When "The Dude" Lebowski is mistaken for a millionaire Lebowski, two thugs urinate on his rug to coerce him into paying a debt he knows nothing about. While attempting to gain recompense for the ruined rug from his wealthy counterpart, he accepts a one-time job with high pay-off. He enlists the help of his bowling buddy, Walter, a gun-toting Jewish-convert with anger issues. Deception leads to more trouble, and it soon seems that everyone from porn empire tycoons to nihilists want something from The Dude.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   rug
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bowling
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   millionaire
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jewish convert
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   money
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Joel Coen
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   Ethan Coen
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ethan Coen
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Joel Coen
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jeff Bridges
  </ator>
  <ator>
   John Goodman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Julianne Moore
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Biggie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felipe_lorescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What makes this an outstanding comedy?!? The fact that you laugh louder the 4th time, the 5th time you watch it. It's not only a comedy of punch lines (when you enjoy it the 1st time, then the 2nd time it's not that funny, cause you already know the catch). It's the classical style of the movie's atmosphere that sets the adorable mood. What makes it a classic?!? The 11th time, the 12th time you watch it, you don't get bored. Perhaps you won't laugh out loud like you previously did, but it still gets you in that mood. In addition, this comedy is sprinkled with some serious social matters. Read between the lines, watch between the scenes...!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Big Lebowski, my hero-the slacker, crime mystery solver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyink01
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Lebowski film plot is centered on a Los Angeles dude, who is a real slacker, pot smoking, White Russian drinker, soon to be hero solving a crime mystery. He happens to have the same name as a millionaire; Jeffrey Lebowski played by David Huddleston, whose wife, Bunny Lebowski (Tara Reid) was kidnapped and owes money to a known pornographer. We are introduced to the Dude as he is shopping for milk and he opened the carton and sniffed it. The Dude wrote a check for 69 cents and returns home. It appears that he is unaware that someone is waiting on him and they attack him in the apartment. One of the hit men urinates on his rug. His prized possession that ties the apartment together, says the Dude. The Dude enlists his bowling buddies, whom we meet in regular league play. His main antagonist and best friend played by John Goodman, as Walter Sobchak. We soon learn that Walter is a practicing Jew who observes the Shabbos day of rest. Walter refuses to lift a finger on the day of rest, but manages to convince the Dude that he needs to find the millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski, and get his rug replaced. Walter drives the car on the Shabbos and says he is just doing it to help out. But turns out he is creating more trouble for the Dude. The millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski is in a wheelchair, but convinces the Dude he needs to deliver the ransom money alone so his kidnapped wife will return. The Dude becomes a crime fighting, urban cowboy. They go through the motions of delivering the money and in the meantime, they say "F it, let's go bowling" park the car in a handicapped zone with the ransom money in it, when they walk outside the car is gone. Panic ensues and Walter always says "Shut the F up, Donny" played by Steve Buscemi. Donny never really gets to say much in the film, but Walter always tells him the same thing. We get introduced to the millionaire's sister, Maude Lebowski portrayed by Julianne Moore. Maude was a nude artist who created her works of art while riding in ceiling harness. She believed the ransom money was kept by the Dude, but he proves to her that there was no money, and he was used by her brother as a scapegoat. The millionaire still has the money. The pornographer hires hit men, thugs to find the money. Once they determine there is no money, they punch the Dude in the face so hard, we see & hear fireworks, and then he is flying through the sky like Superman. Then he lands in the bowling alley. The Dude tackles all his problems inside the walls of the bowling alley. The punch perpetuates him there. Walter's character gets so out of hand he pulls a gun on another bowler because he wants to bowl on Shabbos. This is not going to happen, the police are called but they run right by the pair in the parking lot. They are not even the least bit frazzled about the police being there, we see them running into the alley with guns pulled. The music ties the scenes together in the movie. When the action elevates to a point where they can't handle it anymore, the say let's go bowling. Magically through sound they end up there bowling. Always confronted by larger than life egos and it becomes quite funny how much animosity and hate both lash at each other. One of the teams they are to play against, become real aggressive and say "No one messes with Jesus" (John Turturro) that is the bowler's name. We get a flashback which is so comical showing Jesus as a pedophile going door to door announcing to the neighborhood that he lives there. Music takes us from the bowling alley through that flashback. It is a funny movie showing that even slackers can be heroes. Maude found a purpose for the Dude, as she wanted him to be a sperm donor only, she wanted a child. She was beyond weird, but the Dude liked her style. At the conclusion of the film Donnie dies from shock of seeing the Dude's car on fire. He was not up for all the problems and confrontations that Walter and Dude went through. He was much more fragile than they imagined, best part is he didn't die alone. His best friends were there till the end. Many times over this movie had music transition the picture forward, the voices were covered by different rock songs, and special effects transferred everyone to the next scene. Just by mere suggestion. We were walking in the bowling alley at every problem. I loved how they glorified some of the bowling scenes, especially with the dude going underneath about 50 women down the approach looking up at their crotches. Sometimes even the Dude was embarrassed by what he wished would happen. He couldn't look up at the women he floated upside down the approach of the bowling alley, ashamed of his own thoughts or more like daydreams. The Dude became a crusader of crime, not you're likely candidate to solve a mystery. He did it with the help of Donnie and Walter, despite the constant arguing and bickering between the three. The arguing was the craziest thing that kept them going, for most it would drive them apart. I never imagined this would be a crime mystery movie that was so cleverly written that The Dude seems like someone from real life and not a character at all. He feels so real, that's what makes this movie so special. Anyone can be a hero; you just gotta believe in yourself, even if you're a slacker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true nonsensicomedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roselaar
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Outrageously zany, off-beat comedy the likes only the Coen Brothers can provide. Life is tough for the pot smoking all-round slacker Jeffrey Lebowski, more commonly referred to as "The Dude" (Jeff Bridges in one of the most defining roles of his career). Sharing his last name with a millionaire, he's victimized by thugs who mistake him for that rich man (who owes them a debt), a situation which finds his beloved rug in ruin after having been urinated upon by the perpetrators. When he visits his namesake to try and get him to pay for its cleaning, he soon gets more than he bargained for as he finds himself caught up in what appears to be a kidnap of the wealthy man's trophy wife, but swiftly explodes into a bizarre, inexplicable potpourri of events beyond anybody's control or understanding, thanks to the involvement of a host of wacky, maniacal and thoroughly enjoyable characters, ranging from feminist/nihilist artists and pornographers to White Russians and generally random folk annex narrators. Yet all The Dude asked for was a clean rug and an opportunity to win the local bowling alley's competition he trained so hard for with his two best buddies (John Goodman with severe anger management problems and Steve Buscemi who can't take a hint when he's asked to shut up). The Coens don't ask you to make sense of it all, they just want you to roll with it (pun intended), as The Dude does himself. Nevertheless, despite this absence of a clearly defined plot, or more likely because of it, The Big Lebowski proves all kinds of fun. The pair of directors used the same tactic a decade later with Burn After Reading to similar results, proving them the masters of this subgenre of 'nonsensicomedy' (for the record, I just made that term up and I hope it catches on). In both cases they were aided by an impressive cast of character actors and/or movie stars who felt like doing something different for a change, in The Big Lebowski's case including Philip Seymour Hoffman, John Turturro, Julianne Moore and Sam Elliott. Though the film was met with moderately tempered critical reviews and disappointing box office results back in 1998, time has proved the Coens right, as it has since become a widely accepted cult classic with serious tendencies towards an eventual, seemingly unavoidable shedding of the moniker 'cult'. When Burn After Reading came along in 2008, the majority of both audience and critics finally understood this type of film, and that movie did much, much better business accordingly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite a nice combination of comedy and crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has so many reviews that it doesn't need mine, so I won't review it. But since I write a blurb on each movie I see so that I can recollect it, I'll attempt to write 10 lines about this one. First off, it's a very satirical movie. I think it will be just as funny on a second viewing. There's too much swearing in the movie, you know, the f-word. After awhile, that became very tiring, and for me it impeded the comedy. I also thought that this was hard on the actors forced to insert this word so many times. They didn't sound 100% convincing at it after awhile. John Turturro's part is not that big, but he's very good in it. I didn't think Steve Buscemi had that many comic lines. It was really John Goodman's show. I liked his interactions with Jeff Bridges. Mr. Bridges remains a huge talent, as far as I can tell. David Huddleston is a very good actor. He was a tad over the top here. The film somehow made good use of Sam Elliott, who might be an underrated actor. Some of the other supporting actors didn't have that much to do in the way of comedy. In comedy you can say things you wouldn't ordinarily say seriously, and I felt that the Coens were taking the opportunity to poke fun at a lot of their favorite targets, but not in a peevish way. The film is above average. Maybe it's even an 8, but so many reviewers are raving so much about it excessively, as IMDb reviewers are wont to do, that I'm expressing less enthusiasm. See it, if you haven't already. You'll enjoy it, as long as you don't mind hearing a very great deal of the f-word. By the way, in Scarface with Pacino, the profanity seemed just right and worked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films, period - Dude!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barmstrong-782-631970
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Come on! This is the best film ever. i', even raising this above LOTR, since this is contemporary. I grew up living like the Dude. The Dude reminds me of my Uncle...not in a bad way, but with deep respect to living one's own life. The Coen brothers have created a film to be topped, if it was possible. Barton Fink was great..Fargo, yeah it was exceptional story-telling. But, the Dude - that was well-crafted cinema. The only other film that I have seen of theirs that captured me as much was No Country for Old Men. Can't wait for the next surprise!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG - Not Funny, Not Funny, Not Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NickyCee
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the heck did I tell you the Big Lebowski is not funny three times? Because this is once for every 20 people that told me this movie was the funniest most entertaining movie EVER. After years of being berated at parties and get-togethers with people spewing line after line from the movie, I gave in last week. I finally rented it. Wow. It's so bad on so many levels it's hard to describe. It's not funny - at - all. It's mildly amusing in parts but of the six people I watched it with, no one laughed once. Not once. I don't think it's a spoiler to tell you the language is sickeningly bad. Up there with Team America bad. There is one reason and one reason only that this movie is popular: College aged men (or guys who wish they were college aged) own the DVD and watch it repeatedly. Once memorizing the movie, on subsequent viewings they elbow each other before each "big" scene almost spilling their friend's beer and yelling, "HERE IT IS! HERE IT IS!" They then laugh at how clever they think they are. They're part of "The DUDE" club and they are very, very special indeed. This is the most unfunny movie I have ever seen. Other than Scarface and Team America, the movie containing the foulest most unnecessary language I've ever seen, and overall one of top five worst movies I've ever seen (and yes, this includes You Tube cat movies).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1998's The Big Lebowski Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of The Coen Brothers Direction And Screenplay, The Score, The Cinematography By Roger Deakins And Jeff Bridges Performance As Jeff Lebowski, My Mom Kelli Krajci Watched This Movie A Little On DVD That I Own That I Have In My DVD Collection, I Like To Laugh When I Watch Funny Movies On DVD, My Favorite Comedy Film Is 1933's Duck Soup With The Marx Brothers, 1988 Was 10 Years Old In 1998, 1982 Was 16 Years Old In 1998, 1953 Was 45 Years Old In 1998, This Movie Turned 10 Years In 2008, It Is Going To Turn 20 Years Old In 2018, Another Coen Brothers Film 1996's Fargo Is One Of My Favorite Films As Well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themadhouseyt
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funniest movie i've ever seen very good performances strong script very well directed deserved an Oscar. For me Jeff Bridges and John Goodman should have deserved an Oscar or at least a nomination, it's not that kind of comedy which is funny and at the half of the movie the jokes start to get annoying, the whole movie keeps you entertained, at least i didn't want the movie to end. The only thing that bothered me is that they haven't done a part 2, i want to know what is going to happen to "The Dude" and Walter i don't really care about other characters really (That doesn't mean that the other actors weren't good) I really would love if it lasted more. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Without a doubt, this is the funniest film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Coen Brothers are perhaps better known for their work in colder films such as 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men' but with 'The Big Lebowski' they manage to create a clever and highly enjoyable comedy. I've seen the film a number of times now and on each viewing I have been more impressed by what I have seen. The movie combines a talented cast with each actor bringing their own unique character to the screen, humour that is intelligent and subtle in places, brilliant sets such as those used in the bowling alley, costumes and a soundtrack that brilliantly adds to the feel of film. Although 'The Big Lebowski' is nothing like the films of 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men', it contains many of the Coen Brothers usual plot devices and techniques that they used. The plot of the film is relatively straight forward, but is layered over with bizarre twists with nothing going as easy as planned. The film is focused around a millionaire whose wife is kidnapped for a $1,000,000 ransom with Jeffrey Lebowski hiring a 'bum' of the same name to act as a middle man in a deal to get here back. Immediately 'Dude' as he likes to be known suspects that the kidnapping is not as straightforward as outlined and that Lebowski's wife Bunny has kidnapped herself in order to get rich from a man who would not normally allow her such money, sound a bit like 'Fargo'? Unlike Fargo which can be seen as a 'dark comedy', The Big Lebowski is more a feel-good film that's style can probably be better compared to an earlier comedy of the Coen Brothers 'Raising Arizona', a film also which featured John Goodman (who also appeared in the Coen Brothers' film 'Barton Fink'). I feel that John Goodman's performance in this film is one worthy of a best supporting actor Oscar. Goodman portrays Walter; one of the Dude's bowling buddies that becomes involved in the Dude's task to transfer money between Lebowski and the kidnappers. Walter provides a lot of the film's humour and best scenes; he is an aggressive war veteran who makes constant references to his fighting at Vietnam and is constantly arguing with fellow bowling buddy Donny. Donny is portrayed by Steve Buscemi who is one of my favourite actors who seems to play a totally different character in every film he appears in. It seems strange that him and Goodman would go on to star together again in 'Monsters Inc.' but the two have great chemistry in this film, Donny is mocked throughout by Walter and the two provide some great scenes for us such as 'I am the walrus?'. John Turturro (who starred in 'Barton Fink' and later 'O Brother, Where Art Thou?') also features in a less prominent role as Jesus Quintana, a convicted paedophile that is set to face the Dude's bowling team in an upcoming tournament round. Although he doesn't have much time on screen, when he does he provides us with some of the films most enjoyable scenes, in fact this is the case for nearly all the scenes that are set in the bowling alley. Sam Elliott is also used effectively in his role as the mysterious narrator. There are other strong supporting performances such as those from Julianne Moore and Philip Seymour Hoffman but the star is undoubtedly Jeff Bridges as 'the Dude'. Jeff Bridges brings character and style to the leading character who is ultimately a bum that spends his life getting high and bowling with his friends. It's hard to imagine anybody else in such a role, the film acts an ode to the characters laid back, chilled lifestyle which makes the film so enjoyable. As it is with other Coen Brothers' films, the cinematography is superb and the duo have created a fantastic setting for a film. In 'Fargo' we saw the gritty and dark atmosphere reflected in the cold setting of North Dakota, in 'The Big Lebowski' the Coen Brothers' use Los Angeles as their location, at times the film can feel dark but at others we get light, as already said the bowling alley provides an excellent setting for many of the films' scenes. The Coen Brothers' also use a number of bizarre yet enjoyable dream sequences to give their film another dimension.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mistaken Identity of Dude.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cupcake_movie_goer
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this eccentric comedy/crime film by the Coen brothers, they created an outstanding movie. The actors/actress in the film was perfectly unified in a great way that audience could build a vision of the plot. If you can handle the graphic dialogue used and suggestive behavior this is the right movie for you. The theme of the film is Jeff "Dude"Lebowski (Jeff Bridges) discovers he is a victim of mistaken identity. Thugs were sent to his home by Jackie Treehorn (Ben Gazzara) to recover a debit; Big Lebowski's (The Millionaire) wife owes him. Before the thugs realize they have the wrong Lebowski and that he's the "Dude" they urinate of his rug; leaving Dude in disgust. Dude pays BigLebowski (David Huddleston) a visit to be compensated for his rug being destroyed. Big Lebowski filled with arrogance; felt he was there looking for a hand out. Dude felt the conversation wasn't getting anywhere and decided he would take a rug from Lebowski home to be even. When Bunny (Tara Reid) disappears (Lebowski's wife); Big Lebowski contacts Dude making him an offer to be the bagman. The only thing Dude has to do is deliver the ransom money for Bunny. Dude brings Walter (John Goodman) along to make the drop. When the drop goes to pieces it creates a ricochet of others trying to reclaim the ransom money. While home listening to the soothing sounds of the bowling pins being knocked down, he discovers 3 people standing over him. They knocked him out and he begins to hallucinate; the lighting becomes dark with bright lights in the sky as he floats in sky. During the hallucination Dude see the rug he confiscated from Big Lebowski's. He is woken once his bowling ball drops him back to the surface. After coming back to reality, Dude is greeted by a women flying through the air on a stripe line in the nude, Maude Lebowski (Julianne Moore). Dude and Maude forms a relationship. Dude without realizing has been sized up to be a sperm donor of her child. Dude experienced many encounters because he was trying to clear his identity. After having sex with Maude and enjoy a marijuana joint, at that moment Dude realized the reasoning behind the mistaken identity fiasco. In conclusion, as a motif in the film "Dude" was the main character's name; however, it was used as a common word of expression during dialogue. Dude was able to regain his identity and continued being the old lazy, laid back, unemployed, and bowler from Southern California.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Biggie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felipe_lorescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What makes this an outstanding comedy?!? The fact that you laugh louder the 4th time, the 5th time you watch it. It's not only a comedy of punch lines (when you enjoy it the 1st time, then the 2nd time it's not that funny, cause you already know the catch). It's the classical style of the movie's atmosphere that sets the adorable mood. What makes it a classic?!? The 11th time, the 12th time you watch it, you don't get bored. Perhaps you won't laugh out loud like you previously did, but it still gets you in that mood. In addition, this comedy is sprinkled with some serious social matters. Read between the lines, watch between the scenes...!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Big Lebowski, my hero-the slacker, crime mystery solver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyink01
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Lebowski film plot is centered on a Los Angeles dude, who is a real slacker, pot smoking, White Russian drinker, soon to be hero solving a crime mystery. He happens to have the same name as a millionaire; Jeffrey Lebowski played by David Huddleston, whose wife, Bunny Lebowski (Tara Reid) was kidnapped and owes money to a known pornographer. We are introduced to the Dude as he is shopping for milk and he opened the carton and sniffed it. The Dude wrote a check for 69 cents and returns home. It appears that he is unaware that someone is waiting on him and they attack him in the apartment. One of the hit men urinates on his rug. His prized possession that ties the apartment together, says the Dude. The Dude enlists his bowling buddies, whom we meet in regular league play. His main antagonist and best friend played by John Goodman, as Walter Sobchak. We soon learn that Walter is a practicing Jew who observes the Shabbos day of rest. Walter refuses to lift a finger on the day of rest, but manages to convince the Dude that he needs to find the millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski, and get his rug replaced. Walter drives the car on the Shabbos and says he is just doing it to help out. But turns out he is creating more trouble for the Dude. The millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski is in a wheelchair, but convinces the Dude he needs to deliver the ransom money alone so his kidnapped wife will return. The Dude becomes a crime fighting, urban cowboy. They go through the motions of delivering the money and in the meantime, they say "F it, let's go bowling" park the car in a handicapped zone with the ransom money in it, when they walk outside the car is gone. Panic ensues and Walter always says "Shut the F up, Donny" played by Steve Buscemi. Donny never really gets to say much in the film, but Walter always tells him the same thing. We get introduced to the millionaire's sister, Maude Lebowski portrayed by Julianne Moore. Maude was a nude artist who created her works of art while riding in ceiling harness. She believed the ransom money was kept by the Dude, but he proves to her that there was no money, and he was used by her brother as a scapegoat. The millionaire still has the money. The pornographer hires hit men, thugs to find the money. Once they determine there is no money, they punch the Dude in the face so hard, we see & hear fireworks, and then he is flying through the sky like Superman. Then he lands in the bowling alley. The Dude tackles all his problems inside the walls of the bowling alley. The punch perpetuates him there. Walter's character gets so out of hand he pulls a gun on another bowler because he wants to bowl on Shabbos. This is not going to happen, the police are called but they run right by the pair in the parking lot. They are not even the least bit frazzled about the police being there, we see them running into the alley with guns pulled. The music ties the scenes together in the movie. When the action elevates to a point where they can't handle it anymore, the say let's go bowling. Magically through sound they end up there bowling. Always confronted by larger than life egos and it becomes quite funny how much animosity and hate both lash at each other. One of the teams they are to play against, become real aggressive and say "No one messes with Jesus" (John Turturro) that is the bowler's name. We get a flashback which is so comical showing Jesus as a pedophile going door to door announcing to the neighborhood that he lives there. Music takes us from the bowling alley through that flashback. It is a funny movie showing that even slackers can be heroes. Maude found a purpose for the Dude, as she wanted him to be a sperm donor only, she wanted a child. She was beyond weird, but the Dude liked her style. At the conclusion of the film Donnie dies from shock of seeing the Dude's car on fire. He was not up for all the problems and confrontations that Walter and Dude went through. He was much more fragile than they imagined, best part is he didn't die alone. His best friends were there till the end. Many times over this movie had music transition the picture forward, the voices were covered by different rock songs, and special effects transferred everyone to the next scene. Just by mere suggestion. We were walking in the bowling alley at every problem. I loved how they glorified some of the bowling scenes, especially with the dude going underneath about 50 women down the approach looking up at their crotches. Sometimes even the Dude was embarrassed by what he wished would happen. He couldn't look up at the women he floated upside down the approach of the bowling alley, ashamed of his own thoughts or more like daydreams. The Dude became a crusader of crime, not you're likely candidate to solve a mystery. He did it with the help of Donnie and Walter, despite the constant arguing and bickering between the three. The arguing was the craziest thing that kept them going, for most it would drive them apart. I never imagined this would be a crime mystery movie that was so cleverly written that The Dude seems like someone from real life and not a character at all. He feels so real, that's what makes this movie so special. Anyone can be a hero; you just gotta believe in yourself, even if you're a slacker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true nonsensicomedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roselaar
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Outrageously zany, off-beat comedy the likes only the Coen Brothers can provide. Life is tough for the pot smoking all-round slacker Jeffrey Lebowski, more commonly referred to as "The Dude" (Jeff Bridges in one of the most defining roles of his career). Sharing his last name with a millionaire, he's victimized by thugs who mistake him for that rich man (who owes them a debt), a situation which finds his beloved rug in ruin after having been urinated upon by the perpetrators. When he visits his namesake to try and get him to pay for its cleaning, he soon gets more than he bargained for as he finds himself caught up in what appears to be a kidnap of the wealthy man's trophy wife, but swiftly explodes into a bizarre, inexplicable potpourri of events beyond anybody's control or understanding, thanks to the involvement of a host of wacky, maniacal and thoroughly enjoyable characters, ranging from feminist/nihilist artists and pornographers to White Russians and generally random folk annex narrators. Yet all The Dude asked for was a clean rug and an opportunity to win the local bowling alley's competition he trained so hard for with his two best buddies (John Goodman with severe anger management problems and Steve Buscemi who can't take a hint when he's asked to shut up). The Coens don't ask you to make sense of it all, they just want you to roll with it (pun intended), as The Dude does himself. Nevertheless, despite this absence of a clearly defined plot, or more likely because of it, The Big Lebowski proves all kinds of fun. The pair of directors used the same tactic a decade later with Burn After Reading to similar results, proving them the masters of this subgenre of 'nonsensicomedy' (for the record, I just made that term up and I hope it catches on). In both cases they were aided by an impressive cast of character actors and/or movie stars who felt like doing something different for a change, in The Big Lebowski's case including Philip Seymour Hoffman, John Turturro, Julianne Moore and Sam Elliott. Though the film was met with moderately tempered critical reviews and disappointing box office results back in 1998, time has proved the Coens right, as it has since become a widely accepted cult classic with serious tendencies towards an eventual, seemingly unavoidable shedding of the moniker 'cult'. When Burn After Reading came along in 2008, the majority of both audience and critics finally understood this type of film, and that movie did much, much better business accordingly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite a nice combination of comedy and crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has so many reviews that it doesn't need mine, so I won't review it. But since I write a blurb on each movie I see so that I can recollect it, I'll attempt to write 10 lines about this one. First off, it's a very satirical movie. I think it will be just as funny on a second viewing. There's too much swearing in the movie, you know, the f-word. After awhile, that became very tiring, and for me it impeded the comedy. I also thought that this was hard on the actors forced to insert this word so many times. They didn't sound 100% convincing at it after awhile. John Turturro's part is not that big, but he's very good in it. I didn't think Steve Buscemi had that many comic lines. It was really John Goodman's show. I liked his interactions with Jeff Bridges. Mr. Bridges remains a huge talent, as far as I can tell. David Huddleston is a very good actor. He was a tad over the top here. The film somehow made good use of Sam Elliott, who might be an underrated actor. Some of the other supporting actors didn't have that much to do in the way of comedy. In comedy you can say things you wouldn't ordinarily say seriously, and I felt that the Coens were taking the opportunity to poke fun at a lot of their favorite targets, but not in a peevish way. The film is above average. Maybe it's even an 8, but so many reviewers are raving so much about it excessively, as IMDb reviewers are wont to do, that I'm expressing less enthusiasm. See it, if you haven't already. You'll enjoy it, as long as you don't mind hearing a very great deal of the f-word. By the way, in Scarface with Pacino, the profanity seemed just right and worked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films, period - Dude!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barmstrong-782-631970
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Come on! This is the best film ever. i', even raising this above LOTR, since this is contemporary. I grew up living like the Dude. The Dude reminds me of my Uncle...not in a bad way, but with deep respect to living one's own life. The Coen brothers have created a film to be topped, if it was possible. Barton Fink was great..Fargo, yeah it was exceptional story-telling. But, the Dude - that was well-crafted cinema. The only other film that I have seen of theirs that captured me as much was No Country for Old Men. Can't wait for the next surprise!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG - Not Funny, Not Funny, Not Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NickyCee
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the heck did I tell you the Big Lebowski is not funny three times? Because this is once for every 20 people that told me this movie was the funniest most entertaining movie EVER. After years of being berated at parties and get-togethers with people spewing line after line from the movie, I gave in last week. I finally rented it. Wow. It's so bad on so many levels it's hard to describe. It's not funny - at - all. It's mildly amusing in parts but of the six people I watched it with, no one laughed once. Not once. I don't think it's a spoiler to tell you the language is sickeningly bad. Up there with Team America bad. There is one reason and one reason only that this movie is popular: College aged men (or guys who wish they were college aged) own the DVD and watch it repeatedly. Once memorizing the movie, on subsequent viewings they elbow each other before each "big" scene almost spilling their friend's beer and yelling, "HERE IT IS! HERE IT IS!" They then laugh at how clever they think they are. They're part of "The DUDE" club and they are very, very special indeed. This is the most unfunny movie I have ever seen. Other than Scarface and Team America, the movie containing the foulest most unnecessary language I've ever seen, and overall one of top five worst movies I've ever seen (and yes, this includes You Tube cat movies).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1998's The Big Lebowski Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of The Coen Brothers Direction And Screenplay, The Score, The Cinematography By Roger Deakins And Jeff Bridges Performance As Jeff Lebowski, My Mom Kelli Krajci Watched This Movie A Little On DVD That I Own That I Have In My DVD Collection, I Like To Laugh When I Watch Funny Movies On DVD, My Favorite Comedy Film Is 1933's Duck Soup With The Marx Brothers, 1988 Was 10 Years Old In 1998, 1982 Was 16 Years Old In 1998, 1953 Was 45 Years Old In 1998, This Movie Turned 10 Years In 2008, It Is Going To Turn 20 Years Old In 2018, Another Coen Brothers Film 1996's Fargo Is One Of My Favorite Films As Well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themadhouseyt
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funniest movie i've ever seen very good performances strong script very well directed deserved an Oscar. For me Jeff Bridges and John Goodman should have deserved an Oscar or at least a nomination, it's not that kind of comedy which is funny and at the half of the movie the jokes start to get annoying, the whole movie keeps you entertained, at least i didn't want the movie to end. The only thing that bothered me is that they haven't done a part 2, i want to know what is going to happen to "The Dude" and Walter i don't really care about other characters really (That doesn't mean that the other actors weren't good) I really would love if it lasted more. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Without a doubt, this is the funniest film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Coen Brothers are perhaps better known for their work in colder films such as 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men' but with 'The Big Lebowski' they manage to create a clever and highly enjoyable comedy. I've seen the film a number of times now and on each viewing I have been more impressed by what I have seen. The movie combines a talented cast with each actor bringing their own unique character to the screen, humour that is intelligent and subtle in places, brilliant sets such as those used in the bowling alley, costumes and a soundtrack that brilliantly adds to the feel of film. Although 'The Big Lebowski' is nothing like the films of 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men', it contains many of the Coen Brothers usual plot devices and techniques that they used. The plot of the film is relatively straight forward, but is layered over with bizarre twists with nothing going as easy as planned. The film is focused around a millionaire whose wife is kidnapped for a $1,000,000 ransom with Jeffrey Lebowski hiring a 'bum' of the same name to act as a middle man in a deal to get here back. Immediately 'Dude' as he likes to be known suspects that the kidnapping is not as straightforward as outlined and that Lebowski's wife Bunny has kidnapped herself in order to get rich from a man who would not normally allow her such money, sound a bit like 'Fargo'? Unlike Fargo which can be seen as a 'dark comedy', The Big Lebowski is more a feel-good film that's style can probably be better compared to an earlier comedy of the Coen Brothers 'Raising Arizona', a film also which featured John Goodman (who also appeared in the Coen Brothers' film 'Barton Fink'). I feel that John Goodman's performance in this film is one worthy of a best supporting actor Oscar. Goodman portrays Walter; one of the Dude's bowling buddies that becomes involved in the Dude's task to transfer money between Lebowski and the kidnappers. Walter provides a lot of the film's humour and best scenes; he is an aggressive war veteran who makes constant references to his fighting at Vietnam and is constantly arguing with fellow bowling buddy Donny. Donny is portrayed by Steve Buscemi who is one of my favourite actors who seems to play a totally different character in every film he appears in. It seems strange that him and Goodman would go on to star together again in 'Monsters Inc.' but the two have great chemistry in this film, Donny is mocked throughout by Walter and the two provide some great scenes for us such as 'I am the walrus?'. John Turturro (who starred in 'Barton Fink' and later 'O Brother, Where Art Thou?') also features in a less prominent role as Jesus Quintana, a convicted paedophile that is set to face the Dude's bowling team in an upcoming tournament round. Although he doesn't have much time on screen, when he does he provides us with some of the films most enjoyable scenes, in fact this is the case for nearly all the scenes that are set in the bowling alley. Sam Elliott is also used effectively in his role as the mysterious narrator. There are other strong supporting performances such as those from Julianne Moore and Philip Seymour Hoffman but the star is undoubtedly Jeff Bridges as 'the Dude'. Jeff Bridges brings character and style to the leading character who is ultimately a bum that spends his life getting high and bowling with his friends. It's hard to imagine anybody else in such a role, the film acts an ode to the characters laid back, chilled lifestyle which makes the film so enjoyable. As it is with other Coen Brothers' films, the cinematography is superb and the duo have created a fantastic setting for a film. In 'Fargo' we saw the gritty and dark atmosphere reflected in the cold setting of North Dakota, in 'The Big Lebowski' the Coen Brothers' use Los Angeles as their location, at times the film can feel dark but at others we get light, as already said the bowling alley provides an excellent setting for many of the films' scenes. The Coen Brothers' also use a number of bizarre yet enjoyable dream sequences to give their film another dimension.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mistaken Identity of Dude.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cupcake_movie_goer
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this eccentric comedy/crime film by the Coen brothers, they created an outstanding movie. The actors/actress in the film was perfectly unified in a great way that audience could build a vision of the plot. If you can handle the graphic dialogue used and suggestive behavior this is the right movie for you. The theme of the film is Jeff "Dude"Lebowski (Jeff Bridges) discovers he is a victim of mistaken identity. Thugs were sent to his home by Jackie Treehorn (Ben Gazzara) to recover a debit; Big Lebowski's (The Millionaire) wife owes him. Before the thugs realize they have the wrong Lebowski and that he's the "Dude" they urinate of his rug; leaving Dude in disgust. Dude pays BigLebowski (David Huddleston) a visit to be compensated for his rug being destroyed. Big Lebowski filled with arrogance; felt he was there looking for a hand out. Dude felt the conversation wasn't getting anywhere and decided he would take a rug from Lebowski home to be even. When Bunny (Tara Reid) disappears (Lebowski's wife); Big Lebowski contacts Dude making him an offer to be the bagman. The only thing Dude has to do is deliver the ransom money for Bunny. Dude brings Walter (John Goodman) along to make the drop. When the drop goes to pieces it creates a ricochet of others trying to reclaim the ransom money. While home listening to the soothing sounds of the bowling pins being knocked down, he discovers 3 people standing over him. They knocked him out and he begins to hallucinate; the lighting becomes dark with bright lights in the sky as he floats in sky. During the hallucination Dude see the rug he confiscated from Big Lebowski's. He is woken once his bowling ball drops him back to the surface. After coming back to reality, Dude is greeted by a women flying through the air on a stripe line in the nude, Maude Lebowski (Julianne Moore). Dude and Maude forms a relationship. Dude without realizing has been sized up to be a sperm donor of her child. Dude experienced many encounters because he was trying to clear his identity. After having sex with Maude and enjoy a marijuana joint, at that moment Dude realized the reasoning behind the mistaken identity fiasco. In conclusion, as a motif in the film "Dude" was the main character's name; however, it was used as a common word of expression during dialogue. Dude was able to regain his identity and continued being the old lazy, laid back, unemployed, and bowler from Southern California.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Biggie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felipe_lorescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What makes this an outstanding comedy?!? The fact that you laugh louder the 4th time, the 5th time you watch it. It's not only a comedy of punch lines (when you enjoy it the 1st time, then the 2nd time it's not that funny, cause you already know the catch). It's the classical style of the movie's atmosphere that sets the adorable mood. What makes it a classic?!? The 11th time, the 12th time you watch it, you don't get bored. Perhaps you won't laugh out loud like you previously did, but it still gets you in that mood. In addition, this comedy is sprinkled with some serious social matters. Read between the lines, watch between the scenes...!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Big Lebowski, my hero-the slacker, crime mystery solver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyink01
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Lebowski film plot is centered on a Los Angeles dude, who is a real slacker, pot smoking, White Russian drinker, soon to be hero solving a crime mystery. He happens to have the same name as a millionaire; Jeffrey Lebowski played by David Huddleston, whose wife, Bunny Lebowski (Tara Reid) was kidnapped and owes money to a known pornographer. We are introduced to the Dude as he is shopping for milk and he opened the carton and sniffed it. The Dude wrote a check for 69 cents and returns home. It appears that he is unaware that someone is waiting on him and they attack him in the apartment. One of the hit men urinates on his rug. His prized possession that ties the apartment together, says the Dude. The Dude enlists his bowling buddies, whom we meet in regular league play. His main antagonist and best friend played by John Goodman, as Walter Sobchak. We soon learn that Walter is a practicing Jew who observes the Shabbos day of rest. Walter refuses to lift a finger on the day of rest, but manages to convince the Dude that he needs to find the millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski, and get his rug replaced. Walter drives the car on the Shabbos and says he is just doing it to help out. But turns out he is creating more trouble for the Dude. The millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski is in a wheelchair, but convinces the Dude he needs to deliver the ransom money alone so his kidnapped wife will return. The Dude becomes a crime fighting, urban cowboy. They go through the motions of delivering the money and in the meantime, they say "F it, let's go bowling" park the car in a handicapped zone with the ransom money in it, when they walk outside the car is gone. Panic ensues and Walter always says "Shut the F up, Donny" played by Steve Buscemi. Donny never really gets to say much in the film, but Walter always tells him the same thing. We get introduced to the millionaire's sister, Maude Lebowski portrayed by Julianne Moore. Maude was a nude artist who created her works of art while riding in ceiling harness. She believed the ransom money was kept by the Dude, but he proves to her that there was no money, and he was used by her brother as a scapegoat. The millionaire still has the money. The pornographer hires hit men, thugs to find the money. Once they determine there is no money, they punch the Dude in the face so hard, we see & hear fireworks, and then he is flying through the sky like Superman. Then he lands in the bowling alley. The Dude tackles all his problems inside the walls of the bowling alley. The punch perpetuates him there. Walter's character gets so out of hand he pulls a gun on another bowler because he wants to bowl on Shabbos. This is not going to happen, the police are called but they run right by the pair in the parking lot. They are not even the least bit frazzled about the police being there, we see them running into the alley with guns pulled. The music ties the scenes together in the movie. When the action elevates to a point where they can't handle it anymore, the say let's go bowling. Magically through sound they end up there bowling. Always confronted by larger than life egos and it becomes quite funny how much animosity and hate both lash at each other. One of the teams they are to play against, become real aggressive and say "No one messes with Jesus" (John Turturro) that is the bowler's name. We get a flashback which is so comical showing Jesus as a pedophile going door to door announcing to the neighborhood that he lives there. Music takes us from the bowling alley through that flashback. It is a funny movie showing that even slackers can be heroes. Maude found a purpose for the Dude, as she wanted him to be a sperm donor only, she wanted a child. She was beyond weird, but the Dude liked her style. At the conclusion of the film Donnie dies from shock of seeing the Dude's car on fire. He was not up for all the problems and confrontations that Walter and Dude went through. He was much more fragile than they imagined, best part is he didn't die alone. His best friends were there till the end. Many times over this movie had music transition the picture forward, the voices were covered by different rock songs, and special effects transferred everyone to the next scene. Just by mere suggestion. We were walking in the bowling alley at every problem. I loved how they glorified some of the bowling scenes, especially with the dude going underneath about 50 women down the approach looking up at their crotches. Sometimes even the Dude was embarrassed by what he wished would happen. He couldn't look up at the women he floated upside down the approach of the bowling alley, ashamed of his own thoughts or more like daydreams. The Dude became a crusader of crime, not you're likely candidate to solve a mystery. He did it with the help of Donnie and Walter, despite the constant arguing and bickering between the three. The arguing was the craziest thing that kept them going, for most it would drive them apart. I never imagined this would be a crime mystery movie that was so cleverly written that The Dude seems like someone from real life and not a character at all. He feels so real, that's what makes this movie so special. Anyone can be a hero; you just gotta believe in yourself, even if you're a slacker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true nonsensicomedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roselaar
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Outrageously zany, off-beat comedy the likes only the Coen Brothers can provide. Life is tough for the pot smoking all-round slacker Jeffrey Lebowski, more commonly referred to as "The Dude" (Jeff Bridges in one of the most defining roles of his career). Sharing his last name with a millionaire, he's victimized by thugs who mistake him for that rich man (who owes them a debt), a situation which finds his beloved rug in ruin after having been urinated upon by the perpetrators. When he visits his namesake to try and get him to pay for its cleaning, he soon gets more than he bargained for as he finds himself caught up in what appears to be a kidnap of the wealthy man's trophy wife, but swiftly explodes into a bizarre, inexplicable potpourri of events beyond anybody's control or understanding, thanks to the involvement of a host of wacky, maniacal and thoroughly enjoyable characters, ranging from feminist/nihilist artists and pornographers to White Russians and generally random folk annex narrators. Yet all The Dude asked for was a clean rug and an opportunity to win the local bowling alley's competition he trained so hard for with his two best buddies (John Goodman with severe anger management problems and Steve Buscemi who can't take a hint when he's asked to shut up). The Coens don't ask you to make sense of it all, they just want you to roll with it (pun intended), as The Dude does himself. Nevertheless, despite this absence of a clearly defined plot, or more likely because of it, The Big Lebowski proves all kinds of fun. The pair of directors used the same tactic a decade later with Burn After Reading to similar results, proving them the masters of this subgenre of 'nonsensicomedy' (for the record, I just made that term up and I hope it catches on). In both cases they were aided by an impressive cast of character actors and/or movie stars who felt like doing something different for a change, in The Big Lebowski's case including Philip Seymour Hoffman, John Turturro, Julianne Moore and Sam Elliott. Though the film was met with moderately tempered critical reviews and disappointing box office results back in 1998, time has proved the Coens right, as it has since become a widely accepted cult classic with serious tendencies towards an eventual, seemingly unavoidable shedding of the moniker 'cult'. When Burn After Reading came along in 2008, the majority of both audience and critics finally understood this type of film, and that movie did much, much better business accordingly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite a nice combination of comedy and crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has so many reviews that it doesn't need mine, so I won't review it. But since I write a blurb on each movie I see so that I can recollect it, I'll attempt to write 10 lines about this one. First off, it's a very satirical movie. I think it will be just as funny on a second viewing. There's too much swearing in the movie, you know, the f-word. After awhile, that became very tiring, and for me it impeded the comedy. I also thought that this was hard on the actors forced to insert this word so many times. They didn't sound 100% convincing at it after awhile. John Turturro's part is not that big, but he's very good in it. I didn't think Steve Buscemi had that many comic lines. It was really John Goodman's show. I liked his interactions with Jeff Bridges. Mr. Bridges remains a huge talent, as far as I can tell. David Huddleston is a very good actor. He was a tad over the top here. The film somehow made good use of Sam Elliott, who might be an underrated actor. Some of the other supporting actors didn't have that much to do in the way of comedy. In comedy you can say things you wouldn't ordinarily say seriously, and I felt that the Coens were taking the opportunity to poke fun at a lot of their favorite targets, but not in a peevish way. The film is above average. Maybe it's even an 8, but so many reviewers are raving so much about it excessively, as IMDb reviewers are wont to do, that I'm expressing less enthusiasm. See it, if you haven't already. You'll enjoy it, as long as you don't mind hearing a very great deal of the f-word. By the way, in Scarface with Pacino, the profanity seemed just right and worked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films, period - Dude!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barmstrong-782-631970
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Come on! This is the best film ever. i', even raising this above LOTR, since this is contemporary. I grew up living like the Dude. The Dude reminds me of my Uncle...not in a bad way, but with deep respect to living one's own life. The Coen brothers have created a film to be topped, if it was possible. Barton Fink was great..Fargo, yeah it was exceptional story-telling. But, the Dude - that was well-crafted cinema. The only other film that I have seen of theirs that captured me as much was No Country for Old Men. Can't wait for the next surprise!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG - Not Funny, Not Funny, Not Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NickyCee
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the heck did I tell you the Big Lebowski is not funny three times? Because this is once for every 20 people that told me this movie was the funniest most entertaining movie EVER. After years of being berated at parties and get-togethers with people spewing line after line from the movie, I gave in last week. I finally rented it. Wow. It's so bad on so many levels it's hard to describe. It's not funny - at - all. It's mildly amusing in parts but of the six people I watched it with, no one laughed once. Not once. I don't think it's a spoiler to tell you the language is sickeningly bad. Up there with Team America bad. There is one reason and one reason only that this movie is popular: College aged men (or guys who wish they were college aged) own the DVD and watch it repeatedly. Once memorizing the movie, on subsequent viewings they elbow each other before each "big" scene almost spilling their friend's beer and yelling, "HERE IT IS! HERE IT IS!" They then laugh at how clever they think they are. They're part of "The DUDE" club and they are very, very special indeed. This is the most unfunny movie I have ever seen. Other than Scarface and Team America, the movie containing the foulest most unnecessary language I've ever seen, and overall one of top five worst movies I've ever seen (and yes, this includes You Tube cat movies).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1998's The Big Lebowski Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of The Coen Brothers Direction And Screenplay, The Score, The Cinematography By Roger Deakins And Jeff Bridges Performance As Jeff Lebowski, My Mom Kelli Krajci Watched This Movie A Little On DVD That I Own That I Have In My DVD Collection, I Like To Laugh When I Watch Funny Movies On DVD, My Favorite Comedy Film Is 1933's Duck Soup With The Marx Brothers, 1988 Was 10 Years Old In 1998, 1982 Was 16 Years Old In 1998, 1953 Was 45 Years Old In 1998, This Movie Turned 10 Years In 2008, It Is Going To Turn 20 Years Old In 2018, Another Coen Brothers Film 1996's Fargo Is One Of My Favorite Films As Well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themadhouseyt
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funniest movie i've ever seen very good performances strong script very well directed deserved an Oscar. For me Jeff Bridges and John Goodman should have deserved an Oscar or at least a nomination, it's not that kind of comedy which is funny and at the half of the movie the jokes start to get annoying, the whole movie keeps you entertained, at least i didn't want the movie to end. The only thing that bothered me is that they haven't done a part 2, i want to know what is going to happen to "The Dude" and Walter i don't really care about other characters really (That doesn't mean that the other actors weren't good) I really would love if it lasted more. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Without a doubt, this is the funniest film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Coen Brothers are perhaps better known for their work in colder films such as 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men' but with 'The Big Lebowski' they manage to create a clever and highly enjoyable comedy. I've seen the film a number of times now and on each viewing I have been more impressed by what I have seen. The movie combines a talented cast with each actor bringing their own unique character to the screen, humour that is intelligent and subtle in places, brilliant sets such as those used in the bowling alley, costumes and a soundtrack that brilliantly adds to the feel of film. Although 'The Big Lebowski' is nothing like the films of 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men', it contains many of the Coen Brothers usual plot devices and techniques that they used. The plot of the film is relatively straight forward, but is layered over with bizarre twists with nothing going as easy as planned. The film is focused around a millionaire whose wife is kidnapped for a $1,000,000 ransom with Jeffrey Lebowski hiring a 'bum' of the same name to act as a middle man in a deal to get here back. Immediately 'Dude' as he likes to be known suspects that the kidnapping is not as straightforward as outlined and that Lebowski's wife Bunny has kidnapped herself in order to get rich from a man who would not normally allow her such money, sound a bit like 'Fargo'? Unlike Fargo which can be seen as a 'dark comedy', The Big Lebowski is more a feel-good film that's style can probably be better compared to an earlier comedy of the Coen Brothers 'Raising Arizona', a film also which featured John Goodman (who also appeared in the Coen Brothers' film 'Barton Fink'). I feel that John Goodman's performance in this film is one worthy of a best supporting actor Oscar. Goodman portrays Walter; one of the Dude's bowling buddies that becomes involved in the Dude's task to transfer money between Lebowski and the kidnappers. Walter provides a lot of the film's humour and best scenes; he is an aggressive war veteran who makes constant references to his fighting at Vietnam and is constantly arguing with fellow bowling buddy Donny. Donny is portrayed by Steve Buscemi who is one of my favourite actors who seems to play a totally different character in every film he appears in. It seems strange that him and Goodman would go on to star together again in 'Monsters Inc.' but the two have great chemistry in this film, Donny is mocked throughout by Walter and the two provide some great scenes for us such as 'I am the walrus?'. John Turturro (who starred in 'Barton Fink' and later 'O Brother, Where Art Thou?') also features in a less prominent role as Jesus Quintana, a convicted paedophile that is set to face the Dude's bowling team in an upcoming tournament round. Although he doesn't have much time on screen, when he does he provides us with some of the films most enjoyable scenes, in fact this is the case for nearly all the scenes that are set in the bowling alley. Sam Elliott is also used effectively in his role as the mysterious narrator. There are other strong supporting performances such as those from Julianne Moore and Philip Seymour Hoffman but the star is undoubtedly Jeff Bridges as 'the Dude'. Jeff Bridges brings character and style to the leading character who is ultimately a bum that spends his life getting high and bowling with his friends. It's hard to imagine anybody else in such a role, the film acts an ode to the characters laid back, chilled lifestyle which makes the film so enjoyable. As it is with other Coen Brothers' films, the cinematography is superb and the duo have created a fantastic setting for a film. In 'Fargo' we saw the gritty and dark atmosphere reflected in the cold setting of North Dakota, in 'The Big Lebowski' the Coen Brothers' use Los Angeles as their location, at times the film can feel dark but at others we get light, as already said the bowling alley provides an excellent setting for many of the films' scenes. The Coen Brothers' also use a number of bizarre yet enjoyable dream sequences to give their film another dimension.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mistaken Identity of Dude.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cupcake_movie_goer
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this eccentric comedy/crime film by the Coen brothers, they created an outstanding movie. The actors/actress in the film was perfectly unified in a great way that audience could build a vision of the plot. If you can handle the graphic dialogue used and suggestive behavior this is the right movie for you. The theme of the film is Jeff "Dude"Lebowski (Jeff Bridges) discovers he is a victim of mistaken identity. Thugs were sent to his home by Jackie Treehorn (Ben Gazzara) to recover a debit; Big Lebowski's (The Millionaire) wife owes him. Before the thugs realize they have the wrong Lebowski and that he's the "Dude" they urinate of his rug; leaving Dude in disgust. Dude pays BigLebowski (David Huddleston) a visit to be compensated for his rug being destroyed. Big Lebowski filled with arrogance; felt he was there looking for a hand out. Dude felt the conversation wasn't getting anywhere and decided he would take a rug from Lebowski home to be even. When Bunny (Tara Reid) disappears (Lebowski's wife); Big Lebowski contacts Dude making him an offer to be the bagman. The only thing Dude has to do is deliver the ransom money for Bunny. Dude brings Walter (John Goodman) along to make the drop. When the drop goes to pieces it creates a ricochet of others trying to reclaim the ransom money. While home listening to the soothing sounds of the bowling pins being knocked down, he discovers 3 people standing over him. They knocked him out and he begins to hallucinate; the lighting becomes dark with bright lights in the sky as he floats in sky. During the hallucination Dude see the rug he confiscated from Big Lebowski's. He is woken once his bowling ball drops him back to the surface. After coming back to reality, Dude is greeted by a women flying through the air on a stripe line in the nude, Maude Lebowski (Julianne Moore). Dude and Maude forms a relationship. Dude without realizing has been sized up to be a sperm donor of her child. Dude experienced many encounters because he was trying to clear his identity. After having sex with Maude and enjoy a marijuana joint, at that moment Dude realized the reasoning behind the mistaken identity fiasco. In conclusion, as a motif in the film "Dude" was the main character's name; however, it was used as a common word of expression during dialogue. Dude was able to regain his identity and continued being the old lazy, laid back, unemployed, and bowler from Southern California.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Biggie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felipe_lorescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What makes this an outstanding comedy?!? The fact that you laugh louder the 4th time, the 5th time you watch it. It's not only a comedy of punch lines (when you enjoy it the 1st time, then the 2nd time it's not that funny, cause you already know the catch). It's the classical style of the movie's atmosphere that sets the adorable mood. What makes it a classic?!? The 11th time, the 12th time you watch it, you don't get bored. Perhaps you won't laugh out loud like you previously did, but it still gets you in that mood. In addition, this comedy is sprinkled with some serious social matters. Read between the lines, watch between the scenes...!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Big Lebowski, my hero-the slacker, crime mystery solver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyink01
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Lebowski film plot is centered on a Los Angeles dude, who is a real slacker, pot smoking, White Russian drinker, soon to be hero solving a crime mystery. He happens to have the same name as a millionaire; Jeffrey Lebowski played by David Huddleston, whose wife, Bunny Lebowski (Tara Reid) was kidnapped and owes money to a known pornographer. We are introduced to the Dude as he is shopping for milk and he opened the carton and sniffed it. The Dude wrote a check for 69 cents and returns home. It appears that he is unaware that someone is waiting on him and they attack him in the apartment. One of the hit men urinates on his rug. His prized possession that ties the apartment together, says the Dude. The Dude enlists his bowling buddies, whom we meet in regular league play. His main antagonist and best friend played by John Goodman, as Walter Sobchak. We soon learn that Walter is a practicing Jew who observes the Shabbos day of rest. Walter refuses to lift a finger on the day of rest, but manages to convince the Dude that he needs to find the millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski, and get his rug replaced. Walter drives the car on the Shabbos and says he is just doing it to help out. But turns out he is creating more trouble for the Dude. The millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski is in a wheelchair, but convinces the Dude he needs to deliver the ransom money alone so his kidnapped wife will return. The Dude becomes a crime fighting, urban cowboy. They go through the motions of delivering the money and in the meantime, they say "F it, let's go bowling" park the car in a handicapped zone with the ransom money in it, when they walk outside the car is gone. Panic ensues and Walter always says "Shut the F up, Donny" played by Steve Buscemi. Donny never really gets to say much in the film, but Walter always tells him the same thing. We get introduced to the millionaire's sister, Maude Lebowski portrayed by Julianne Moore. Maude was a nude artist who created her works of art while riding in ceiling harness. She believed the ransom money was kept by the Dude, but he proves to her that there was no money, and he was used by her brother as a scapegoat. The millionaire still has the money. The pornographer hires hit men, thugs to find the money. Once they determine there is no money, they punch the Dude in the face so hard, we see & hear fireworks, and then he is flying through the sky like Superman. Then he lands in the bowling alley. The Dude tackles all his problems inside the walls of the bowling alley. The punch perpetuates him there. Walter's character gets so out of hand he pulls a gun on another bowler because he wants to bowl on Shabbos. This is not going to happen, the police are called but they run right by the pair in the parking lot. They are not even the least bit frazzled about the police being there, we see them running into the alley with guns pulled. The music ties the scenes together in the movie. When the action elevates to a point where they can't handle it anymore, the say let's go bowling. Magically through sound they end up there bowling. Always confronted by larger than life egos and it becomes quite funny how much animosity and hate both lash at each other. One of the teams they are to play against, become real aggressive and say "No one messes with Jesus" (John Turturro) that is the bowler's name. We get a flashback which is so comical showing Jesus as a pedophile going door to door announcing to the neighborhood that he lives there. Music takes us from the bowling alley through that flashback. It is a funny movie showing that even slackers can be heroes. Maude found a purpose for the Dude, as she wanted him to be a sperm donor only, she wanted a child. She was beyond weird, but the Dude liked her style. At the conclusion of the film Donnie dies from shock of seeing the Dude's car on fire. He was not up for all the problems and confrontations that Walter and Dude went through. He was much more fragile than they imagined, best part is he didn't die alone. His best friends were there till the end. Many times over this movie had music transition the picture forward, the voices were covered by different rock songs, and special effects transferred everyone to the next scene. Just by mere suggestion. We were walking in the bowling alley at every problem. I loved how they glorified some of the bowling scenes, especially with the dude going underneath about 50 women down the approach looking up at their crotches. Sometimes even the Dude was embarrassed by what he wished would happen. He couldn't look up at the women he floated upside down the approach of the bowling alley, ashamed of his own thoughts or more like daydreams. The Dude became a crusader of crime, not you're likely candidate to solve a mystery. He did it with the help of Donnie and Walter, despite the constant arguing and bickering between the three. The arguing was the craziest thing that kept them going, for most it would drive them apart. I never imagined this would be a crime mystery movie that was so cleverly written that The Dude seems like someone from real life and not a character at all. He feels so real, that's what makes this movie so special. Anyone can be a hero; you just gotta believe in yourself, even if you're a slacker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true nonsensicomedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roselaar
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Outrageously zany, off-beat comedy the likes only the Coen Brothers can provide. Life is tough for the pot smoking all-round slacker Jeffrey Lebowski, more commonly referred to as "The Dude" (Jeff Bridges in one of the most defining roles of his career). Sharing his last name with a millionaire, he's victimized by thugs who mistake him for that rich man (who owes them a debt), a situation which finds his beloved rug in ruin after having been urinated upon by the perpetrators. When he visits his namesake to try and get him to pay for its cleaning, he soon gets more than he bargained for as he finds himself caught up in what appears to be a kidnap of the wealthy man's trophy wife, but swiftly explodes into a bizarre, inexplicable potpourri of events beyond anybody's control or understanding, thanks to the involvement of a host of wacky, maniacal and thoroughly enjoyable characters, ranging from feminist/nihilist artists and pornographers to White Russians and generally random folk annex narrators. Yet all The Dude asked for was a clean rug and an opportunity to win the local bowling alley's competition he trained so hard for with his two best buddies (John Goodman with severe anger management problems and Steve Buscemi who can't take a hint when he's asked to shut up). The Coens don't ask you to make sense of it all, they just want you to roll with it (pun intended), as The Dude does himself. Nevertheless, despite this absence of a clearly defined plot, or more likely because of it, The Big Lebowski proves all kinds of fun. The pair of directors used the same tactic a decade later with Burn After Reading to similar results, proving them the masters of this subgenre of 'nonsensicomedy' (for the record, I just made that term up and I hope it catches on). In both cases they were aided by an impressive cast of character actors and/or movie stars who felt like doing something different for a change, in The Big Lebowski's case including Philip Seymour Hoffman, John Turturro, Julianne Moore and Sam Elliott. Though the film was met with moderately tempered critical reviews and disappointing box office results back in 1998, time has proved the Coens right, as it has since become a widely accepted cult classic with serious tendencies towards an eventual, seemingly unavoidable shedding of the moniker 'cult'. When Burn After Reading came along in 2008, the majority of both audience and critics finally understood this type of film, and that movie did much, much better business accordingly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite a nice combination of comedy and crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has so many reviews that it doesn't need mine, so I won't review it. But since I write a blurb on each movie I see so that I can recollect it, I'll attempt to write 10 lines about this one. First off, it's a very satirical movie. I think it will be just as funny on a second viewing. There's too much swearing in the movie, you know, the f-word. After awhile, that became very tiring, and for me it impeded the comedy. I also thought that this was hard on the actors forced to insert this word so many times. They didn't sound 100% convincing at it after awhile. John Turturro's part is not that big, but he's very good in it. I didn't think Steve Buscemi had that many comic lines. It was really John Goodman's show. I liked his interactions with Jeff Bridges. Mr. Bridges remains a huge talent, as far as I can tell. David Huddleston is a very good actor. He was a tad over the top here. The film somehow made good use of Sam Elliott, who might be an underrated actor. Some of the other supporting actors didn't have that much to do in the way of comedy. In comedy you can say things you wouldn't ordinarily say seriously, and I felt that the Coens were taking the opportunity to poke fun at a lot of their favorite targets, but not in a peevish way. The film is above average. Maybe it's even an 8, but so many reviewers are raving so much about it excessively, as IMDb reviewers are wont to do, that I'm expressing less enthusiasm. See it, if you haven't already. You'll enjoy it, as long as you don't mind hearing a very great deal of the f-word. By the way, in Scarface with Pacino, the profanity seemed just right and worked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films, period - Dude!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barmstrong-782-631970
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Come on! This is the best film ever. i', even raising this above LOTR, since this is contemporary. I grew up living like the Dude. The Dude reminds me of my Uncle...not in a bad way, but with deep respect to living one's own life. The Coen brothers have created a film to be topped, if it was possible. Barton Fink was great..Fargo, yeah it was exceptional story-telling. But, the Dude - that was well-crafted cinema. The only other film that I have seen of theirs that captured me as much was No Country for Old Men. Can't wait for the next surprise!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG - Not Funny, Not Funny, Not Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NickyCee
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the heck did I tell you the Big Lebowski is not funny three times? Because this is once for every 20 people that told me this movie was the funniest most entertaining movie EVER. After years of being berated at parties and get-togethers with people spewing line after line from the movie, I gave in last week. I finally rented it. Wow. It's so bad on so many levels it's hard to describe. It's not funny - at - all. It's mildly amusing in parts but of the six people I watched it with, no one laughed once. Not once. I don't think it's a spoiler to tell you the language is sickeningly bad. Up there with Team America bad. There is one reason and one reason only that this movie is popular: College aged men (or guys who wish they were college aged) own the DVD and watch it repeatedly. Once memorizing the movie, on subsequent viewings they elbow each other before each "big" scene almost spilling their friend's beer and yelling, "HERE IT IS! HERE IT IS!" They then laugh at how clever they think they are. They're part of "The DUDE" club and they are very, very special indeed. This is the most unfunny movie I have ever seen. Other than Scarface and Team America, the movie containing the foulest most unnecessary language I've ever seen, and overall one of top five worst movies I've ever seen (and yes, this includes You Tube cat movies).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1998's The Big Lebowski Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of The Coen Brothers Direction And Screenplay, The Score, The Cinematography By Roger Deakins And Jeff Bridges Performance As Jeff Lebowski, My Mom Kelli Krajci Watched This Movie A Little On DVD That I Own That I Have In My DVD Collection, I Like To Laugh When I Watch Funny Movies On DVD, My Favorite Comedy Film Is 1933's Duck Soup With The Marx Brothers, 1988 Was 10 Years Old In 1998, 1982 Was 16 Years Old In 1998, 1953 Was 45 Years Old In 1998, This Movie Turned 10 Years In 2008, It Is Going To Turn 20 Years Old In 2018, Another Coen Brothers Film 1996's Fargo Is One Of My Favorite Films As Well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themadhouseyt
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funniest movie i've ever seen very good performances strong script very well directed deserved an Oscar. For me Jeff Bridges and John Goodman should have deserved an Oscar or at least a nomination, it's not that kind of comedy which is funny and at the half of the movie the jokes start to get annoying, the whole movie keeps you entertained, at least i didn't want the movie to end. The only thing that bothered me is that they haven't done a part 2, i want to know what is going to happen to "The Dude" and Walter i don't really care about other characters really (That doesn't mean that the other actors weren't good) I really would love if it lasted more. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Without a doubt, this is the funniest film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Coen Brothers are perhaps better known for their work in colder films such as 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men' but with 'The Big Lebowski' they manage to create a clever and highly enjoyable comedy. I've seen the film a number of times now and on each viewing I have been more impressed by what I have seen. The movie combines a talented cast with each actor bringing their own unique character to the screen, humour that is intelligent and subtle in places, brilliant sets such as those used in the bowling alley, costumes and a soundtrack that brilliantly adds to the feel of film. Although 'The Big Lebowski' is nothing like the films of 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men', it contains many of the Coen Brothers usual plot devices and techniques that they used. The plot of the film is relatively straight forward, but is layered over with bizarre twists with nothing going as easy as planned. The film is focused around a millionaire whose wife is kidnapped for a $1,000,000 ransom with Jeffrey Lebowski hiring a 'bum' of the same name to act as a middle man in a deal to get here back. Immediately 'Dude' as he likes to be known suspects that the kidnapping is not as straightforward as outlined and that Lebowski's wife Bunny has kidnapped herself in order to get rich from a man who would not normally allow her such money, sound a bit like 'Fargo'? Unlike Fargo which can be seen as a 'dark comedy', The Big Lebowski is more a feel-good film that's style can probably be better compared to an earlier comedy of the Coen Brothers 'Raising Arizona', a film also which featured John Goodman (who also appeared in the Coen Brothers' film 'Barton Fink'). I feel that John Goodman's performance in this film is one worthy of a best supporting actor Oscar. Goodman portrays Walter; one of the Dude's bowling buddies that becomes involved in the Dude's task to transfer money between Lebowski and the kidnappers. Walter provides a lot of the film's humour and best scenes; he is an aggressive war veteran who makes constant references to his fighting at Vietnam and is constantly arguing with fellow bowling buddy Donny. Donny is portrayed by Steve Buscemi who is one of my favourite actors who seems to play a totally different character in every film he appears in. It seems strange that him and Goodman would go on to star together again in 'Monsters Inc.' but the two have great chemistry in this film, Donny is mocked throughout by Walter and the two provide some great scenes for us such as 'I am the walrus?'. John Turturro (who starred in 'Barton Fink' and later 'O Brother, Where Art Thou?') also features in a less prominent role as Jesus Quintana, a convicted paedophile that is set to face the Dude's bowling team in an upcoming tournament round. Although he doesn't have much time on screen, when he does he provides us with some of the films most enjoyable scenes, in fact this is the case for nearly all the scenes that are set in the bowling alley. Sam Elliott is also used effectively in his role as the mysterious narrator. There are other strong supporting performances such as those from Julianne Moore and Philip Seymour Hoffman but the star is undoubtedly Jeff Bridges as 'the Dude'. Jeff Bridges brings character and style to the leading character who is ultimately a bum that spends his life getting high and bowling with his friends. It's hard to imagine anybody else in such a role, the film acts an ode to the characters laid back, chilled lifestyle which makes the film so enjoyable. As it is with other Coen Brothers' films, the cinematography is superb and the duo have created a fantastic setting for a film. In 'Fargo' we saw the gritty and dark atmosphere reflected in the cold setting of North Dakota, in 'The Big Lebowski' the Coen Brothers' use Los Angeles as their location, at times the film can feel dark but at others we get light, as already said the bowling alley provides an excellent setting for many of the films' scenes. The Coen Brothers' also use a number of bizarre yet enjoyable dream sequences to give their film another dimension.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mistaken Identity of Dude.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cupcake_movie_goer
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this eccentric comedy/crime film by the Coen brothers, they created an outstanding movie. The actors/actress in the film was perfectly unified in a great way that audience could build a vision of the plot. If you can handle the graphic dialogue used and suggestive behavior this is the right movie for you. The theme of the film is Jeff "Dude"Lebowski (Jeff Bridges) discovers he is a victim of mistaken identity. Thugs were sent to his home by Jackie Treehorn (Ben Gazzara) to recover a debit; Big Lebowski's (The Millionaire) wife owes him. Before the thugs realize they have the wrong Lebowski and that he's the "Dude" they urinate of his rug; leaving Dude in disgust. Dude pays BigLebowski (David Huddleston) a visit to be compensated for his rug being destroyed. Big Lebowski filled with arrogance; felt he was there looking for a hand out. Dude felt the conversation wasn't getting anywhere and decided he would take a rug from Lebowski home to be even. When Bunny (Tara Reid) disappears (Lebowski's wife); Big Lebowski contacts Dude making him an offer to be the bagman. The only thing Dude has to do is deliver the ransom money for Bunny. Dude brings Walter (John Goodman) along to make the drop. When the drop goes to pieces it creates a ricochet of others trying to reclaim the ransom money. While home listening to the soothing sounds of the bowling pins being knocked down, he discovers 3 people standing over him. They knocked him out and he begins to hallucinate; the lighting becomes dark with bright lights in the sky as he floats in sky. During the hallucination Dude see the rug he confiscated from Big Lebowski's. He is woken once his bowling ball drops him back to the surface. After coming back to reality, Dude is greeted by a women flying through the air on a stripe line in the nude, Maude Lebowski (Julianne Moore). Dude and Maude forms a relationship. Dude without realizing has been sized up to be a sperm donor of her child. Dude experienced many encounters because he was trying to clear his identity. After having sex with Maude and enjoy a marijuana joint, at that moment Dude realized the reasoning behind the mistaken identity fiasco. In conclusion, as a motif in the film "Dude" was the main character's name; however, it was used as a common word of expression during dialogue. Dude was able to regain his identity and continued being the old lazy, laid back, unemployed, and bowler from Southern California.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Biggie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felipe_lorescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What makes this an outstanding comedy?!? The fact that you laugh louder the 4th time, the 5th time you watch it. It's not only a comedy of punch lines (when you enjoy it the 1st time, then the 2nd time it's not that funny, cause you already know the catch). It's the classical style of the movie's atmosphere that sets the adorable mood. What makes it a classic?!? The 11th time, the 12th time you watch it, you don't get bored. Perhaps you won't laugh out loud like you previously did, but it still gets you in that mood. In addition, this comedy is sprinkled with some serious social matters. Read between the lines, watch between the scenes...!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Big Lebowski, my hero-the slacker, crime mystery solver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyink01
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Lebowski film plot is centered on a Los Angeles dude, who is a real slacker, pot smoking, White Russian drinker, soon to be hero solving a crime mystery. He happens to have the same name as a millionaire; Jeffrey Lebowski played by David Huddleston, whose wife, Bunny Lebowski (Tara Reid) was kidnapped and owes money to a known pornographer. We are introduced to the Dude as he is shopping for milk and he opened the carton and sniffed it. The Dude wrote a check for 69 cents and returns home. It appears that he is unaware that someone is waiting on him and they attack him in the apartment. One of the hit men urinates on his rug. His prized possession that ties the apartment together, says the Dude. The Dude enlists his bowling buddies, whom we meet in regular league play. His main antagonist and best friend played by John Goodman, as Walter Sobchak. We soon learn that Walter is a practicing Jew who observes the Shabbos day of rest. Walter refuses to lift a finger on the day of rest, but manages to convince the Dude that he needs to find the millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski, and get his rug replaced. Walter drives the car on the Shabbos and says he is just doing it to help out. But turns out he is creating more trouble for the Dude. The millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski is in a wheelchair, but convinces the Dude he needs to deliver the ransom money alone so his kidnapped wife will return. The Dude becomes a crime fighting, urban cowboy. They go through the motions of delivering the money and in the meantime, they say "F it, let's go bowling" park the car in a handicapped zone with the ransom money in it, when they walk outside the car is gone. Panic ensues and Walter always says "Shut the F up, Donny" played by Steve Buscemi. Donny never really gets to say much in the film, but Walter always tells him the same thing. We get introduced to the millionaire's sister, Maude Lebowski portrayed by Julianne Moore. Maude was a nude artist who created her works of art while riding in ceiling harness. She believed the ransom money was kept by the Dude, but he proves to her that there was no money, and he was used by her brother as a scapegoat. The millionaire still has the money. The pornographer hires hit men, thugs to find the money. Once they determine there is no money, they punch the Dude in the face so hard, we see & hear fireworks, and then he is flying through the sky like Superman. Then he lands in the bowling alley. The Dude tackles all his problems inside the walls of the bowling alley. The punch perpetuates him there. Walter's character gets so out of hand he pulls a gun on another bowler because he wants to bowl on Shabbos. This is not going to happen, the police are called but they run right by the pair in the parking lot. They are not even the least bit frazzled about the police being there, we see them running into the alley with guns pulled. The music ties the scenes together in the movie. When the action elevates to a point where they can't handle it anymore, the say let's go bowling. Magically through sound they end up there bowling. Always confronted by larger than life egos and it becomes quite funny how much animosity and hate both lash at each other. One of the teams they are to play against, become real aggressive and say "No one messes with Jesus" (John Turturro) that is the bowler's name. We get a flashback which is so comical showing Jesus as a pedophile going door to door announcing to the neighborhood that he lives there. Music takes us from the bowling alley through that flashback. It is a funny movie showing that even slackers can be heroes. Maude found a purpose for the Dude, as she wanted him to be a sperm donor only, she wanted a child. She was beyond weird, but the Dude liked her style. At the conclusion of the film Donnie dies from shock of seeing the Dude's car on fire. He was not up for all the problems and confrontations that Walter and Dude went through. He was much more fragile than they imagined, best part is he didn't die alone. His best friends were there till the end. Many times over this movie had music transition the picture forward, the voices were covered by different rock songs, and special effects transferred everyone to the next scene. Just by mere suggestion. We were walking in the bowling alley at every problem. I loved how they glorified some of the bowling scenes, especially with the dude going underneath about 50 women down the approach looking up at their crotches. Sometimes even the Dude was embarrassed by what he wished would happen. He couldn't look up at the women he floated upside down the approach of the bowling alley, ashamed of his own thoughts or more like daydreams. The Dude became a crusader of crime, not you're likely candidate to solve a mystery. He did it with the help of Donnie and Walter, despite the constant arguing and bickering between the three. The arguing was the craziest thing that kept them going, for most it would drive them apart. I never imagined this would be a crime mystery movie that was so cleverly written that The Dude seems like someone from real life and not a character at all. He feels so real, that's what makes this movie so special. Anyone can be a hero; you just gotta believe in yourself, even if you're a slacker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true nonsensicomedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roselaar
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Outrageously zany, off-beat comedy the likes only the Coen Brothers can provide. Life is tough for the pot smoking all-round slacker Jeffrey Lebowski, more commonly referred to as "The Dude" (Jeff Bridges in one of the most defining roles of his career). Sharing his last name with a millionaire, he's victimized by thugs who mistake him for that rich man (who owes them a debt), a situation which finds his beloved rug in ruin after having been urinated upon by the perpetrators. When he visits his namesake to try and get him to pay for its cleaning, he soon gets more than he bargained for as he finds himself caught up in what appears to be a kidnap of the wealthy man's trophy wife, but swiftly explodes into a bizarre, inexplicable potpourri of events beyond anybody's control or understanding, thanks to the involvement of a host of wacky, maniacal and thoroughly enjoyable characters, ranging from feminist/nihilist artists and pornographers to White Russians and generally random folk annex narrators. Yet all The Dude asked for was a clean rug and an opportunity to win the local bowling alley's competition he trained so hard for with his two best buddies (John Goodman with severe anger management problems and Steve Buscemi who can't take a hint when he's asked to shut up). The Coens don't ask you to make sense of it all, they just want you to roll with it (pun intended), as The Dude does himself. Nevertheless, despite this absence of a clearly defined plot, or more likely because of it, The Big Lebowski proves all kinds of fun. The pair of directors used the same tactic a decade later with Burn After Reading to similar results, proving them the masters of this subgenre of 'nonsensicomedy' (for the record, I just made that term up and I hope it catches on). In both cases they were aided by an impressive cast of character actors and/or movie stars who felt like doing something different for a change, in The Big Lebowski's case including Philip Seymour Hoffman, John Turturro, Julianne Moore and Sam Elliott. Though the film was met with moderately tempered critical reviews and disappointing box office results back in 1998, time has proved the Coens right, as it has since become a widely accepted cult classic with serious tendencies towards an eventual, seemingly unavoidable shedding of the moniker 'cult'. When Burn After Reading came along in 2008, the majority of both audience and critics finally understood this type of film, and that movie did much, much better business accordingly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite a nice combination of comedy and crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has so many reviews that it doesn't need mine, so I won't review it. But since I write a blurb on each movie I see so that I can recollect it, I'll attempt to write 10 lines about this one. First off, it's a very satirical movie. I think it will be just as funny on a second viewing. There's too much swearing in the movie, you know, the f-word. After awhile, that became very tiring, and for me it impeded the comedy. I also thought that this was hard on the actors forced to insert this word so many times. They didn't sound 100% convincing at it after awhile. John Turturro's part is not that big, but he's very good in it. I didn't think Steve Buscemi had that many comic lines. It was really John Goodman's show. I liked his interactions with Jeff Bridges. Mr. Bridges remains a huge talent, as far as I can tell. David Huddleston is a very good actor. He was a tad over the top here. The film somehow made good use of Sam Elliott, who might be an underrated actor. Some of the other supporting actors didn't have that much to do in the way of comedy. In comedy you can say things you wouldn't ordinarily say seriously, and I felt that the Coens were taking the opportunity to poke fun at a lot of their favorite targets, but not in a peevish way. The film is above average. Maybe it's even an 8, but so many reviewers are raving so much about it excessively, as IMDb reviewers are wont to do, that I'm expressing less enthusiasm. See it, if you haven't already. You'll enjoy it, as long as you don't mind hearing a very great deal of the f-word. By the way, in Scarface with Pacino, the profanity seemed just right and worked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films, period - Dude!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barmstrong-782-631970
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Come on! This is the best film ever. i', even raising this above LOTR, since this is contemporary. I grew up living like the Dude. The Dude reminds me of my Uncle...not in a bad way, but with deep respect to living one's own life. The Coen brothers have created a film to be topped, if it was possible. Barton Fink was great..Fargo, yeah it was exceptional story-telling. But, the Dude - that was well-crafted cinema. The only other film that I have seen of theirs that captured me as much was No Country for Old Men. Can't wait for the next surprise!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG - Not Funny, Not Funny, Not Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NickyCee
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the heck did I tell you the Big Lebowski is not funny three times? Because this is once for every 20 people that told me this movie was the funniest most entertaining movie EVER. After years of being berated at parties and get-togethers with people spewing line after line from the movie, I gave in last week. I finally rented it. Wow. It's so bad on so many levels it's hard to describe. It's not funny - at - all. It's mildly amusing in parts but of the six people I watched it with, no one laughed once. Not once. I don't think it's a spoiler to tell you the language is sickeningly bad. Up there with Team America bad. There is one reason and one reason only that this movie is popular: College aged men (or guys who wish they were college aged) own the DVD and watch it repeatedly. Once memorizing the movie, on subsequent viewings they elbow each other before each "big" scene almost spilling their friend's beer and yelling, "HERE IT IS! HERE IT IS!" They then laugh at how clever they think they are. They're part of "The DUDE" club and they are very, very special indeed. This is the most unfunny movie I have ever seen. Other than Scarface and Team America, the movie containing the foulest most unnecessary language I've ever seen, and overall one of top five worst movies I've ever seen (and yes, this includes You Tube cat movies).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1998's The Big Lebowski Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of The Coen Brothers Direction And Screenplay, The Score, The Cinematography By Roger Deakins And Jeff Bridges Performance As Jeff Lebowski, My Mom Kelli Krajci Watched This Movie A Little On DVD That I Own That I Have In My DVD Collection, I Like To Laugh When I Watch Funny Movies On DVD, My Favorite Comedy Film Is 1933's Duck Soup With The Marx Brothers, 1988 Was 10 Years Old In 1998, 1982 Was 16 Years Old In 1998, 1953 Was 45 Years Old In 1998, This Movie Turned 10 Years In 2008, It Is Going To Turn 20 Years Old In 2018, Another Coen Brothers Film 1996's Fargo Is One Of My Favorite Films As Well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themadhouseyt
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funniest movie i've ever seen very good performances strong script very well directed deserved an Oscar. For me Jeff Bridges and John Goodman should have deserved an Oscar or at least a nomination, it's not that kind of comedy which is funny and at the half of the movie the jokes start to get annoying, the whole movie keeps you entertained, at least i didn't want the movie to end. The only thing that bothered me is that they haven't done a part 2, i want to know what is going to happen to "The Dude" and Walter i don't really care about other characters really (That doesn't mean that the other actors weren't good) I really would love if it lasted more. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Without a doubt, this is the funniest film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Coen Brothers are perhaps better known for their work in colder films such as 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men' but with 'The Big Lebowski' they manage to create a clever and highly enjoyable comedy. I've seen the film a number of times now and on each viewing I have been more impressed by what I have seen. The movie combines a talented cast with each actor bringing their own unique character to the screen, humour that is intelligent and subtle in places, brilliant sets such as those used in the bowling alley, costumes and a soundtrack that brilliantly adds to the feel of film. Although 'The Big Lebowski' is nothing like the films of 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men', it contains many of the Coen Brothers usual plot devices and techniques that they used. The plot of the film is relatively straight forward, but is layered over with bizarre twists with nothing going as easy as planned. The film is focused around a millionaire whose wife is kidnapped for a $1,000,000 ransom with Jeffrey Lebowski hiring a 'bum' of the same name to act as a middle man in a deal to get here back. Immediately 'Dude' as he likes to be known suspects that the kidnapping is not as straightforward as outlined and that Lebowski's wife Bunny has kidnapped herself in order to get rich from a man who would not normally allow her such money, sound a bit like 'Fargo'? Unlike Fargo which can be seen as a 'dark comedy', The Big Lebowski is more a feel-good film that's style can probably be better compared to an earlier comedy of the Coen Brothers 'Raising Arizona', a film also which featured John Goodman (who also appeared in the Coen Brothers' film 'Barton Fink'). I feel that John Goodman's performance in this film is one worthy of a best supporting actor Oscar. Goodman portrays Walter; one of the Dude's bowling buddies that becomes involved in the Dude's task to transfer money between Lebowski and the kidnappers. Walter provides a lot of the film's humour and best scenes; he is an aggressive war veteran who makes constant references to his fighting at Vietnam and is constantly arguing with fellow bowling buddy Donny. Donny is portrayed by Steve Buscemi who is one of my favourite actors who seems to play a totally different character in every film he appears in. It seems strange that him and Goodman would go on to star together again in 'Monsters Inc.' but the two have great chemistry in this film, Donny is mocked throughout by Walter and the two provide some great scenes for us such as 'I am the walrus?'. John Turturro (who starred in 'Barton Fink' and later 'O Brother, Where Art Thou?') also features in a less prominent role as Jesus Quintana, a convicted paedophile that is set to face the Dude's bowling team in an upcoming tournament round. Although he doesn't have much time on screen, when he does he provides us with some of the films most enjoyable scenes, in fact this is the case for nearly all the scenes that are set in the bowling alley. Sam Elliott is also used effectively in his role as the mysterious narrator. There are other strong supporting performances such as those from Julianne Moore and Philip Seymour Hoffman but the star is undoubtedly Jeff Bridges as 'the Dude'. Jeff Bridges brings character and style to the leading character who is ultimately a bum that spends his life getting high and bowling with his friends. It's hard to imagine anybody else in such a role, the film acts an ode to the characters laid back, chilled lifestyle which makes the film so enjoyable. As it is with other Coen Brothers' films, the cinematography is superb and the duo have created a fantastic setting for a film. In 'Fargo' we saw the gritty and dark atmosphere reflected in the cold setting of North Dakota, in 'The Big Lebowski' the Coen Brothers' use Los Angeles as their location, at times the film can feel dark but at others we get light, as already said the bowling alley provides an excellent setting for many of the films' scenes. The Coen Brothers' also use a number of bizarre yet enjoyable dream sequences to give their film another dimension.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mistaken Identity of Dude.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cupcake_movie_goer
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this eccentric comedy/crime film by the Coen brothers, they created an outstanding movie. The actors/actress in the film was perfectly unified in a great way that audience could build a vision of the plot. If you can handle the graphic dialogue used and suggestive behavior this is the right movie for you. The theme of the film is Jeff "Dude"Lebowski (Jeff Bridges) discovers he is a victim of mistaken identity. Thugs were sent to his home by Jackie Treehorn (Ben Gazzara) to recover a debit; Big Lebowski's (The Millionaire) wife owes him. Before the thugs realize they have the wrong Lebowski and that he's the "Dude" they urinate of his rug; leaving Dude in disgust. Dude pays BigLebowski (David Huddleston) a visit to be compensated for his rug being destroyed. Big Lebowski filled with arrogance; felt he was there looking for a hand out. Dude felt the conversation wasn't getting anywhere and decided he would take a rug from Lebowski home to be even. When Bunny (Tara Reid) disappears (Lebowski's wife); Big Lebowski contacts Dude making him an offer to be the bagman. The only thing Dude has to do is deliver the ransom money for Bunny. Dude brings Walter (John Goodman) along to make the drop. When the drop goes to pieces it creates a ricochet of others trying to reclaim the ransom money. While home listening to the soothing sounds of the bowling pins being knocked down, he discovers 3 people standing over him. They knocked him out and he begins to hallucinate; the lighting becomes dark with bright lights in the sky as he floats in sky. During the hallucination Dude see the rug he confiscated from Big Lebowski's. He is woken once his bowling ball drops him back to the surface. After coming back to reality, Dude is greeted by a women flying through the air on a stripe line in the nude, Maude Lebowski (Julianne Moore). Dude and Maude forms a relationship. Dude without realizing has been sized up to be a sperm donor of her child. Dude experienced many encounters because he was trying to clear his identity. After having sex with Maude and enjoy a marijuana joint, at that moment Dude realized the reasoning behind the mistaken identity fiasco. In conclusion, as a motif in the film "Dude" was the main character's name; however, it was used as a common word of expression during dialogue. Dude was able to regain his identity and continued being the old lazy, laid back, unemployed, and bowler from Southern California.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Biggie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felipe_lorescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What makes this an outstanding comedy?!? The fact that you laugh louder the 4th time, the 5th time you watch it. It's not only a comedy of punch lines (when you enjoy it the 1st time, then the 2nd time it's not that funny, cause you already know the catch). It's the classical style of the movie's atmosphere that sets the adorable mood. What makes it a classic?!? The 11th time, the 12th time you watch it, you don't get bored. Perhaps you won't laugh out loud like you previously did, but it still gets you in that mood. In addition, this comedy is sprinkled with some serious social matters. Read between the lines, watch between the scenes...!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Big Lebowski, my hero-the slacker, crime mystery solver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyink01
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Lebowski film plot is centered on a Los Angeles dude, who is a real slacker, pot smoking, White Russian drinker, soon to be hero solving a crime mystery. He happens to have the same name as a millionaire; Jeffrey Lebowski played by David Huddleston, whose wife, Bunny Lebowski (Tara Reid) was kidnapped and owes money to a known pornographer. We are introduced to the Dude as he is shopping for milk and he opened the carton and sniffed it. The Dude wrote a check for 69 cents and returns home. It appears that he is unaware that someone is waiting on him and they attack him in the apartment. One of the hit men urinates on his rug. His prized possession that ties the apartment together, says the Dude. The Dude enlists his bowling buddies, whom we meet in regular league play. His main antagonist and best friend played by John Goodman, as Walter Sobchak. We soon learn that Walter is a practicing Jew who observes the Shabbos day of rest. Walter refuses to lift a finger on the day of rest, but manages to convince the Dude that he needs to find the millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski, and get his rug replaced. Walter drives the car on the Shabbos and says he is just doing it to help out. But turns out he is creating more trouble for the Dude. The millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski is in a wheelchair, but convinces the Dude he needs to deliver the ransom money alone so his kidnapped wife will return. The Dude becomes a crime fighting, urban cowboy. They go through the motions of delivering the money and in the meantime, they say "F it, let's go bowling" park the car in a handicapped zone with the ransom money in it, when they walk outside the car is gone. Panic ensues and Walter always says "Shut the F up, Donny" played by Steve Buscemi. Donny never really gets to say much in the film, but Walter always tells him the same thing. We get introduced to the millionaire's sister, Maude Lebowski portrayed by Julianne Moore. Maude was a nude artist who created her works of art while riding in ceiling harness. She believed the ransom money was kept by the Dude, but he proves to her that there was no money, and he was used by her brother as a scapegoat. The millionaire still has the money. The pornographer hires hit men, thugs to find the money. Once they determine there is no money, they punch the Dude in the face so hard, we see & hear fireworks, and then he is flying through the sky like Superman. Then he lands in the bowling alley. The Dude tackles all his problems inside the walls of the bowling alley. The punch perpetuates him there. Walter's character gets so out of hand he pulls a gun on another bowler because he wants to bowl on Shabbos. This is not going to happen, the police are called but they run right by the pair in the parking lot. They are not even the least bit frazzled about the police being there, we see them running into the alley with guns pulled. The music ties the scenes together in the movie. When the action elevates to a point where they can't handle it anymore, the say let's go bowling. Magically through sound they end up there bowling. Always confronted by larger than life egos and it becomes quite funny how much animosity and hate both lash at each other. One of the teams they are to play against, become real aggressive and say "No one messes with Jesus" (John Turturro) that is the bowler's name. We get a flashback which is so comical showing Jesus as a pedophile going door to door announcing to the neighborhood that he lives there. Music takes us from the bowling alley through that flashback. It is a funny movie showing that even slackers can be heroes. Maude found a purpose for the Dude, as she wanted him to be a sperm donor only, she wanted a child. She was beyond weird, but the Dude liked her style. At the conclusion of the film Donnie dies from shock of seeing the Dude's car on fire. He was not up for all the problems and confrontations that Walter and Dude went through. He was much more fragile than they imagined, best part is he didn't die alone. His best friends were there till the end. Many times over this movie had music transition the picture forward, the voices were covered by different rock songs, and special effects transferred everyone to the next scene. Just by mere suggestion. We were walking in the bowling alley at every problem. I loved how they glorified some of the bowling scenes, especially with the dude going underneath about 50 women down the approach looking up at their crotches. Sometimes even the Dude was embarrassed by what he wished would happen. He couldn't look up at the women he floated upside down the approach of the bowling alley, ashamed of his own thoughts or more like daydreams. The Dude became a crusader of crime, not you're likely candidate to solve a mystery. He did it with the help of Donnie and Walter, despite the constant arguing and bickering between the three. The arguing was the craziest thing that kept them going, for most it would drive them apart. I never imagined this would be a crime mystery movie that was so cleverly written that The Dude seems like someone from real life and not a character at all. He feels so real, that's what makes this movie so special. Anyone can be a hero; you just gotta believe in yourself, even if you're a slacker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true nonsensicomedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roselaar
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Outrageously zany, off-beat comedy the likes only the Coen Brothers can provide. Life is tough for the pot smoking all-round slacker Jeffrey Lebowski, more commonly referred to as "The Dude" (Jeff Bridges in one of the most defining roles of his career). Sharing his last name with a millionaire, he's victimized by thugs who mistake him for that rich man (who owes them a debt), a situation which finds his beloved rug in ruin after having been urinated upon by the perpetrators. When he visits his namesake to try and get him to pay for its cleaning, he soon gets more than he bargained for as he finds himself caught up in what appears to be a kidnap of the wealthy man's trophy wife, but swiftly explodes into a bizarre, inexplicable potpourri of events beyond anybody's control or understanding, thanks to the involvement of a host of wacky, maniacal and thoroughly enjoyable characters, ranging from feminist/nihilist artists and pornographers to White Russians and generally random folk annex narrators. Yet all The Dude asked for was a clean rug and an opportunity to win the local bowling alley's competition he trained so hard for with his two best buddies (John Goodman with severe anger management problems and Steve Buscemi who can't take a hint when he's asked to shut up). The Coens don't ask you to make sense of it all, they just want you to roll with it (pun intended), as The Dude does himself. Nevertheless, despite this absence of a clearly defined plot, or more likely because of it, The Big Lebowski proves all kinds of fun. The pair of directors used the same tactic a decade later with Burn After Reading to similar results, proving them the masters of this subgenre of 'nonsensicomedy' (for the record, I just made that term up and I hope it catches on). In both cases they were aided by an impressive cast of character actors and/or movie stars who felt like doing something different for a change, in The Big Lebowski's case including Philip Seymour Hoffman, John Turturro, Julianne Moore and Sam Elliott. Though the film was met with moderately tempered critical reviews and disappointing box office results back in 1998, time has proved the Coens right, as it has since become a widely accepted cult classic with serious tendencies towards an eventual, seemingly unavoidable shedding of the moniker 'cult'. When Burn After Reading came along in 2008, the majority of both audience and critics finally understood this type of film, and that movie did much, much better business accordingly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite a nice combination of comedy and crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has so many reviews that it doesn't need mine, so I won't review it. But since I write a blurb on each movie I see so that I can recollect it, I'll attempt to write 10 lines about this one. First off, it's a very satirical movie. I think it will be just as funny on a second viewing. There's too much swearing in the movie, you know, the f-word. After awhile, that became very tiring, and for me it impeded the comedy. I also thought that this was hard on the actors forced to insert this word so many times. They didn't sound 100% convincing at it after awhile. John Turturro's part is not that big, but he's very good in it. I didn't think Steve Buscemi had that many comic lines. It was really John Goodman's show. I liked his interactions with Jeff Bridges. Mr. Bridges remains a huge talent, as far as I can tell. David Huddleston is a very good actor. He was a tad over the top here. The film somehow made good use of Sam Elliott, who might be an underrated actor. Some of the other supporting actors didn't have that much to do in the way of comedy. In comedy you can say things you wouldn't ordinarily say seriously, and I felt that the Coens were taking the opportunity to poke fun at a lot of their favorite targets, but not in a peevish way. The film is above average. Maybe it's even an 8, but so many reviewers are raving so much about it excessively, as IMDb reviewers are wont to do, that I'm expressing less enthusiasm. See it, if you haven't already. You'll enjoy it, as long as you don't mind hearing a very great deal of the f-word. By the way, in Scarface with Pacino, the profanity seemed just right and worked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films, period - Dude!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barmstrong-782-631970
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Come on! This is the best film ever. i', even raising this above LOTR, since this is contemporary. I grew up living like the Dude. The Dude reminds me of my Uncle...not in a bad way, but with deep respect to living one's own life. The Coen brothers have created a film to be topped, if it was possible. Barton Fink was great..Fargo, yeah it was exceptional story-telling. But, the Dude - that was well-crafted cinema. The only other film that I have seen of theirs that captured me as much was No Country for Old Men. Can't wait for the next surprise!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG - Not Funny, Not Funny, Not Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NickyCee
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the heck did I tell you the Big Lebowski is not funny three times? Because this is once for every 20 people that told me this movie was the funniest most entertaining movie EVER. After years of being berated at parties and get-togethers with people spewing line after line from the movie, I gave in last week. I finally rented it. Wow. It's so bad on so many levels it's hard to describe. It's not funny - at - all. It's mildly amusing in parts but of the six people I watched it with, no one laughed once. Not once. I don't think it's a spoiler to tell you the language is sickeningly bad. Up there with Team America bad. There is one reason and one reason only that this movie is popular: College aged men (or guys who wish they were college aged) own the DVD and watch it repeatedly. Once memorizing the movie, on subsequent viewings they elbow each other before each "big" scene almost spilling their friend's beer and yelling, "HERE IT IS! HERE IT IS!" They then laugh at how clever they think they are. They're part of "The DUDE" club and they are very, very special indeed. This is the most unfunny movie I have ever seen. Other than Scarface and Team America, the movie containing the foulest most unnecessary language I've ever seen, and overall one of top five worst movies I've ever seen (and yes, this includes You Tube cat movies).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1998's The Big Lebowski Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of The Coen Brothers Direction And Screenplay, The Score, The Cinematography By Roger Deakins And Jeff Bridges Performance As Jeff Lebowski, My Mom Kelli Krajci Watched This Movie A Little On DVD That I Own That I Have In My DVD Collection, I Like To Laugh When I Watch Funny Movies On DVD, My Favorite Comedy Film Is 1933's Duck Soup With The Marx Brothers, 1988 Was 10 Years Old In 1998, 1982 Was 16 Years Old In 1998, 1953 Was 45 Years Old In 1998, This Movie Turned 10 Years In 2008, It Is Going To Turn 20 Years Old In 2018, Another Coen Brothers Film 1996's Fargo Is One Of My Favorite Films As Well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themadhouseyt
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funniest movie i've ever seen very good performances strong script very well directed deserved an Oscar. For me Jeff Bridges and John Goodman should have deserved an Oscar or at least a nomination, it's not that kind of comedy which is funny and at the half of the movie the jokes start to get annoying, the whole movie keeps you entertained, at least i didn't want the movie to end. The only thing that bothered me is that they haven't done a part 2, i want to know what is going to happen to "The Dude" and Walter i don't really care about other characters really (That doesn't mean that the other actors weren't good) I really would love if it lasted more. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Without a doubt, this is the funniest film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Coen Brothers are perhaps better known for their work in colder films such as 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men' but with 'The Big Lebowski' they manage to create a clever and highly enjoyable comedy. I've seen the film a number of times now and on each viewing I have been more impressed by what I have seen. The movie combines a talented cast with each actor bringing their own unique character to the screen, humour that is intelligent and subtle in places, brilliant sets such as those used in the bowling alley, costumes and a soundtrack that brilliantly adds to the feel of film. Although 'The Big Lebowski' is nothing like the films of 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men', it contains many of the Coen Brothers usual plot devices and techniques that they used. The plot of the film is relatively straight forward, but is layered over with bizarre twists with nothing going as easy as planned. The film is focused around a millionaire whose wife is kidnapped for a $1,000,000 ransom with Jeffrey Lebowski hiring a 'bum' of the same name to act as a middle man in a deal to get here back. Immediately 'Dude' as he likes to be known suspects that the kidnapping is not as straightforward as outlined and that Lebowski's wife Bunny has kidnapped herself in order to get rich from a man who would not normally allow her such money, sound a bit like 'Fargo'? Unlike Fargo which can be seen as a 'dark comedy', The Big Lebowski is more a feel-good film that's style can probably be better compared to an earlier comedy of the Coen Brothers 'Raising Arizona', a film also which featured John Goodman (who also appeared in the Coen Brothers' film 'Barton Fink'). I feel that John Goodman's performance in this film is one worthy of a best supporting actor Oscar. Goodman portrays Walter; one of the Dude's bowling buddies that becomes involved in the Dude's task to transfer money between Lebowski and the kidnappers. Walter provides a lot of the film's humour and best scenes; he is an aggressive war veteran who makes constant references to his fighting at Vietnam and is constantly arguing with fellow bowling buddy Donny. Donny is portrayed by Steve Buscemi who is one of my favourite actors who seems to play a totally different character in every film he appears in. It seems strange that him and Goodman would go on to star together again in 'Monsters Inc.' but the two have great chemistry in this film, Donny is mocked throughout by Walter and the two provide some great scenes for us such as 'I am the walrus?'. John Turturro (who starred in 'Barton Fink' and later 'O Brother, Where Art Thou?') also features in a less prominent role as Jesus Quintana, a convicted paedophile that is set to face the Dude's bowling team in an upcoming tournament round. Although he doesn't have much time on screen, when he does he provides us with some of the films most enjoyable scenes, in fact this is the case for nearly all the scenes that are set in the bowling alley. Sam Elliott is also used effectively in his role as the mysterious narrator. There are other strong supporting performances such as those from Julianne Moore and Philip Seymour Hoffman but the star is undoubtedly Jeff Bridges as 'the Dude'. Jeff Bridges brings character and style to the leading character who is ultimately a bum that spends his life getting high and bowling with his friends. It's hard to imagine anybody else in such a role, the film acts an ode to the characters laid back, chilled lifestyle which makes the film so enjoyable. As it is with other Coen Brothers' films, the cinematography is superb and the duo have created a fantastic setting for a film. In 'Fargo' we saw the gritty and dark atmosphere reflected in the cold setting of North Dakota, in 'The Big Lebowski' the Coen Brothers' use Los Angeles as their location, at times the film can feel dark but at others we get light, as already said the bowling alley provides an excellent setting for many of the films' scenes. The Coen Brothers' also use a number of bizarre yet enjoyable dream sequences to give their film another dimension.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mistaken Identity of Dude.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cupcake_movie_goer
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this eccentric comedy/crime film by the Coen brothers, they created an outstanding movie. The actors/actress in the film was perfectly unified in a great way that audience could build a vision of the plot. If you can handle the graphic dialogue used and suggestive behavior this is the right movie for you. The theme of the film is Jeff "Dude"Lebowski (Jeff Bridges) discovers he is a victim of mistaken identity. Thugs were sent to his home by Jackie Treehorn (Ben Gazzara) to recover a debit; Big Lebowski's (The Millionaire) wife owes him. Before the thugs realize they have the wrong Lebowski and that he's the "Dude" they urinate of his rug; leaving Dude in disgust. Dude pays BigLebowski (David Huddleston) a visit to be compensated for his rug being destroyed. Big Lebowski filled with arrogance; felt he was there looking for a hand out. Dude felt the conversation wasn't getting anywhere and decided he would take a rug from Lebowski home to be even. When Bunny (Tara Reid) disappears (Lebowski's wife); Big Lebowski contacts Dude making him an offer to be the bagman. The only thing Dude has to do is deliver the ransom money for Bunny. Dude brings Walter (John Goodman) along to make the drop. When the drop goes to pieces it creates a ricochet of others trying to reclaim the ransom money. While home listening to the soothing sounds of the bowling pins being knocked down, he discovers 3 people standing over him. They knocked him out and he begins to hallucinate; the lighting becomes dark with bright lights in the sky as he floats in sky. During the hallucination Dude see the rug he confiscated from Big Lebowski's. He is woken once his bowling ball drops him back to the surface. After coming back to reality, Dude is greeted by a women flying through the air on a stripe line in the nude, Maude Lebowski (Julianne Moore). Dude and Maude forms a relationship. Dude without realizing has been sized up to be a sperm donor of her child. Dude experienced many encounters because he was trying to clear his identity. After having sex with Maude and enjoy a marijuana joint, at that moment Dude realized the reasoning behind the mistaken identity fiasco. In conclusion, as a motif in the film "Dude" was the main character's name; however, it was used as a common word of expression during dialogue. Dude was able to regain his identity and continued being the old lazy, laid back, unemployed, and bowler from Southern California.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Biggie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felipe_lorescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What makes this an outstanding comedy?!? The fact that you laugh louder the 4th time, the 5th time you watch it. It's not only a comedy of punch lines (when you enjoy it the 1st time, then the 2nd time it's not that funny, cause you already know the catch). It's the classical style of the movie's atmosphere that sets the adorable mood. What makes it a classic?!? The 11th time, the 12th time you watch it, you don't get bored. Perhaps you won't laugh out loud like you previously did, but it still gets you in that mood. In addition, this comedy is sprinkled with some serious social matters. Read between the lines, watch between the scenes...!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Big Lebowski, my hero-the slacker, crime mystery solver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyink01
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Lebowski film plot is centered on a Los Angeles dude, who is a real slacker, pot smoking, White Russian drinker, soon to be hero solving a crime mystery. He happens to have the same name as a millionaire; Jeffrey Lebowski played by David Huddleston, whose wife, Bunny Lebowski (Tara Reid) was kidnapped and owes money to a known pornographer. We are introduced to the Dude as he is shopping for milk and he opened the carton and sniffed it. The Dude wrote a check for 69 cents and returns home. It appears that he is unaware that someone is waiting on him and they attack him in the apartment. One of the hit men urinates on his rug. His prized possession that ties the apartment together, says the Dude. The Dude enlists his bowling buddies, whom we meet in regular league play. His main antagonist and best friend played by John Goodman, as Walter Sobchak. We soon learn that Walter is a practicing Jew who observes the Shabbos day of rest. Walter refuses to lift a finger on the day of rest, but manages to convince the Dude that he needs to find the millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski, and get his rug replaced. Walter drives the car on the Shabbos and says he is just doing it to help out. But turns out he is creating more trouble for the Dude. The millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski is in a wheelchair, but convinces the Dude he needs to deliver the ransom money alone so his kidnapped wife will return. The Dude becomes a crime fighting, urban cowboy. They go through the motions of delivering the money and in the meantime, they say "F it, let's go bowling" park the car in a handicapped zone with the ransom money in it, when they walk outside the car is gone. Panic ensues and Walter always says "Shut the F up, Donny" played by Steve Buscemi. Donny never really gets to say much in the film, but Walter always tells him the same thing. We get introduced to the millionaire's sister, Maude Lebowski portrayed by Julianne Moore. Maude was a nude artist who created her works of art while riding in ceiling harness. She believed the ransom money was kept by the Dude, but he proves to her that there was no money, and he was used by her brother as a scapegoat. The millionaire still has the money. The pornographer hires hit men, thugs to find the money. Once they determine there is no money, they punch the Dude in the face so hard, we see & hear fireworks, and then he is flying through the sky like Superman. Then he lands in the bowling alley. The Dude tackles all his problems inside the walls of the bowling alley. The punch perpetuates him there. Walter's character gets so out of hand he pulls a gun on another bowler because he wants to bowl on Shabbos. This is not going to happen, the police are called but they run right by the pair in the parking lot. They are not even the least bit frazzled about the police being there, we see them running into the alley with guns pulled. The music ties the scenes together in the movie. When the action elevates to a point where they can't handle it anymore, the say let's go bowling. Magically through sound they end up there bowling. Always confronted by larger than life egos and it becomes quite funny how much animosity and hate both lash at each other. One of the teams they are to play against, become real aggressive and say "No one messes with Jesus" (John Turturro) that is the bowler's name. We get a flashback which is so comical showing Jesus as a pedophile going door to door announcing to the neighborhood that he lives there. Music takes us from the bowling alley through that flashback. It is a funny movie showing that even slackers can be heroes. Maude found a purpose for the Dude, as she wanted him to be a sperm donor only, she wanted a child. She was beyond weird, but the Dude liked her style. At the conclusion of the film Donnie dies from shock of seeing the Dude's car on fire. He was not up for all the problems and confrontations that Walter and Dude went through. He was much more fragile than they imagined, best part is he didn't die alone. His best friends were there till the end. Many times over this movie had music transition the picture forward, the voices were covered by different rock songs, and special effects transferred everyone to the next scene. Just by mere suggestion. We were walking in the bowling alley at every problem. I loved how they glorified some of the bowling scenes, especially with the dude going underneath about 50 women down the approach looking up at their crotches. Sometimes even the Dude was embarrassed by what he wished would happen. He couldn't look up at the women he floated upside down the approach of the bowling alley, ashamed of his own thoughts or more like daydreams. The Dude became a crusader of crime, not you're likely candidate to solve a mystery. He did it with the help of Donnie and Walter, despite the constant arguing and bickering between the three. The arguing was the craziest thing that kept them going, for most it would drive them apart. I never imagined this would be a crime mystery movie that was so cleverly written that The Dude seems like someone from real life and not a character at all. He feels so real, that's what makes this movie so special. Anyone can be a hero; you just gotta believe in yourself, even if you're a slacker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true nonsensicomedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roselaar
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Outrageously zany, off-beat comedy the likes only the Coen Brothers can provide. Life is tough for the pot smoking all-round slacker Jeffrey Lebowski, more commonly referred to as "The Dude" (Jeff Bridges in one of the most defining roles of his career). Sharing his last name with a millionaire, he's victimized by thugs who mistake him for that rich man (who owes them a debt), a situation which finds his beloved rug in ruin after having been urinated upon by the perpetrators. When he visits his namesake to try and get him to pay for its cleaning, he soon gets more than he bargained for as he finds himself caught up in what appears to be a kidnap of the wealthy man's trophy wife, but swiftly explodes into a bizarre, inexplicable potpourri of events beyond anybody's control or understanding, thanks to the involvement of a host of wacky, maniacal and thoroughly enjoyable characters, ranging from feminist/nihilist artists and pornographers to White Russians and generally random folk annex narrators. Yet all The Dude asked for was a clean rug and an opportunity to win the local bowling alley's competition he trained so hard for with his two best buddies (John Goodman with severe anger management problems and Steve Buscemi who can't take a hint when he's asked to shut up). The Coens don't ask you to make sense of it all, they just want you to roll with it (pun intended), as The Dude does himself. Nevertheless, despite this absence of a clearly defined plot, or more likely because of it, The Big Lebowski proves all kinds of fun. The pair of directors used the same tactic a decade later with Burn After Reading to similar results, proving them the masters of this subgenre of 'nonsensicomedy' (for the record, I just made that term up and I hope it catches on). In both cases they were aided by an impressive cast of character actors and/or movie stars who felt like doing something different for a change, in The Big Lebowski's case including Philip Seymour Hoffman, John Turturro, Julianne Moore and Sam Elliott. Though the film was met with moderately tempered critical reviews and disappointing box office results back in 1998, time has proved the Coens right, as it has since become a widely accepted cult classic with serious tendencies towards an eventual, seemingly unavoidable shedding of the moniker 'cult'. When Burn After Reading came along in 2008, the majority of both audience and critics finally understood this type of film, and that movie did much, much better business accordingly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite a nice combination of comedy and crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has so many reviews that it doesn't need mine, so I won't review it. But since I write a blurb on each movie I see so that I can recollect it, I'll attempt to write 10 lines about this one. First off, it's a very satirical movie. I think it will be just as funny on a second viewing. There's too much swearing in the movie, you know, the f-word. After awhile, that became very tiring, and for me it impeded the comedy. I also thought that this was hard on the actors forced to insert this word so many times. They didn't sound 100% convincing at it after awhile. John Turturro's part is not that big, but he's very good in it. I didn't think Steve Buscemi had that many comic lines. It was really John Goodman's show. I liked his interactions with Jeff Bridges. Mr. Bridges remains a huge talent, as far as I can tell. David Huddleston is a very good actor. He was a tad over the top here. The film somehow made good use of Sam Elliott, who might be an underrated actor. Some of the other supporting actors didn't have that much to do in the way of comedy. In comedy you can say things you wouldn't ordinarily say seriously, and I felt that the Coens were taking the opportunity to poke fun at a lot of their favorite targets, but not in a peevish way. The film is above average. Maybe it's even an 8, but so many reviewers are raving so much about it excessively, as IMDb reviewers are wont to do, that I'm expressing less enthusiasm. See it, if you haven't already. You'll enjoy it, as long as you don't mind hearing a very great deal of the f-word. By the way, in Scarface with Pacino, the profanity seemed just right and worked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films, period - Dude!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barmstrong-782-631970
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Come on! This is the best film ever. i', even raising this above LOTR, since this is contemporary. I grew up living like the Dude. The Dude reminds me of my Uncle...not in a bad way, but with deep respect to living one's own life. The Coen brothers have created a film to be topped, if it was possible. Barton Fink was great..Fargo, yeah it was exceptional story-telling. But, the Dude - that was well-crafted cinema. The only other film that I have seen of theirs that captured me as much was No Country for Old Men. Can't wait for the next surprise!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG - Not Funny, Not Funny, Not Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NickyCee
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the heck did I tell you the Big Lebowski is not funny three times? Because this is once for every 20 people that told me this movie was the funniest most entertaining movie EVER. After years of being berated at parties and get-togethers with people spewing line after line from the movie, I gave in last week. I finally rented it. Wow. It's so bad on so many levels it's hard to describe. It's not funny - at - all. It's mildly amusing in parts but of the six people I watched it with, no one laughed once. Not once. I don't think it's a spoiler to tell you the language is sickeningly bad. Up there with Team America bad. There is one reason and one reason only that this movie is popular: College aged men (or guys who wish they were college aged) own the DVD and watch it repeatedly. Once memorizing the movie, on subsequent viewings they elbow each other before each "big" scene almost spilling their friend's beer and yelling, "HERE IT IS! HERE IT IS!" They then laugh at how clever they think they are. They're part of "The DUDE" club and they are very, very special indeed. This is the most unfunny movie I have ever seen. Other than Scarface and Team America, the movie containing the foulest most unnecessary language I've ever seen, and overall one of top five worst movies I've ever seen (and yes, this includes You Tube cat movies).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1998's The Big Lebowski Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of The Coen Brothers Direction And Screenplay, The Score, The Cinematography By Roger Deakins And Jeff Bridges Performance As Jeff Lebowski, My Mom Kelli Krajci Watched This Movie A Little On DVD That I Own That I Have In My DVD Collection, I Like To Laugh When I Watch Funny Movies On DVD, My Favorite Comedy Film Is 1933's Duck Soup With The Marx Brothers, 1988 Was 10 Years Old In 1998, 1982 Was 16 Years Old In 1998, 1953 Was 45 Years Old In 1998, This Movie Turned 10 Years In 2008, It Is Going To Turn 20 Years Old In 2018, Another Coen Brothers Film 1996's Fargo Is One Of My Favorite Films As Well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themadhouseyt
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funniest movie i've ever seen very good performances strong script very well directed deserved an Oscar. For me Jeff Bridges and John Goodman should have deserved an Oscar or at least a nomination, it's not that kind of comedy which is funny and at the half of the movie the jokes start to get annoying, the whole movie keeps you entertained, at least i didn't want the movie to end. The only thing that bothered me is that they haven't done a part 2, i want to know what is going to happen to "The Dude" and Walter i don't really care about other characters really (That doesn't mean that the other actors weren't good) I really would love if it lasted more. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Without a doubt, this is the funniest film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Coen Brothers are perhaps better known for their work in colder films such as 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men' but with 'The Big Lebowski' they manage to create a clever and highly enjoyable comedy. I've seen the film a number of times now and on each viewing I have been more impressed by what I have seen. The movie combines a talented cast with each actor bringing their own unique character to the screen, humour that is intelligent and subtle in places, brilliant sets such as those used in the bowling alley, costumes and a soundtrack that brilliantly adds to the feel of film. Although 'The Big Lebowski' is nothing like the films of 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men', it contains many of the Coen Brothers usual plot devices and techniques that they used. The plot of the film is relatively straight forward, but is layered over with bizarre twists with nothing going as easy as planned. The film is focused around a millionaire whose wife is kidnapped for a $1,000,000 ransom with Jeffrey Lebowski hiring a 'bum' of the same name to act as a middle man in a deal to get here back. Immediately 'Dude' as he likes to be known suspects that the kidnapping is not as straightforward as outlined and that Lebowski's wife Bunny has kidnapped herself in order to get rich from a man who would not normally allow her such money, sound a bit like 'Fargo'? Unlike Fargo which can be seen as a 'dark comedy', The Big Lebowski is more a feel-good film that's style can probably be better compared to an earlier comedy of the Coen Brothers 'Raising Arizona', a film also which featured John Goodman (who also appeared in the Coen Brothers' film 'Barton Fink'). I feel that John Goodman's performance in this film is one worthy of a best supporting actor Oscar. Goodman portrays Walter; one of the Dude's bowling buddies that becomes involved in the Dude's task to transfer money between Lebowski and the kidnappers. Walter provides a lot of the film's humour and best scenes; he is an aggressive war veteran who makes constant references to his fighting at Vietnam and is constantly arguing with fellow bowling buddy Donny. Donny is portrayed by Steve Buscemi who is one of my favourite actors who seems to play a totally different character in every film he appears in. It seems strange that him and Goodman would go on to star together again in 'Monsters Inc.' but the two have great chemistry in this film, Donny is mocked throughout by Walter and the two provide some great scenes for us such as 'I am the walrus?'. John Turturro (who starred in 'Barton Fink' and later 'O Brother, Where Art Thou?') also features in a less prominent role as Jesus Quintana, a convicted paedophile that is set to face the Dude's bowling team in an upcoming tournament round. Although he doesn't have much time on screen, when he does he provides us with some of the films most enjoyable scenes, in fact this is the case for nearly all the scenes that are set in the bowling alley. Sam Elliott is also used effectively in his role as the mysterious narrator. There are other strong supporting performances such as those from Julianne Moore and Philip Seymour Hoffman but the star is undoubtedly Jeff Bridges as 'the Dude'. Jeff Bridges brings character and style to the leading character who is ultimately a bum that spends his life getting high and bowling with his friends. It's hard to imagine anybody else in such a role, the film acts an ode to the characters laid back, chilled lifestyle which makes the film so enjoyable. As it is with other Coen Brothers' films, the cinematography is superb and the duo have created a fantastic setting for a film. In 'Fargo' we saw the gritty and dark atmosphere reflected in the cold setting of North Dakota, in 'The Big Lebowski' the Coen Brothers' use Los Angeles as their location, at times the film can feel dark but at others we get light, as already said the bowling alley provides an excellent setting for many of the films' scenes. The Coen Brothers' also use a number of bizarre yet enjoyable dream sequences to give their film another dimension.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mistaken Identity of Dude.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cupcake_movie_goer
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this eccentric comedy/crime film by the Coen brothers, they created an outstanding movie. The actors/actress in the film was perfectly unified in a great way that audience could build a vision of the plot. If you can handle the graphic dialogue used and suggestive behavior this is the right movie for you. The theme of the film is Jeff "Dude"Lebowski (Jeff Bridges) discovers he is a victim of mistaken identity. Thugs were sent to his home by Jackie Treehorn (Ben Gazzara) to recover a debit; Big Lebowski's (The Millionaire) wife owes him. Before the thugs realize they have the wrong Lebowski and that he's the "Dude" they urinate of his rug; leaving Dude in disgust. Dude pays BigLebowski (David Huddleston) a visit to be compensated for his rug being destroyed. Big Lebowski filled with arrogance; felt he was there looking for a hand out. Dude felt the conversation wasn't getting anywhere and decided he would take a rug from Lebowski home to be even. When Bunny (Tara Reid) disappears (Lebowski's wife); Big Lebowski contacts Dude making him an offer to be the bagman. The only thing Dude has to do is deliver the ransom money for Bunny. Dude brings Walter (John Goodman) along to make the drop. When the drop goes to pieces it creates a ricochet of others trying to reclaim the ransom money. While home listening to the soothing sounds of the bowling pins being knocked down, he discovers 3 people standing over him. They knocked him out and he begins to hallucinate; the lighting becomes dark with bright lights in the sky as he floats in sky. During the hallucination Dude see the rug he confiscated from Big Lebowski's. He is woken once his bowling ball drops him back to the surface. After coming back to reality, Dude is greeted by a women flying through the air on a stripe line in the nude, Maude Lebowski (Julianne Moore). Dude and Maude forms a relationship. Dude without realizing has been sized up to be a sperm donor of her child. Dude experienced many encounters because he was trying to clear his identity. After having sex with Maude and enjoy a marijuana joint, at that moment Dude realized the reasoning behind the mistaken identity fiasco. In conclusion, as a motif in the film "Dude" was the main character's name; however, it was used as a common word of expression during dialogue. Dude was able to regain his identity and continued being the old lazy, laid back, unemployed, and bowler from Southern California.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Biggie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felipe_lorescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What makes this an outstanding comedy?!? The fact that you laugh louder the 4th time, the 5th time you watch it. It's not only a comedy of punch lines (when you enjoy it the 1st time, then the 2nd time it's not that funny, cause you already know the catch). It's the classical style of the movie's atmosphere that sets the adorable mood. What makes it a classic?!? The 11th time, the 12th time you watch it, you don't get bored. Perhaps you won't laugh out loud like you previously did, but it still gets you in that mood. In addition, this comedy is sprinkled with some serious social matters. Read between the lines, watch between the scenes...!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Big Lebowski, my hero-the slacker, crime mystery solver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyink01
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Lebowski film plot is centered on a Los Angeles dude, who is a real slacker, pot smoking, White Russian drinker, soon to be hero solving a crime mystery. He happens to have the same name as a millionaire; Jeffrey Lebowski played by David Huddleston, whose wife, Bunny Lebowski (Tara Reid) was kidnapped and owes money to a known pornographer. We are introduced to the Dude as he is shopping for milk and he opened the carton and sniffed it. The Dude wrote a check for 69 cents and returns home. It appears that he is unaware that someone is waiting on him and they attack him in the apartment. One of the hit men urinates on his rug. His prized possession that ties the apartment together, says the Dude. The Dude enlists his bowling buddies, whom we meet in regular league play. His main antagonist and best friend played by John Goodman, as Walter Sobchak. We soon learn that Walter is a practicing Jew who observes the Shabbos day of rest. Walter refuses to lift a finger on the day of rest, but manages to convince the Dude that he needs to find the millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski, and get his rug replaced. Walter drives the car on the Shabbos and says he is just doing it to help out. But turns out he is creating more trouble for the Dude. The millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski is in a wheelchair, but convinces the Dude he needs to deliver the ransom money alone so his kidnapped wife will return. The Dude becomes a crime fighting, urban cowboy. They go through the motions of delivering the money and in the meantime, they say "F it, let's go bowling" park the car in a handicapped zone with the ransom money in it, when they walk outside the car is gone. Panic ensues and Walter always says "Shut the F up, Donny" played by Steve Buscemi. Donny never really gets to say much in the film, but Walter always tells him the same thing. We get introduced to the millionaire's sister, Maude Lebowski portrayed by Julianne Moore. Maude was a nude artist who created her works of art while riding in ceiling harness. She believed the ransom money was kept by the Dude, but he proves to her that there was no money, and he was used by her brother as a scapegoat. The millionaire still has the money. The pornographer hires hit men, thugs to find the money. Once they determine there is no money, they punch the Dude in the face so hard, we see & hear fireworks, and then he is flying through the sky like Superman. Then he lands in the bowling alley. The Dude tackles all his problems inside the walls of the bowling alley. The punch perpetuates him there. Walter's character gets so out of hand he pulls a gun on another bowler because he wants to bowl on Shabbos. This is not going to happen, the police are called but they run right by the pair in the parking lot. They are not even the least bit frazzled about the police being there, we see them running into the alley with guns pulled. The music ties the scenes together in the movie. When the action elevates to a point where they can't handle it anymore, the say let's go bowling. Magically through sound they end up there bowling. Always confronted by larger than life egos and it becomes quite funny how much animosity and hate both lash at each other. One of the teams they are to play against, become real aggressive and say "No one messes with Jesus" (John Turturro) that is the bowler's name. We get a flashback which is so comical showing Jesus as a pedophile going door to door announcing to the neighborhood that he lives there. Music takes us from the bowling alley through that flashback. It is a funny movie showing that even slackers can be heroes. Maude found a purpose for the Dude, as she wanted him to be a sperm donor only, she wanted a child. She was beyond weird, but the Dude liked her style. At the conclusion of the film Donnie dies from shock of seeing the Dude's car on fire. He was not up for all the problems and confrontations that Walter and Dude went through. He was much more fragile than they imagined, best part is he didn't die alone. His best friends were there till the end. Many times over this movie had music transition the picture forward, the voices were covered by different rock songs, and special effects transferred everyone to the next scene. Just by mere suggestion. We were walking in the bowling alley at every problem. I loved how they glorified some of the bowling scenes, especially with the dude going underneath about 50 women down the approach looking up at their crotches. Sometimes even the Dude was embarrassed by what he wished would happen. He couldn't look up at the women he floated upside down the approach of the bowling alley, ashamed of his own thoughts or more like daydreams. The Dude became a crusader of crime, not you're likely candidate to solve a mystery. He did it with the help of Donnie and Walter, despite the constant arguing and bickering between the three. The arguing was the craziest thing that kept them going, for most it would drive them apart. I never imagined this would be a crime mystery movie that was so cleverly written that The Dude seems like someone from real life and not a character at all. He feels so real, that's what makes this movie so special. Anyone can be a hero; you just gotta believe in yourself, even if you're a slacker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true nonsensicomedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roselaar
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Outrageously zany, off-beat comedy the likes only the Coen Brothers can provide. Life is tough for the pot smoking all-round slacker Jeffrey Lebowski, more commonly referred to as "The Dude" (Jeff Bridges in one of the most defining roles of his career). Sharing his last name with a millionaire, he's victimized by thugs who mistake him for that rich man (who owes them a debt), a situation which finds his beloved rug in ruin after having been urinated upon by the perpetrators. When he visits his namesake to try and get him to pay for its cleaning, he soon gets more than he bargained for as he finds himself caught up in what appears to be a kidnap of the wealthy man's trophy wife, but swiftly explodes into a bizarre, inexplicable potpourri of events beyond anybody's control or understanding, thanks to the involvement of a host of wacky, maniacal and thoroughly enjoyable characters, ranging from feminist/nihilist artists and pornographers to White Russians and generally random folk annex narrators. Yet all The Dude asked for was a clean rug and an opportunity to win the local bowling alley's competition he trained so hard for with his two best buddies (John Goodman with severe anger management problems and Steve Buscemi who can't take a hint when he's asked to shut up). The Coens don't ask you to make sense of it all, they just want you to roll with it (pun intended), as The Dude does himself. Nevertheless, despite this absence of a clearly defined plot, or more likely because of it, The Big Lebowski proves all kinds of fun. The pair of directors used the same tactic a decade later with Burn After Reading to similar results, proving them the masters of this subgenre of 'nonsensicomedy' (for the record, I just made that term up and I hope it catches on). In both cases they were aided by an impressive cast of character actors and/or movie stars who felt like doing something different for a change, in The Big Lebowski's case including Philip Seymour Hoffman, John Turturro, Julianne Moore and Sam Elliott. Though the film was met with moderately tempered critical reviews and disappointing box office results back in 1998, time has proved the Coens right, as it has since become a widely accepted cult classic with serious tendencies towards an eventual, seemingly unavoidable shedding of the moniker 'cult'. When Burn After Reading came along in 2008, the majority of both audience and critics finally understood this type of film, and that movie did much, much better business accordingly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite a nice combination of comedy and crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has so many reviews that it doesn't need mine, so I won't review it. But since I write a blurb on each movie I see so that I can recollect it, I'll attempt to write 10 lines about this one. First off, it's a very satirical movie. I think it will be just as funny on a second viewing. There's too much swearing in the movie, you know, the f-word. After awhile, that became very tiring, and for me it impeded the comedy. I also thought that this was hard on the actors forced to insert this word so many times. They didn't sound 100% convincing at it after awhile. John Turturro's part is not that big, but he's very good in it. I didn't think Steve Buscemi had that many comic lines. It was really John Goodman's show. I liked his interactions with Jeff Bridges. Mr. Bridges remains a huge talent, as far as I can tell. David Huddleston is a very good actor. He was a tad over the top here. The film somehow made good use of Sam Elliott, who might be an underrated actor. Some of the other supporting actors didn't have that much to do in the way of comedy. In comedy you can say things you wouldn't ordinarily say seriously, and I felt that the Coens were taking the opportunity to poke fun at a lot of their favorite targets, but not in a peevish way. The film is above average. Maybe it's even an 8, but so many reviewers are raving so much about it excessively, as IMDb reviewers are wont to do, that I'm expressing less enthusiasm. See it, if you haven't already. You'll enjoy it, as long as you don't mind hearing a very great deal of the f-word. By the way, in Scarface with Pacino, the profanity seemed just right and worked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films, period - Dude!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barmstrong-782-631970
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Come on! This is the best film ever. i', even raising this above LOTR, since this is contemporary. I grew up living like the Dude. The Dude reminds me of my Uncle...not in a bad way, but with deep respect to living one's own life. The Coen brothers have created a film to be topped, if it was possible. Barton Fink was great..Fargo, yeah it was exceptional story-telling. But, the Dude - that was well-crafted cinema. The only other film that I have seen of theirs that captured me as much was No Country for Old Men. Can't wait for the next surprise!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG - Not Funny, Not Funny, Not Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NickyCee
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the heck did I tell you the Big Lebowski is not funny three times? Because this is once for every 20 people that told me this movie was the funniest most entertaining movie EVER. After years of being berated at parties and get-togethers with people spewing line after line from the movie, I gave in last week. I finally rented it. Wow. It's so bad on so many levels it's hard to describe. It's not funny - at - all. It's mildly amusing in parts but of the six people I watched it with, no one laughed once. Not once. I don't think it's a spoiler to tell you the language is sickeningly bad. Up there with Team America bad. There is one reason and one reason only that this movie is popular: College aged men (or guys who wish they were college aged) own the DVD and watch it repeatedly. Once memorizing the movie, on subsequent viewings they elbow each other before each "big" scene almost spilling their friend's beer and yelling, "HERE IT IS! HERE IT IS!" They then laugh at how clever they think they are. They're part of "The DUDE" club and they are very, very special indeed. This is the most unfunny movie I have ever seen. Other than Scarface and Team America, the movie containing the foulest most unnecessary language I've ever seen, and overall one of top five worst movies I've ever seen (and yes, this includes You Tube cat movies).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1998's The Big Lebowski Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of The Coen Brothers Direction And Screenplay, The Score, The Cinematography By Roger Deakins And Jeff Bridges Performance As Jeff Lebowski, My Mom Kelli Krajci Watched This Movie A Little On DVD That I Own That I Have In My DVD Collection, I Like To Laugh When I Watch Funny Movies On DVD, My Favorite Comedy Film Is 1933's Duck Soup With The Marx Brothers, 1988 Was 10 Years Old In 1998, 1982 Was 16 Years Old In 1998, 1953 Was 45 Years Old In 1998, This Movie Turned 10 Years In 2008, It Is Going To Turn 20 Years Old In 2018, Another Coen Brothers Film 1996's Fargo Is One Of My Favorite Films As Well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themadhouseyt
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funniest movie i've ever seen very good performances strong script very well directed deserved an Oscar. For me Jeff Bridges and John Goodman should have deserved an Oscar or at least a nomination, it's not that kind of comedy which is funny and at the half of the movie the jokes start to get annoying, the whole movie keeps you entertained, at least i didn't want the movie to end. The only thing that bothered me is that they haven't done a part 2, i want to know what is going to happen to "The Dude" and Walter i don't really care about other characters really (That doesn't mean that the other actors weren't good) I really would love if it lasted more. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Without a doubt, this is the funniest film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Coen Brothers are perhaps better known for their work in colder films such as 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men' but with 'The Big Lebowski' they manage to create a clever and highly enjoyable comedy. I've seen the film a number of times now and on each viewing I have been more impressed by what I have seen. The movie combines a talented cast with each actor bringing their own unique character to the screen, humour that is intelligent and subtle in places, brilliant sets such as those used in the bowling alley, costumes and a soundtrack that brilliantly adds to the feel of film. Although 'The Big Lebowski' is nothing like the films of 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men', it contains many of the Coen Brothers usual plot devices and techniques that they used. The plot of the film is relatively straight forward, but is layered over with bizarre twists with nothing going as easy as planned. The film is focused around a millionaire whose wife is kidnapped for a $1,000,000 ransom with Jeffrey Lebowski hiring a 'bum' of the same name to act as a middle man in a deal to get here back. Immediately 'Dude' as he likes to be known suspects that the kidnapping is not as straightforward as outlined and that Lebowski's wife Bunny has kidnapped herself in order to get rich from a man who would not normally allow her such money, sound a bit like 'Fargo'? Unlike Fargo which can be seen as a 'dark comedy', The Big Lebowski is more a feel-good film that's style can probably be better compared to an earlier comedy of the Coen Brothers 'Raising Arizona', a film also which featured John Goodman (who also appeared in the Coen Brothers' film 'Barton Fink'). I feel that John Goodman's performance in this film is one worthy of a best supporting actor Oscar. Goodman portrays Walter; one of the Dude's bowling buddies that becomes involved in the Dude's task to transfer money between Lebowski and the kidnappers. Walter provides a lot of the film's humour and best scenes; he is an aggressive war veteran who makes constant references to his fighting at Vietnam and is constantly arguing with fellow bowling buddy Donny. Donny is portrayed by Steve Buscemi who is one of my favourite actors who seems to play a totally different character in every film he appears in. It seems strange that him and Goodman would go on to star together again in 'Monsters Inc.' but the two have great chemistry in this film, Donny is mocked throughout by Walter and the two provide some great scenes for us such as 'I am the walrus?'. John Turturro (who starred in 'Barton Fink' and later 'O Brother, Where Art Thou?') also features in a less prominent role as Jesus Quintana, a convicted paedophile that is set to face the Dude's bowling team in an upcoming tournament round. Although he doesn't have much time on screen, when he does he provides us with some of the films most enjoyable scenes, in fact this is the case for nearly all the scenes that are set in the bowling alley. Sam Elliott is also used effectively in his role as the mysterious narrator. There are other strong supporting performances such as those from Julianne Moore and Philip Seymour Hoffman but the star is undoubtedly Jeff Bridges as 'the Dude'. Jeff Bridges brings character and style to the leading character who is ultimately a bum that spends his life getting high and bowling with his friends. It's hard to imagine anybody else in such a role, the film acts an ode to the characters laid back, chilled lifestyle which makes the film so enjoyable. As it is with other Coen Brothers' films, the cinematography is superb and the duo have created a fantastic setting for a film. In 'Fargo' we saw the gritty and dark atmosphere reflected in the cold setting of North Dakota, in 'The Big Lebowski' the Coen Brothers' use Los Angeles as their location, at times the film can feel dark but at others we get light, as already said the bowling alley provides an excellent setting for many of the films' scenes. The Coen Brothers' also use a number of bizarre yet enjoyable dream sequences to give their film another dimension.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mistaken Identity of Dude.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cupcake_movie_goer
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this eccentric comedy/crime film by the Coen brothers, they created an outstanding movie. The actors/actress in the film was perfectly unified in a great way that audience could build a vision of the plot. If you can handle the graphic dialogue used and suggestive behavior this is the right movie for you. The theme of the film is Jeff "Dude"Lebowski (Jeff Bridges) discovers he is a victim of mistaken identity. Thugs were sent to his home by Jackie Treehorn (Ben Gazzara) to recover a debit; Big Lebowski's (The Millionaire) wife owes him. Before the thugs realize they have the wrong Lebowski and that he's the "Dude" they urinate of his rug; leaving Dude in disgust. Dude pays BigLebowski (David Huddleston) a visit to be compensated for his rug being destroyed. Big Lebowski filled with arrogance; felt he was there looking for a hand out. Dude felt the conversation wasn't getting anywhere and decided he would take a rug from Lebowski home to be even. When Bunny (Tara Reid) disappears (Lebowski's wife); Big Lebowski contacts Dude making him an offer to be the bagman. The only thing Dude has to do is deliver the ransom money for Bunny. Dude brings Walter (John Goodman) along to make the drop. When the drop goes to pieces it creates a ricochet of others trying to reclaim the ransom money. While home listening to the soothing sounds of the bowling pins being knocked down, he discovers 3 people standing over him. They knocked him out and he begins to hallucinate; the lighting becomes dark with bright lights in the sky as he floats in sky. During the hallucination Dude see the rug he confiscated from Big Lebowski's. He is woken once his bowling ball drops him back to the surface. After coming back to reality, Dude is greeted by a women flying through the air on a stripe line in the nude, Maude Lebowski (Julianne Moore). Dude and Maude forms a relationship. Dude without realizing has been sized up to be a sperm donor of her child. Dude experienced many encounters because he was trying to clear his identity. After having sex with Maude and enjoy a marijuana joint, at that moment Dude realized the reasoning behind the mistaken identity fiasco. In conclusion, as a motif in the film "Dude" was the main character's name; however, it was used as a common word of expression during dialogue. Dude was able to regain his identity and continued being the old lazy, laid back, unemployed, and bowler from Southern California.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Biggie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felipe_lorescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What makes this an outstanding comedy?!? The fact that you laugh louder the 4th time, the 5th time you watch it. It's not only a comedy of punch lines (when you enjoy it the 1st time, then the 2nd time it's not that funny, cause you already know the catch). It's the classical style of the movie's atmosphere that sets the adorable mood. What makes it a classic?!? The 11th time, the 12th time you watch it, you don't get bored. Perhaps you won't laugh out loud like you previously did, but it still gets you in that mood. In addition, this comedy is sprinkled with some serious social matters. Read between the lines, watch between the scenes...!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Big Lebowski, my hero-the slacker, crime mystery solver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyink01
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Lebowski film plot is centered on a Los Angeles dude, who is a real slacker, pot smoking, White Russian drinker, soon to be hero solving a crime mystery. He happens to have the same name as a millionaire; Jeffrey Lebowski played by David Huddleston, whose wife, Bunny Lebowski (Tara Reid) was kidnapped and owes money to a known pornographer. We are introduced to the Dude as he is shopping for milk and he opened the carton and sniffed it. The Dude wrote a check for 69 cents and returns home. It appears that he is unaware that someone is waiting on him and they attack him in the apartment. One of the hit men urinates on his rug. His prized possession that ties the apartment together, says the Dude. The Dude enlists his bowling buddies, whom we meet in regular league play. His main antagonist and best friend played by John Goodman, as Walter Sobchak. We soon learn that Walter is a practicing Jew who observes the Shabbos day of rest. Walter refuses to lift a finger on the day of rest, but manages to convince the Dude that he needs to find the millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski, and get his rug replaced. Walter drives the car on the Shabbos and says he is just doing it to help out. But turns out he is creating more trouble for the Dude. The millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski is in a wheelchair, but convinces the Dude he needs to deliver the ransom money alone so his kidnapped wife will return. The Dude becomes a crime fighting, urban cowboy. They go through the motions of delivering the money and in the meantime, they say "F it, let's go bowling" park the car in a handicapped zone with the ransom money in it, when they walk outside the car is gone. Panic ensues and Walter always says "Shut the F up, Donny" played by Steve Buscemi. Donny never really gets to say much in the film, but Walter always tells him the same thing. We get introduced to the millionaire's sister, Maude Lebowski portrayed by Julianne Moore. Maude was a nude artist who created her works of art while riding in ceiling harness. She believed the ransom money was kept by the Dude, but he proves to her that there was no money, and he was used by her brother as a scapegoat. The millionaire still has the money. The pornographer hires hit men, thugs to find the money. Once they determine there is no money, they punch the Dude in the face so hard, we see & hear fireworks, and then he is flying through the sky like Superman. Then he lands in the bowling alley. The Dude tackles all his problems inside the walls of the bowling alley. The punch perpetuates him there. Walter's character gets so out of hand he pulls a gun on another bowler because he wants to bowl on Shabbos. This is not going to happen, the police are called but they run right by the pair in the parking lot. They are not even the least bit frazzled about the police being there, we see them running into the alley with guns pulled. The music ties the scenes together in the movie. When the action elevates to a point where they can't handle it anymore, the say let's go bowling. Magically through sound they end up there bowling. Always confronted by larger than life egos and it becomes quite funny how much animosity and hate both lash at each other. One of the teams they are to play against, become real aggressive and say "No one messes with Jesus" (John Turturro) that is the bowler's name. We get a flashback which is so comical showing Jesus as a pedophile going door to door announcing to the neighborhood that he lives there. Music takes us from the bowling alley through that flashback. It is a funny movie showing that even slackers can be heroes. Maude found a purpose for the Dude, as she wanted him to be a sperm donor only, she wanted a child. She was beyond weird, but the Dude liked her style. At the conclusion of the film Donnie dies from shock of seeing the Dude's car on fire. He was not up for all the problems and confrontations that Walter and Dude went through. He was much more fragile than they imagined, best part is he didn't die alone. His best friends were there till the end. Many times over this movie had music transition the picture forward, the voices were covered by different rock songs, and special effects transferred everyone to the next scene. Just by mere suggestion. We were walking in the bowling alley at every problem. I loved how they glorified some of the bowling scenes, especially with the dude going underneath about 50 women down the approach looking up at their crotches. Sometimes even the Dude was embarrassed by what he wished would happen. He couldn't look up at the women he floated upside down the approach of the bowling alley, ashamed of his own thoughts or more like daydreams. The Dude became a crusader of crime, not you're likely candidate to solve a mystery. He did it with the help of Donnie and Walter, despite the constant arguing and bickering between the three. The arguing was the craziest thing that kept them going, for most it would drive them apart. I never imagined this would be a crime mystery movie that was so cleverly written that The Dude seems like someone from real life and not a character at all. He feels so real, that's what makes this movie so special. Anyone can be a hero; you just gotta believe in yourself, even if you're a slacker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true nonsensicomedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roselaar
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Outrageously zany, off-beat comedy the likes only the Coen Brothers can provide. Life is tough for the pot smoking all-round slacker Jeffrey Lebowski, more commonly referred to as "The Dude" (Jeff Bridges in one of the most defining roles of his career). Sharing his last name with a millionaire, he's victimized by thugs who mistake him for that rich man (who owes them a debt), a situation which finds his beloved rug in ruin after having been urinated upon by the perpetrators. When he visits his namesake to try and get him to pay for its cleaning, he soon gets more than he bargained for as he finds himself caught up in what appears to be a kidnap of the wealthy man's trophy wife, but swiftly explodes into a bizarre, inexplicable potpourri of events beyond anybody's control or understanding, thanks to the involvement of a host of wacky, maniacal and thoroughly enjoyable characters, ranging from feminist/nihilist artists and pornographers to White Russians and generally random folk annex narrators. Yet all The Dude asked for was a clean rug and an opportunity to win the local bowling alley's competition he trained so hard for with his two best buddies (John Goodman with severe anger management problems and Steve Buscemi who can't take a hint when he's asked to shut up). The Coens don't ask you to make sense of it all, they just want you to roll with it (pun intended), as The Dude does himself. Nevertheless, despite this absence of a clearly defined plot, or more likely because of it, The Big Lebowski proves all kinds of fun. The pair of directors used the same tactic a decade later with Burn After Reading to similar results, proving them the masters of this subgenre of 'nonsensicomedy' (for the record, I just made that term up and I hope it catches on). In both cases they were aided by an impressive cast of character actors and/or movie stars who felt like doing something different for a change, in The Big Lebowski's case including Philip Seymour Hoffman, John Turturro, Julianne Moore and Sam Elliott. Though the film was met with moderately tempered critical reviews and disappointing box office results back in 1998, time has proved the Coens right, as it has since become a widely accepted cult classic with serious tendencies towards an eventual, seemingly unavoidable shedding of the moniker 'cult'. When Burn After Reading came along in 2008, the majority of both audience and critics finally understood this type of film, and that movie did much, much better business accordingly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite a nice combination of comedy and crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has so many reviews that it doesn't need mine, so I won't review it. But since I write a blurb on each movie I see so that I can recollect it, I'll attempt to write 10 lines about this one. First off, it's a very satirical movie. I think it will be just as funny on a second viewing. There's too much swearing in the movie, you know, the f-word. After awhile, that became very tiring, and for me it impeded the comedy. I also thought that this was hard on the actors forced to insert this word so many times. They didn't sound 100% convincing at it after awhile. John Turturro's part is not that big, but he's very good in it. I didn't think Steve Buscemi had that many comic lines. It was really John Goodman's show. I liked his interactions with Jeff Bridges. Mr. Bridges remains a huge talent, as far as I can tell. David Huddleston is a very good actor. He was a tad over the top here. The film somehow made good use of Sam Elliott, who might be an underrated actor. Some of the other supporting actors didn't have that much to do in the way of comedy. In comedy you can say things you wouldn't ordinarily say seriously, and I felt that the Coens were taking the opportunity to poke fun at a lot of their favorite targets, but not in a peevish way. The film is above average. Maybe it's even an 8, but so many reviewers are raving so much about it excessively, as IMDb reviewers are wont to do, that I'm expressing less enthusiasm. See it, if you haven't already. You'll enjoy it, as long as you don't mind hearing a very great deal of the f-word. By the way, in Scarface with Pacino, the profanity seemed just right and worked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films, period - Dude!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barmstrong-782-631970
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Come on! This is the best film ever. i', even raising this above LOTR, since this is contemporary. I grew up living like the Dude. The Dude reminds me of my Uncle...not in a bad way, but with deep respect to living one's own life. The Coen brothers have created a film to be topped, if it was possible. Barton Fink was great..Fargo, yeah it was exceptional story-telling. But, the Dude - that was well-crafted cinema. The only other film that I have seen of theirs that captured me as much was No Country for Old Men. Can't wait for the next surprise!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG - Not Funny, Not Funny, Not Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NickyCee
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the heck did I tell you the Big Lebowski is not funny three times? Because this is once for every 20 people that told me this movie was the funniest most entertaining movie EVER. After years of being berated at parties and get-togethers with people spewing line after line from the movie, I gave in last week. I finally rented it. Wow. It's so bad on so many levels it's hard to describe. It's not funny - at - all. It's mildly amusing in parts but of the six people I watched it with, no one laughed once. Not once. I don't think it's a spoiler to tell you the language is sickeningly bad. Up there with Team America bad. There is one reason and one reason only that this movie is popular: College aged men (or guys who wish they were college aged) own the DVD and watch it repeatedly. Once memorizing the movie, on subsequent viewings they elbow each other before each "big" scene almost spilling their friend's beer and yelling, "HERE IT IS! HERE IT IS!" They then laugh at how clever they think they are. They're part of "The DUDE" club and they are very, very special indeed. This is the most unfunny movie I have ever seen. Other than Scarface and Team America, the movie containing the foulest most unnecessary language I've ever seen, and overall one of top five worst movies I've ever seen (and yes, this includes You Tube cat movies).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1998's The Big Lebowski Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of The Coen Brothers Direction And Screenplay, The Score, The Cinematography By Roger Deakins And Jeff Bridges Performance As Jeff Lebowski, My Mom Kelli Krajci Watched This Movie A Little On DVD That I Own That I Have In My DVD Collection, I Like To Laugh When I Watch Funny Movies On DVD, My Favorite Comedy Film Is 1933's Duck Soup With The Marx Brothers, 1988 Was 10 Years Old In 1998, 1982 Was 16 Years Old In 1998, 1953 Was 45 Years Old In 1998, This Movie Turned 10 Years In 2008, It Is Going To Turn 20 Years Old In 2018, Another Coen Brothers Film 1996's Fargo Is One Of My Favorite Films As Well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themadhouseyt
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funniest movie i've ever seen very good performances strong script very well directed deserved an Oscar. For me Jeff Bridges and John Goodman should have deserved an Oscar or at least a nomination, it's not that kind of comedy which is funny and at the half of the movie the jokes start to get annoying, the whole movie keeps you entertained, at least i didn't want the movie to end. The only thing that bothered me is that they haven't done a part 2, i want to know what is going to happen to "The Dude" and Walter i don't really care about other characters really (That doesn't mean that the other actors weren't good) I really would love if it lasted more. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Without a doubt, this is the funniest film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Coen Brothers are perhaps better known for their work in colder films such as 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men' but with 'The Big Lebowski' they manage to create a clever and highly enjoyable comedy. I've seen the film a number of times now and on each viewing I have been more impressed by what I have seen. The movie combines a talented cast with each actor bringing their own unique character to the screen, humour that is intelligent and subtle in places, brilliant sets such as those used in the bowling alley, costumes and a soundtrack that brilliantly adds to the feel of film. Although 'The Big Lebowski' is nothing like the films of 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men', it contains many of the Coen Brothers usual plot devices and techniques that they used. The plot of the film is relatively straight forward, but is layered over with bizarre twists with nothing going as easy as planned. The film is focused around a millionaire whose wife is kidnapped for a $1,000,000 ransom with Jeffrey Lebowski hiring a 'bum' of the same name to act as a middle man in a deal to get here back. Immediately 'Dude' as he likes to be known suspects that the kidnapping is not as straightforward as outlined and that Lebowski's wife Bunny has kidnapped herself in order to get rich from a man who would not normally allow her such money, sound a bit like 'Fargo'? Unlike Fargo which can be seen as a 'dark comedy', The Big Lebowski is more a feel-good film that's style can probably be better compared to an earlier comedy of the Coen Brothers 'Raising Arizona', a film also which featured John Goodman (who also appeared in the Coen Brothers' film 'Barton Fink'). I feel that John Goodman's performance in this film is one worthy of a best supporting actor Oscar. Goodman portrays Walter; one of the Dude's bowling buddies that becomes involved in the Dude's task to transfer money between Lebowski and the kidnappers. Walter provides a lot of the film's humour and best scenes; he is an aggressive war veteran who makes constant references to his fighting at Vietnam and is constantly arguing with fellow bowling buddy Donny. Donny is portrayed by Steve Buscemi who is one of my favourite actors who seems to play a totally different character in every film he appears in. It seems strange that him and Goodman would go on to star together again in 'Monsters Inc.' but the two have great chemistry in this film, Donny is mocked throughout by Walter and the two provide some great scenes for us such as 'I am the walrus?'. John Turturro (who starred in 'Barton Fink' and later 'O Brother, Where Art Thou?') also features in a less prominent role as Jesus Quintana, a convicted paedophile that is set to face the Dude's bowling team in an upcoming tournament round. Although he doesn't have much time on screen, when he does he provides us with some of the films most enjoyable scenes, in fact this is the case for nearly all the scenes that are set in the bowling alley. Sam Elliott is also used effectively in his role as the mysterious narrator. There are other strong supporting performances such as those from Julianne Moore and Philip Seymour Hoffman but the star is undoubtedly Jeff Bridges as 'the Dude'. Jeff Bridges brings character and style to the leading character who is ultimately a bum that spends his life getting high and bowling with his friends. It's hard to imagine anybody else in such a role, the film acts an ode to the characters laid back, chilled lifestyle which makes the film so enjoyable. As it is with other Coen Brothers' films, the cinematography is superb and the duo have created a fantastic setting for a film. In 'Fargo' we saw the gritty and dark atmosphere reflected in the cold setting of North Dakota, in 'The Big Lebowski' the Coen Brothers' use Los Angeles as their location, at times the film can feel dark but at others we get light, as already said the bowling alley provides an excellent setting for many of the films' scenes. The Coen Brothers' also use a number of bizarre yet enjoyable dream sequences to give their film another dimension.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mistaken Identity of Dude.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cupcake_movie_goer
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this eccentric comedy/crime film by the Coen brothers, they created an outstanding movie. The actors/actress in the film was perfectly unified in a great way that audience could build a vision of the plot. If you can handle the graphic dialogue used and suggestive behavior this is the right movie for you. The theme of the film is Jeff "Dude"Lebowski (Jeff Bridges) discovers he is a victim of mistaken identity. Thugs were sent to his home by Jackie Treehorn (Ben Gazzara) to recover a debit; Big Lebowski's (The Millionaire) wife owes him. Before the thugs realize they have the wrong Lebowski and that he's the "Dude" they urinate of his rug; leaving Dude in disgust. Dude pays BigLebowski (David Huddleston) a visit to be compensated for his rug being destroyed. Big Lebowski filled with arrogance; felt he was there looking for a hand out. Dude felt the conversation wasn't getting anywhere and decided he would take a rug from Lebowski home to be even. When Bunny (Tara Reid) disappears (Lebowski's wife); Big Lebowski contacts Dude making him an offer to be the bagman. The only thing Dude has to do is deliver the ransom money for Bunny. Dude brings Walter (John Goodman) along to make the drop. When the drop goes to pieces it creates a ricochet of others trying to reclaim the ransom money. While home listening to the soothing sounds of the bowling pins being knocked down, he discovers 3 people standing over him. They knocked him out and he begins to hallucinate; the lighting becomes dark with bright lights in the sky as he floats in sky. During the hallucination Dude see the rug he confiscated from Big Lebowski's. He is woken once his bowling ball drops him back to the surface. After coming back to reality, Dude is greeted by a women flying through the air on a stripe line in the nude, Maude Lebowski (Julianne Moore). Dude and Maude forms a relationship. Dude without realizing has been sized up to be a sperm donor of her child. Dude experienced many encounters because he was trying to clear his identity. After having sex with Maude and enjoy a marijuana joint, at that moment Dude realized the reasoning behind the mistaken identity fiasco. In conclusion, as a motif in the film "Dude" was the main character's name; however, it was used as a common word of expression during dialogue. Dude was able to regain his identity and continued being the old lazy, laid back, unemployed, and bowler from Southern California.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Biggie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    felipe_lorescu
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What makes this an outstanding comedy?!? The fact that you laugh louder the 4th time, the 5th time you watch it. It's not only a comedy of punch lines (when you enjoy it the 1st time, then the 2nd time it's not that funny, cause you already know the catch). It's the classical style of the movie's atmosphere that sets the adorable mood. What makes it a classic?!? The 11th time, the 12th time you watch it, you don't get bored. Perhaps you won't laugh out loud like you previously did, but it still gets you in that mood. In addition, this comedy is sprinkled with some serious social matters. Read between the lines, watch between the scenes...!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Big Lebowski, my hero-the slacker, crime mystery solver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eyink01
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Lebowski film plot is centered on a Los Angeles dude, who is a real slacker, pot smoking, White Russian drinker, soon to be hero solving a crime mystery. He happens to have the same name as a millionaire; Jeffrey Lebowski played by David Huddleston, whose wife, Bunny Lebowski (Tara Reid) was kidnapped and owes money to a known pornographer. We are introduced to the Dude as he is shopping for milk and he opened the carton and sniffed it. The Dude wrote a check for 69 cents and returns home. It appears that he is unaware that someone is waiting on him and they attack him in the apartment. One of the hit men urinates on his rug. His prized possession that ties the apartment together, says the Dude. The Dude enlists his bowling buddies, whom we meet in regular league play. His main antagonist and best friend played by John Goodman, as Walter Sobchak. We soon learn that Walter is a practicing Jew who observes the Shabbos day of rest. Walter refuses to lift a finger on the day of rest, but manages to convince the Dude that he needs to find the millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski, and get his rug replaced. Walter drives the car on the Shabbos and says he is just doing it to help out. But turns out he is creating more trouble for the Dude. The millionaire Jeffrey Lebowski is in a wheelchair, but convinces the Dude he needs to deliver the ransom money alone so his kidnapped wife will return. The Dude becomes a crime fighting, urban cowboy. They go through the motions of delivering the money and in the meantime, they say "F it, let's go bowling" park the car in a handicapped zone with the ransom money in it, when they walk outside the car is gone. Panic ensues and Walter always says "Shut the F up, Donny" played by Steve Buscemi. Donny never really gets to say much in the film, but Walter always tells him the same thing. We get introduced to the millionaire's sister, Maude Lebowski portrayed by Julianne Moore. Maude was a nude artist who created her works of art while riding in ceiling harness. She believed the ransom money was kept by the Dude, but he proves to her that there was no money, and he was used by her brother as a scapegoat. The millionaire still has the money. The pornographer hires hit men, thugs to find the money. Once they determine there is no money, they punch the Dude in the face so hard, we see & hear fireworks, and then he is flying through the sky like Superman. Then he lands in the bowling alley. The Dude tackles all his problems inside the walls of the bowling alley. The punch perpetuates him there. Walter's character gets so out of hand he pulls a gun on another bowler because he wants to bowl on Shabbos. This is not going to happen, the police are called but they run right by the pair in the parking lot. They are not even the least bit frazzled about the police being there, we see them running into the alley with guns pulled. The music ties the scenes together in the movie. When the action elevates to a point where they can't handle it anymore, the say let's go bowling. Magically through sound they end up there bowling. Always confronted by larger than life egos and it becomes quite funny how much animosity and hate both lash at each other. One of the teams they are to play against, become real aggressive and say "No one messes with Jesus" (John Turturro) that is the bowler's name. We get a flashback which is so comical showing Jesus as a pedophile going door to door announcing to the neighborhood that he lives there. Music takes us from the bowling alley through that flashback. It is a funny movie showing that even slackers can be heroes. Maude found a purpose for the Dude, as she wanted him to be a sperm donor only, she wanted a child. She was beyond weird, but the Dude liked her style. At the conclusion of the film Donnie dies from shock of seeing the Dude's car on fire. He was not up for all the problems and confrontations that Walter and Dude went through. He was much more fragile than they imagined, best part is he didn't die alone. His best friends were there till the end. Many times over this movie had music transition the picture forward, the voices were covered by different rock songs, and special effects transferred everyone to the next scene. Just by mere suggestion. We were walking in the bowling alley at every problem. I loved how they glorified some of the bowling scenes, especially with the dude going underneath about 50 women down the approach looking up at their crotches. Sometimes even the Dude was embarrassed by what he wished would happen. He couldn't look up at the women he floated upside down the approach of the bowling alley, ashamed of his own thoughts or more like daydreams. The Dude became a crusader of crime, not you're likely candidate to solve a mystery. He did it with the help of Donnie and Walter, despite the constant arguing and bickering between the three. The arguing was the craziest thing that kept them going, for most it would drive them apart. I never imagined this would be a crime mystery movie that was so cleverly written that The Dude seems like someone from real life and not a character at all. He feels so real, that's what makes this movie so special. Anyone can be a hero; you just gotta believe in yourself, even if you're a slacker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A true nonsensicomedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    roselaar
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Outrageously zany, off-beat comedy the likes only the Coen Brothers can provide. Life is tough for the pot smoking all-round slacker Jeffrey Lebowski, more commonly referred to as "The Dude" (Jeff Bridges in one of the most defining roles of his career). Sharing his last name with a millionaire, he's victimized by thugs who mistake him for that rich man (who owes them a debt), a situation which finds his beloved rug in ruin after having been urinated upon by the perpetrators. When he visits his namesake to try and get him to pay for its cleaning, he soon gets more than he bargained for as he finds himself caught up in what appears to be a kidnap of the wealthy man's trophy wife, but swiftly explodes into a bizarre, inexplicable potpourri of events beyond anybody's control or understanding, thanks to the involvement of a host of wacky, maniacal and thoroughly enjoyable characters, ranging from feminist/nihilist artists and pornographers to White Russians and generally random folk annex narrators. Yet all The Dude asked for was a clean rug and an opportunity to win the local bowling alley's competition he trained so hard for with his two best buddies (John Goodman with severe anger management problems and Steve Buscemi who can't take a hint when he's asked to shut up). The Coens don't ask you to make sense of it all, they just want you to roll with it (pun intended), as The Dude does himself. Nevertheless, despite this absence of a clearly defined plot, or more likely because of it, The Big Lebowski proves all kinds of fun. The pair of directors used the same tactic a decade later with Burn After Reading to similar results, proving them the masters of this subgenre of 'nonsensicomedy' (for the record, I just made that term up and I hope it catches on). In both cases they were aided by an impressive cast of character actors and/or movie stars who felt like doing something different for a change, in The Big Lebowski's case including Philip Seymour Hoffman, John Turturro, Julianne Moore and Sam Elliott. Though the film was met with moderately tempered critical reviews and disappointing box office results back in 1998, time has proved the Coens right, as it has since become a widely accepted cult classic with serious tendencies towards an eventual, seemingly unavoidable shedding of the moniker 'cult'. When Burn After Reading came along in 2008, the majority of both audience and critics finally understood this type of film, and that movie did much, much better business accordingly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite a nice combination of comedy and crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has so many reviews that it doesn't need mine, so I won't review it. But since I write a blurb on each movie I see so that I can recollect it, I'll attempt to write 10 lines about this one. First off, it's a very satirical movie. I think it will be just as funny on a second viewing. There's too much swearing in the movie, you know, the f-word. After awhile, that became very tiring, and for me it impeded the comedy. I also thought that this was hard on the actors forced to insert this word so many times. They didn't sound 100% convincing at it after awhile. John Turturro's part is not that big, but he's very good in it. I didn't think Steve Buscemi had that many comic lines. It was really John Goodman's show. I liked his interactions with Jeff Bridges. Mr. Bridges remains a huge talent, as far as I can tell. David Huddleston is a very good actor. He was a tad over the top here. The film somehow made good use of Sam Elliott, who might be an underrated actor. Some of the other supporting actors didn't have that much to do in the way of comedy. In comedy you can say things you wouldn't ordinarily say seriously, and I felt that the Coens were taking the opportunity to poke fun at a lot of their favorite targets, but not in a peevish way. The film is above average. Maybe it's even an 8, but so many reviewers are raving so much about it excessively, as IMDb reviewers are wont to do, that I'm expressing less enthusiasm. See it, if you haven't already. You'll enjoy it, as long as you don't mind hearing a very great deal of the f-word. By the way, in Scarface with Pacino, the profanity seemed just right and worked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films, period - Dude!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barmstrong-782-631970
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Come on! This is the best film ever. i', even raising this above LOTR, since this is contemporary. I grew up living like the Dude. The Dude reminds me of my Uncle...not in a bad way, but with deep respect to living one's own life. The Coen brothers have created a film to be topped, if it was possible. Barton Fink was great..Fargo, yeah it was exceptional story-telling. But, the Dude - that was well-crafted cinema. The only other film that I have seen of theirs that captured me as much was No Country for Old Men. Can't wait for the next surprise!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    OMG - Not Funny, Not Funny, Not Funny!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    NickyCee
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the heck did I tell you the Big Lebowski is not funny three times? Because this is once for every 20 people that told me this movie was the funniest most entertaining movie EVER. After years of being berated at parties and get-togethers with people spewing line after line from the movie, I gave in last week. I finally rented it. Wow. It's so bad on so many levels it's hard to describe. It's not funny - at - all. It's mildly amusing in parts but of the six people I watched it with, no one laughed once. Not once. I don't think it's a spoiler to tell you the language is sickeningly bad. Up there with Team America bad. There is one reason and one reason only that this movie is popular: College aged men (or guys who wish they were college aged) own the DVD and watch it repeatedly. Once memorizing the movie, on subsequent viewings they elbow each other before each "big" scene almost spilling their friend's beer and yelling, "HERE IT IS! HERE IT IS!" They then laugh at how clever they think they are. They're part of "The DUDE" club and they are very, very special indeed. This is the most unfunny movie I have ever seen. Other than Scarface and Team America, the movie containing the foulest most unnecessary language I've ever seen, and overall one of top five worst movies I've ever seen (and yes, this includes You Tube cat movies).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of My Favorite Films
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Krajci
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    1998's The Big Lebowski Is One Of My Favorite Films, I Like It Because Of The Coen Brothers Direction And Screenplay, The Score, The Cinematography By Roger Deakins And Jeff Bridges Performance As Jeff Lebowski, My Mom Kelli Krajci Watched This Movie A Little On DVD That I Own That I Have In My DVD Collection, I Like To Laugh When I Watch Funny Movies On DVD, My Favorite Comedy Film Is 1933's Duck Soup With The Marx Brothers, 1988 Was 10 Years Old In 1998, 1982 Was 16 Years Old In 1998, 1953 Was 45 Years Old In 1998, This Movie Turned 10 Years In 2008, It Is Going To Turn 20 Years Old In 2018, Another Coen Brothers Film 1996's Fargo Is One Of My Favorite Films As Well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    themadhouseyt
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funniest movie i've ever seen very good performances strong script very well directed deserved an Oscar. For me Jeff Bridges and John Goodman should have deserved an Oscar or at least a nomination, it's not that kind of comedy which is funny and at the half of the movie the jokes start to get annoying, the whole movie keeps you entertained, at least i didn't want the movie to end. The only thing that bothered me is that they haven't done a part 2, i want to know what is going to happen to "The Dude" and Walter i don't really care about other characters really (That doesn't mean that the other actors weren't good) I really would love if it lasted more. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Without a doubt, this is the funniest film ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Daniel Metcalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Coen Brothers are perhaps better known for their work in colder films such as 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men' but with 'The Big Lebowski' they manage to create a clever and highly enjoyable comedy. I've seen the film a number of times now and on each viewing I have been more impressed by what I have seen. The movie combines a talented cast with each actor bringing their own unique character to the screen, humour that is intelligent and subtle in places, brilliant sets such as those used in the bowling alley, costumes and a soundtrack that brilliantly adds to the feel of film. Although 'The Big Lebowski' is nothing like the films of 'Fargo' and 'No Country for Old Men', it contains many of the Coen Brothers usual plot devices and techniques that they used. The plot of the film is relatively straight forward, but is layered over with bizarre twists with nothing going as easy as planned. The film is focused around a millionaire whose wife is kidnapped for a $1,000,000 ransom with Jeffrey Lebowski hiring a 'bum' of the same name to act as a middle man in a deal to get here back. Immediately 'Dude' as he likes to be known suspects that the kidnapping is not as straightforward as outlined and that Lebowski's wife Bunny has kidnapped herself in order to get rich from a man who would not normally allow her such money, sound a bit like 'Fargo'? Unlike Fargo which can be seen as a 'dark comedy', The Big Lebowski is more a feel-good film that's style can probably be better compared to an earlier comedy of the Coen Brothers 'Raising Arizona', a film also which featured John Goodman (who also appeared in the Coen Brothers' film 'Barton Fink'). I feel that John Goodman's performance in this film is one worthy of a best supporting actor Oscar. Goodman portrays Walter; one of the Dude's bowling buddies that becomes involved in the Dude's task to transfer money between Lebowski and the kidnappers. Walter provides a lot of the film's humour and best scenes; he is an aggressive war veteran who makes constant references to his fighting at Vietnam and is constantly arguing with fellow bowling buddy Donny. Donny is portrayed by Steve Buscemi who is one of my favourite actors who seems to play a totally different character in every film he appears in. It seems strange that him and Goodman would go on to star together again in 'Monsters Inc.' but the two have great chemistry in this film, Donny is mocked throughout by Walter and the two provide some great scenes for us such as 'I am the walrus?'. John Turturro (who starred in 'Barton Fink' and later 'O Brother, Where Art Thou?') also features in a less prominent role as Jesus Quintana, a convicted paedophile that is set to face the Dude's bowling team in an upcoming tournament round. Although he doesn't have much time on screen, when he does he provides us with some of the films most enjoyable scenes, in fact this is the case for nearly all the scenes that are set in the bowling alley. Sam Elliott is also used effectively in his role as the mysterious narrator. There are other strong supporting performances such as those from Julianne Moore and Philip Seymour Hoffman but the star is undoubtedly Jeff Bridges as 'the Dude'. Jeff Bridges brings character and style to the leading character who is ultimately a bum that spends his life getting high and bowling with his friends. It's hard to imagine anybody else in such a role, the film acts an ode to the characters laid back, chilled lifestyle which makes the film so enjoyable. As it is with other Coen Brothers' films, the cinematography is superb and the duo have created a fantastic setting for a film. In 'Fargo' we saw the gritty and dark atmosphere reflected in the cold setting of North Dakota, in 'The Big Lebowski' the Coen Brothers' use Los Angeles as their location, at times the film can feel dark but at others we get light, as already said the bowling alley provides an excellent setting for many of the films' scenes. The Coen Brothers' also use a number of bizarre yet enjoyable dream sequences to give their film another dimension.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Mistaken Identity of Dude.......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cupcake_movie_goer
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this eccentric comedy/crime film by the Coen brothers, they created an outstanding movie. The actors/actress in the film was perfectly unified in a great way that audience could build a vision of the plot. If you can handle the graphic dialogue used and suggestive behavior this is the right movie for you. The theme of the film is Jeff "Dude"Lebowski (Jeff Bridges) discovers he is a victim of mistaken identity. Thugs were sent to his home by Jackie Treehorn (Ben Gazzara) to recover a debit; Big Lebowski's (The Millionaire) wife owes him. Before the thugs realize they have the wrong Lebowski and that he's the "Dude" they urinate of his rug; leaving Dude in disgust. Dude pays BigLebowski (David Huddleston) a visit to be compensated for his rug being destroyed. Big Lebowski filled with arrogance; felt he was there looking for a hand out. Dude felt the conversation wasn't getting anywhere and decided he would take a rug from Lebowski home to be even. When Bunny (Tara Reid) disappears (Lebowski's wife); Big Lebowski contacts Dude making him an offer to be the bagman. The only thing Dude has to do is deliver the ransom money for Bunny. Dude brings Walter (John Goodman) along to make the drop. When the drop goes to pieces it creates a ricochet of others trying to reclaim the ransom money. While home listening to the soothing sounds of the bowling pins being knocked down, he discovers 3 people standing over him. They knocked him out and he begins to hallucinate; the lighting becomes dark with bright lights in the sky as he floats in sky. During the hallucination Dude see the rug he confiscated from Big Lebowski's. He is woken once his bowling ball drops him back to the surface. After coming back to reality, Dude is greeted by a women flying through the air on a stripe line in the nude, Maude Lebowski (Julianne Moore). Dude and Maude forms a relationship. Dude without realizing has been sized up to be a sperm donor of her child. Dude experienced many encounters because he was trying to clear his identity. After having sex with Maude and enjoy a marijuana joint, at that moment Dude realized the reasoning behind the mistaken identity fiasco. In conclusion, as a motif in the film "Dude" was the main character's name; however, it was used as a common word of expression during dialogue. Dude was able to regain his identity and continued being the old lazy, laid back, unemployed, and bowler from Southern California.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
