<filme>
 <id>
  903
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118566
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Despertar do Desejo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A handyman with marital problems meets a housewife with the same.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Two families are unhappy with their respective relationships: first of ambitious businessman Jeffrey Byron and sexually frustrated Marianne and second of repair contractor Lucky Mann and former B-movie actress Phyllis. When Lucky arrives to Byron's apartment to make some minor repair and Marianne becomes obsessed with him, the everyday balance breaks.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   repair
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   housewife
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   businessman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   handyman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   older man younger woman relationship
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Alan Rudolph
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Alan Rudolph
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Nick Nolte
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Julie Christie
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lara Flynn Boyle
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Afterglow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This immoral and involuntarily couple-swapping modern-day allegory has its conspicuous foible to cater for a wider demography, a self-consumingly pitched battle falls unfulfilled, one can feel the highly-contrived scheme runs amok at the latter part, and the films ends in an emotional gratification which is too Utopian to be credible to believe. The film garners a third Oscar nomination for the divine Julie Christie (after a 26 year hiatus since MCCABE & MRS. MILLER in 1971), whose role is the thorniest among the two pairs, and the film's pathos concretely hinges on her crack knack to embody the old lady who has her personal magnetism to fling with a frigid and wealthy pretty boy (only half of her age) at a convincing ease. Julie gracefully accomplishes her mission meanwhile Nolte, Miller and Boyle are all in solid shape to enliven their characters with ample credibility, although the thunder remains to belong to Ms. Christie. The central trauma orbits a childless status quo, which both couple yearn to alter, Christie tries to find her daughter back (who has deserted her 8 years ago after overhearing a hidden truth); while the bourgeois young wife Boyle is in eager to get pregnant when his sexually glacial husband refuses or is unable to commit the task. The mirror reflection has been exerted as a recurring gambit in the film, and the not-so-often witty wisecracks could be derived from director/writer Alan's strenuous endeavor on the script. Overall this low-budget marital vignette delivers a dramatic thesis on the lust-harvesting adult world with less-than-eloquent material and theatrical mechanics. Only Julie Christie exhibits a satisfying portrayal to deserve the time and dime we proffer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Made no sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stancym-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only give it a 2 instead of a 1 because Julie Christie is always such a joy to watch. The problem is, you can't figure out what is going on much of the time. Plot lines seem to make no sense. Example: at the end, Christie is crying. Has her daughter died or not? That is never made clear. If not, what is she sobbing about? Then there is the scene where Christie tries to seduce husband Nolte. She is attempting to repair their marriage. It is not clear why he rejects her, he seems to love her and it was she who had called off their sex life, not he. There is no discussion of this event afterward to clarify things. Characters throughout behave in ways that seem very unlikely and you can't figure them out. If a movie is going to be this surreal and confusing, it should be funny or suspenseful. This is neither. The Jonny Lee Miller character is peculiar beyond belief and that is never resolved. You can't figure him out at all,even at the end. Enough said, avoid this movie. You can see Christie in Away from Her, a far superior film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Holds Up Better Thinking About It Than It Does Watching It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Afterglow" is one of those rare movies that I enjoyed thinking about afterwards more than I did actually watching it. Julie Christie and Nick Nolte give phenomenal performances as two adults engaged in naughty infidelities that have serious impacts on them and those they love. Director Alan Rudolph, a prot&eacute;g&eacute; of Robert Altman back when Altman was alive, gives the film a gauzy, dream-like quality that makes it stick in the mind long after you've watched it. The ending especially I found to be unnerving and haunting. Christie received her third Best Actress Academy Award nomination and her first since "McCabe and Mrs. Miller" 26 years earlier. Grade: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an instant favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Agnelin
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched this movie, and it has become one of my favorites. It takes great amounts of talent and a sensitive spirit to make a gripping, involving narration of something as common as two married couples with communication, emotional and sexual problems -but Alan Rudolph not only manages to do this, but offers us an absolutely perfect narration, filled with beauty and a sensitive and compassionate look on some of the most common human weaknesses, mistakes, wishes, and dreams. The movie introduces us to two couples: the middle-aged Manns, Lucky (Nolte) and Phyllis (a sublime Christie), and the in-their-thirties Byrons, Jeffrey (Miller) and Marianne (Boyle). The former are working class, and the latter are well-off. Both are in the middle of a crisis, due to different reasons, but parenthood and their sex life (or lack thereof) are some of the most obvious. Basically, the movie lets us have a look into each of the characters' desires and dreams, what they want out of their marriage and of life. Logically, the older couple has more regrets about the past, and each of the younger partners is more looking forward to a better future. The four people will become involved with each other in different ways, all full of potential for something better... or for disaster. All in all, the story is easy to follow and, although calm, it is never boring; all of the scenes reveal something important about the characters. Like some other commentators said, Rudolph has an especially good understanding of the female mind, and he is an admirer of the female beauty -he brings out the best, most beautiful and most admirable in Lara Flynn Boyle and Julie Christie, but also of other supporting female characters. The movie isn't as predictable as one might think, it isn't merely a story of dissatisfaction and relationship problems, and it has a few surprises in store for the viewer, but nothing too extravagant or hard to believe. It is, ultimately, a finely crafted parable of the loss of passion -for life, for love, for our dreams and aspirations- and how it is possible to get it back. I would recommend this movie to anyone. My rating is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The MOST Boring Movie--Had to Fastforward A LOT
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sarahanne2
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably the worst movie that I have ever seen. No sense of depth or fullness. Can't believe that this movie could be made. Shocked by Nick Nolte's hair---it was never combed once throughout the entire movie. The movie was very hard to sit through---I just didn't feel any sense of connection to the characters at all. I am trying to understand why some people seemed to enjoy it so much. To post on this board, you have to write ten lines about a movie. I am at a total loss on how to do that when the movie itself was so empty. This is a movie that you will not want to waste any amount of time on. Take my advice, do not watch this movie, even if it is the only one that you have access to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Julie Christie is great, LFB is rotten, well-lensed, poorly penned...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KrankyKryptonian (graythomasmovies@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** Caution --- Contains spoilers *** This film had potential; the beautiful and talented Julie Christie and the not-so-beautiful but talented Nick Nolte as husband and wife in a sexless marriage, where the partners have agreed that handyman Lucky (Nolte) can have "no-strings-attached" affairs (as if such a thing is possible). Jonny Lee Miller and Laura Flynn Boyle play the younger couple with a similar loveless/sexless (?) relationship. They are both easy on the eyes, but their acting talents pale in comparison to their looks and to the talents of Christie and Nolte. Amazingly, these two couples end up with each others' spouses when they decide to have an affair. I mean, what are the odds of that? (That's sarcasm, in case it's not clear from my tone of voice, ha-ha) There is a subplot with a coworker of the Miller character coming out of the closet, with the implication that the husband might be a repressed homosexual. There's a nice scene where the coworker comes to tell Miller that he is leaving the company. As he leaves the hotel through the revolving door, Phyllis (Christie) arrives in the next section of the door, making a visual metaphor to "swinging both ways" (Sorry, I couldn't resist.). Jonny Lee Miller impressed me with his acting ability here, compared to some of his earlier films, say Hackers, for example. However, I can't help but think how a few casting changes might have improved this movie. Peter Sarsgaard for Miller, and Kris Kristofferson for Nolte. LFB is easily the worst actor in this movie; almost anyone would be an improvement. She may improve with age or experience, but she was miscast in this movie. I enjoyed many of the visual elements of this movie. Christie and Nolte are talented and give good performances here; Christie, Miller, and LFB are easy on the eyes, as are the apartment sets, and some of the outdoor scenes. The movie as a whole, however, demands far too much "willing suspension of disbelief", even if you take it as a fantasy. There are better ways to spend your money; but, if you are sitting at home with nothing to do some day and this movie comes to cable, you might give it a try. That's what I did. Not sorry I saw it, but it's not worth seeing again, or buying the DVD, or seeing it in a theater. It's just OK - 4/10 stars. -- Gray Thomas, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, USA
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Only Film I've Ever Walked Out On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marinar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dreadful puns. Unbearable middle-class, underwritten archness. Acting, script that jars even more mercilessly once you realize they're not elements of an avant-garde distanciation strategy. Probably the only film I've ever seen that elicited sheer untrammeled loathing at every moment of viewing, usually bad films only evoke a mild bemusement and wondering when it'll be over, an expectation that it may improve. Compare with meeting someone who fills you with such futility and tedium after the first few words of conversation that you just walk away from them with no excuses or explanations. This film is that person. tedious, irritating schlock.A pristine 'chamber piece' of fatuous complacency. The 1st 20 min came with such an undertow of nauseous inertia, life flashing before eyes, etc, that didn't stick with it. Maybe should watch it again? Do they all get blown up in the end?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delectable treat for those who can chew with patience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jugu Abraham (jugu_abraham@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the movie for a second time, 5 years after the first viewing, and realized that this is not a movie to view casually on a tired evening. My initial assessment was that Julie Christie and Nick Nolte were arresting in a movie with some clever camera-work by Toyomichi Kurita assisted with some interesting music by Mark Isham. Period. The second, more-attentive viewing allowed me to savor the intelligent script and unusual direction of Alan Rudolph. The script is remarkably close to Edward Albee's "Who's afraid of Viginia Woolf"-both have two sets of couples, each set a generation apart, the older one ruing the loss of a child. Rudolph presents a script on sex without sex though peppered with wit that could make Noel Coward pale in comparison. For example: "I'm Jeffrey Byron III. There won't be a IV. We Byrons quit when we get it right." Or "I did notice your wedding ring!" And the response "It's removable!" The wit is not obviousI missed much of it on the first casual viewingunlike the name of the lead character "Lucky Mann," married to an attractive actress who is can be acerbic with her very attractive aging handyman husband as she smirks "How was work today, Lucky? Unclog a few tubes?" The film is not propped up by the Shawian script alone (interestingly Director Robert Altman is the producer), but Director Rudolph extracts fascinating performance from top four actors who are thoroughly believable. The anguished cry of Julie Christie is the key to the film that transforms Rudolph's script from clever humor to mature tragedy. It is this cry that makes you reevaluate the entire film, why Jeffery (Jonny Lee Miller) balances on roof edges, why Phyllis' (the mesmerizing Julie Christie) "soul needs an overhaul", and why Rudolph allows Kurita to make his camera do a cartwheel at several points in the film. Clever, Mr Rudolph, but how many will have the patience to savor it all. Finally, Rudolph has successfully brought out the incredible charm of Julie Christie and the potential of Nick Nolte as actors. It is a pity Christie missed a second Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good Alan Rudolph movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marymorrissey
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    elements of it really are cringe worthy, the name lucky Mann and the smarmy way Nick Nolte talks to his ladies above all. johnny lee miller is so hot, so hot/cold, so interesting I'd never seen him in anything before he looks kind of like an actor from the 40s only with real skin and that turns out to be remarkably hot. as Julie Christie says he is "young and beautiful". Julie Christie really is "a revelation" although in a couple of her scenes the choices do seem a bit extreme or the direction but she deserved a nomination or something. I mean the last shot of her is really well cringe worthy but when you think about actually it it makes sense. she feels nick and Lara are making the nursery together with the idea of having this baby together. she thinks this girl has given him what she did not, having duped him instead, so her despair makes sense. still ... the shot is like oh wow what is this in its wailing pouring ashes upon ones' head it seems to come out of nowhere and it lasts forever and it's pretty unpleasant viewing no two ways about it. in answer to the question what is johnny's problem with Lara well it does appear that he's into older women. what's puzzling is the problem he has with Julie Christie when she humiliates this guy he really hates and turns to him like let's do it and he's like no that was a turn off, you were too slutty with him, we are supposed to imagine he has concluded, basically. say what? she was hardly being slutty, her seductiveness was mocking when she says "perhaps another time", emasculating. she even takes the man's phallic symbol champagne bottle from him in case you didn't get it. I felt really cheated that Julie Christie didn't' get laid but I guess the idea is she was already impregnated years before and nick is now making' a baby of his own that she doesn't get to share and thus the rip in their union is healed. as for Lara and johnny, well, they get to be Young and beautiful and perhaps when Lara is older and johnny is a geezer he will want her more! in answer to the question what is this film about what the heck was it all of Alan Rudolph's movies pretty much are about the one and only about "once I'm married my wives own me" as mickey says in choose me "it's other people who pull you apart" he goes to extreme lengths to prove this rather like Stanley Kubrick going overboard to defend freedom of thought in a clockwork orange. anyway this one is a good one not disappointing because it's funny and kinda sweet and kinda sexy and it has that amazing Alan Rudolph style, the slow camera movements through which various objects pass on different paths, these gavotte like "spires of martinville" like polyphonic spacial relationships are explored so seductively. it was a tad too long. and yeah the sets were awesome. the score was really nice too with some particularly gorgeous haunting moments when that female solo voice reiterates the one note... also the girl who has the nonspeaking role of the daughter of nick and Julie is just gorgeous. Good Alan Rudolph movie. not like "mrs parker" which was one of the disappointing ones or "trixie" which was nauseating. . .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an elegant film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (pat@globalxpres.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The writer/ director Alan Rudolph clearly understands the beauty of woman. The combination of Julie Christie and Lara Flynn Boyle is beautifully juxtaposed. Nick Nolte provides the rough male energy that highlights the facets of the younger / older woman beauty esthetic. The screenplay provided excellent scenes and the camera work and lighting was top notch. My only disappointment was that I did not see this gem on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Afterglow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This immoral and involuntarily couple-swapping modern-day allegory has its conspicuous foible to cater for a wider demography, a self-consumingly pitched battle falls unfulfilled, one can feel the highly-contrived scheme runs amok at the latter part, and the films ends in an emotional gratification which is too Utopian to be credible to believe. The film garners a third Oscar nomination for the divine Julie Christie (after a 26 year hiatus since MCCABE & MRS. MILLER in 1971), whose role is the thorniest among the two pairs, and the film's pathos concretely hinges on her crack knack to embody the old lady who has her personal magnetism to fling with a frigid and wealthy pretty boy (only half of her age) at a convincing ease. Julie gracefully accomplishes her mission meanwhile Nolte, Miller and Boyle are all in solid shape to enliven their characters with ample credibility, although the thunder remains to belong to Ms. Christie. The central trauma orbits a childless status quo, which both couple yearn to alter, Christie tries to find her daughter back (who has deserted her 8 years ago after overhearing a hidden truth); while the bourgeois young wife Boyle is in eager to get pregnant when his sexually glacial husband refuses or is unable to commit the task. The mirror reflection has been exerted as a recurring gambit in the film, and the not-so-often witty wisecracks could be derived from director/writer Alan's strenuous endeavor on the script. Overall this low-budget marital vignette delivers a dramatic thesis on the lust-harvesting adult world with less-than-eloquent material and theatrical mechanics. Only Julie Christie exhibits a satisfying portrayal to deserve the time and dime we proffer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Made no sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stancym-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only give it a 2 instead of a 1 because Julie Christie is always such a joy to watch. The problem is, you can't figure out what is going on much of the time. Plot lines seem to make no sense. Example: at the end, Christie is crying. Has her daughter died or not? That is never made clear. If not, what is she sobbing about? Then there is the scene where Christie tries to seduce husband Nolte. She is attempting to repair their marriage. It is not clear why he rejects her, he seems to love her and it was she who had called off their sex life, not he. There is no discussion of this event afterward to clarify things. Characters throughout behave in ways that seem very unlikely and you can't figure them out. If a movie is going to be this surreal and confusing, it should be funny or suspenseful. This is neither. The Jonny Lee Miller character is peculiar beyond belief and that is never resolved. You can't figure him out at all,even at the end. Enough said, avoid this movie. You can see Christie in Away from Her, a far superior film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Holds Up Better Thinking About It Than It Does Watching It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Afterglow" is one of those rare movies that I enjoyed thinking about afterwards more than I did actually watching it. Julie Christie and Nick Nolte give phenomenal performances as two adults engaged in naughty infidelities that have serious impacts on them and those they love. Director Alan Rudolph, a prot&eacute;g&eacute; of Robert Altman back when Altman was alive, gives the film a gauzy, dream-like quality that makes it stick in the mind long after you've watched it. The ending especially I found to be unnerving and haunting. Christie received her third Best Actress Academy Award nomination and her first since "McCabe and Mrs. Miller" 26 years earlier. Grade: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an instant favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Agnelin
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched this movie, and it has become one of my favorites. It takes great amounts of talent and a sensitive spirit to make a gripping, involving narration of something as common as two married couples with communication, emotional and sexual problems -but Alan Rudolph not only manages to do this, but offers us an absolutely perfect narration, filled with beauty and a sensitive and compassionate look on some of the most common human weaknesses, mistakes, wishes, and dreams. The movie introduces us to two couples: the middle-aged Manns, Lucky (Nolte) and Phyllis (a sublime Christie), and the in-their-thirties Byrons, Jeffrey (Miller) and Marianne (Boyle). The former are working class, and the latter are well-off. Both are in the middle of a crisis, due to different reasons, but parenthood and their sex life (or lack thereof) are some of the most obvious. Basically, the movie lets us have a look into each of the characters' desires and dreams, what they want out of their marriage and of life. Logically, the older couple has more regrets about the past, and each of the younger partners is more looking forward to a better future. The four people will become involved with each other in different ways, all full of potential for something better... or for disaster. All in all, the story is easy to follow and, although calm, it is never boring; all of the scenes reveal something important about the characters. Like some other commentators said, Rudolph has an especially good understanding of the female mind, and he is an admirer of the female beauty -he brings out the best, most beautiful and most admirable in Lara Flynn Boyle and Julie Christie, but also of other supporting female characters. The movie isn't as predictable as one might think, it isn't merely a story of dissatisfaction and relationship problems, and it has a few surprises in store for the viewer, but nothing too extravagant or hard to believe. It is, ultimately, a finely crafted parable of the loss of passion -for life, for love, for our dreams and aspirations- and how it is possible to get it back. I would recommend this movie to anyone. My rating is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The MOST Boring Movie--Had to Fastforward A LOT
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sarahanne2
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably the worst movie that I have ever seen. No sense of depth or fullness. Can't believe that this movie could be made. Shocked by Nick Nolte's hair---it was never combed once throughout the entire movie. The movie was very hard to sit through---I just didn't feel any sense of connection to the characters at all. I am trying to understand why some people seemed to enjoy it so much. To post on this board, you have to write ten lines about a movie. I am at a total loss on how to do that when the movie itself was so empty. This is a movie that you will not want to waste any amount of time on. Take my advice, do not watch this movie, even if it is the only one that you have access to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Julie Christie is great, LFB is rotten, well-lensed, poorly penned...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KrankyKryptonian (graythomasmovies@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** Caution --- Contains spoilers *** This film had potential; the beautiful and talented Julie Christie and the not-so-beautiful but talented Nick Nolte as husband and wife in a sexless marriage, where the partners have agreed that handyman Lucky (Nolte) can have "no-strings-attached" affairs (as if such a thing is possible). Jonny Lee Miller and Laura Flynn Boyle play the younger couple with a similar loveless/sexless (?) relationship. They are both easy on the eyes, but their acting talents pale in comparison to their looks and to the talents of Christie and Nolte. Amazingly, these two couples end up with each others' spouses when they decide to have an affair. I mean, what are the odds of that? (That's sarcasm, in case it's not clear from my tone of voice, ha-ha) There is a subplot with a coworker of the Miller character coming out of the closet, with the implication that the husband might be a repressed homosexual. There's a nice scene where the coworker comes to tell Miller that he is leaving the company. As he leaves the hotel through the revolving door, Phyllis (Christie) arrives in the next section of the door, making a visual metaphor to "swinging both ways" (Sorry, I couldn't resist.). Jonny Lee Miller impressed me with his acting ability here, compared to some of his earlier films, say Hackers, for example. However, I can't help but think how a few casting changes might have improved this movie. Peter Sarsgaard for Miller, and Kris Kristofferson for Nolte. LFB is easily the worst actor in this movie; almost anyone would be an improvement. She may improve with age or experience, but she was miscast in this movie. I enjoyed many of the visual elements of this movie. Christie and Nolte are talented and give good performances here; Christie, Miller, and LFB are easy on the eyes, as are the apartment sets, and some of the outdoor scenes. The movie as a whole, however, demands far too much "willing suspension of disbelief", even if you take it as a fantasy. There are better ways to spend your money; but, if you are sitting at home with nothing to do some day and this movie comes to cable, you might give it a try. That's what I did. Not sorry I saw it, but it's not worth seeing again, or buying the DVD, or seeing it in a theater. It's just OK - 4/10 stars. -- Gray Thomas, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, USA
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Only Film I've Ever Walked Out On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marinar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dreadful puns. Unbearable middle-class, underwritten archness. Acting, script that jars even more mercilessly once you realize they're not elements of an avant-garde distanciation strategy. Probably the only film I've ever seen that elicited sheer untrammeled loathing at every moment of viewing, usually bad films only evoke a mild bemusement and wondering when it'll be over, an expectation that it may improve. Compare with meeting someone who fills you with such futility and tedium after the first few words of conversation that you just walk away from them with no excuses or explanations. This film is that person. tedious, irritating schlock.A pristine 'chamber piece' of fatuous complacency. The 1st 20 min came with such an undertow of nauseous inertia, life flashing before eyes, etc, that didn't stick with it. Maybe should watch it again? Do they all get blown up in the end?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delectable treat for those who can chew with patience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jugu Abraham (jugu_abraham@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the movie for a second time, 5 years after the first viewing, and realized that this is not a movie to view casually on a tired evening. My initial assessment was that Julie Christie and Nick Nolte were arresting in a movie with some clever camera-work by Toyomichi Kurita assisted with some interesting music by Mark Isham. Period. The second, more-attentive viewing allowed me to savor the intelligent script and unusual direction of Alan Rudolph. The script is remarkably close to Edward Albee's "Who's afraid of Viginia Woolf"-both have two sets of couples, each set a generation apart, the older one ruing the loss of a child. Rudolph presents a script on sex without sex though peppered with wit that could make Noel Coward pale in comparison. For example: "I'm Jeffrey Byron III. There won't be a IV. We Byrons quit when we get it right." Or "I did notice your wedding ring!" And the response "It's removable!" The wit is not obviousI missed much of it on the first casual viewingunlike the name of the lead character "Lucky Mann," married to an attractive actress who is can be acerbic with her very attractive aging handyman husband as she smirks "How was work today, Lucky? Unclog a few tubes?" The film is not propped up by the Shawian script alone (interestingly Director Robert Altman is the producer), but Director Rudolph extracts fascinating performance from top four actors who are thoroughly believable. The anguished cry of Julie Christie is the key to the film that transforms Rudolph's script from clever humor to mature tragedy. It is this cry that makes you reevaluate the entire film, why Jeffery (Jonny Lee Miller) balances on roof edges, why Phyllis' (the mesmerizing Julie Christie) "soul needs an overhaul", and why Rudolph allows Kurita to make his camera do a cartwheel at several points in the film. Clever, Mr Rudolph, but how many will have the patience to savor it all. Finally, Rudolph has successfully brought out the incredible charm of Julie Christie and the potential of Nick Nolte as actors. It is a pity Christie missed a second Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good Alan Rudolph movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marymorrissey
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    elements of it really are cringe worthy, the name lucky Mann and the smarmy way Nick Nolte talks to his ladies above all. johnny lee miller is so hot, so hot/cold, so interesting I'd never seen him in anything before he looks kind of like an actor from the 40s only with real skin and that turns out to be remarkably hot. as Julie Christie says he is "young and beautiful". Julie Christie really is "a revelation" although in a couple of her scenes the choices do seem a bit extreme or the direction but she deserved a nomination or something. I mean the last shot of her is really well cringe worthy but when you think about actually it it makes sense. she feels nick and Lara are making the nursery together with the idea of having this baby together. she thinks this girl has given him what she did not, having duped him instead, so her despair makes sense. still ... the shot is like oh wow what is this in its wailing pouring ashes upon ones' head it seems to come out of nowhere and it lasts forever and it's pretty unpleasant viewing no two ways about it. in answer to the question what is johnny's problem with Lara well it does appear that he's into older women. what's puzzling is the problem he has with Julie Christie when she humiliates this guy he really hates and turns to him like let's do it and he's like no that was a turn off, you were too slutty with him, we are supposed to imagine he has concluded, basically. say what? she was hardly being slutty, her seductiveness was mocking when she says "perhaps another time", emasculating. she even takes the man's phallic symbol champagne bottle from him in case you didn't get it. I felt really cheated that Julie Christie didn't' get laid but I guess the idea is she was already impregnated years before and nick is now making' a baby of his own that she doesn't get to share and thus the rip in their union is healed. as for Lara and johnny, well, they get to be Young and beautiful and perhaps when Lara is older and johnny is a geezer he will want her more! in answer to the question what is this film about what the heck was it all of Alan Rudolph's movies pretty much are about the one and only about "once I'm married my wives own me" as mickey says in choose me "it's other people who pull you apart" he goes to extreme lengths to prove this rather like Stanley Kubrick going overboard to defend freedom of thought in a clockwork orange. anyway this one is a good one not disappointing because it's funny and kinda sweet and kinda sexy and it has that amazing Alan Rudolph style, the slow camera movements through which various objects pass on different paths, these gavotte like "spires of martinville" like polyphonic spacial relationships are explored so seductively. it was a tad too long. and yeah the sets were awesome. the score was really nice too with some particularly gorgeous haunting moments when that female solo voice reiterates the one note... also the girl who has the nonspeaking role of the daughter of nick and Julie is just gorgeous. Good Alan Rudolph movie. not like "mrs parker" which was one of the disappointing ones or "trixie" which was nauseating. . .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an elegant film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (pat@globalxpres.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The writer/ director Alan Rudolph clearly understands the beauty of woman. The combination of Julie Christie and Lara Flynn Boyle is beautifully juxtaposed. Nick Nolte provides the rough male energy that highlights the facets of the younger / older woman beauty esthetic. The screenplay provided excellent scenes and the camera work and lighting was top notch. My only disappointment was that I did not see this gem on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Afterglow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This immoral and involuntarily couple-swapping modern-day allegory has its conspicuous foible to cater for a wider demography, a self-consumingly pitched battle falls unfulfilled, one can feel the highly-contrived scheme runs amok at the latter part, and the films ends in an emotional gratification which is too Utopian to be credible to believe. The film garners a third Oscar nomination for the divine Julie Christie (after a 26 year hiatus since MCCABE & MRS. MILLER in 1971), whose role is the thorniest among the two pairs, and the film's pathos concretely hinges on her crack knack to embody the old lady who has her personal magnetism to fling with a frigid and wealthy pretty boy (only half of her age) at a convincing ease. Julie gracefully accomplishes her mission meanwhile Nolte, Miller and Boyle are all in solid shape to enliven their characters with ample credibility, although the thunder remains to belong to Ms. Christie. The central trauma orbits a childless status quo, which both couple yearn to alter, Christie tries to find her daughter back (who has deserted her 8 years ago after overhearing a hidden truth); while the bourgeois young wife Boyle is in eager to get pregnant when his sexually glacial husband refuses or is unable to commit the task. The mirror reflection has been exerted as a recurring gambit in the film, and the not-so-often witty wisecracks could be derived from director/writer Alan's strenuous endeavor on the script. Overall this low-budget marital vignette delivers a dramatic thesis on the lust-harvesting adult world with less-than-eloquent material and theatrical mechanics. Only Julie Christie exhibits a satisfying portrayal to deserve the time and dime we proffer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Made no sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stancym-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only give it a 2 instead of a 1 because Julie Christie is always such a joy to watch. The problem is, you can't figure out what is going on much of the time. Plot lines seem to make no sense. Example: at the end, Christie is crying. Has her daughter died or not? That is never made clear. If not, what is she sobbing about? Then there is the scene where Christie tries to seduce husband Nolte. She is attempting to repair their marriage. It is not clear why he rejects her, he seems to love her and it was she who had called off their sex life, not he. There is no discussion of this event afterward to clarify things. Characters throughout behave in ways that seem very unlikely and you can't figure them out. If a movie is going to be this surreal and confusing, it should be funny or suspenseful. This is neither. The Jonny Lee Miller character is peculiar beyond belief and that is never resolved. You can't figure him out at all,even at the end. Enough said, avoid this movie. You can see Christie in Away from Her, a far superior film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Holds Up Better Thinking About It Than It Does Watching It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Afterglow" is one of those rare movies that I enjoyed thinking about afterwards more than I did actually watching it. Julie Christie and Nick Nolte give phenomenal performances as two adults engaged in naughty infidelities that have serious impacts on them and those they love. Director Alan Rudolph, a prot&eacute;g&eacute; of Robert Altman back when Altman was alive, gives the film a gauzy, dream-like quality that makes it stick in the mind long after you've watched it. The ending especially I found to be unnerving and haunting. Christie received her third Best Actress Academy Award nomination and her first since "McCabe and Mrs. Miller" 26 years earlier. Grade: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an instant favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Agnelin
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched this movie, and it has become one of my favorites. It takes great amounts of talent and a sensitive spirit to make a gripping, involving narration of something as common as two married couples with communication, emotional and sexual problems -but Alan Rudolph not only manages to do this, but offers us an absolutely perfect narration, filled with beauty and a sensitive and compassionate look on some of the most common human weaknesses, mistakes, wishes, and dreams. The movie introduces us to two couples: the middle-aged Manns, Lucky (Nolte) and Phyllis (a sublime Christie), and the in-their-thirties Byrons, Jeffrey (Miller) and Marianne (Boyle). The former are working class, and the latter are well-off. Both are in the middle of a crisis, due to different reasons, but parenthood and their sex life (or lack thereof) are some of the most obvious. Basically, the movie lets us have a look into each of the characters' desires and dreams, what they want out of their marriage and of life. Logically, the older couple has more regrets about the past, and each of the younger partners is more looking forward to a better future. The four people will become involved with each other in different ways, all full of potential for something better... or for disaster. All in all, the story is easy to follow and, although calm, it is never boring; all of the scenes reveal something important about the characters. Like some other commentators said, Rudolph has an especially good understanding of the female mind, and he is an admirer of the female beauty -he brings out the best, most beautiful and most admirable in Lara Flynn Boyle and Julie Christie, but also of other supporting female characters. The movie isn't as predictable as one might think, it isn't merely a story of dissatisfaction and relationship problems, and it has a few surprises in store for the viewer, but nothing too extravagant or hard to believe. It is, ultimately, a finely crafted parable of the loss of passion -for life, for love, for our dreams and aspirations- and how it is possible to get it back. I would recommend this movie to anyone. My rating is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The MOST Boring Movie--Had to Fastforward A LOT
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sarahanne2
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably the worst movie that I have ever seen. No sense of depth or fullness. Can't believe that this movie could be made. Shocked by Nick Nolte's hair---it was never combed once throughout the entire movie. The movie was very hard to sit through---I just didn't feel any sense of connection to the characters at all. I am trying to understand why some people seemed to enjoy it so much. To post on this board, you have to write ten lines about a movie. I am at a total loss on how to do that when the movie itself was so empty. This is a movie that you will not want to waste any amount of time on. Take my advice, do not watch this movie, even if it is the only one that you have access to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Julie Christie is great, LFB is rotten, well-lensed, poorly penned...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KrankyKryptonian (graythomasmovies@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** Caution --- Contains spoilers *** This film had potential; the beautiful and talented Julie Christie and the not-so-beautiful but talented Nick Nolte as husband and wife in a sexless marriage, where the partners have agreed that handyman Lucky (Nolte) can have "no-strings-attached" affairs (as if such a thing is possible). Jonny Lee Miller and Laura Flynn Boyle play the younger couple with a similar loveless/sexless (?) relationship. They are both easy on the eyes, but their acting talents pale in comparison to their looks and to the talents of Christie and Nolte. Amazingly, these two couples end up with each others' spouses when they decide to have an affair. I mean, what are the odds of that? (That's sarcasm, in case it's not clear from my tone of voice, ha-ha) There is a subplot with a coworker of the Miller character coming out of the closet, with the implication that the husband might be a repressed homosexual. There's a nice scene where the coworker comes to tell Miller that he is leaving the company. As he leaves the hotel through the revolving door, Phyllis (Christie) arrives in the next section of the door, making a visual metaphor to "swinging both ways" (Sorry, I couldn't resist.). Jonny Lee Miller impressed me with his acting ability here, compared to some of his earlier films, say Hackers, for example. However, I can't help but think how a few casting changes might have improved this movie. Peter Sarsgaard for Miller, and Kris Kristofferson for Nolte. LFB is easily the worst actor in this movie; almost anyone would be an improvement. She may improve with age or experience, but she was miscast in this movie. I enjoyed many of the visual elements of this movie. Christie and Nolte are talented and give good performances here; Christie, Miller, and LFB are easy on the eyes, as are the apartment sets, and some of the outdoor scenes. The movie as a whole, however, demands far too much "willing suspension of disbelief", even if you take it as a fantasy. There are better ways to spend your money; but, if you are sitting at home with nothing to do some day and this movie comes to cable, you might give it a try. That's what I did. Not sorry I saw it, but it's not worth seeing again, or buying the DVD, or seeing it in a theater. It's just OK - 4/10 stars. -- Gray Thomas, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, USA
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Only Film I've Ever Walked Out On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marinar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dreadful puns. Unbearable middle-class, underwritten archness. Acting, script that jars even more mercilessly once you realize they're not elements of an avant-garde distanciation strategy. Probably the only film I've ever seen that elicited sheer untrammeled loathing at every moment of viewing, usually bad films only evoke a mild bemusement and wondering when it'll be over, an expectation that it may improve. Compare with meeting someone who fills you with such futility and tedium after the first few words of conversation that you just walk away from them with no excuses or explanations. This film is that person. tedious, irritating schlock.A pristine 'chamber piece' of fatuous complacency. The 1st 20 min came with such an undertow of nauseous inertia, life flashing before eyes, etc, that didn't stick with it. Maybe should watch it again? Do they all get blown up in the end?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delectable treat for those who can chew with patience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jugu Abraham (jugu_abraham@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the movie for a second time, 5 years after the first viewing, and realized that this is not a movie to view casually on a tired evening. My initial assessment was that Julie Christie and Nick Nolte were arresting in a movie with some clever camera-work by Toyomichi Kurita assisted with some interesting music by Mark Isham. Period. The second, more-attentive viewing allowed me to savor the intelligent script and unusual direction of Alan Rudolph. The script is remarkably close to Edward Albee's "Who's afraid of Viginia Woolf"-both have two sets of couples, each set a generation apart, the older one ruing the loss of a child. Rudolph presents a script on sex without sex though peppered with wit that could make Noel Coward pale in comparison. For example: "I'm Jeffrey Byron III. There won't be a IV. We Byrons quit when we get it right." Or "I did notice your wedding ring!" And the response "It's removable!" The wit is not obviousI missed much of it on the first casual viewingunlike the name of the lead character "Lucky Mann," married to an attractive actress who is can be acerbic with her very attractive aging handyman husband as she smirks "How was work today, Lucky? Unclog a few tubes?" The film is not propped up by the Shawian script alone (interestingly Director Robert Altman is the producer), but Director Rudolph extracts fascinating performance from top four actors who are thoroughly believable. The anguished cry of Julie Christie is the key to the film that transforms Rudolph's script from clever humor to mature tragedy. It is this cry that makes you reevaluate the entire film, why Jeffery (Jonny Lee Miller) balances on roof edges, why Phyllis' (the mesmerizing Julie Christie) "soul needs an overhaul", and why Rudolph allows Kurita to make his camera do a cartwheel at several points in the film. Clever, Mr Rudolph, but how many will have the patience to savor it all. Finally, Rudolph has successfully brought out the incredible charm of Julie Christie and the potential of Nick Nolte as actors. It is a pity Christie missed a second Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good Alan Rudolph movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marymorrissey
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    elements of it really are cringe worthy, the name lucky Mann and the smarmy way Nick Nolte talks to his ladies above all. johnny lee miller is so hot, so hot/cold, so interesting I'd never seen him in anything before he looks kind of like an actor from the 40s only with real skin and that turns out to be remarkably hot. as Julie Christie says he is "young and beautiful". Julie Christie really is "a revelation" although in a couple of her scenes the choices do seem a bit extreme or the direction but she deserved a nomination or something. I mean the last shot of her is really well cringe worthy but when you think about actually it it makes sense. she feels nick and Lara are making the nursery together with the idea of having this baby together. she thinks this girl has given him what she did not, having duped him instead, so her despair makes sense. still ... the shot is like oh wow what is this in its wailing pouring ashes upon ones' head it seems to come out of nowhere and it lasts forever and it's pretty unpleasant viewing no two ways about it. in answer to the question what is johnny's problem with Lara well it does appear that he's into older women. what's puzzling is the problem he has with Julie Christie when she humiliates this guy he really hates and turns to him like let's do it and he's like no that was a turn off, you were too slutty with him, we are supposed to imagine he has concluded, basically. say what? she was hardly being slutty, her seductiveness was mocking when she says "perhaps another time", emasculating. she even takes the man's phallic symbol champagne bottle from him in case you didn't get it. I felt really cheated that Julie Christie didn't' get laid but I guess the idea is she was already impregnated years before and nick is now making' a baby of his own that she doesn't get to share and thus the rip in their union is healed. as for Lara and johnny, well, they get to be Young and beautiful and perhaps when Lara is older and johnny is a geezer he will want her more! in answer to the question what is this film about what the heck was it all of Alan Rudolph's movies pretty much are about the one and only about "once I'm married my wives own me" as mickey says in choose me "it's other people who pull you apart" he goes to extreme lengths to prove this rather like Stanley Kubrick going overboard to defend freedom of thought in a clockwork orange. anyway this one is a good one not disappointing because it's funny and kinda sweet and kinda sexy and it has that amazing Alan Rudolph style, the slow camera movements through which various objects pass on different paths, these gavotte like "spires of martinville" like polyphonic spacial relationships are explored so seductively. it was a tad too long. and yeah the sets were awesome. the score was really nice too with some particularly gorgeous haunting moments when that female solo voice reiterates the one note... also the girl who has the nonspeaking role of the daughter of nick and Julie is just gorgeous. Good Alan Rudolph movie. not like "mrs parker" which was one of the disappointing ones or "trixie" which was nauseating. . .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an elegant film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (pat@globalxpres.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The writer/ director Alan Rudolph clearly understands the beauty of woman. The combination of Julie Christie and Lara Flynn Boyle is beautifully juxtaposed. Nick Nolte provides the rough male energy that highlights the facets of the younger / older woman beauty esthetic. The screenplay provided excellent scenes and the camera work and lighting was top notch. My only disappointment was that I did not see this gem on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Afterglow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This immoral and involuntarily couple-swapping modern-day allegory has its conspicuous foible to cater for a wider demography, a self-consumingly pitched battle falls unfulfilled, one can feel the highly-contrived scheme runs amok at the latter part, and the films ends in an emotional gratification which is too Utopian to be credible to believe. The film garners a third Oscar nomination for the divine Julie Christie (after a 26 year hiatus since MCCABE & MRS. MILLER in 1971), whose role is the thorniest among the two pairs, and the film's pathos concretely hinges on her crack knack to embody the old lady who has her personal magnetism to fling with a frigid and wealthy pretty boy (only half of her age) at a convincing ease. Julie gracefully accomplishes her mission meanwhile Nolte, Miller and Boyle are all in solid shape to enliven their characters with ample credibility, although the thunder remains to belong to Ms. Christie. The central trauma orbits a childless status quo, which both couple yearn to alter, Christie tries to find her daughter back (who has deserted her 8 years ago after overhearing a hidden truth); while the bourgeois young wife Boyle is in eager to get pregnant when his sexually glacial husband refuses or is unable to commit the task. The mirror reflection has been exerted as a recurring gambit in the film, and the not-so-often witty wisecracks could be derived from director/writer Alan's strenuous endeavor on the script. Overall this low-budget marital vignette delivers a dramatic thesis on the lust-harvesting adult world with less-than-eloquent material and theatrical mechanics. Only Julie Christie exhibits a satisfying portrayal to deserve the time and dime we proffer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Made no sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stancym-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only give it a 2 instead of a 1 because Julie Christie is always such a joy to watch. The problem is, you can't figure out what is going on much of the time. Plot lines seem to make no sense. Example: at the end, Christie is crying. Has her daughter died or not? That is never made clear. If not, what is she sobbing about? Then there is the scene where Christie tries to seduce husband Nolte. She is attempting to repair their marriage. It is not clear why he rejects her, he seems to love her and it was she who had called off their sex life, not he. There is no discussion of this event afterward to clarify things. Characters throughout behave in ways that seem very unlikely and you can't figure them out. If a movie is going to be this surreal and confusing, it should be funny or suspenseful. This is neither. The Jonny Lee Miller character is peculiar beyond belief and that is never resolved. You can't figure him out at all,even at the end. Enough said, avoid this movie. You can see Christie in Away from Her, a far superior film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Holds Up Better Thinking About It Than It Does Watching It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Afterglow" is one of those rare movies that I enjoyed thinking about afterwards more than I did actually watching it. Julie Christie and Nick Nolte give phenomenal performances as two adults engaged in naughty infidelities that have serious impacts on them and those they love. Director Alan Rudolph, a prot&eacute;g&eacute; of Robert Altman back when Altman was alive, gives the film a gauzy, dream-like quality that makes it stick in the mind long after you've watched it. The ending especially I found to be unnerving and haunting. Christie received her third Best Actress Academy Award nomination and her first since "McCabe and Mrs. Miller" 26 years earlier. Grade: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an instant favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Agnelin
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched this movie, and it has become one of my favorites. It takes great amounts of talent and a sensitive spirit to make a gripping, involving narration of something as common as two married couples with communication, emotional and sexual problems -but Alan Rudolph not only manages to do this, but offers us an absolutely perfect narration, filled with beauty and a sensitive and compassionate look on some of the most common human weaknesses, mistakes, wishes, and dreams. The movie introduces us to two couples: the middle-aged Manns, Lucky (Nolte) and Phyllis (a sublime Christie), and the in-their-thirties Byrons, Jeffrey (Miller) and Marianne (Boyle). The former are working class, and the latter are well-off. Both are in the middle of a crisis, due to different reasons, but parenthood and their sex life (or lack thereof) are some of the most obvious. Basically, the movie lets us have a look into each of the characters' desires and dreams, what they want out of their marriage and of life. Logically, the older couple has more regrets about the past, and each of the younger partners is more looking forward to a better future. The four people will become involved with each other in different ways, all full of potential for something better... or for disaster. All in all, the story is easy to follow and, although calm, it is never boring; all of the scenes reveal something important about the characters. Like some other commentators said, Rudolph has an especially good understanding of the female mind, and he is an admirer of the female beauty -he brings out the best, most beautiful and most admirable in Lara Flynn Boyle and Julie Christie, but also of other supporting female characters. The movie isn't as predictable as one might think, it isn't merely a story of dissatisfaction and relationship problems, and it has a few surprises in store for the viewer, but nothing too extravagant or hard to believe. It is, ultimately, a finely crafted parable of the loss of passion -for life, for love, for our dreams and aspirations- and how it is possible to get it back. I would recommend this movie to anyone. My rating is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The MOST Boring Movie--Had to Fastforward A LOT
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sarahanne2
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably the worst movie that I have ever seen. No sense of depth or fullness. Can't believe that this movie could be made. Shocked by Nick Nolte's hair---it was never combed once throughout the entire movie. The movie was very hard to sit through---I just didn't feel any sense of connection to the characters at all. I am trying to understand why some people seemed to enjoy it so much. To post on this board, you have to write ten lines about a movie. I am at a total loss on how to do that when the movie itself was so empty. This is a movie that you will not want to waste any amount of time on. Take my advice, do not watch this movie, even if it is the only one that you have access to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Julie Christie is great, LFB is rotten, well-lensed, poorly penned...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KrankyKryptonian (graythomasmovies@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** Caution --- Contains spoilers *** This film had potential; the beautiful and talented Julie Christie and the not-so-beautiful but talented Nick Nolte as husband and wife in a sexless marriage, where the partners have agreed that handyman Lucky (Nolte) can have "no-strings-attached" affairs (as if such a thing is possible). Jonny Lee Miller and Laura Flynn Boyle play the younger couple with a similar loveless/sexless (?) relationship. They are both easy on the eyes, but their acting talents pale in comparison to their looks and to the talents of Christie and Nolte. Amazingly, these two couples end up with each others' spouses when they decide to have an affair. I mean, what are the odds of that? (That's sarcasm, in case it's not clear from my tone of voice, ha-ha) There is a subplot with a coworker of the Miller character coming out of the closet, with the implication that the husband might be a repressed homosexual. There's a nice scene where the coworker comes to tell Miller that he is leaving the company. As he leaves the hotel through the revolving door, Phyllis (Christie) arrives in the next section of the door, making a visual metaphor to "swinging both ways" (Sorry, I couldn't resist.). Jonny Lee Miller impressed me with his acting ability here, compared to some of his earlier films, say Hackers, for example. However, I can't help but think how a few casting changes might have improved this movie. Peter Sarsgaard for Miller, and Kris Kristofferson for Nolte. LFB is easily the worst actor in this movie; almost anyone would be an improvement. She may improve with age or experience, but she was miscast in this movie. I enjoyed many of the visual elements of this movie. Christie and Nolte are talented and give good performances here; Christie, Miller, and LFB are easy on the eyes, as are the apartment sets, and some of the outdoor scenes. The movie as a whole, however, demands far too much "willing suspension of disbelief", even if you take it as a fantasy. There are better ways to spend your money; but, if you are sitting at home with nothing to do some day and this movie comes to cable, you might give it a try. That's what I did. Not sorry I saw it, but it's not worth seeing again, or buying the DVD, or seeing it in a theater. It's just OK - 4/10 stars. -- Gray Thomas, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, USA
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Only Film I've Ever Walked Out On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marinar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dreadful puns. Unbearable middle-class, underwritten archness. Acting, script that jars even more mercilessly once you realize they're not elements of an avant-garde distanciation strategy. Probably the only film I've ever seen that elicited sheer untrammeled loathing at every moment of viewing, usually bad films only evoke a mild bemusement and wondering when it'll be over, an expectation that it may improve. Compare with meeting someone who fills you with such futility and tedium after the first few words of conversation that you just walk away from them with no excuses or explanations. This film is that person. tedious, irritating schlock.A pristine 'chamber piece' of fatuous complacency. The 1st 20 min came with such an undertow of nauseous inertia, life flashing before eyes, etc, that didn't stick with it. Maybe should watch it again? Do they all get blown up in the end?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delectable treat for those who can chew with patience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jugu Abraham (jugu_abraham@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the movie for a second time, 5 years after the first viewing, and realized that this is not a movie to view casually on a tired evening. My initial assessment was that Julie Christie and Nick Nolte were arresting in a movie with some clever camera-work by Toyomichi Kurita assisted with some interesting music by Mark Isham. Period. The second, more-attentive viewing allowed me to savor the intelligent script and unusual direction of Alan Rudolph. The script is remarkably close to Edward Albee's "Who's afraid of Viginia Woolf"-both have two sets of couples, each set a generation apart, the older one ruing the loss of a child. Rudolph presents a script on sex without sex though peppered with wit that could make Noel Coward pale in comparison. For example: "I'm Jeffrey Byron III. There won't be a IV. We Byrons quit when we get it right." Or "I did notice your wedding ring!" And the response "It's removable!" The wit is not obviousI missed much of it on the first casual viewingunlike the name of the lead character "Lucky Mann," married to an attractive actress who is can be acerbic with her very attractive aging handyman husband as she smirks "How was work today, Lucky? Unclog a few tubes?" The film is not propped up by the Shawian script alone (interestingly Director Robert Altman is the producer), but Director Rudolph extracts fascinating performance from top four actors who are thoroughly believable. The anguished cry of Julie Christie is the key to the film that transforms Rudolph's script from clever humor to mature tragedy. It is this cry that makes you reevaluate the entire film, why Jeffery (Jonny Lee Miller) balances on roof edges, why Phyllis' (the mesmerizing Julie Christie) "soul needs an overhaul", and why Rudolph allows Kurita to make his camera do a cartwheel at several points in the film. Clever, Mr Rudolph, but how many will have the patience to savor it all. Finally, Rudolph has successfully brought out the incredible charm of Julie Christie and the potential of Nick Nolte as actors. It is a pity Christie missed a second Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good Alan Rudolph movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marymorrissey
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    elements of it really are cringe worthy, the name lucky Mann and the smarmy way Nick Nolte talks to his ladies above all. johnny lee miller is so hot, so hot/cold, so interesting I'd never seen him in anything before he looks kind of like an actor from the 40s only with real skin and that turns out to be remarkably hot. as Julie Christie says he is "young and beautiful". Julie Christie really is "a revelation" although in a couple of her scenes the choices do seem a bit extreme or the direction but she deserved a nomination or something. I mean the last shot of her is really well cringe worthy but when you think about actually it it makes sense. she feels nick and Lara are making the nursery together with the idea of having this baby together. she thinks this girl has given him what she did not, having duped him instead, so her despair makes sense. still ... the shot is like oh wow what is this in its wailing pouring ashes upon ones' head it seems to come out of nowhere and it lasts forever and it's pretty unpleasant viewing no two ways about it. in answer to the question what is johnny's problem with Lara well it does appear that he's into older women. what's puzzling is the problem he has with Julie Christie when she humiliates this guy he really hates and turns to him like let's do it and he's like no that was a turn off, you were too slutty with him, we are supposed to imagine he has concluded, basically. say what? she was hardly being slutty, her seductiveness was mocking when she says "perhaps another time", emasculating. she even takes the man's phallic symbol champagne bottle from him in case you didn't get it. I felt really cheated that Julie Christie didn't' get laid but I guess the idea is she was already impregnated years before and nick is now making' a baby of his own that she doesn't get to share and thus the rip in their union is healed. as for Lara and johnny, well, they get to be Young and beautiful and perhaps when Lara is older and johnny is a geezer he will want her more! in answer to the question what is this film about what the heck was it all of Alan Rudolph's movies pretty much are about the one and only about "once I'm married my wives own me" as mickey says in choose me "it's other people who pull you apart" he goes to extreme lengths to prove this rather like Stanley Kubrick going overboard to defend freedom of thought in a clockwork orange. anyway this one is a good one not disappointing because it's funny and kinda sweet and kinda sexy and it has that amazing Alan Rudolph style, the slow camera movements through which various objects pass on different paths, these gavotte like "spires of martinville" like polyphonic spacial relationships are explored so seductively. it was a tad too long. and yeah the sets were awesome. the score was really nice too with some particularly gorgeous haunting moments when that female solo voice reiterates the one note... also the girl who has the nonspeaking role of the daughter of nick and Julie is just gorgeous. Good Alan Rudolph movie. not like "mrs parker" which was one of the disappointing ones or "trixie" which was nauseating. . .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an elegant film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (pat@globalxpres.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The writer/ director Alan Rudolph clearly understands the beauty of woman. The combination of Julie Christie and Lara Flynn Boyle is beautifully juxtaposed. Nick Nolte provides the rough male energy that highlights the facets of the younger / older woman beauty esthetic. The screenplay provided excellent scenes and the camera work and lighting was top notch. My only disappointment was that I did not see this gem on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Afterglow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This immoral and involuntarily couple-swapping modern-day allegory has its conspicuous foible to cater for a wider demography, a self-consumingly pitched battle falls unfulfilled, one can feel the highly-contrived scheme runs amok at the latter part, and the films ends in an emotional gratification which is too Utopian to be credible to believe. The film garners a third Oscar nomination for the divine Julie Christie (after a 26 year hiatus since MCCABE & MRS. MILLER in 1971), whose role is the thorniest among the two pairs, and the film's pathos concretely hinges on her crack knack to embody the old lady who has her personal magnetism to fling with a frigid and wealthy pretty boy (only half of her age) at a convincing ease. Julie gracefully accomplishes her mission meanwhile Nolte, Miller and Boyle are all in solid shape to enliven their characters with ample credibility, although the thunder remains to belong to Ms. Christie. The central trauma orbits a childless status quo, which both couple yearn to alter, Christie tries to find her daughter back (who has deserted her 8 years ago after overhearing a hidden truth); while the bourgeois young wife Boyle is in eager to get pregnant when his sexually glacial husband refuses or is unable to commit the task. The mirror reflection has been exerted as a recurring gambit in the film, and the not-so-often witty wisecracks could be derived from director/writer Alan's strenuous endeavor on the script. Overall this low-budget marital vignette delivers a dramatic thesis on the lust-harvesting adult world with less-than-eloquent material and theatrical mechanics. Only Julie Christie exhibits a satisfying portrayal to deserve the time and dime we proffer.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Made no sense
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stancym-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I only give it a 2 instead of a 1 because Julie Christie is always such a joy to watch. The problem is, you can't figure out what is going on much of the time. Plot lines seem to make no sense. Example: at the end, Christie is crying. Has her daughter died or not? That is never made clear. If not, what is she sobbing about? Then there is the scene where Christie tries to seduce husband Nolte. She is attempting to repair their marriage. It is not clear why he rejects her, he seems to love her and it was she who had called off their sex life, not he. There is no discussion of this event afterward to clarify things. Characters throughout behave in ways that seem very unlikely and you can't figure them out. If a movie is going to be this surreal and confusing, it should be funny or suspenseful. This is neither. The Jonny Lee Miller character is peculiar beyond belief and that is never resolved. You can't figure him out at all,even at the end. Enough said, avoid this movie. You can see Christie in Away from Her, a far superior film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Holds Up Better Thinking About It Than It Does Watching It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Afterglow" is one of those rare movies that I enjoyed thinking about afterwards more than I did actually watching it. Julie Christie and Nick Nolte give phenomenal performances as two adults engaged in naughty infidelities that have serious impacts on them and those they love. Director Alan Rudolph, a prot&eacute;g&eacute; of Robert Altman back when Altman was alive, gives the film a gauzy, dream-like quality that makes it stick in the mind long after you've watched it. The ending especially I found to be unnerving and haunting. Christie received her third Best Actress Academy Award nomination and her first since "McCabe and Mrs. Miller" 26 years earlier. Grade: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an instant favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Agnelin
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched this movie, and it has become one of my favorites. It takes great amounts of talent and a sensitive spirit to make a gripping, involving narration of something as common as two married couples with communication, emotional and sexual problems -but Alan Rudolph not only manages to do this, but offers us an absolutely perfect narration, filled with beauty and a sensitive and compassionate look on some of the most common human weaknesses, mistakes, wishes, and dreams. The movie introduces us to two couples: the middle-aged Manns, Lucky (Nolte) and Phyllis (a sublime Christie), and the in-their-thirties Byrons, Jeffrey (Miller) and Marianne (Boyle). The former are working class, and the latter are well-off. Both are in the middle of a crisis, due to different reasons, but parenthood and their sex life (or lack thereof) are some of the most obvious. Basically, the movie lets us have a look into each of the characters' desires and dreams, what they want out of their marriage and of life. Logically, the older couple has more regrets about the past, and each of the younger partners is more looking forward to a better future. The four people will become involved with each other in different ways, all full of potential for something better... or for disaster. All in all, the story is easy to follow and, although calm, it is never boring; all of the scenes reveal something important about the characters. Like some other commentators said, Rudolph has an especially good understanding of the female mind, and he is an admirer of the female beauty -he brings out the best, most beautiful and most admirable in Lara Flynn Boyle and Julie Christie, but also of other supporting female characters. The movie isn't as predictable as one might think, it isn't merely a story of dissatisfaction and relationship problems, and it has a few surprises in store for the viewer, but nothing too extravagant or hard to believe. It is, ultimately, a finely crafted parable of the loss of passion -for life, for love, for our dreams and aspirations- and how it is possible to get it back. I would recommend this movie to anyone. My rating is 10/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The MOST Boring Movie--Had to Fastforward A LOT
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sarahanne2
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Probably the worst movie that I have ever seen. No sense of depth or fullness. Can't believe that this movie could be made. Shocked by Nick Nolte's hair---it was never combed once throughout the entire movie. The movie was very hard to sit through---I just didn't feel any sense of connection to the characters at all. I am trying to understand why some people seemed to enjoy it so much. To post on this board, you have to write ten lines about a movie. I am at a total loss on how to do that when the movie itself was so empty. This is a movie that you will not want to waste any amount of time on. Take my advice, do not watch this movie, even if it is the only one that you have access to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Julie Christie is great, LFB is rotten, well-lensed, poorly penned...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KrankyKryptonian (graythomasmovies@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *** Caution --- Contains spoilers *** This film had potential; the beautiful and talented Julie Christie and the not-so-beautiful but talented Nick Nolte as husband and wife in a sexless marriage, where the partners have agreed that handyman Lucky (Nolte) can have "no-strings-attached" affairs (as if such a thing is possible). Jonny Lee Miller and Laura Flynn Boyle play the younger couple with a similar loveless/sexless (?) relationship. They are both easy on the eyes, but their acting talents pale in comparison to their looks and to the talents of Christie and Nolte. Amazingly, these two couples end up with each others' spouses when they decide to have an affair. I mean, what are the odds of that? (That's sarcasm, in case it's not clear from my tone of voice, ha-ha) There is a subplot with a coworker of the Miller character coming out of the closet, with the implication that the husband might be a repressed homosexual. There's a nice scene where the coworker comes to tell Miller that he is leaving the company. As he leaves the hotel through the revolving door, Phyllis (Christie) arrives in the next section of the door, making a visual metaphor to "swinging both ways" (Sorry, I couldn't resist.). Jonny Lee Miller impressed me with his acting ability here, compared to some of his earlier films, say Hackers, for example. However, I can't help but think how a few casting changes might have improved this movie. Peter Sarsgaard for Miller, and Kris Kristofferson for Nolte. LFB is easily the worst actor in this movie; almost anyone would be an improvement. She may improve with age or experience, but she was miscast in this movie. I enjoyed many of the visual elements of this movie. Christie and Nolte are talented and give good performances here; Christie, Miller, and LFB are easy on the eyes, as are the apartment sets, and some of the outdoor scenes. The movie as a whole, however, demands far too much "willing suspension of disbelief", even if you take it as a fantasy. There are better ways to spend your money; but, if you are sitting at home with nothing to do some day and this movie comes to cable, you might give it a try. That's what I did. Not sorry I saw it, but it's not worth seeing again, or buying the DVD, or seeing it in a theater. It's just OK - 4/10 stars. -- Gray Thomas, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, USA
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Only Film I've Ever Walked Out On
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marinar-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dreadful puns. Unbearable middle-class, underwritten archness. Acting, script that jars even more mercilessly once you realize they're not elements of an avant-garde distanciation strategy. Probably the only film I've ever seen that elicited sheer untrammeled loathing at every moment of viewing, usually bad films only evoke a mild bemusement and wondering when it'll be over, an expectation that it may improve. Compare with meeting someone who fills you with such futility and tedium after the first few words of conversation that you just walk away from them with no excuses or explanations. This film is that person. tedious, irritating schlock.A pristine 'chamber piece' of fatuous complacency. The 1st 20 min came with such an undertow of nauseous inertia, life flashing before eyes, etc, that didn't stick with it. Maybe should watch it again? Do they all get blown up in the end?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delectable treat for those who can chew with patience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jugu Abraham (jugu_abraham@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw the movie for a second time, 5 years after the first viewing, and realized that this is not a movie to view casually on a tired evening. My initial assessment was that Julie Christie and Nick Nolte were arresting in a movie with some clever camera-work by Toyomichi Kurita assisted with some interesting music by Mark Isham. Period. The second, more-attentive viewing allowed me to savor the intelligent script and unusual direction of Alan Rudolph. The script is remarkably close to Edward Albee's "Who's afraid of Viginia Woolf"-both have two sets of couples, each set a generation apart, the older one ruing the loss of a child. Rudolph presents a script on sex without sex though peppered with wit that could make Noel Coward pale in comparison. For example: "I'm Jeffrey Byron III. There won't be a IV. We Byrons quit when we get it right." Or "I did notice your wedding ring!" And the response "It's removable!" The wit is not obviousI missed much of it on the first casual viewingunlike the name of the lead character "Lucky Mann," married to an attractive actress who is can be acerbic with her very attractive aging handyman husband as she smirks "How was work today, Lucky? Unclog a few tubes?" The film is not propped up by the Shawian script alone (interestingly Director Robert Altman is the producer), but Director Rudolph extracts fascinating performance from top four actors who are thoroughly believable. The anguished cry of Julie Christie is the key to the film that transforms Rudolph's script from clever humor to mature tragedy. It is this cry that makes you reevaluate the entire film, why Jeffery (Jonny Lee Miller) balances on roof edges, why Phyllis' (the mesmerizing Julie Christie) "soul needs an overhaul", and why Rudolph allows Kurita to make his camera do a cartwheel at several points in the film. Clever, Mr Rudolph, but how many will have the patience to savor it all. Finally, Rudolph has successfully brought out the incredible charm of Julie Christie and the potential of Nick Nolte as actors. It is a pity Christie missed a second Academy Award!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good Alan Rudolph movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marymorrissey
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    elements of it really are cringe worthy, the name lucky Mann and the smarmy way Nick Nolte talks to his ladies above all. johnny lee miller is so hot, so hot/cold, so interesting I'd never seen him in anything before he looks kind of like an actor from the 40s only with real skin and that turns out to be remarkably hot. as Julie Christie says he is "young and beautiful". Julie Christie really is "a revelation" although in a couple of her scenes the choices do seem a bit extreme or the direction but she deserved a nomination or something. I mean the last shot of her is really well cringe worthy but when you think about actually it it makes sense. she feels nick and Lara are making the nursery together with the idea of having this baby together. she thinks this girl has given him what she did not, having duped him instead, so her despair makes sense. still ... the shot is like oh wow what is this in its wailing pouring ashes upon ones' head it seems to come out of nowhere and it lasts forever and it's pretty unpleasant viewing no two ways about it. in answer to the question what is johnny's problem with Lara well it does appear that he's into older women. what's puzzling is the problem he has with Julie Christie when she humiliates this guy he really hates and turns to him like let's do it and he's like no that was a turn off, you were too slutty with him, we are supposed to imagine he has concluded, basically. say what? she was hardly being slutty, her seductiveness was mocking when she says "perhaps another time", emasculating. she even takes the man's phallic symbol champagne bottle from him in case you didn't get it. I felt really cheated that Julie Christie didn't' get laid but I guess the idea is she was already impregnated years before and nick is now making' a baby of his own that she doesn't get to share and thus the rip in their union is healed. as for Lara and johnny, well, they get to be Young and beautiful and perhaps when Lara is older and johnny is a geezer he will want her more! in answer to the question what is this film about what the heck was it all of Alan Rudolph's movies pretty much are about the one and only about "once I'm married my wives own me" as mickey says in choose me "it's other people who pull you apart" he goes to extreme lengths to prove this rather like Stanley Kubrick going overboard to defend freedom of thought in a clockwork orange. anyway this one is a good one not disappointing because it's funny and kinda sweet and kinda sexy and it has that amazing Alan Rudolph style, the slow camera movements through which various objects pass on different paths, these gavotte like "spires of martinville" like polyphonic spacial relationships are explored so seductively. it was a tad too long. and yeah the sets were awesome. the score was really nice too with some particularly gorgeous haunting moments when that female solo voice reiterates the one note... also the girl who has the nonspeaking role of the daughter of nick and Julie is just gorgeous. Good Alan Rudolph movie. not like "mrs parker" which was one of the disappointing ones or "trixie" which was nauseating. . .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an elegant film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (pat@globalxpres.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The writer/ director Alan Rudolph clearly understands the beauty of woman. The combination of Julie Christie and Lara Flynn Boyle is beautifully juxtaposed. Nick Nolte provides the rough male energy that highlights the facets of the younger / older woman beauty esthetic. The screenplay provided excellent scenes and the camera work and lighting was top notch. My only disappointment was that I did not see this gem on the big screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
