<filme>
 <id>
  904
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119590
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Minha Vida em Cor-de-Rosa
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Ludovic is a small boy who cross-dresses and generally acts like a girl, talks of marrying his neighbor's son and can not understand why everyone is so surprised about it. His actions lead ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Ludovic is a small boy who cross-dresses and generally acts like a girl, talks of marrying his neighbor's son and can not understand why everyone is so surprised about it. His actions lead to problems for him and his family.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   boy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   girl
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   neighbor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new neighbor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gender
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Alain Berliner
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Alain Berliner
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Chris Vander Stappen
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Georges Du Fresne
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Mich&egrave;le Laroque
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jean-Philippe &Eacute;coffey
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    fantastic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Valentin
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Life in Pink is a french drama of a 7 year old boy named Ludovic who wishes to be a girl, henceforth decides to dress and act like one, but his actions begin to slowly anger the citizens of the conservative neighborhood they live in, and the problems begin. A film that takes a rarely touched upon subject and treats it with care and gravity. Filming it in such a way that you are experiencing the events through the eyes of Ludovic, you grow a care for the child, because he is so innocent and sincere that you can't help but feel bad or angry at the people berating and punishing him all throughout the story. Ludovic's parents had a difficult role as they try to control and take away something that is slowly but surely beginning to affect their normal lives as well. Their acting is just fantastic, and they were written very well, and while the film revolves around Ludovic, the stars of the film are his parents IMO. Props to Mich&egrave;le Laroque and Jean- Philippe &Eacute;coffey. With a well executed drama, the film also has very subtle symbolism on religion and social norms that i feel should be noted, as it gives an extra sense of value to the film, especially since the filmmakers didn't make the symbolism obvious and in your face. The only thing i can say i didn't like was the ending, while the whole scene felt mostly metaphorical, and it's possible i missed something, i can't help but feel it was forced and poorly handled to have a happy ending. but that is only one small part of an otherwise good drama. If you enjoy, heartfelt, social dramas i feel you may enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tells it like it is...possibly triggering?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neuroplastic42
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **spoiler alert** This movie very accurately portrayed what its like growing up with a feminine gender expression, while having been coercively assigned male at birth. Having yet to experience years of sexual harassment and bullying, Ludovic's simple straightforward insistence that she is a girl is heartfelt and unassuming. She sees no danger with dressing in the clothes her sister gets to wear, pretending to be a bride, or telling her new friends she'll be a girl someday. But sadly, it seems everyone else in the film wants to strip that internal confidence from Ludovic. Her parents bully her so much, culminating in physical abuse, as well as Ludo's mother holding her down and cutting her hair. All this causes poor Ludo to attempt suicide and move out of her parents house, because her family hates and blames her. At age seven. The scenes with the father were difficult to watch...scary men shouldn't have a place in a young trans girl's life. I had to stop the movie and watch over two nights. It was like living with my father again.. so, really good directing, I guess. Not a happy ending, either. As far as I can tell, Ludo has hidden her feminine activities for fear of her parents reactions. When offered feminine clothing, Ludo's face lights up, and then quickly darkens in fear (excellent acting!). Ludo's fears are confirmed, as she is hit across the face multiple times and strangled by her mother. Mere MINUTES after the abuse, Ludo's mother says "You can wear whatever you want".....Are we supposed to believe that statement? Are we supposed to believe that an abuser has stopped abusing, with no treatment? It's clear that Ludo can never return to that innocent age of childhood, where gender expression was simply "what I want to do". Ludo entered into the transgender world of adults at the age of seven, learning that feminine gender expression can make you a target of sexual violence, even from your own parents. This is a movie that does not act as a role model for how to accept trans children in your community. This is not a feel-good family movie comedy. This movie shows what children with atypical gender expression go through right now, every day.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Imperfect, but original and worth seeing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very sweet, well intended, good-natured film about a 7 year old boy who is convinced he's supposed to be a girl, and wants to dress and act accordingly. His parents' confusion, and inability to deal with the situation are shown without making them monsters, even as it all starts to tear at the fabric of the family, costing the father his job, etc. What didn't work as well for me was the weaving in of the Tim Burton-esque magical realism/fantasy element of the young boy's dream world. Somehow, in the end, the film felt too light and sunny to really rip at your guts, and yet too dark to just enjoy as a wish fulfillment fantasy of the way the world should be. So while well worth seeing, it ends up as a little less than it has signs of becoming.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite lovely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian W. Fairbanks (brianwfairbanks@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Ma Vie En Rose," winner of the 1997 Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film (its English title is "My Life in Pink"), concerns Ludo, a 7-year-old boy who likes to dress up as a girl and dreams of marrying a boy, even staging a mock wedding with himself decked out in a pink satin dress and pearls. His parents are appalled. When Ludo makes an appearance at a family gathering dressed as a girl, the father covers his embarrassment with nervous laughter and insists his son is just joking. The mother drags him to the sink to wash off his lipstick. When Ludo continues to cross-dress, they take him to a therapist "to set him straight." Ludo's attempts to be a typical boy prove disastrous, however. When he tries to kiss a girl, she knocks him to the ground. "I don't kiss girls," she sneers. He proves too gentle for football, and when another boy sees him through the opening of a toilet stall, sitting down to pee, he explains that he's a "girl-boy." Of course, Ludo is almost certain to grow up to be homosexual or transgender, perhaps opting to change his gender through surgery. The film doesn't take us that far into the future, but does conclude on a note of acceptance. "Whatever happens, you'll always be my child," the father tells Ludo, shortly before the credits roll. The boy in "Ma Vie En Rose" is adorable, and is very convincing when dolled up as a female. The film itself is quite lovely. Undoubtedly, there are those who would assail it as propaganda meant to promote tolerance toward homosexuals and gender-bending boys. Maybe it is, but the fact remains that there are boys who want to be girls, and such boys would exist even if a film like Ma Vie En Rose did not. If it succeeds in making the life of a "girl boy" easier, what's wrong with that? Brian W. Fairbanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An exceptional film about acceptance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Loisroselyn
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just finished earning my master's degree in Psychology. This film fits right in with what I've learned. It is touching and enlightening. I believe that every person should view this film before having children. Accept everyone for who they are and don't try to change them. We live in a diverse world, we should enjoy it instead of manipulating it. Open your eyes. This story is not limited to gender specifications and expectations. It is about being accepted for who we are - period. I highly recommend this film. I rented it from Netflix, so I know that it's available. It's important to recognize the name as "Ma Vie En Rose," rather than "La Vie En Rose."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A girlboy, for the love of God! This is all your fault!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This ain't Peter Pan! When Ludovic (Georges Du Fresne) wants to escape, he gets Pam (Delphine Cadet) a Barbie-like creature that sprinkles magic dust and flies off with Ludovic in tow. Ludovic is different, maybe a transsexual, he is only seven, you know, but he likes to dress up like a girls. he plans to marry his father's boss' son when he is older. You can look at this film as being about homophobia, but you can also take the larger view that it is about society's ostracizing of anyone who doesn't fit in their cookie-cutter mold. It is a sweet tale about a boy that you just can't help loving. And, if he doesn't want to go off with Pam, I will.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes, it's French - but don't let that stop you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cinemaphyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there's someone in your family who is "different" - or even if there isn't - don't miss "Ma Vie en Rose", the utterly charming and moving story of a 7-year-old boy named Ludovic Fabre who believes he should have been born a girl and whose dearest wish in life is to be like "Pam", the French version of Barbie. Alain Berliner treats his subject with great tenderness and humor; there are neither heroes nor villains in the French suburb where the film takes place, just some ordinary, flawed humans muddling their way towards clarity - or its opposite. There is real substance behind the souffl&eacute;-like lightness of tone, and the pink veil of Ludovic's childish imaginings conceals moments of genuine pain. But there is nothing here that will outrage or frighten, making the R rating a complete mystery. The film could be shown to an older child (10 and up). Ludovic, as played by Georges du Fresne, will steal your heart. His performance in this film is nothing short of memorable. His mother and grandmother run a close second, but Ludovic will stay with you long after this film is over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hazards of Smoking While Pregnant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I like "Muriel's Wedding," which covered the same general territory, better. Superficially, this is a story about a girl in a boy's body. At least all the descriptions and summaries say so. And the parents in this think so. It isn't a life, only a couple weeks, and we have no idea what happens to this child. Even though a joke is made of misunderstanding the science of sex, the characters here (and the filmmaker too, it seems) conflate homosexual, transgender, hermaphrodite and crossdressing behavior. (There should be a word for this class. But I suppose anyone in it would exclude some others.) Never mind. The gender business is merely an excuse to explore deeper issues of disconnection between child and parent. Though I suspect few viewers will have had similar gender confusion, all will resonate to how difficult it is to make the story you inhabit. This is a movie with the child's movie within. Following Ted's rule, the level of abstraction between the movie and the movie within is the same distance as between the movie and us. Its well enough engineered to make you cry. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You owe it to yourself to see this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You do owe it to yourself to see this film. It shows the bias of the MPAA that this film is rated R, don't listen to them, if you have children, show it to them, if you don't, you owe them an explanation as to why not. This is an outstanding movie. They rated it R for using the F bomb once (it is written but you probably won't notice it). It is a well made movie and gives an accurate portrayal of a transsexual. It doesn't go too far over the top, just a little bit but still, it is the most accurate to date. The movie is touching in a "it's a wonderful life" type way. At least rent the movie if you are curious about it. I bought it and don't regret it. Don't let it deter you that it is french, after a while, you won't even realize that you are reading subtitles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie taught me the word "tolerance"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samsoum
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a movie fanatic and reviewer, I was invited to the "Semaine du Cinema Francophone" in Beirut (francophone cinema week). The movie taught me the word "tolerance" as I was one of these stupid guys who mocked on effeminate people. (Maybe to reject my desire at this age to be free to disguise myself, like Ludovic did in the movie). What I know is that being in a place that was supposed to gather cultivated people, journalists and movie reviewers, cinema lovers, artists, etc. I was chocked to hear people laughing at some scenes that were supposed to be moving, sensitive and very important humanely. Also the sound going out public mouth: "tsss tsss tsss" was so chocking that I felt more the pressure of "non-tolerant' society inside the movie theater itself, more than the pressure Ludovic had to endure in his story. My personality was projected into Ludovic who suffered his moments in the film, while I was personally suffering inside the theater and trying to vibe with the movie, despite chocked snobbish people's reaction. An excellent movie. Rather a drama than a comedy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    fantastic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Valentin
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Life in Pink is a french drama of a 7 year old boy named Ludovic who wishes to be a girl, henceforth decides to dress and act like one, but his actions begin to slowly anger the citizens of the conservative neighborhood they live in, and the problems begin. A film that takes a rarely touched upon subject and treats it with care and gravity. Filming it in such a way that you are experiencing the events through the eyes of Ludovic, you grow a care for the child, because he is so innocent and sincere that you can't help but feel bad or angry at the people berating and punishing him all throughout the story. Ludovic's parents had a difficult role as they try to control and take away something that is slowly but surely beginning to affect their normal lives as well. Their acting is just fantastic, and they were written very well, and while the film revolves around Ludovic, the stars of the film are his parents IMO. Props to Mich&egrave;le Laroque and Jean- Philippe &Eacute;coffey. With a well executed drama, the film also has very subtle symbolism on religion and social norms that i feel should be noted, as it gives an extra sense of value to the film, especially since the filmmakers didn't make the symbolism obvious and in your face. The only thing i can say i didn't like was the ending, while the whole scene felt mostly metaphorical, and it's possible i missed something, i can't help but feel it was forced and poorly handled to have a happy ending. but that is only one small part of an otherwise good drama. If you enjoy, heartfelt, social dramas i feel you may enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tells it like it is...possibly triggering?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neuroplastic42
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **spoiler alert** This movie very accurately portrayed what its like growing up with a feminine gender expression, while having been coercively assigned male at birth. Having yet to experience years of sexual harassment and bullying, Ludovic's simple straightforward insistence that she is a girl is heartfelt and unassuming. She sees no danger with dressing in the clothes her sister gets to wear, pretending to be a bride, or telling her new friends she'll be a girl someday. But sadly, it seems everyone else in the film wants to strip that internal confidence from Ludovic. Her parents bully her so much, culminating in physical abuse, as well as Ludo's mother holding her down and cutting her hair. All this causes poor Ludo to attempt suicide and move out of her parents house, because her family hates and blames her. At age seven. The scenes with the father were difficult to watch...scary men shouldn't have a place in a young trans girl's life. I had to stop the movie and watch over two nights. It was like living with my father again.. so, really good directing, I guess. Not a happy ending, either. As far as I can tell, Ludo has hidden her feminine activities for fear of her parents reactions. When offered feminine clothing, Ludo's face lights up, and then quickly darkens in fear (excellent acting!). Ludo's fears are confirmed, as she is hit across the face multiple times and strangled by her mother. Mere MINUTES after the abuse, Ludo's mother says "You can wear whatever you want".....Are we supposed to believe that statement? Are we supposed to believe that an abuser has stopped abusing, with no treatment? It's clear that Ludo can never return to that innocent age of childhood, where gender expression was simply "what I want to do". Ludo entered into the transgender world of adults at the age of seven, learning that feminine gender expression can make you a target of sexual violence, even from your own parents. This is a movie that does not act as a role model for how to accept trans children in your community. This is not a feel-good family movie comedy. This movie shows what children with atypical gender expression go through right now, every day.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Imperfect, but original and worth seeing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very sweet, well intended, good-natured film about a 7 year old boy who is convinced he's supposed to be a girl, and wants to dress and act accordingly. His parents' confusion, and inability to deal with the situation are shown without making them monsters, even as it all starts to tear at the fabric of the family, costing the father his job, etc. What didn't work as well for me was the weaving in of the Tim Burton-esque magical realism/fantasy element of the young boy's dream world. Somehow, in the end, the film felt too light and sunny to really rip at your guts, and yet too dark to just enjoy as a wish fulfillment fantasy of the way the world should be. So while well worth seeing, it ends up as a little less than it has signs of becoming.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite lovely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian W. Fairbanks (brianwfairbanks@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Ma Vie En Rose," winner of the 1997 Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film (its English title is "My Life in Pink"), concerns Ludo, a 7-year-old boy who likes to dress up as a girl and dreams of marrying a boy, even staging a mock wedding with himself decked out in a pink satin dress and pearls. His parents are appalled. When Ludo makes an appearance at a family gathering dressed as a girl, the father covers his embarrassment with nervous laughter and insists his son is just joking. The mother drags him to the sink to wash off his lipstick. When Ludo continues to cross-dress, they take him to a therapist "to set him straight." Ludo's attempts to be a typical boy prove disastrous, however. When he tries to kiss a girl, she knocks him to the ground. "I don't kiss girls," she sneers. He proves too gentle for football, and when another boy sees him through the opening of a toilet stall, sitting down to pee, he explains that he's a "girl-boy." Of course, Ludo is almost certain to grow up to be homosexual or transgender, perhaps opting to change his gender through surgery. The film doesn't take us that far into the future, but does conclude on a note of acceptance. "Whatever happens, you'll always be my child," the father tells Ludo, shortly before the credits roll. The boy in "Ma Vie En Rose" is adorable, and is very convincing when dolled up as a female. The film itself is quite lovely. Undoubtedly, there are those who would assail it as propaganda meant to promote tolerance toward homosexuals and gender-bending boys. Maybe it is, but the fact remains that there are boys who want to be girls, and such boys would exist even if a film like Ma Vie En Rose did not. If it succeeds in making the life of a "girl boy" easier, what's wrong with that? Brian W. Fairbanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An exceptional film about acceptance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Loisroselyn
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just finished earning my master's degree in Psychology. This film fits right in with what I've learned. It is touching and enlightening. I believe that every person should view this film before having children. Accept everyone for who they are and don't try to change them. We live in a diverse world, we should enjoy it instead of manipulating it. Open your eyes. This story is not limited to gender specifications and expectations. It is about being accepted for who we are - period. I highly recommend this film. I rented it from Netflix, so I know that it's available. It's important to recognize the name as "Ma Vie En Rose," rather than "La Vie En Rose."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A girlboy, for the love of God! This is all your fault!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This ain't Peter Pan! When Ludovic (Georges Du Fresne) wants to escape, he gets Pam (Delphine Cadet) a Barbie-like creature that sprinkles magic dust and flies off with Ludovic in tow. Ludovic is different, maybe a transsexual, he is only seven, you know, but he likes to dress up like a girls. he plans to marry his father's boss' son when he is older. You can look at this film as being about homophobia, but you can also take the larger view that it is about society's ostracizing of anyone who doesn't fit in their cookie-cutter mold. It is a sweet tale about a boy that you just can't help loving. And, if he doesn't want to go off with Pam, I will.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes, it's French - but don't let that stop you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cinemaphyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there's someone in your family who is "different" - or even if there isn't - don't miss "Ma Vie en Rose", the utterly charming and moving story of a 7-year-old boy named Ludovic Fabre who believes he should have been born a girl and whose dearest wish in life is to be like "Pam", the French version of Barbie. Alain Berliner treats his subject with great tenderness and humor; there are neither heroes nor villains in the French suburb where the film takes place, just some ordinary, flawed humans muddling their way towards clarity - or its opposite. There is real substance behind the souffl&eacute;-like lightness of tone, and the pink veil of Ludovic's childish imaginings conceals moments of genuine pain. But there is nothing here that will outrage or frighten, making the R rating a complete mystery. The film could be shown to an older child (10 and up). Ludovic, as played by Georges du Fresne, will steal your heart. His performance in this film is nothing short of memorable. His mother and grandmother run a close second, but Ludovic will stay with you long after this film is over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hazards of Smoking While Pregnant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I like "Muriel's Wedding," which covered the same general territory, better. Superficially, this is a story about a girl in a boy's body. At least all the descriptions and summaries say so. And the parents in this think so. It isn't a life, only a couple weeks, and we have no idea what happens to this child. Even though a joke is made of misunderstanding the science of sex, the characters here (and the filmmaker too, it seems) conflate homosexual, transgender, hermaphrodite and crossdressing behavior. (There should be a word for this class. But I suppose anyone in it would exclude some others.) Never mind. The gender business is merely an excuse to explore deeper issues of disconnection between child and parent. Though I suspect few viewers will have had similar gender confusion, all will resonate to how difficult it is to make the story you inhabit. This is a movie with the child's movie within. Following Ted's rule, the level of abstraction between the movie and the movie within is the same distance as between the movie and us. Its well enough engineered to make you cry. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You owe it to yourself to see this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You do owe it to yourself to see this film. It shows the bias of the MPAA that this film is rated R, don't listen to them, if you have children, show it to them, if you don't, you owe them an explanation as to why not. This is an outstanding movie. They rated it R for using the F bomb once (it is written but you probably won't notice it). It is a well made movie and gives an accurate portrayal of a transsexual. It doesn't go too far over the top, just a little bit but still, it is the most accurate to date. The movie is touching in a "it's a wonderful life" type way. At least rent the movie if you are curious about it. I bought it and don't regret it. Don't let it deter you that it is french, after a while, you won't even realize that you are reading subtitles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie taught me the word "tolerance"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samsoum
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a movie fanatic and reviewer, I was invited to the "Semaine du Cinema Francophone" in Beirut (francophone cinema week). The movie taught me the word "tolerance" as I was one of these stupid guys who mocked on effeminate people. (Maybe to reject my desire at this age to be free to disguise myself, like Ludovic did in the movie). What I know is that being in a place that was supposed to gather cultivated people, journalists and movie reviewers, cinema lovers, artists, etc. I was chocked to hear people laughing at some scenes that were supposed to be moving, sensitive and very important humanely. Also the sound going out public mouth: "tsss tsss tsss" was so chocking that I felt more the pressure of "non-tolerant' society inside the movie theater itself, more than the pressure Ludovic had to endure in his story. My personality was projected into Ludovic who suffered his moments in the film, while I was personally suffering inside the theater and trying to vibe with the movie, despite chocked snobbish people's reaction. An excellent movie. Rather a drama than a comedy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    fantastic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Valentin
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Life in Pink is a french drama of a 7 year old boy named Ludovic who wishes to be a girl, henceforth decides to dress and act like one, but his actions begin to slowly anger the citizens of the conservative neighborhood they live in, and the problems begin. A film that takes a rarely touched upon subject and treats it with care and gravity. Filming it in such a way that you are experiencing the events through the eyes of Ludovic, you grow a care for the child, because he is so innocent and sincere that you can't help but feel bad or angry at the people berating and punishing him all throughout the story. Ludovic's parents had a difficult role as they try to control and take away something that is slowly but surely beginning to affect their normal lives as well. Their acting is just fantastic, and they were written very well, and while the film revolves around Ludovic, the stars of the film are his parents IMO. Props to Mich&egrave;le Laroque and Jean- Philippe &Eacute;coffey. With a well executed drama, the film also has very subtle symbolism on religion and social norms that i feel should be noted, as it gives an extra sense of value to the film, especially since the filmmakers didn't make the symbolism obvious and in your face. The only thing i can say i didn't like was the ending, while the whole scene felt mostly metaphorical, and it's possible i missed something, i can't help but feel it was forced and poorly handled to have a happy ending. but that is only one small part of an otherwise good drama. If you enjoy, heartfelt, social dramas i feel you may enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tells it like it is...possibly triggering?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neuroplastic42
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **spoiler alert** This movie very accurately portrayed what its like growing up with a feminine gender expression, while having been coercively assigned male at birth. Having yet to experience years of sexual harassment and bullying, Ludovic's simple straightforward insistence that she is a girl is heartfelt and unassuming. She sees no danger with dressing in the clothes her sister gets to wear, pretending to be a bride, or telling her new friends she'll be a girl someday. But sadly, it seems everyone else in the film wants to strip that internal confidence from Ludovic. Her parents bully her so much, culminating in physical abuse, as well as Ludo's mother holding her down and cutting her hair. All this causes poor Ludo to attempt suicide and move out of her parents house, because her family hates and blames her. At age seven. The scenes with the father were difficult to watch...scary men shouldn't have a place in a young trans girl's life. I had to stop the movie and watch over two nights. It was like living with my father again.. so, really good directing, I guess. Not a happy ending, either. As far as I can tell, Ludo has hidden her feminine activities for fear of her parents reactions. When offered feminine clothing, Ludo's face lights up, and then quickly darkens in fear (excellent acting!). Ludo's fears are confirmed, as she is hit across the face multiple times and strangled by her mother. Mere MINUTES after the abuse, Ludo's mother says "You can wear whatever you want".....Are we supposed to believe that statement? Are we supposed to believe that an abuser has stopped abusing, with no treatment? It's clear that Ludo can never return to that innocent age of childhood, where gender expression was simply "what I want to do". Ludo entered into the transgender world of adults at the age of seven, learning that feminine gender expression can make you a target of sexual violence, even from your own parents. This is a movie that does not act as a role model for how to accept trans children in your community. This is not a feel-good family movie comedy. This movie shows what children with atypical gender expression go through right now, every day.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Imperfect, but original and worth seeing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very sweet, well intended, good-natured film about a 7 year old boy who is convinced he's supposed to be a girl, and wants to dress and act accordingly. His parents' confusion, and inability to deal with the situation are shown without making them monsters, even as it all starts to tear at the fabric of the family, costing the father his job, etc. What didn't work as well for me was the weaving in of the Tim Burton-esque magical realism/fantasy element of the young boy's dream world. Somehow, in the end, the film felt too light and sunny to really rip at your guts, and yet too dark to just enjoy as a wish fulfillment fantasy of the way the world should be. So while well worth seeing, it ends up as a little less than it has signs of becoming.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite lovely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian W. Fairbanks (brianwfairbanks@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Ma Vie En Rose," winner of the 1997 Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film (its English title is "My Life in Pink"), concerns Ludo, a 7-year-old boy who likes to dress up as a girl and dreams of marrying a boy, even staging a mock wedding with himself decked out in a pink satin dress and pearls. His parents are appalled. When Ludo makes an appearance at a family gathering dressed as a girl, the father covers his embarrassment with nervous laughter and insists his son is just joking. The mother drags him to the sink to wash off his lipstick. When Ludo continues to cross-dress, they take him to a therapist "to set him straight." Ludo's attempts to be a typical boy prove disastrous, however. When he tries to kiss a girl, she knocks him to the ground. "I don't kiss girls," she sneers. He proves too gentle for football, and when another boy sees him through the opening of a toilet stall, sitting down to pee, he explains that he's a "girl-boy." Of course, Ludo is almost certain to grow up to be homosexual or transgender, perhaps opting to change his gender through surgery. The film doesn't take us that far into the future, but does conclude on a note of acceptance. "Whatever happens, you'll always be my child," the father tells Ludo, shortly before the credits roll. The boy in "Ma Vie En Rose" is adorable, and is very convincing when dolled up as a female. The film itself is quite lovely. Undoubtedly, there are those who would assail it as propaganda meant to promote tolerance toward homosexuals and gender-bending boys. Maybe it is, but the fact remains that there are boys who want to be girls, and such boys would exist even if a film like Ma Vie En Rose did not. If it succeeds in making the life of a "girl boy" easier, what's wrong with that? Brian W. Fairbanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An exceptional film about acceptance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Loisroselyn
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just finished earning my master's degree in Psychology. This film fits right in with what I've learned. It is touching and enlightening. I believe that every person should view this film before having children. Accept everyone for who they are and don't try to change them. We live in a diverse world, we should enjoy it instead of manipulating it. Open your eyes. This story is not limited to gender specifications and expectations. It is about being accepted for who we are - period. I highly recommend this film. I rented it from Netflix, so I know that it's available. It's important to recognize the name as "Ma Vie En Rose," rather than "La Vie En Rose."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A girlboy, for the love of God! This is all your fault!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This ain't Peter Pan! When Ludovic (Georges Du Fresne) wants to escape, he gets Pam (Delphine Cadet) a Barbie-like creature that sprinkles magic dust and flies off with Ludovic in tow. Ludovic is different, maybe a transsexual, he is only seven, you know, but he likes to dress up like a girls. he plans to marry his father's boss' son when he is older. You can look at this film as being about homophobia, but you can also take the larger view that it is about society's ostracizing of anyone who doesn't fit in their cookie-cutter mold. It is a sweet tale about a boy that you just can't help loving. And, if he doesn't want to go off with Pam, I will.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes, it's French - but don't let that stop you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cinemaphyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there's someone in your family who is "different" - or even if there isn't - don't miss "Ma Vie en Rose", the utterly charming and moving story of a 7-year-old boy named Ludovic Fabre who believes he should have been born a girl and whose dearest wish in life is to be like "Pam", the French version of Barbie. Alain Berliner treats his subject with great tenderness and humor; there are neither heroes nor villains in the French suburb where the film takes place, just some ordinary, flawed humans muddling their way towards clarity - or its opposite. There is real substance behind the souffl&eacute;-like lightness of tone, and the pink veil of Ludovic's childish imaginings conceals moments of genuine pain. But there is nothing here that will outrage or frighten, making the R rating a complete mystery. The film could be shown to an older child (10 and up). Ludovic, as played by Georges du Fresne, will steal your heart. His performance in this film is nothing short of memorable. His mother and grandmother run a close second, but Ludovic will stay with you long after this film is over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hazards of Smoking While Pregnant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I like "Muriel's Wedding," which covered the same general territory, better. Superficially, this is a story about a girl in a boy's body. At least all the descriptions and summaries say so. And the parents in this think so. It isn't a life, only a couple weeks, and we have no idea what happens to this child. Even though a joke is made of misunderstanding the science of sex, the characters here (and the filmmaker too, it seems) conflate homosexual, transgender, hermaphrodite and crossdressing behavior. (There should be a word for this class. But I suppose anyone in it would exclude some others.) Never mind. The gender business is merely an excuse to explore deeper issues of disconnection between child and parent. Though I suspect few viewers will have had similar gender confusion, all will resonate to how difficult it is to make the story you inhabit. This is a movie with the child's movie within. Following Ted's rule, the level of abstraction between the movie and the movie within is the same distance as between the movie and us. Its well enough engineered to make you cry. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You owe it to yourself to see this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You do owe it to yourself to see this film. It shows the bias of the MPAA that this film is rated R, don't listen to them, if you have children, show it to them, if you don't, you owe them an explanation as to why not. This is an outstanding movie. They rated it R for using the F bomb once (it is written but you probably won't notice it). It is a well made movie and gives an accurate portrayal of a transsexual. It doesn't go too far over the top, just a little bit but still, it is the most accurate to date. The movie is touching in a "it's a wonderful life" type way. At least rent the movie if you are curious about it. I bought it and don't regret it. Don't let it deter you that it is french, after a while, you won't even realize that you are reading subtitles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie taught me the word "tolerance"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samsoum
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a movie fanatic and reviewer, I was invited to the "Semaine du Cinema Francophone" in Beirut (francophone cinema week). The movie taught me the word "tolerance" as I was one of these stupid guys who mocked on effeminate people. (Maybe to reject my desire at this age to be free to disguise myself, like Ludovic did in the movie). What I know is that being in a place that was supposed to gather cultivated people, journalists and movie reviewers, cinema lovers, artists, etc. I was chocked to hear people laughing at some scenes that were supposed to be moving, sensitive and very important humanely. Also the sound going out public mouth: "tsss tsss tsss" was so chocking that I felt more the pressure of "non-tolerant' society inside the movie theater itself, more than the pressure Ludovic had to endure in his story. My personality was projected into Ludovic who suffered his moments in the film, while I was personally suffering inside the theater and trying to vibe with the movie, despite chocked snobbish people's reaction. An excellent movie. Rather a drama than a comedy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    fantastic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Valentin
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Life in Pink is a french drama of a 7 year old boy named Ludovic who wishes to be a girl, henceforth decides to dress and act like one, but his actions begin to slowly anger the citizens of the conservative neighborhood they live in, and the problems begin. A film that takes a rarely touched upon subject and treats it with care and gravity. Filming it in such a way that you are experiencing the events through the eyes of Ludovic, you grow a care for the child, because he is so innocent and sincere that you can't help but feel bad or angry at the people berating and punishing him all throughout the story. Ludovic's parents had a difficult role as they try to control and take away something that is slowly but surely beginning to affect their normal lives as well. Their acting is just fantastic, and they were written very well, and while the film revolves around Ludovic, the stars of the film are his parents IMO. Props to Mich&egrave;le Laroque and Jean- Philippe &Eacute;coffey. With a well executed drama, the film also has very subtle symbolism on religion and social norms that i feel should be noted, as it gives an extra sense of value to the film, especially since the filmmakers didn't make the symbolism obvious and in your face. The only thing i can say i didn't like was the ending, while the whole scene felt mostly metaphorical, and it's possible i missed something, i can't help but feel it was forced and poorly handled to have a happy ending. but that is only one small part of an otherwise good drama. If you enjoy, heartfelt, social dramas i feel you may enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tells it like it is...possibly triggering?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neuroplastic42
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **spoiler alert** This movie very accurately portrayed what its like growing up with a feminine gender expression, while having been coercively assigned male at birth. Having yet to experience years of sexual harassment and bullying, Ludovic's simple straightforward insistence that she is a girl is heartfelt and unassuming. She sees no danger with dressing in the clothes her sister gets to wear, pretending to be a bride, or telling her new friends she'll be a girl someday. But sadly, it seems everyone else in the film wants to strip that internal confidence from Ludovic. Her parents bully her so much, culminating in physical abuse, as well as Ludo's mother holding her down and cutting her hair. All this causes poor Ludo to attempt suicide and move out of her parents house, because her family hates and blames her. At age seven. The scenes with the father were difficult to watch...scary men shouldn't have a place in a young trans girl's life. I had to stop the movie and watch over two nights. It was like living with my father again.. so, really good directing, I guess. Not a happy ending, either. As far as I can tell, Ludo has hidden her feminine activities for fear of her parents reactions. When offered feminine clothing, Ludo's face lights up, and then quickly darkens in fear (excellent acting!). Ludo's fears are confirmed, as she is hit across the face multiple times and strangled by her mother. Mere MINUTES after the abuse, Ludo's mother says "You can wear whatever you want".....Are we supposed to believe that statement? Are we supposed to believe that an abuser has stopped abusing, with no treatment? It's clear that Ludo can never return to that innocent age of childhood, where gender expression was simply "what I want to do". Ludo entered into the transgender world of adults at the age of seven, learning that feminine gender expression can make you a target of sexual violence, even from your own parents. This is a movie that does not act as a role model for how to accept trans children in your community. This is not a feel-good family movie comedy. This movie shows what children with atypical gender expression go through right now, every day.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Imperfect, but original and worth seeing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very sweet, well intended, good-natured film about a 7 year old boy who is convinced he's supposed to be a girl, and wants to dress and act accordingly. His parents' confusion, and inability to deal with the situation are shown without making them monsters, even as it all starts to tear at the fabric of the family, costing the father his job, etc. What didn't work as well for me was the weaving in of the Tim Burton-esque magical realism/fantasy element of the young boy's dream world. Somehow, in the end, the film felt too light and sunny to really rip at your guts, and yet too dark to just enjoy as a wish fulfillment fantasy of the way the world should be. So while well worth seeing, it ends up as a little less than it has signs of becoming.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite lovely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian W. Fairbanks (brianwfairbanks@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Ma Vie En Rose," winner of the 1997 Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film (its English title is "My Life in Pink"), concerns Ludo, a 7-year-old boy who likes to dress up as a girl and dreams of marrying a boy, even staging a mock wedding with himself decked out in a pink satin dress and pearls. His parents are appalled. When Ludo makes an appearance at a family gathering dressed as a girl, the father covers his embarrassment with nervous laughter and insists his son is just joking. The mother drags him to the sink to wash off his lipstick. When Ludo continues to cross-dress, they take him to a therapist "to set him straight." Ludo's attempts to be a typical boy prove disastrous, however. When he tries to kiss a girl, she knocks him to the ground. "I don't kiss girls," she sneers. He proves too gentle for football, and when another boy sees him through the opening of a toilet stall, sitting down to pee, he explains that he's a "girl-boy." Of course, Ludo is almost certain to grow up to be homosexual or transgender, perhaps opting to change his gender through surgery. The film doesn't take us that far into the future, but does conclude on a note of acceptance. "Whatever happens, you'll always be my child," the father tells Ludo, shortly before the credits roll. The boy in "Ma Vie En Rose" is adorable, and is very convincing when dolled up as a female. The film itself is quite lovely. Undoubtedly, there are those who would assail it as propaganda meant to promote tolerance toward homosexuals and gender-bending boys. Maybe it is, but the fact remains that there are boys who want to be girls, and such boys would exist even if a film like Ma Vie En Rose did not. If it succeeds in making the life of a "girl boy" easier, what's wrong with that? Brian W. Fairbanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An exceptional film about acceptance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Loisroselyn
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just finished earning my master's degree in Psychology. This film fits right in with what I've learned. It is touching and enlightening. I believe that every person should view this film before having children. Accept everyone for who they are and don't try to change them. We live in a diverse world, we should enjoy it instead of manipulating it. Open your eyes. This story is not limited to gender specifications and expectations. It is about being accepted for who we are - period. I highly recommend this film. I rented it from Netflix, so I know that it's available. It's important to recognize the name as "Ma Vie En Rose," rather than "La Vie En Rose."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A girlboy, for the love of God! This is all your fault!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This ain't Peter Pan! When Ludovic (Georges Du Fresne) wants to escape, he gets Pam (Delphine Cadet) a Barbie-like creature that sprinkles magic dust and flies off with Ludovic in tow. Ludovic is different, maybe a transsexual, he is only seven, you know, but he likes to dress up like a girls. he plans to marry his father's boss' son when he is older. You can look at this film as being about homophobia, but you can also take the larger view that it is about society's ostracizing of anyone who doesn't fit in their cookie-cutter mold. It is a sweet tale about a boy that you just can't help loving. And, if he doesn't want to go off with Pam, I will.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes, it's French - but don't let that stop you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cinemaphyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there's someone in your family who is "different" - or even if there isn't - don't miss "Ma Vie en Rose", the utterly charming and moving story of a 7-year-old boy named Ludovic Fabre who believes he should have been born a girl and whose dearest wish in life is to be like "Pam", the French version of Barbie. Alain Berliner treats his subject with great tenderness and humor; there are neither heroes nor villains in the French suburb where the film takes place, just some ordinary, flawed humans muddling their way towards clarity - or its opposite. There is real substance behind the souffl&eacute;-like lightness of tone, and the pink veil of Ludovic's childish imaginings conceals moments of genuine pain. But there is nothing here that will outrage or frighten, making the R rating a complete mystery. The film could be shown to an older child (10 and up). Ludovic, as played by Georges du Fresne, will steal your heart. His performance in this film is nothing short of memorable. His mother and grandmother run a close second, but Ludovic will stay with you long after this film is over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hazards of Smoking While Pregnant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I like "Muriel's Wedding," which covered the same general territory, better. Superficially, this is a story about a girl in a boy's body. At least all the descriptions and summaries say so. And the parents in this think so. It isn't a life, only a couple weeks, and we have no idea what happens to this child. Even though a joke is made of misunderstanding the science of sex, the characters here (and the filmmaker too, it seems) conflate homosexual, transgender, hermaphrodite and crossdressing behavior. (There should be a word for this class. But I suppose anyone in it would exclude some others.) Never mind. The gender business is merely an excuse to explore deeper issues of disconnection between child and parent. Though I suspect few viewers will have had similar gender confusion, all will resonate to how difficult it is to make the story you inhabit. This is a movie with the child's movie within. Following Ted's rule, the level of abstraction between the movie and the movie within is the same distance as between the movie and us. Its well enough engineered to make you cry. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You owe it to yourself to see this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You do owe it to yourself to see this film. It shows the bias of the MPAA that this film is rated R, don't listen to them, if you have children, show it to them, if you don't, you owe them an explanation as to why not. This is an outstanding movie. They rated it R for using the F bomb once (it is written but you probably won't notice it). It is a well made movie and gives an accurate portrayal of a transsexual. It doesn't go too far over the top, just a little bit but still, it is the most accurate to date. The movie is touching in a "it's a wonderful life" type way. At least rent the movie if you are curious about it. I bought it and don't regret it. Don't let it deter you that it is french, after a while, you won't even realize that you are reading subtitles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie taught me the word "tolerance"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samsoum
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a movie fanatic and reviewer, I was invited to the "Semaine du Cinema Francophone" in Beirut (francophone cinema week). The movie taught me the word "tolerance" as I was one of these stupid guys who mocked on effeminate people. (Maybe to reject my desire at this age to be free to disguise myself, like Ludovic did in the movie). What I know is that being in a place that was supposed to gather cultivated people, journalists and movie reviewers, cinema lovers, artists, etc. I was chocked to hear people laughing at some scenes that were supposed to be moving, sensitive and very important humanely. Also the sound going out public mouth: "tsss tsss tsss" was so chocking that I felt more the pressure of "non-tolerant' society inside the movie theater itself, more than the pressure Ludovic had to endure in his story. My personality was projected into Ludovic who suffered his moments in the film, while I was personally suffering inside the theater and trying to vibe with the movie, despite chocked snobbish people's reaction. An excellent movie. Rather a drama than a comedy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    fantastic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Valentin
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Life in Pink is a french drama of a 7 year old boy named Ludovic who wishes to be a girl, henceforth decides to dress and act like one, but his actions begin to slowly anger the citizens of the conservative neighborhood they live in, and the problems begin. A film that takes a rarely touched upon subject and treats it with care and gravity. Filming it in such a way that you are experiencing the events through the eyes of Ludovic, you grow a care for the child, because he is so innocent and sincere that you can't help but feel bad or angry at the people berating and punishing him all throughout the story. Ludovic's parents had a difficult role as they try to control and take away something that is slowly but surely beginning to affect their normal lives as well. Their acting is just fantastic, and they were written very well, and while the film revolves around Ludovic, the stars of the film are his parents IMO. Props to Mich&egrave;le Laroque and Jean- Philippe &Eacute;coffey. With a well executed drama, the film also has very subtle symbolism on religion and social norms that i feel should be noted, as it gives an extra sense of value to the film, especially since the filmmakers didn't make the symbolism obvious and in your face. The only thing i can say i didn't like was the ending, while the whole scene felt mostly metaphorical, and it's possible i missed something, i can't help but feel it was forced and poorly handled to have a happy ending. but that is only one small part of an otherwise good drama. If you enjoy, heartfelt, social dramas i feel you may enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tells it like it is...possibly triggering?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neuroplastic42
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **spoiler alert** This movie very accurately portrayed what its like growing up with a feminine gender expression, while having been coercively assigned male at birth. Having yet to experience years of sexual harassment and bullying, Ludovic's simple straightforward insistence that she is a girl is heartfelt and unassuming. She sees no danger with dressing in the clothes her sister gets to wear, pretending to be a bride, or telling her new friends she'll be a girl someday. But sadly, it seems everyone else in the film wants to strip that internal confidence from Ludovic. Her parents bully her so much, culminating in physical abuse, as well as Ludo's mother holding her down and cutting her hair. All this causes poor Ludo to attempt suicide and move out of her parents house, because her family hates and blames her. At age seven. The scenes with the father were difficult to watch...scary men shouldn't have a place in a young trans girl's life. I had to stop the movie and watch over two nights. It was like living with my father again.. so, really good directing, I guess. Not a happy ending, either. As far as I can tell, Ludo has hidden her feminine activities for fear of her parents reactions. When offered feminine clothing, Ludo's face lights up, and then quickly darkens in fear (excellent acting!). Ludo's fears are confirmed, as she is hit across the face multiple times and strangled by her mother. Mere MINUTES after the abuse, Ludo's mother says "You can wear whatever you want".....Are we supposed to believe that statement? Are we supposed to believe that an abuser has stopped abusing, with no treatment? It's clear that Ludo can never return to that innocent age of childhood, where gender expression was simply "what I want to do". Ludo entered into the transgender world of adults at the age of seven, learning that feminine gender expression can make you a target of sexual violence, even from your own parents. This is a movie that does not act as a role model for how to accept trans children in your community. This is not a feel-good family movie comedy. This movie shows what children with atypical gender expression go through right now, every day.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Imperfect, but original and worth seeing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very sweet, well intended, good-natured film about a 7 year old boy who is convinced he's supposed to be a girl, and wants to dress and act accordingly. His parents' confusion, and inability to deal with the situation are shown without making them monsters, even as it all starts to tear at the fabric of the family, costing the father his job, etc. What didn't work as well for me was the weaving in of the Tim Burton-esque magical realism/fantasy element of the young boy's dream world. Somehow, in the end, the film felt too light and sunny to really rip at your guts, and yet too dark to just enjoy as a wish fulfillment fantasy of the way the world should be. So while well worth seeing, it ends up as a little less than it has signs of becoming.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite lovely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian W. Fairbanks (brianwfairbanks@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Ma Vie En Rose," winner of the 1997 Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film (its English title is "My Life in Pink"), concerns Ludo, a 7-year-old boy who likes to dress up as a girl and dreams of marrying a boy, even staging a mock wedding with himself decked out in a pink satin dress and pearls. His parents are appalled. When Ludo makes an appearance at a family gathering dressed as a girl, the father covers his embarrassment with nervous laughter and insists his son is just joking. The mother drags him to the sink to wash off his lipstick. When Ludo continues to cross-dress, they take him to a therapist "to set him straight." Ludo's attempts to be a typical boy prove disastrous, however. When he tries to kiss a girl, she knocks him to the ground. "I don't kiss girls," she sneers. He proves too gentle for football, and when another boy sees him through the opening of a toilet stall, sitting down to pee, he explains that he's a "girl-boy." Of course, Ludo is almost certain to grow up to be homosexual or transgender, perhaps opting to change his gender through surgery. The film doesn't take us that far into the future, but does conclude on a note of acceptance. "Whatever happens, you'll always be my child," the father tells Ludo, shortly before the credits roll. The boy in "Ma Vie En Rose" is adorable, and is very convincing when dolled up as a female. The film itself is quite lovely. Undoubtedly, there are those who would assail it as propaganda meant to promote tolerance toward homosexuals and gender-bending boys. Maybe it is, but the fact remains that there are boys who want to be girls, and such boys would exist even if a film like Ma Vie En Rose did not. If it succeeds in making the life of a "girl boy" easier, what's wrong with that? Brian W. Fairbanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An exceptional film about acceptance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Loisroselyn
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just finished earning my master's degree in Psychology. This film fits right in with what I've learned. It is touching and enlightening. I believe that every person should view this film before having children. Accept everyone for who they are and don't try to change them. We live in a diverse world, we should enjoy it instead of manipulating it. Open your eyes. This story is not limited to gender specifications and expectations. It is about being accepted for who we are - period. I highly recommend this film. I rented it from Netflix, so I know that it's available. It's important to recognize the name as "Ma Vie En Rose," rather than "La Vie En Rose."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A girlboy, for the love of God! This is all your fault!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This ain't Peter Pan! When Ludovic (Georges Du Fresne) wants to escape, he gets Pam (Delphine Cadet) a Barbie-like creature that sprinkles magic dust and flies off with Ludovic in tow. Ludovic is different, maybe a transsexual, he is only seven, you know, but he likes to dress up like a girls. he plans to marry his father's boss' son when he is older. You can look at this film as being about homophobia, but you can also take the larger view that it is about society's ostracizing of anyone who doesn't fit in their cookie-cutter mold. It is a sweet tale about a boy that you just can't help loving. And, if he doesn't want to go off with Pam, I will.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes, it's French - but don't let that stop you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cinemaphyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there's someone in your family who is "different" - or even if there isn't - don't miss "Ma Vie en Rose", the utterly charming and moving story of a 7-year-old boy named Ludovic Fabre who believes he should have been born a girl and whose dearest wish in life is to be like "Pam", the French version of Barbie. Alain Berliner treats his subject with great tenderness and humor; there are neither heroes nor villains in the French suburb where the film takes place, just some ordinary, flawed humans muddling their way towards clarity - or its opposite. There is real substance behind the souffl&eacute;-like lightness of tone, and the pink veil of Ludovic's childish imaginings conceals moments of genuine pain. But there is nothing here that will outrage or frighten, making the R rating a complete mystery. The film could be shown to an older child (10 and up). Ludovic, as played by Georges du Fresne, will steal your heart. His performance in this film is nothing short of memorable. His mother and grandmother run a close second, but Ludovic will stay with you long after this film is over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hazards of Smoking While Pregnant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I like "Muriel's Wedding," which covered the same general territory, better. Superficially, this is a story about a girl in a boy's body. At least all the descriptions and summaries say so. And the parents in this think so. It isn't a life, only a couple weeks, and we have no idea what happens to this child. Even though a joke is made of misunderstanding the science of sex, the characters here (and the filmmaker too, it seems) conflate homosexual, transgender, hermaphrodite and crossdressing behavior. (There should be a word for this class. But I suppose anyone in it would exclude some others.) Never mind. The gender business is merely an excuse to explore deeper issues of disconnection between child and parent. Though I suspect few viewers will have had similar gender confusion, all will resonate to how difficult it is to make the story you inhabit. This is a movie with the child's movie within. Following Ted's rule, the level of abstraction between the movie and the movie within is the same distance as between the movie and us. Its well enough engineered to make you cry. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You owe it to yourself to see this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You do owe it to yourself to see this film. It shows the bias of the MPAA that this film is rated R, don't listen to them, if you have children, show it to them, if you don't, you owe them an explanation as to why not. This is an outstanding movie. They rated it R for using the F bomb once (it is written but you probably won't notice it). It is a well made movie and gives an accurate portrayal of a transsexual. It doesn't go too far over the top, just a little bit but still, it is the most accurate to date. The movie is touching in a "it's a wonderful life" type way. At least rent the movie if you are curious about it. I bought it and don't regret it. Don't let it deter you that it is french, after a while, you won't even realize that you are reading subtitles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie taught me the word "tolerance"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samsoum
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a movie fanatic and reviewer, I was invited to the "Semaine du Cinema Francophone" in Beirut (francophone cinema week). The movie taught me the word "tolerance" as I was one of these stupid guys who mocked on effeminate people. (Maybe to reject my desire at this age to be free to disguise myself, like Ludovic did in the movie). What I know is that being in a place that was supposed to gather cultivated people, journalists and movie reviewers, cinema lovers, artists, etc. I was chocked to hear people laughing at some scenes that were supposed to be moving, sensitive and very important humanely. Also the sound going out public mouth: "tsss tsss tsss" was so chocking that I felt more the pressure of "non-tolerant' society inside the movie theater itself, more than the pressure Ludovic had to endure in his story. My personality was projected into Ludovic who suffered his moments in the film, while I was personally suffering inside the theater and trying to vibe with the movie, despite chocked snobbish people's reaction. An excellent movie. Rather a drama than a comedy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    fantastic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Valentin
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Life in Pink is a french drama of a 7 year old boy named Ludovic who wishes to be a girl, henceforth decides to dress and act like one, but his actions begin to slowly anger the citizens of the conservative neighborhood they live in, and the problems begin. A film that takes a rarely touched upon subject and treats it with care and gravity. Filming it in such a way that you are experiencing the events through the eyes of Ludovic, you grow a care for the child, because he is so innocent and sincere that you can't help but feel bad or angry at the people berating and punishing him all throughout the story. Ludovic's parents had a difficult role as they try to control and take away something that is slowly but surely beginning to affect their normal lives as well. Their acting is just fantastic, and they were written very well, and while the film revolves around Ludovic, the stars of the film are his parents IMO. Props to Mich&egrave;le Laroque and Jean- Philippe &Eacute;coffey. With a well executed drama, the film also has very subtle symbolism on religion and social norms that i feel should be noted, as it gives an extra sense of value to the film, especially since the filmmakers didn't make the symbolism obvious and in your face. The only thing i can say i didn't like was the ending, while the whole scene felt mostly metaphorical, and it's possible i missed something, i can't help but feel it was forced and poorly handled to have a happy ending. but that is only one small part of an otherwise good drama. If you enjoy, heartfelt, social dramas i feel you may enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tells it like it is...possibly triggering?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neuroplastic42
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **spoiler alert** This movie very accurately portrayed what its like growing up with a feminine gender expression, while having been coercively assigned male at birth. Having yet to experience years of sexual harassment and bullying, Ludovic's simple straightforward insistence that she is a girl is heartfelt and unassuming. She sees no danger with dressing in the clothes her sister gets to wear, pretending to be a bride, or telling her new friends she'll be a girl someday. But sadly, it seems everyone else in the film wants to strip that internal confidence from Ludovic. Her parents bully her so much, culminating in physical abuse, as well as Ludo's mother holding her down and cutting her hair. All this causes poor Ludo to attempt suicide and move out of her parents house, because her family hates and blames her. At age seven. The scenes with the father were difficult to watch...scary men shouldn't have a place in a young trans girl's life. I had to stop the movie and watch over two nights. It was like living with my father again.. so, really good directing, I guess. Not a happy ending, either. As far as I can tell, Ludo has hidden her feminine activities for fear of her parents reactions. When offered feminine clothing, Ludo's face lights up, and then quickly darkens in fear (excellent acting!). Ludo's fears are confirmed, as she is hit across the face multiple times and strangled by her mother. Mere MINUTES after the abuse, Ludo's mother says "You can wear whatever you want".....Are we supposed to believe that statement? Are we supposed to believe that an abuser has stopped abusing, with no treatment? It's clear that Ludo can never return to that innocent age of childhood, where gender expression was simply "what I want to do". Ludo entered into the transgender world of adults at the age of seven, learning that feminine gender expression can make you a target of sexual violence, even from your own parents. This is a movie that does not act as a role model for how to accept trans children in your community. This is not a feel-good family movie comedy. This movie shows what children with atypical gender expression go through right now, every day.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Imperfect, but original and worth seeing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very sweet, well intended, good-natured film about a 7 year old boy who is convinced he's supposed to be a girl, and wants to dress and act accordingly. His parents' confusion, and inability to deal with the situation are shown without making them monsters, even as it all starts to tear at the fabric of the family, costing the father his job, etc. What didn't work as well for me was the weaving in of the Tim Burton-esque magical realism/fantasy element of the young boy's dream world. Somehow, in the end, the film felt too light and sunny to really rip at your guts, and yet too dark to just enjoy as a wish fulfillment fantasy of the way the world should be. So while well worth seeing, it ends up as a little less than it has signs of becoming.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite lovely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian W. Fairbanks (brianwfairbanks@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Ma Vie En Rose," winner of the 1997 Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film (its English title is "My Life in Pink"), concerns Ludo, a 7-year-old boy who likes to dress up as a girl and dreams of marrying a boy, even staging a mock wedding with himself decked out in a pink satin dress and pearls. His parents are appalled. When Ludo makes an appearance at a family gathering dressed as a girl, the father covers his embarrassment with nervous laughter and insists his son is just joking. The mother drags him to the sink to wash off his lipstick. When Ludo continues to cross-dress, they take him to a therapist "to set him straight." Ludo's attempts to be a typical boy prove disastrous, however. When he tries to kiss a girl, she knocks him to the ground. "I don't kiss girls," she sneers. He proves too gentle for football, and when another boy sees him through the opening of a toilet stall, sitting down to pee, he explains that he's a "girl-boy." Of course, Ludo is almost certain to grow up to be homosexual or transgender, perhaps opting to change his gender through surgery. The film doesn't take us that far into the future, but does conclude on a note of acceptance. "Whatever happens, you'll always be my child," the father tells Ludo, shortly before the credits roll. The boy in "Ma Vie En Rose" is adorable, and is very convincing when dolled up as a female. The film itself is quite lovely. Undoubtedly, there are those who would assail it as propaganda meant to promote tolerance toward homosexuals and gender-bending boys. Maybe it is, but the fact remains that there are boys who want to be girls, and such boys would exist even if a film like Ma Vie En Rose did not. If it succeeds in making the life of a "girl boy" easier, what's wrong with that? Brian W. Fairbanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An exceptional film about acceptance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Loisroselyn
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just finished earning my master's degree in Psychology. This film fits right in with what I've learned. It is touching and enlightening. I believe that every person should view this film before having children. Accept everyone for who they are and don't try to change them. We live in a diverse world, we should enjoy it instead of manipulating it. Open your eyes. This story is not limited to gender specifications and expectations. It is about being accepted for who we are - period. I highly recommend this film. I rented it from Netflix, so I know that it's available. It's important to recognize the name as "Ma Vie En Rose," rather than "La Vie En Rose."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A girlboy, for the love of God! This is all your fault!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This ain't Peter Pan! When Ludovic (Georges Du Fresne) wants to escape, he gets Pam (Delphine Cadet) a Barbie-like creature that sprinkles magic dust and flies off with Ludovic in tow. Ludovic is different, maybe a transsexual, he is only seven, you know, but he likes to dress up like a girls. he plans to marry his father's boss' son when he is older. You can look at this film as being about homophobia, but you can also take the larger view that it is about society's ostracizing of anyone who doesn't fit in their cookie-cutter mold. It is a sweet tale about a boy that you just can't help loving. And, if he doesn't want to go off with Pam, I will.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes, it's French - but don't let that stop you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cinemaphyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there's someone in your family who is "different" - or even if there isn't - don't miss "Ma Vie en Rose", the utterly charming and moving story of a 7-year-old boy named Ludovic Fabre who believes he should have been born a girl and whose dearest wish in life is to be like "Pam", the French version of Barbie. Alain Berliner treats his subject with great tenderness and humor; there are neither heroes nor villains in the French suburb where the film takes place, just some ordinary, flawed humans muddling their way towards clarity - or its opposite. There is real substance behind the souffl&eacute;-like lightness of tone, and the pink veil of Ludovic's childish imaginings conceals moments of genuine pain. But there is nothing here that will outrage or frighten, making the R rating a complete mystery. The film could be shown to an older child (10 and up). Ludovic, as played by Georges du Fresne, will steal your heart. His performance in this film is nothing short of memorable. His mother and grandmother run a close second, but Ludovic will stay with you long after this film is over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hazards of Smoking While Pregnant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I like "Muriel's Wedding," which covered the same general territory, better. Superficially, this is a story about a girl in a boy's body. At least all the descriptions and summaries say so. And the parents in this think so. It isn't a life, only a couple weeks, and we have no idea what happens to this child. Even though a joke is made of misunderstanding the science of sex, the characters here (and the filmmaker too, it seems) conflate homosexual, transgender, hermaphrodite and crossdressing behavior. (There should be a word for this class. But I suppose anyone in it would exclude some others.) Never mind. The gender business is merely an excuse to explore deeper issues of disconnection between child and parent. Though I suspect few viewers will have had similar gender confusion, all will resonate to how difficult it is to make the story you inhabit. This is a movie with the child's movie within. Following Ted's rule, the level of abstraction between the movie and the movie within is the same distance as between the movie and us. Its well enough engineered to make you cry. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You owe it to yourself to see this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You do owe it to yourself to see this film. It shows the bias of the MPAA that this film is rated R, don't listen to them, if you have children, show it to them, if you don't, you owe them an explanation as to why not. This is an outstanding movie. They rated it R for using the F bomb once (it is written but you probably won't notice it). It is a well made movie and gives an accurate portrayal of a transsexual. It doesn't go too far over the top, just a little bit but still, it is the most accurate to date. The movie is touching in a "it's a wonderful life" type way. At least rent the movie if you are curious about it. I bought it and don't regret it. Don't let it deter you that it is french, after a while, you won't even realize that you are reading subtitles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie taught me the word "tolerance"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samsoum
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a movie fanatic and reviewer, I was invited to the "Semaine du Cinema Francophone" in Beirut (francophone cinema week). The movie taught me the word "tolerance" as I was one of these stupid guys who mocked on effeminate people. (Maybe to reject my desire at this age to be free to disguise myself, like Ludovic did in the movie). What I know is that being in a place that was supposed to gather cultivated people, journalists and movie reviewers, cinema lovers, artists, etc. I was chocked to hear people laughing at some scenes that were supposed to be moving, sensitive and very important humanely. Also the sound going out public mouth: "tsss tsss tsss" was so chocking that I felt more the pressure of "non-tolerant' society inside the movie theater itself, more than the pressure Ludovic had to endure in his story. My personality was projected into Ludovic who suffered his moments in the film, while I was personally suffering inside the theater and trying to vibe with the movie, despite chocked snobbish people's reaction. An excellent movie. Rather a drama than a comedy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    fantastic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Alex Valentin
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My Life in Pink is a french drama of a 7 year old boy named Ludovic who wishes to be a girl, henceforth decides to dress and act like one, but his actions begin to slowly anger the citizens of the conservative neighborhood they live in, and the problems begin. A film that takes a rarely touched upon subject and treats it with care and gravity. Filming it in such a way that you are experiencing the events through the eyes of Ludovic, you grow a care for the child, because he is so innocent and sincere that you can't help but feel bad or angry at the people berating and punishing him all throughout the story. Ludovic's parents had a difficult role as they try to control and take away something that is slowly but surely beginning to affect their normal lives as well. Their acting is just fantastic, and they were written very well, and while the film revolves around Ludovic, the stars of the film are his parents IMO. Props to Mich&egrave;le Laroque and Jean- Philippe &Eacute;coffey. With a well executed drama, the film also has very subtle symbolism on religion and social norms that i feel should be noted, as it gives an extra sense of value to the film, especially since the filmmakers didn't make the symbolism obvious and in your face. The only thing i can say i didn't like was the ending, while the whole scene felt mostly metaphorical, and it's possible i missed something, i can't help but feel it was forced and poorly handled to have a happy ending. but that is only one small part of an otherwise good drama. If you enjoy, heartfelt, social dramas i feel you may enjoy the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tells it like it is...possibly triggering?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    neuroplastic42
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    **spoiler alert** This movie very accurately portrayed what its like growing up with a feminine gender expression, while having been coercively assigned male at birth. Having yet to experience years of sexual harassment and bullying, Ludovic's simple straightforward insistence that she is a girl is heartfelt and unassuming. She sees no danger with dressing in the clothes her sister gets to wear, pretending to be a bride, or telling her new friends she'll be a girl someday. But sadly, it seems everyone else in the film wants to strip that internal confidence from Ludovic. Her parents bully her so much, culminating in physical abuse, as well as Ludo's mother holding her down and cutting her hair. All this causes poor Ludo to attempt suicide and move out of her parents house, because her family hates and blames her. At age seven. The scenes with the father were difficult to watch...scary men shouldn't have a place in a young trans girl's life. I had to stop the movie and watch over two nights. It was like living with my father again.. so, really good directing, I guess. Not a happy ending, either. As far as I can tell, Ludo has hidden her feminine activities for fear of her parents reactions. When offered feminine clothing, Ludo's face lights up, and then quickly darkens in fear (excellent acting!). Ludo's fears are confirmed, as she is hit across the face multiple times and strangled by her mother. Mere MINUTES after the abuse, Ludo's mother says "You can wear whatever you want".....Are we supposed to believe that statement? Are we supposed to believe that an abuser has stopped abusing, with no treatment? It's clear that Ludo can never return to that innocent age of childhood, where gender expression was simply "what I want to do". Ludo entered into the transgender world of adults at the age of seven, learning that feminine gender expression can make you a target of sexual violence, even from your own parents. This is a movie that does not act as a role model for how to accept trans children in your community. This is not a feel-good family movie comedy. This movie shows what children with atypical gender expression go through right now, every day.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Imperfect, but original and worth seeing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    runamokprods
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very sweet, well intended, good-natured film about a 7 year old boy who is convinced he's supposed to be a girl, and wants to dress and act accordingly. His parents' confusion, and inability to deal with the situation are shown without making them monsters, even as it all starts to tear at the fabric of the family, costing the father his job, etc. What didn't work as well for me was the weaving in of the Tim Burton-esque magical realism/fantasy element of the young boy's dream world. Somehow, in the end, the film felt too light and sunny to really rip at your guts, and yet too dark to just enjoy as a wish fulfillment fantasy of the way the world should be. So while well worth seeing, it ends up as a little less than it has signs of becoming.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite lovely
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian W. Fairbanks (brianwfairbanks@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Ma Vie En Rose," winner of the 1997 Golden Globe for Best Foreign Language Film (its English title is "My Life in Pink"), concerns Ludo, a 7-year-old boy who likes to dress up as a girl and dreams of marrying a boy, even staging a mock wedding with himself decked out in a pink satin dress and pearls. His parents are appalled. When Ludo makes an appearance at a family gathering dressed as a girl, the father covers his embarrassment with nervous laughter and insists his son is just joking. The mother drags him to the sink to wash off his lipstick. When Ludo continues to cross-dress, they take him to a therapist "to set him straight." Ludo's attempts to be a typical boy prove disastrous, however. When he tries to kiss a girl, she knocks him to the ground. "I don't kiss girls," she sneers. He proves too gentle for football, and when another boy sees him through the opening of a toilet stall, sitting down to pee, he explains that he's a "girl-boy." Of course, Ludo is almost certain to grow up to be homosexual or transgender, perhaps opting to change his gender through surgery. The film doesn't take us that far into the future, but does conclude on a note of acceptance. "Whatever happens, you'll always be my child," the father tells Ludo, shortly before the credits roll. The boy in "Ma Vie En Rose" is adorable, and is very convincing when dolled up as a female. The film itself is quite lovely. Undoubtedly, there are those who would assail it as propaganda meant to promote tolerance toward homosexuals and gender-bending boys. Maybe it is, but the fact remains that there are boys who want to be girls, and such boys would exist even if a film like Ma Vie En Rose did not. If it succeeds in making the life of a "girl boy" easier, what's wrong with that? Brian W. Fairbanks
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An exceptional film about acceptance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Loisroselyn
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've just finished earning my master's degree in Psychology. This film fits right in with what I've learned. It is touching and enlightening. I believe that every person should view this film before having children. Accept everyone for who they are and don't try to change them. We live in a diverse world, we should enjoy it instead of manipulating it. Open your eyes. This story is not limited to gender specifications and expectations. It is about being accepted for who we are - period. I highly recommend this film. I rented it from Netflix, so I know that it's available. It's important to recognize the name as "Ma Vie En Rose," rather than "La Vie En Rose."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A girlboy, for the love of God! This is all your fault!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This ain't Peter Pan! When Ludovic (Georges Du Fresne) wants to escape, he gets Pam (Delphine Cadet) a Barbie-like creature that sprinkles magic dust and flies off with Ludovic in tow. Ludovic is different, maybe a transsexual, he is only seven, you know, but he likes to dress up like a girls. he plans to marry his father's boss' son when he is older. You can look at this film as being about homophobia, but you can also take the larger view that it is about society's ostracizing of anyone who doesn't fit in their cookie-cutter mold. It is a sweet tale about a boy that you just can't help loving. And, if he doesn't want to go off with Pam, I will.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yes, it's French - but don't let that stop you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cinemaphyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If there's someone in your family who is "different" - or even if there isn't - don't miss "Ma Vie en Rose", the utterly charming and moving story of a 7-year-old boy named Ludovic Fabre who believes he should have been born a girl and whose dearest wish in life is to be like "Pam", the French version of Barbie. Alain Berliner treats his subject with great tenderness and humor; there are neither heroes nor villains in the French suburb where the film takes place, just some ordinary, flawed humans muddling their way towards clarity - or its opposite. There is real substance behind the souffl&eacute;-like lightness of tone, and the pink veil of Ludovic's childish imaginings conceals moments of genuine pain. But there is nothing here that will outrage or frighten, making the R rating a complete mystery. The film could be shown to an older child (10 and up). Ludovic, as played by Georges du Fresne, will steal your heart. His performance in this film is nothing short of memorable. His mother and grandmother run a close second, but Ludovic will stay with you long after this film is over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Hazards of Smoking While Pregnant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tedg (tedg@FilmsFolded.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I like "Muriel's Wedding," which covered the same general territory, better. Superficially, this is a story about a girl in a boy's body. At least all the descriptions and summaries say so. And the parents in this think so. It isn't a life, only a couple weeks, and we have no idea what happens to this child. Even though a joke is made of misunderstanding the science of sex, the characters here (and the filmmaker too, it seems) conflate homosexual, transgender, hermaphrodite and crossdressing behavior. (There should be a word for this class. But I suppose anyone in it would exclude some others.) Never mind. The gender business is merely an excuse to explore deeper issues of disconnection between child and parent. Though I suspect few viewers will have had similar gender confusion, all will resonate to how difficult it is to make the story you inhabit. This is a movie with the child's movie within. Following Ted's rule, the level of abstraction between the movie and the movie within is the same distance as between the movie and us. Its well enough engineered to make you cry. Ted's Evaluation -- 3 of 3: Worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You owe it to yourself to see this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You do owe it to yourself to see this film. It shows the bias of the MPAA that this film is rated R, don't listen to them, if you have children, show it to them, if you don't, you owe them an explanation as to why not. This is an outstanding movie. They rated it R for using the F bomb once (it is written but you probably won't notice it). It is a well made movie and gives an accurate portrayal of a transsexual. It doesn't go too far over the top, just a little bit but still, it is the most accurate to date. The movie is touching in a "it's a wonderful life" type way. At least rent the movie if you are curious about it. I bought it and don't regret it. Don't let it deter you that it is french, after a while, you won't even realize that you are reading subtitles.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie taught me the word "tolerance"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samsoum
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being a movie fanatic and reviewer, I was invited to the "Semaine du Cinema Francophone" in Beirut (francophone cinema week). The movie taught me the word "tolerance" as I was one of these stupid guys who mocked on effeminate people. (Maybe to reject my desire at this age to be free to disguise myself, like Ludovic did in the movie). What I know is that being in a place that was supposed to gather cultivated people, journalists and movie reviewers, cinema lovers, artists, etc. I was chocked to hear people laughing at some scenes that were supposed to be moving, sensitive and very important humanely. Also the sound going out public mouth: "tsss tsss tsss" was so chocking that I felt more the pressure of "non-tolerant' society inside the movie theater itself, more than the pressure Ludovic had to endure in his story. My personality was projected into Ludovic who suffered his moments in the film, while I was personally suffering inside the theater and trying to vibe with the movie, despite chocked snobbish people's reaction. An excellent movie. Rather a drama than a comedy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
