<filme>
 <id>
  905
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119223
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1998
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Grandes Esperan&ccedil;as
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Modernization of Charles Dickens classic story finds the hapless Finn as a painter in New York pursuing his unrequited and haughty childhood love.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Based on Charles Dickens' timeless tale, this is a story of the love of a man for an unreachable woman. Updated to modern day New York City, the story concerns a man of modest background who falls in love with a rich girl. But when a mysterious benefactor greenlights the man to make his dreams come true, everything done has the ultimate goal of making Estella fall in love with him...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   painter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gulf coast
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   charles dickens
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   florida
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Charles Dickens
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Mitch Glazer
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Ethan Hawke
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gwyneth Paltrow
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Hank Azaria
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My rating: 6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vihren Mitev
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic story as a whole, again the main theme - love and not love at all, but first love from childhood. She is rich and cold from little, but beautiful, and he is sensitive, closed, poor, but very talented artist. Once kindled love between them, the fate separates them at a distance from each other for a long period of time. Ultimately, it appears that fate has the whims of one man and one woman, which I define as fantastic in the plot of the film, which catches the eye with some very good acting or directing. Even the appearance of Robert De Niro failed to make the film one of "those movies." My opinion on the subject is this - what is there in the end? Sensitive and vulnerable man hardens with age and learns to achieve its objectives, to live among the people and to be strong. Meanwhile, the cold woman softens by the years, began to think and rethink her life and her inadequate behavior and softens. And at some point of intersection of these two processes they come together to live together. Well, yes but I do not think so! Such a situation is worthy only in a movie and a movie from that class. As much as I am a romantic, I can not find a place for such behavior (especially the male role) in life. The rest - about the talent that if you develop it, it'll make way in your life and you will meet people to go with you in one direction, for that I agree. About that you have never to forget where you're going and the people who lived with you, also making always good no matter what you receive in return, yes I agree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Movie that Could've Been Great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing Great Expectations has going for it is the breathtaking, inventive, beautiful cinematography. The look of the picture is unreal and unfortunately, ends up being the film's fault. It's such a good looking picture, when it comes to analytical thought, it ends up being a looky film, not a thoughtful one. It almost sleepwalks through scenes that were written with potential to scratch deep into character's minds, but decides not to take the extra mile. Great Expectations doesn't deliver the inside of the movie, just the outside. I enjoy the update of this old tale, the film's story is an interesting one. It intrigues the audience because we can all relate to wanting something that is "better" than us; we love the things that are unattainable. It tries to takes some profound stances on topics, but doesn't succeed, because the director, Alfonso Cuaron, and the actors have a problem communicating information of the character's thoughts to the audience. Everything we should get becomes obscure. Ethan Hawke doesn't row down the riverbank, nor does he sink, he just floats, not affecting any of the actors, not the director, he's just there to look nice and move the adaptation from scene to scene. Gwyneth Paltrow embodies the aspects of a first love nicely. Robert DeNiro has some great short scenes in the film, but the ultimate twist in the end ruins his character for me. I thought the twist was excessive and unnecessary. It cheapened the story and the solid ground the film built upon. Great Expectations sets out with great intentions, seeking to lecture the audience about kindness, love, and that in success comes tragedy, but the film is like looking through the glass windows of your favorite shopping store in the mall with an empty wallet. It's stunning to look at, but fails to psychologically tell the story. Great Expectations celebrates art as well, I wish Cuaron would've dug deeper into the thoughts, motivations, and intentions of the characters because the audience is left empty. A good movie that could've been great. Rating: 6/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it appropriates an immortal literary classic, Hollywood has no qualms about rewriting the original story. "A Little Princess" director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n and "Scrooged" scenarist Mitch Glazer maintain that venerable Tinsel Town tradition with the latest cinematic adaptation of "Great Expectations," a boy-meets-girl and boy-loses-girl tearjerker. Ethan Hawke, Gwyneth Paltrow, Robert De Niro, and Anne Bancroft topline this entertaining but offbeat social drama. Tony Burrough's elegant production designs, "Reality Bites" lenser Emmanuel Lubezki's lush cinematography, and Cuaron's own poetic vision bolster "Great Expectations" far above Glazer's loquacious as well as predictable screenplay. "Great Expectations" qualifies easily as either a chick flick or a date flick, unless you're going to compare it with the six previous versions produced either for the silver screen or the boob tube. Unless you have scanned the Cliff Notes for "Great Expectations" recently, you may find yourself swamped by this free-spirited adaptation. Hollywood has changed some things. Glazer uproots the plot from its original Victorian English setting and transplants it to contemporary Florida. Charles Dickens named his protagonist Pip, but Glazer gives him the name Finn. Undoubtedly, literary types are struggling to figure out what a Mark Twain nickname and an Ernst Hemingway setting can have in common with a Dickens tale. Me, too. My B.A. was in English Literature and I've never seen Dickens like this. Not only does Glazer rechristen his lead character, but also he rechristens Miss Havisham as Ms. Dinsmoor. The criminal Magwitch is now Arthur Lustig, a death-row inmate who killed a mob boss. Estella is still Estella. Of course, Cuar&oacute;n has altered several other things, too, but that will give you literature professors something to bitch about in class. Condensing a Dickens' epic in less than two hours in a film with names that you can pronounce might have something to do with this nonsense. Briefly, Finnegan Bell (Ethan Hawke of "Dead Poets Society") takes life easy in sunny coastal Florida, just the kind of lifestyle Huckleberry Finn would yearn for in his wildest dreams. Orphaned, Finn resides with Maggie, his weirdo sister (Kim Dickens of "Brazil"), and Joe, his lower class, brother-in-law, handyman (Chris Cooper of "Lone Star"). Joe has trouble keeping food on the table and money in his pocket, so Maggie bails on them. "Great Expectations" makes women look like kennel club members, while the men emerge as good people who take care of one other. Finn spends his time cruising around in his outboard when he is not drawing pictures. Francesco Clemente received credit for those drawings, but he must have been channeling Walter Anderson. One day, the vicious convict Lustig (Robert De Nero of "Goodfellas") surprises Finn and forces him to help him escape. The escape plan goes sour for Lusting, but Finn gets away. Finn fares far less lucky during his next encounter. He meets an eccentric unmarried woman, Ms. Dinsmoor (Anne Bancroft of "The Graduate"). She is a dotty old dame abandoned at the altar by a worthless suitor. Languishing away in a magnificent mansion that has gradually gone to seed since her disastrous wedding day, Dinsmoor has left things the way they had been set up for the wedding ceremony. "Great Expectations" looks like a feminine version of "Heart of Darkness," but let us not trash a great guy like Joseph Conrad. Ms. Dinsmoor, it seems, wants a playmate for her snotty niece Estella, so she pages and pays for Finn. Poor Finn is immediately entranced by the cold, haughty Estella. Estella shocks Finn with a surprise kiss at a water fountain, and the filmmakers make that a recurring scene. When Finn reveals that he cannot dance for her, Ms. Dinsmoor allows him to draw. Reluctant initially to pose, Estella finds herself forced to sit for his portrait. Finn thinks she is beautiful but snobbish. Ms. Dinsmoor lectures Finn about the incompatibility of the sexes and the irony of love. Every time Finn meets Estella, she treats him indifferently, leaving him before anything can happen. She is the stuck-up, ice maiden of all time until the ending, but until then Finn recklessly pursues her. The unhappy day comes when Estella leaves Florida and travels to France for her education. Meanwhile, Finn sticks around Florida, works with Joe as a commercial fisherman and gives up painting. Suddenly, fortune befriends inn. Not only does he learn a benefactor has paid his airfare to New York City, but also that an art show is scheduled for his work. Quickly, Finn pulls together some new works and becomes an overnight sensation. Nevertheless, he still has problems with Estella. She takes up with a well-heeled architect, Walter Plane (Hank Azaria), and Finn's dreams appear to elude him againalmost, but you will have to suffer through the sorrow to see what happens. "Great Expectations" is a sensational looking picture. Emmanuel Lubezki's postcard photography is so gorgeous that at times it distracts you from the story. Everything in "Great Expectations" has a soft, ethereal texture. Tony Burroughs' cluttered looking production designs come the closest to recapturing the Victorian spirit of Charles Dickens. The Dinsmoor mansion is fantastic in its excessive, back-to-nature grunge. The story maybe as old as Dickens, but director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n makes it a richly palatable experience. He jump-starts the action occasionally. For example, during a dancing scene between the young Finn and Estella, Cuar&oacute;n dissolves to the grown-up Finn and Estella without altering the scenery. Cuar&oacute;n is especially adept with the appropriate light touch in treating the erotic scenes with flair and ingenuity. Paltrow strips for Hawke in one scene (remind you of "Titanic") so he can draw her in the nude. Meantime, the only nudity shown appears on paper. A later erotic encounter tastefully skirts the issue by letting your imagination do the rest. See, it's a chick flick. If you want a good cry, "Great Expectations" will live up to your anticipations. It's not a "Great" movie, but it is a "Good" one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and dramatic piece of drama!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not read the novel "Great expectations" (written by Charles Dickens). It is the novel this movie is based on, but I did not even know this book, so my review is quite objective because I cannot make any comparisons between the movie and the novel. What I can say is that this movie is a very good drama. I will not say it is a top movie because the pace is sometimes too slow, however the movie is amusing enough and the twists near and in the end of the movie are great. The cast is composed by actors like Ethan Hawke, Robert De Niro, Gwyneth Paltrow and Chris Cooper, who are very good actors delivering very good performances in this movie. In my opinion, although De Niro is objectively the best actor nowadays, Ethan Hawke delivers the best performance in this movie. Gwyneth is great and beautiful while Cooper does a very good job, as well. Robert De Niro has a short but very relevant role with a very good acting. Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (the director) should have paid more attention to the movie's pace, but he has done a more than decent job with this film. As said before, the pace is its worse point while its cast, performances and final twists are the best thing in the film. In conclusion, "Great expectations" is a very recommendable drama that nearly everyone should watch. It talks about coincidences, love and shattered dreams I think. 7,5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some incredible scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rebecca Ziggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some obvious problems with the film, particularly towards the end, but overall it was great. It's one of those films where certain scenes are nailed to perfection while others seem underdeveloped. There's a fantastic scene where Patrick Doyle's 'Kissing in the Rain' plays in the background, and Finn, oblivious to everyone around him, runs disoriented out of an exhibition, through the streets, and into a Chinese restaurant Estella is eating at with her fianc&eacute;e and their friends. The surrealism of the scene starts with the fact that he happens to know exactly which restaurant they are in. He walks in and asks Estella to dance. In the background her fianc&eacute;e is trying to remain composed, keeping a politely bemused look on his face as this stranger starts dancing with his fianc&eacute;e, and then starts to walk her out of the restaurant. Kudos to Ethan Hawke in this moment, who captures perfectly someone whose impulses have overridden any sense of propriety, who in that moment takes control of their relationship for the first time. Estella watches him as she leads him out of the restaurant, slightly in awe of the new Finn. I can't think of any other film that has illustrated the attraction between two people more skilfully. Such an underrated film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dickens..Would..Not..Be..Amused
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The two lead actors are wrong for this...so were behind the 8 ball before we pick up the cue. Ethan Hawke does not have the screen presence for this, and he is exposed badly. The Estelle character needed to be sexy and beautiful....Gwyneth Paltrow is neither. Hank Azaria is the only actor here who gives a good performance. The script is painfully predictable, and quite simply the idea of making this Charles Dickens Classic in modern day America ..does not work on any level. When Hawke is frantically painting Paltrow (with absurd pop music playing) it becomes so bad.....its funny. There are no memorable moments in this, and when De Niro turns up near the end, farce is in the air. A movie to avoid....if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well made with a great score, Bancroft and DeNiro, but the story and the leads don't quite convince
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was not expecting a completely faithful adaptation of Dickens' book, it was made clear that this was a loose adaptation and I was expecting that. On its own terms, it is definitely worth the viewing, but I was a little underwhelmed considering the talent involved. Great Expectations(1998) is certainly not a bad movie. It looks amazing, with gorgeous scenery and some of the best cinematography I've seen recently. The music is haunting and sweeping, complimenting the film wonderfully. The script has its frothy moments, but also moments of tension and wit. The supporting cast really help to carry the film, especially Anne Bancroft's haunting, deranged Mrs Dinsmoor and Robert DeNiro's caring criminal-type character in the name of Lustig. However, I wasn't as convinced by the leads. Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow look handsome certainly and their chemistry is okay, but overall I did find Hawke too sensitive and Paltrow too shallow. The story is loose as anticipated but also a rather clich&eacute;d poor-to-rich sort of story with some elements of draggy pacing and preachy tone. Alfonso Cuaron's direction was stylish certainly but forgets to give the film much substance and if anybody is looking for any of the basic underlying themes of the book you won't find much here sadly. All in all, stunning and stylish visually with a great score and supporting cast but the direction I had mixed feelings about, the story is rather clich&eacute;d and doesn't have enough substance to make me forgive that and the two leads are unconvincing, in my opinion. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost Substace in Film. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mobeans03
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember reading this novel in middle school, however as an 8th grader I was not equipped well enough to perceive this story as Dickens might have intended. Fast forward a few years and I gave myself another shot at digesting this once confusing piece of literature. That being said I thoroughly enjoyed the book and would recommend it to anyone. Not only is the story line so unique for its time, but the characters are all so vividly described (as expected) at times it felt as if you were there filled with suspense, agony and the occasional comic relief. Honestly this movie fell monumentally short of my expectations and trust me, mine were not as "great" as Pips. The casting was one of the major disappointments in this film, Ethan Hawke never gave Fin a chance to progress in the movie looks wise he seemed as poor and tentative as when he was a fisherman in spite of the new found success. When I saw the little girl who played Estella I was pleasantly surprised to know that she fit the description on the book. Gwyneth Paltrow on the other hand might have ruined it for me, she is just not pretty but I speculate that there actors were the happening thing in the late 90's I cant remember. The movie was rushed with rightful reason but it lost a great deal of story and depth. I gave this movie a 4 due to the fact that it was rushed beyond reason and ultimately costing the movie depth and story. Casting was a failure, and acting was sub par. I hope the upcoming remake in November 2012 will do the book more justice. Thanks for reading. AC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far Exceeded My Expectations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read Charles Dickens's novel on which 'Great Expectations' is based thus I cannot comment on its accuracy. However, I was very pleasantly surprised by Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n's which is an enchanting cinematic experience. It's visually mesmerizing thanks to the amazing sets and art direction and perhaps mostly to the stunning cinematography. Cuar&oacute;n certainly has an eye for visuals and in my opinion, this is one of the finest examples of first-rate cinematography. I was especially drawn by the long shots. Then there's the wonderful soundtrack which contributes beautifully to the lyrical flow and the surreal feel the film creates. The sound effects and lighting are on par. In addition, the dialogues are eloquently written. A lot is said with a few words and the few words that are spoken are poetry. The pacing is smooth. There is not a single boring moment. 'Great Expectations' reminds me that Ethan Hawk is one of the finest actors today and unlike many of his contemporaries, he manages to keep a low profile and let his work speak. His performance is transcendent, unaffected by the visuals. Chris Cooper is equally good good as Fin's guardian who loves him no matter what. Gwyneth Paltrow looks alluring (albeit a little too thin). Anne Bancroft is haunting. Robert de Niro is awesome. I didn't know that Cuaron was the director and I wasn't expecting much from a cinematic adaptation of a Dickens novel but I got far more than what I has expected. It's been a while since a film has so wholly engaged and involved me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Impressie1!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherrie Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always going to be a challenge to take a classic novel and turn it into be a movie that will satisfy everyone, especially when the story is being changed and adapted to fit a modern setting. If what you want to find from this movie is an exact translation of the book you will be unimpressed. I personally loved this movie, it is completely stylish thanks to a brilliant soundtrack and the gorgeous leads Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow (who is cast perfectly as the beautiful ice queen). They are helped along by a strong supporting cast of Anne Bancroft (wonderfully eccentric as Ms. Nora Dinsmoor), Chris Cooper and Robert DiNero. The problem, however, is that in trying to fit a story as long and complicated as 'Great expectations' into a 90 minute movie you loose a lot of the development of the characters necessary to identify and have an emotional reaction to them. Rather than linger on these issues Alfonso Cuaron concentrated on the visual aspect of the movie and the result is a movie that is great to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My rating: 6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vihren Mitev
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic story as a whole, again the main theme - love and not love at all, but first love from childhood. She is rich and cold from little, but beautiful, and he is sensitive, closed, poor, but very talented artist. Once kindled love between them, the fate separates them at a distance from each other for a long period of time. Ultimately, it appears that fate has the whims of one man and one woman, which I define as fantastic in the plot of the film, which catches the eye with some very good acting or directing. Even the appearance of Robert De Niro failed to make the film one of "those movies." My opinion on the subject is this - what is there in the end? Sensitive and vulnerable man hardens with age and learns to achieve its objectives, to live among the people and to be strong. Meanwhile, the cold woman softens by the years, began to think and rethink her life and her inadequate behavior and softens. And at some point of intersection of these two processes they come together to live together. Well, yes but I do not think so! Such a situation is worthy only in a movie and a movie from that class. As much as I am a romantic, I can not find a place for such behavior (especially the male role) in life. The rest - about the talent that if you develop it, it'll make way in your life and you will meet people to go with you in one direction, for that I agree. About that you have never to forget where you're going and the people who lived with you, also making always good no matter what you receive in return, yes I agree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Movie that Could've Been Great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing Great Expectations has going for it is the breathtaking, inventive, beautiful cinematography. The look of the picture is unreal and unfortunately, ends up being the film's fault. It's such a good looking picture, when it comes to analytical thought, it ends up being a looky film, not a thoughtful one. It almost sleepwalks through scenes that were written with potential to scratch deep into character's minds, but decides not to take the extra mile. Great Expectations doesn't deliver the inside of the movie, just the outside. I enjoy the update of this old tale, the film's story is an interesting one. It intrigues the audience because we can all relate to wanting something that is "better" than us; we love the things that are unattainable. It tries to takes some profound stances on topics, but doesn't succeed, because the director, Alfonso Cuaron, and the actors have a problem communicating information of the character's thoughts to the audience. Everything we should get becomes obscure. Ethan Hawke doesn't row down the riverbank, nor does he sink, he just floats, not affecting any of the actors, not the director, he's just there to look nice and move the adaptation from scene to scene. Gwyneth Paltrow embodies the aspects of a first love nicely. Robert DeNiro has some great short scenes in the film, but the ultimate twist in the end ruins his character for me. I thought the twist was excessive and unnecessary. It cheapened the story and the solid ground the film built upon. Great Expectations sets out with great intentions, seeking to lecture the audience about kindness, love, and that in success comes tragedy, but the film is like looking through the glass windows of your favorite shopping store in the mall with an empty wallet. It's stunning to look at, but fails to psychologically tell the story. Great Expectations celebrates art as well, I wish Cuaron would've dug deeper into the thoughts, motivations, and intentions of the characters because the audience is left empty. A good movie that could've been great. Rating: 6/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it appropriates an immortal literary classic, Hollywood has no qualms about rewriting the original story. "A Little Princess" director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n and "Scrooged" scenarist Mitch Glazer maintain that venerable Tinsel Town tradition with the latest cinematic adaptation of "Great Expectations," a boy-meets-girl and boy-loses-girl tearjerker. Ethan Hawke, Gwyneth Paltrow, Robert De Niro, and Anne Bancroft topline this entertaining but offbeat social drama. Tony Burrough's elegant production designs, "Reality Bites" lenser Emmanuel Lubezki's lush cinematography, and Cuaron's own poetic vision bolster "Great Expectations" far above Glazer's loquacious as well as predictable screenplay. "Great Expectations" qualifies easily as either a chick flick or a date flick, unless you're going to compare it with the six previous versions produced either for the silver screen or the boob tube. Unless you have scanned the Cliff Notes for "Great Expectations" recently, you may find yourself swamped by this free-spirited adaptation. Hollywood has changed some things. Glazer uproots the plot from its original Victorian English setting and transplants it to contemporary Florida. Charles Dickens named his protagonist Pip, but Glazer gives him the name Finn. Undoubtedly, literary types are struggling to figure out what a Mark Twain nickname and an Ernst Hemingway setting can have in common with a Dickens tale. Me, too. My B.A. was in English Literature and I've never seen Dickens like this. Not only does Glazer rechristen his lead character, but also he rechristens Miss Havisham as Ms. Dinsmoor. The criminal Magwitch is now Arthur Lustig, a death-row inmate who killed a mob boss. Estella is still Estella. Of course, Cuar&oacute;n has altered several other things, too, but that will give you literature professors something to bitch about in class. Condensing a Dickens' epic in less than two hours in a film with names that you can pronounce might have something to do with this nonsense. Briefly, Finnegan Bell (Ethan Hawke of "Dead Poets Society") takes life easy in sunny coastal Florida, just the kind of lifestyle Huckleberry Finn would yearn for in his wildest dreams. Orphaned, Finn resides with Maggie, his weirdo sister (Kim Dickens of "Brazil"), and Joe, his lower class, brother-in-law, handyman (Chris Cooper of "Lone Star"). Joe has trouble keeping food on the table and money in his pocket, so Maggie bails on them. "Great Expectations" makes women look like kennel club members, while the men emerge as good people who take care of one other. Finn spends his time cruising around in his outboard when he is not drawing pictures. Francesco Clemente received credit for those drawings, but he must have been channeling Walter Anderson. One day, the vicious convict Lustig (Robert De Nero of "Goodfellas") surprises Finn and forces him to help him escape. The escape plan goes sour for Lusting, but Finn gets away. Finn fares far less lucky during his next encounter. He meets an eccentric unmarried woman, Ms. Dinsmoor (Anne Bancroft of "The Graduate"). She is a dotty old dame abandoned at the altar by a worthless suitor. Languishing away in a magnificent mansion that has gradually gone to seed since her disastrous wedding day, Dinsmoor has left things the way they had been set up for the wedding ceremony. "Great Expectations" looks like a feminine version of "Heart of Darkness," but let us not trash a great guy like Joseph Conrad. Ms. Dinsmoor, it seems, wants a playmate for her snotty niece Estella, so she pages and pays for Finn. Poor Finn is immediately entranced by the cold, haughty Estella. Estella shocks Finn with a surprise kiss at a water fountain, and the filmmakers make that a recurring scene. When Finn reveals that he cannot dance for her, Ms. Dinsmoor allows him to draw. Reluctant initially to pose, Estella finds herself forced to sit for his portrait. Finn thinks she is beautiful but snobbish. Ms. Dinsmoor lectures Finn about the incompatibility of the sexes and the irony of love. Every time Finn meets Estella, she treats him indifferently, leaving him before anything can happen. She is the stuck-up, ice maiden of all time until the ending, but until then Finn recklessly pursues her. The unhappy day comes when Estella leaves Florida and travels to France for her education. Meanwhile, Finn sticks around Florida, works with Joe as a commercial fisherman and gives up painting. Suddenly, fortune befriends inn. Not only does he learn a benefactor has paid his airfare to New York City, but also that an art show is scheduled for his work. Quickly, Finn pulls together some new works and becomes an overnight sensation. Nevertheless, he still has problems with Estella. She takes up with a well-heeled architect, Walter Plane (Hank Azaria), and Finn's dreams appear to elude him againalmost, but you will have to suffer through the sorrow to see what happens. "Great Expectations" is a sensational looking picture. Emmanuel Lubezki's postcard photography is so gorgeous that at times it distracts you from the story. Everything in "Great Expectations" has a soft, ethereal texture. Tony Burroughs' cluttered looking production designs come the closest to recapturing the Victorian spirit of Charles Dickens. The Dinsmoor mansion is fantastic in its excessive, back-to-nature grunge. The story maybe as old as Dickens, but director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n makes it a richly palatable experience. He jump-starts the action occasionally. For example, during a dancing scene between the young Finn and Estella, Cuar&oacute;n dissolves to the grown-up Finn and Estella without altering the scenery. Cuar&oacute;n is especially adept with the appropriate light touch in treating the erotic scenes with flair and ingenuity. Paltrow strips for Hawke in one scene (remind you of "Titanic") so he can draw her in the nude. Meantime, the only nudity shown appears on paper. A later erotic encounter tastefully skirts the issue by letting your imagination do the rest. See, it's a chick flick. If you want a good cry, "Great Expectations" will live up to your anticipations. It's not a "Great" movie, but it is a "Good" one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and dramatic piece of drama!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not read the novel "Great expectations" (written by Charles Dickens). It is the novel this movie is based on, but I did not even know this book, so my review is quite objective because I cannot make any comparisons between the movie and the novel. What I can say is that this movie is a very good drama. I will not say it is a top movie because the pace is sometimes too slow, however the movie is amusing enough and the twists near and in the end of the movie are great. The cast is composed by actors like Ethan Hawke, Robert De Niro, Gwyneth Paltrow and Chris Cooper, who are very good actors delivering very good performances in this movie. In my opinion, although De Niro is objectively the best actor nowadays, Ethan Hawke delivers the best performance in this movie. Gwyneth is great and beautiful while Cooper does a very good job, as well. Robert De Niro has a short but very relevant role with a very good acting. Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (the director) should have paid more attention to the movie's pace, but he has done a more than decent job with this film. As said before, the pace is its worse point while its cast, performances and final twists are the best thing in the film. In conclusion, "Great expectations" is a very recommendable drama that nearly everyone should watch. It talks about coincidences, love and shattered dreams I think. 7,5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some incredible scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rebecca Ziggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some obvious problems with the film, particularly towards the end, but overall it was great. It's one of those films where certain scenes are nailed to perfection while others seem underdeveloped. There's a fantastic scene where Patrick Doyle's 'Kissing in the Rain' plays in the background, and Finn, oblivious to everyone around him, runs disoriented out of an exhibition, through the streets, and into a Chinese restaurant Estella is eating at with her fianc&eacute;e and their friends. The surrealism of the scene starts with the fact that he happens to know exactly which restaurant they are in. He walks in and asks Estella to dance. In the background her fianc&eacute;e is trying to remain composed, keeping a politely bemused look on his face as this stranger starts dancing with his fianc&eacute;e, and then starts to walk her out of the restaurant. Kudos to Ethan Hawke in this moment, who captures perfectly someone whose impulses have overridden any sense of propriety, who in that moment takes control of their relationship for the first time. Estella watches him as she leads him out of the restaurant, slightly in awe of the new Finn. I can't think of any other film that has illustrated the attraction between two people more skilfully. Such an underrated film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dickens..Would..Not..Be..Amused
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The two lead actors are wrong for this...so were behind the 8 ball before we pick up the cue. Ethan Hawke does not have the screen presence for this, and he is exposed badly. The Estelle character needed to be sexy and beautiful....Gwyneth Paltrow is neither. Hank Azaria is the only actor here who gives a good performance. The script is painfully predictable, and quite simply the idea of making this Charles Dickens Classic in modern day America ..does not work on any level. When Hawke is frantically painting Paltrow (with absurd pop music playing) it becomes so bad.....its funny. There are no memorable moments in this, and when De Niro turns up near the end, farce is in the air. A movie to avoid....if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well made with a great score, Bancroft and DeNiro, but the story and the leads don't quite convince
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was not expecting a completely faithful adaptation of Dickens' book, it was made clear that this was a loose adaptation and I was expecting that. On its own terms, it is definitely worth the viewing, but I was a little underwhelmed considering the talent involved. Great Expectations(1998) is certainly not a bad movie. It looks amazing, with gorgeous scenery and some of the best cinematography I've seen recently. The music is haunting and sweeping, complimenting the film wonderfully. The script has its frothy moments, but also moments of tension and wit. The supporting cast really help to carry the film, especially Anne Bancroft's haunting, deranged Mrs Dinsmoor and Robert DeNiro's caring criminal-type character in the name of Lustig. However, I wasn't as convinced by the leads. Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow look handsome certainly and their chemistry is okay, but overall I did find Hawke too sensitive and Paltrow too shallow. The story is loose as anticipated but also a rather clich&eacute;d poor-to-rich sort of story with some elements of draggy pacing and preachy tone. Alfonso Cuaron's direction was stylish certainly but forgets to give the film much substance and if anybody is looking for any of the basic underlying themes of the book you won't find much here sadly. All in all, stunning and stylish visually with a great score and supporting cast but the direction I had mixed feelings about, the story is rather clich&eacute;d and doesn't have enough substance to make me forgive that and the two leads are unconvincing, in my opinion. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost Substace in Film. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mobeans03
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember reading this novel in middle school, however as an 8th grader I was not equipped well enough to perceive this story as Dickens might have intended. Fast forward a few years and I gave myself another shot at digesting this once confusing piece of literature. That being said I thoroughly enjoyed the book and would recommend it to anyone. Not only is the story line so unique for its time, but the characters are all so vividly described (as expected) at times it felt as if you were there filled with suspense, agony and the occasional comic relief. Honestly this movie fell monumentally short of my expectations and trust me, mine were not as "great" as Pips. The casting was one of the major disappointments in this film, Ethan Hawke never gave Fin a chance to progress in the movie looks wise he seemed as poor and tentative as when he was a fisherman in spite of the new found success. When I saw the little girl who played Estella I was pleasantly surprised to know that she fit the description on the book. Gwyneth Paltrow on the other hand might have ruined it for me, she is just not pretty but I speculate that there actors were the happening thing in the late 90's I cant remember. The movie was rushed with rightful reason but it lost a great deal of story and depth. I gave this movie a 4 due to the fact that it was rushed beyond reason and ultimately costing the movie depth and story. Casting was a failure, and acting was sub par. I hope the upcoming remake in November 2012 will do the book more justice. Thanks for reading. AC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far Exceeded My Expectations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read Charles Dickens's novel on which 'Great Expectations' is based thus I cannot comment on its accuracy. However, I was very pleasantly surprised by Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n's which is an enchanting cinematic experience. It's visually mesmerizing thanks to the amazing sets and art direction and perhaps mostly to the stunning cinematography. Cuar&oacute;n certainly has an eye for visuals and in my opinion, this is one of the finest examples of first-rate cinematography. I was especially drawn by the long shots. Then there's the wonderful soundtrack which contributes beautifully to the lyrical flow and the surreal feel the film creates. The sound effects and lighting are on par. In addition, the dialogues are eloquently written. A lot is said with a few words and the few words that are spoken are poetry. The pacing is smooth. There is not a single boring moment. 'Great Expectations' reminds me that Ethan Hawk is one of the finest actors today and unlike many of his contemporaries, he manages to keep a low profile and let his work speak. His performance is transcendent, unaffected by the visuals. Chris Cooper is equally good good as Fin's guardian who loves him no matter what. Gwyneth Paltrow looks alluring (albeit a little too thin). Anne Bancroft is haunting. Robert de Niro is awesome. I didn't know that Cuaron was the director and I wasn't expecting much from a cinematic adaptation of a Dickens novel but I got far more than what I has expected. It's been a while since a film has so wholly engaged and involved me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Impressie1!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherrie Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always going to be a challenge to take a classic novel and turn it into be a movie that will satisfy everyone, especially when the story is being changed and adapted to fit a modern setting. If what you want to find from this movie is an exact translation of the book you will be unimpressed. I personally loved this movie, it is completely stylish thanks to a brilliant soundtrack and the gorgeous leads Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow (who is cast perfectly as the beautiful ice queen). They are helped along by a strong supporting cast of Anne Bancroft (wonderfully eccentric as Ms. Nora Dinsmoor), Chris Cooper and Robert DiNero. The problem, however, is that in trying to fit a story as long and complicated as 'Great expectations' into a 90 minute movie you loose a lot of the development of the characters necessary to identify and have an emotional reaction to them. Rather than linger on these issues Alfonso Cuaron concentrated on the visual aspect of the movie and the result is a movie that is great to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My rating: 6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vihren Mitev
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic story as a whole, again the main theme - love and not love at all, but first love from childhood. She is rich and cold from little, but beautiful, and he is sensitive, closed, poor, but very talented artist. Once kindled love between them, the fate separates them at a distance from each other for a long period of time. Ultimately, it appears that fate has the whims of one man and one woman, which I define as fantastic in the plot of the film, which catches the eye with some very good acting or directing. Even the appearance of Robert De Niro failed to make the film one of "those movies." My opinion on the subject is this - what is there in the end? Sensitive and vulnerable man hardens with age and learns to achieve its objectives, to live among the people and to be strong. Meanwhile, the cold woman softens by the years, began to think and rethink her life and her inadequate behavior and softens. And at some point of intersection of these two processes they come together to live together. Well, yes but I do not think so! Such a situation is worthy only in a movie and a movie from that class. As much as I am a romantic, I can not find a place for such behavior (especially the male role) in life. The rest - about the talent that if you develop it, it'll make way in your life and you will meet people to go with you in one direction, for that I agree. About that you have never to forget where you're going and the people who lived with you, also making always good no matter what you receive in return, yes I agree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Movie that Could've Been Great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing Great Expectations has going for it is the breathtaking, inventive, beautiful cinematography. The look of the picture is unreal and unfortunately, ends up being the film's fault. It's such a good looking picture, when it comes to analytical thought, it ends up being a looky film, not a thoughtful one. It almost sleepwalks through scenes that were written with potential to scratch deep into character's minds, but decides not to take the extra mile. Great Expectations doesn't deliver the inside of the movie, just the outside. I enjoy the update of this old tale, the film's story is an interesting one. It intrigues the audience because we can all relate to wanting something that is "better" than us; we love the things that are unattainable. It tries to takes some profound stances on topics, but doesn't succeed, because the director, Alfonso Cuaron, and the actors have a problem communicating information of the character's thoughts to the audience. Everything we should get becomes obscure. Ethan Hawke doesn't row down the riverbank, nor does he sink, he just floats, not affecting any of the actors, not the director, he's just there to look nice and move the adaptation from scene to scene. Gwyneth Paltrow embodies the aspects of a first love nicely. Robert DeNiro has some great short scenes in the film, but the ultimate twist in the end ruins his character for me. I thought the twist was excessive and unnecessary. It cheapened the story and the solid ground the film built upon. Great Expectations sets out with great intentions, seeking to lecture the audience about kindness, love, and that in success comes tragedy, but the film is like looking through the glass windows of your favorite shopping store in the mall with an empty wallet. It's stunning to look at, but fails to psychologically tell the story. Great Expectations celebrates art as well, I wish Cuaron would've dug deeper into the thoughts, motivations, and intentions of the characters because the audience is left empty. A good movie that could've been great. Rating: 6/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it appropriates an immortal literary classic, Hollywood has no qualms about rewriting the original story. "A Little Princess" director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n and "Scrooged" scenarist Mitch Glazer maintain that venerable Tinsel Town tradition with the latest cinematic adaptation of "Great Expectations," a boy-meets-girl and boy-loses-girl tearjerker. Ethan Hawke, Gwyneth Paltrow, Robert De Niro, and Anne Bancroft topline this entertaining but offbeat social drama. Tony Burrough's elegant production designs, "Reality Bites" lenser Emmanuel Lubezki's lush cinematography, and Cuaron's own poetic vision bolster "Great Expectations" far above Glazer's loquacious as well as predictable screenplay. "Great Expectations" qualifies easily as either a chick flick or a date flick, unless you're going to compare it with the six previous versions produced either for the silver screen or the boob tube. Unless you have scanned the Cliff Notes for "Great Expectations" recently, you may find yourself swamped by this free-spirited adaptation. Hollywood has changed some things. Glazer uproots the plot from its original Victorian English setting and transplants it to contemporary Florida. Charles Dickens named his protagonist Pip, but Glazer gives him the name Finn. Undoubtedly, literary types are struggling to figure out what a Mark Twain nickname and an Ernst Hemingway setting can have in common with a Dickens tale. Me, too. My B.A. was in English Literature and I've never seen Dickens like this. Not only does Glazer rechristen his lead character, but also he rechristens Miss Havisham as Ms. Dinsmoor. The criminal Magwitch is now Arthur Lustig, a death-row inmate who killed a mob boss. Estella is still Estella. Of course, Cuar&oacute;n has altered several other things, too, but that will give you literature professors something to bitch about in class. Condensing a Dickens' epic in less than two hours in a film with names that you can pronounce might have something to do with this nonsense. Briefly, Finnegan Bell (Ethan Hawke of "Dead Poets Society") takes life easy in sunny coastal Florida, just the kind of lifestyle Huckleberry Finn would yearn for in his wildest dreams. Orphaned, Finn resides with Maggie, his weirdo sister (Kim Dickens of "Brazil"), and Joe, his lower class, brother-in-law, handyman (Chris Cooper of "Lone Star"). Joe has trouble keeping food on the table and money in his pocket, so Maggie bails on them. "Great Expectations" makes women look like kennel club members, while the men emerge as good people who take care of one other. Finn spends his time cruising around in his outboard when he is not drawing pictures. Francesco Clemente received credit for those drawings, but he must have been channeling Walter Anderson. One day, the vicious convict Lustig (Robert De Nero of "Goodfellas") surprises Finn and forces him to help him escape. The escape plan goes sour for Lusting, but Finn gets away. Finn fares far less lucky during his next encounter. He meets an eccentric unmarried woman, Ms. Dinsmoor (Anne Bancroft of "The Graduate"). She is a dotty old dame abandoned at the altar by a worthless suitor. Languishing away in a magnificent mansion that has gradually gone to seed since her disastrous wedding day, Dinsmoor has left things the way they had been set up for the wedding ceremony. "Great Expectations" looks like a feminine version of "Heart of Darkness," but let us not trash a great guy like Joseph Conrad. Ms. Dinsmoor, it seems, wants a playmate for her snotty niece Estella, so she pages and pays for Finn. Poor Finn is immediately entranced by the cold, haughty Estella. Estella shocks Finn with a surprise kiss at a water fountain, and the filmmakers make that a recurring scene. When Finn reveals that he cannot dance for her, Ms. Dinsmoor allows him to draw. Reluctant initially to pose, Estella finds herself forced to sit for his portrait. Finn thinks she is beautiful but snobbish. Ms. Dinsmoor lectures Finn about the incompatibility of the sexes and the irony of love. Every time Finn meets Estella, she treats him indifferently, leaving him before anything can happen. She is the stuck-up, ice maiden of all time until the ending, but until then Finn recklessly pursues her. The unhappy day comes when Estella leaves Florida and travels to France for her education. Meanwhile, Finn sticks around Florida, works with Joe as a commercial fisherman and gives up painting. Suddenly, fortune befriends inn. Not only does he learn a benefactor has paid his airfare to New York City, but also that an art show is scheduled for his work. Quickly, Finn pulls together some new works and becomes an overnight sensation. Nevertheless, he still has problems with Estella. She takes up with a well-heeled architect, Walter Plane (Hank Azaria), and Finn's dreams appear to elude him againalmost, but you will have to suffer through the sorrow to see what happens. "Great Expectations" is a sensational looking picture. Emmanuel Lubezki's postcard photography is so gorgeous that at times it distracts you from the story. Everything in "Great Expectations" has a soft, ethereal texture. Tony Burroughs' cluttered looking production designs come the closest to recapturing the Victorian spirit of Charles Dickens. The Dinsmoor mansion is fantastic in its excessive, back-to-nature grunge. The story maybe as old as Dickens, but director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n makes it a richly palatable experience. He jump-starts the action occasionally. For example, during a dancing scene between the young Finn and Estella, Cuar&oacute;n dissolves to the grown-up Finn and Estella without altering the scenery. Cuar&oacute;n is especially adept with the appropriate light touch in treating the erotic scenes with flair and ingenuity. Paltrow strips for Hawke in one scene (remind you of "Titanic") so he can draw her in the nude. Meantime, the only nudity shown appears on paper. A later erotic encounter tastefully skirts the issue by letting your imagination do the rest. See, it's a chick flick. If you want a good cry, "Great Expectations" will live up to your anticipations. It's not a "Great" movie, but it is a "Good" one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and dramatic piece of drama!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not read the novel "Great expectations" (written by Charles Dickens). It is the novel this movie is based on, but I did not even know this book, so my review is quite objective because I cannot make any comparisons between the movie and the novel. What I can say is that this movie is a very good drama. I will not say it is a top movie because the pace is sometimes too slow, however the movie is amusing enough and the twists near and in the end of the movie are great. The cast is composed by actors like Ethan Hawke, Robert De Niro, Gwyneth Paltrow and Chris Cooper, who are very good actors delivering very good performances in this movie. In my opinion, although De Niro is objectively the best actor nowadays, Ethan Hawke delivers the best performance in this movie. Gwyneth is great and beautiful while Cooper does a very good job, as well. Robert De Niro has a short but very relevant role with a very good acting. Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (the director) should have paid more attention to the movie's pace, but he has done a more than decent job with this film. As said before, the pace is its worse point while its cast, performances and final twists are the best thing in the film. In conclusion, "Great expectations" is a very recommendable drama that nearly everyone should watch. It talks about coincidences, love and shattered dreams I think. 7,5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some incredible scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rebecca Ziggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some obvious problems with the film, particularly towards the end, but overall it was great. It's one of those films where certain scenes are nailed to perfection while others seem underdeveloped. There's a fantastic scene where Patrick Doyle's 'Kissing in the Rain' plays in the background, and Finn, oblivious to everyone around him, runs disoriented out of an exhibition, through the streets, and into a Chinese restaurant Estella is eating at with her fianc&eacute;e and their friends. The surrealism of the scene starts with the fact that he happens to know exactly which restaurant they are in. He walks in and asks Estella to dance. In the background her fianc&eacute;e is trying to remain composed, keeping a politely bemused look on his face as this stranger starts dancing with his fianc&eacute;e, and then starts to walk her out of the restaurant. Kudos to Ethan Hawke in this moment, who captures perfectly someone whose impulses have overridden any sense of propriety, who in that moment takes control of their relationship for the first time. Estella watches him as she leads him out of the restaurant, slightly in awe of the new Finn. I can't think of any other film that has illustrated the attraction between two people more skilfully. Such an underrated film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dickens..Would..Not..Be..Amused
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The two lead actors are wrong for this...so were behind the 8 ball before we pick up the cue. Ethan Hawke does not have the screen presence for this, and he is exposed badly. The Estelle character needed to be sexy and beautiful....Gwyneth Paltrow is neither. Hank Azaria is the only actor here who gives a good performance. The script is painfully predictable, and quite simply the idea of making this Charles Dickens Classic in modern day America ..does not work on any level. When Hawke is frantically painting Paltrow (with absurd pop music playing) it becomes so bad.....its funny. There are no memorable moments in this, and when De Niro turns up near the end, farce is in the air. A movie to avoid....if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well made with a great score, Bancroft and DeNiro, but the story and the leads don't quite convince
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was not expecting a completely faithful adaptation of Dickens' book, it was made clear that this was a loose adaptation and I was expecting that. On its own terms, it is definitely worth the viewing, but I was a little underwhelmed considering the talent involved. Great Expectations(1998) is certainly not a bad movie. It looks amazing, with gorgeous scenery and some of the best cinematography I've seen recently. The music is haunting and sweeping, complimenting the film wonderfully. The script has its frothy moments, but also moments of tension and wit. The supporting cast really help to carry the film, especially Anne Bancroft's haunting, deranged Mrs Dinsmoor and Robert DeNiro's caring criminal-type character in the name of Lustig. However, I wasn't as convinced by the leads. Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow look handsome certainly and their chemistry is okay, but overall I did find Hawke too sensitive and Paltrow too shallow. The story is loose as anticipated but also a rather clich&eacute;d poor-to-rich sort of story with some elements of draggy pacing and preachy tone. Alfonso Cuaron's direction was stylish certainly but forgets to give the film much substance and if anybody is looking for any of the basic underlying themes of the book you won't find much here sadly. All in all, stunning and stylish visually with a great score and supporting cast but the direction I had mixed feelings about, the story is rather clich&eacute;d and doesn't have enough substance to make me forgive that and the two leads are unconvincing, in my opinion. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost Substace in Film. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mobeans03
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember reading this novel in middle school, however as an 8th grader I was not equipped well enough to perceive this story as Dickens might have intended. Fast forward a few years and I gave myself another shot at digesting this once confusing piece of literature. That being said I thoroughly enjoyed the book and would recommend it to anyone. Not only is the story line so unique for its time, but the characters are all so vividly described (as expected) at times it felt as if you were there filled with suspense, agony and the occasional comic relief. Honestly this movie fell monumentally short of my expectations and trust me, mine were not as "great" as Pips. The casting was one of the major disappointments in this film, Ethan Hawke never gave Fin a chance to progress in the movie looks wise he seemed as poor and tentative as when he was a fisherman in spite of the new found success. When I saw the little girl who played Estella I was pleasantly surprised to know that she fit the description on the book. Gwyneth Paltrow on the other hand might have ruined it for me, she is just not pretty but I speculate that there actors were the happening thing in the late 90's I cant remember. The movie was rushed with rightful reason but it lost a great deal of story and depth. I gave this movie a 4 due to the fact that it was rushed beyond reason and ultimately costing the movie depth and story. Casting was a failure, and acting was sub par. I hope the upcoming remake in November 2012 will do the book more justice. Thanks for reading. AC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far Exceeded My Expectations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read Charles Dickens's novel on which 'Great Expectations' is based thus I cannot comment on its accuracy. However, I was very pleasantly surprised by Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n's which is an enchanting cinematic experience. It's visually mesmerizing thanks to the amazing sets and art direction and perhaps mostly to the stunning cinematography. Cuar&oacute;n certainly has an eye for visuals and in my opinion, this is one of the finest examples of first-rate cinematography. I was especially drawn by the long shots. Then there's the wonderful soundtrack which contributes beautifully to the lyrical flow and the surreal feel the film creates. The sound effects and lighting are on par. In addition, the dialogues are eloquently written. A lot is said with a few words and the few words that are spoken are poetry. The pacing is smooth. There is not a single boring moment. 'Great Expectations' reminds me that Ethan Hawk is one of the finest actors today and unlike many of his contemporaries, he manages to keep a low profile and let his work speak. His performance is transcendent, unaffected by the visuals. Chris Cooper is equally good good as Fin's guardian who loves him no matter what. Gwyneth Paltrow looks alluring (albeit a little too thin). Anne Bancroft is haunting. Robert de Niro is awesome. I didn't know that Cuaron was the director and I wasn't expecting much from a cinematic adaptation of a Dickens novel but I got far more than what I has expected. It's been a while since a film has so wholly engaged and involved me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Impressie1!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherrie Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always going to be a challenge to take a classic novel and turn it into be a movie that will satisfy everyone, especially when the story is being changed and adapted to fit a modern setting. If what you want to find from this movie is an exact translation of the book you will be unimpressed. I personally loved this movie, it is completely stylish thanks to a brilliant soundtrack and the gorgeous leads Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow (who is cast perfectly as the beautiful ice queen). They are helped along by a strong supporting cast of Anne Bancroft (wonderfully eccentric as Ms. Nora Dinsmoor), Chris Cooper and Robert DiNero. The problem, however, is that in trying to fit a story as long and complicated as 'Great expectations' into a 90 minute movie you loose a lot of the development of the characters necessary to identify and have an emotional reaction to them. Rather than linger on these issues Alfonso Cuaron concentrated on the visual aspect of the movie and the result is a movie that is great to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My rating: 6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vihren Mitev
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic story as a whole, again the main theme - love and not love at all, but first love from childhood. She is rich and cold from little, but beautiful, and he is sensitive, closed, poor, but very talented artist. Once kindled love between them, the fate separates them at a distance from each other for a long period of time. Ultimately, it appears that fate has the whims of one man and one woman, which I define as fantastic in the plot of the film, which catches the eye with some very good acting or directing. Even the appearance of Robert De Niro failed to make the film one of "those movies." My opinion on the subject is this - what is there in the end? Sensitive and vulnerable man hardens with age and learns to achieve its objectives, to live among the people and to be strong. Meanwhile, the cold woman softens by the years, began to think and rethink her life and her inadequate behavior and softens. And at some point of intersection of these two processes they come together to live together. Well, yes but I do not think so! Such a situation is worthy only in a movie and a movie from that class. As much as I am a romantic, I can not find a place for such behavior (especially the male role) in life. The rest - about the talent that if you develop it, it'll make way in your life and you will meet people to go with you in one direction, for that I agree. About that you have never to forget where you're going and the people who lived with you, also making always good no matter what you receive in return, yes I agree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Movie that Could've Been Great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing Great Expectations has going for it is the breathtaking, inventive, beautiful cinematography. The look of the picture is unreal and unfortunately, ends up being the film's fault. It's such a good looking picture, when it comes to analytical thought, it ends up being a looky film, not a thoughtful one. It almost sleepwalks through scenes that were written with potential to scratch deep into character's minds, but decides not to take the extra mile. Great Expectations doesn't deliver the inside of the movie, just the outside. I enjoy the update of this old tale, the film's story is an interesting one. It intrigues the audience because we can all relate to wanting something that is "better" than us; we love the things that are unattainable. It tries to takes some profound stances on topics, but doesn't succeed, because the director, Alfonso Cuaron, and the actors have a problem communicating information of the character's thoughts to the audience. Everything we should get becomes obscure. Ethan Hawke doesn't row down the riverbank, nor does he sink, he just floats, not affecting any of the actors, not the director, he's just there to look nice and move the adaptation from scene to scene. Gwyneth Paltrow embodies the aspects of a first love nicely. Robert DeNiro has some great short scenes in the film, but the ultimate twist in the end ruins his character for me. I thought the twist was excessive and unnecessary. It cheapened the story and the solid ground the film built upon. Great Expectations sets out with great intentions, seeking to lecture the audience about kindness, love, and that in success comes tragedy, but the film is like looking through the glass windows of your favorite shopping store in the mall with an empty wallet. It's stunning to look at, but fails to psychologically tell the story. Great Expectations celebrates art as well, I wish Cuaron would've dug deeper into the thoughts, motivations, and intentions of the characters because the audience is left empty. A good movie that could've been great. Rating: 6/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it appropriates an immortal literary classic, Hollywood has no qualms about rewriting the original story. "A Little Princess" director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n and "Scrooged" scenarist Mitch Glazer maintain that venerable Tinsel Town tradition with the latest cinematic adaptation of "Great Expectations," a boy-meets-girl and boy-loses-girl tearjerker. Ethan Hawke, Gwyneth Paltrow, Robert De Niro, and Anne Bancroft topline this entertaining but offbeat social drama. Tony Burrough's elegant production designs, "Reality Bites" lenser Emmanuel Lubezki's lush cinematography, and Cuaron's own poetic vision bolster "Great Expectations" far above Glazer's loquacious as well as predictable screenplay. "Great Expectations" qualifies easily as either a chick flick or a date flick, unless you're going to compare it with the six previous versions produced either for the silver screen or the boob tube. Unless you have scanned the Cliff Notes for "Great Expectations" recently, you may find yourself swamped by this free-spirited adaptation. Hollywood has changed some things. Glazer uproots the plot from its original Victorian English setting and transplants it to contemporary Florida. Charles Dickens named his protagonist Pip, but Glazer gives him the name Finn. Undoubtedly, literary types are struggling to figure out what a Mark Twain nickname and an Ernst Hemingway setting can have in common with a Dickens tale. Me, too. My B.A. was in English Literature and I've never seen Dickens like this. Not only does Glazer rechristen his lead character, but also he rechristens Miss Havisham as Ms. Dinsmoor. The criminal Magwitch is now Arthur Lustig, a death-row inmate who killed a mob boss. Estella is still Estella. Of course, Cuar&oacute;n has altered several other things, too, but that will give you literature professors something to bitch about in class. Condensing a Dickens' epic in less than two hours in a film with names that you can pronounce might have something to do with this nonsense. Briefly, Finnegan Bell (Ethan Hawke of "Dead Poets Society") takes life easy in sunny coastal Florida, just the kind of lifestyle Huckleberry Finn would yearn for in his wildest dreams. Orphaned, Finn resides with Maggie, his weirdo sister (Kim Dickens of "Brazil"), and Joe, his lower class, brother-in-law, handyman (Chris Cooper of "Lone Star"). Joe has trouble keeping food on the table and money in his pocket, so Maggie bails on them. "Great Expectations" makes women look like kennel club members, while the men emerge as good people who take care of one other. Finn spends his time cruising around in his outboard when he is not drawing pictures. Francesco Clemente received credit for those drawings, but he must have been channeling Walter Anderson. One day, the vicious convict Lustig (Robert De Nero of "Goodfellas") surprises Finn and forces him to help him escape. The escape plan goes sour for Lusting, but Finn gets away. Finn fares far less lucky during his next encounter. He meets an eccentric unmarried woman, Ms. Dinsmoor (Anne Bancroft of "The Graduate"). She is a dotty old dame abandoned at the altar by a worthless suitor. Languishing away in a magnificent mansion that has gradually gone to seed since her disastrous wedding day, Dinsmoor has left things the way they had been set up for the wedding ceremony. "Great Expectations" looks like a feminine version of "Heart of Darkness," but let us not trash a great guy like Joseph Conrad. Ms. Dinsmoor, it seems, wants a playmate for her snotty niece Estella, so she pages and pays for Finn. Poor Finn is immediately entranced by the cold, haughty Estella. Estella shocks Finn with a surprise kiss at a water fountain, and the filmmakers make that a recurring scene. When Finn reveals that he cannot dance for her, Ms. Dinsmoor allows him to draw. Reluctant initially to pose, Estella finds herself forced to sit for his portrait. Finn thinks she is beautiful but snobbish. Ms. Dinsmoor lectures Finn about the incompatibility of the sexes and the irony of love. Every time Finn meets Estella, she treats him indifferently, leaving him before anything can happen. She is the stuck-up, ice maiden of all time until the ending, but until then Finn recklessly pursues her. The unhappy day comes when Estella leaves Florida and travels to France for her education. Meanwhile, Finn sticks around Florida, works with Joe as a commercial fisherman and gives up painting. Suddenly, fortune befriends inn. Not only does he learn a benefactor has paid his airfare to New York City, but also that an art show is scheduled for his work. Quickly, Finn pulls together some new works and becomes an overnight sensation. Nevertheless, he still has problems with Estella. She takes up with a well-heeled architect, Walter Plane (Hank Azaria), and Finn's dreams appear to elude him againalmost, but you will have to suffer through the sorrow to see what happens. "Great Expectations" is a sensational looking picture. Emmanuel Lubezki's postcard photography is so gorgeous that at times it distracts you from the story. Everything in "Great Expectations" has a soft, ethereal texture. Tony Burroughs' cluttered looking production designs come the closest to recapturing the Victorian spirit of Charles Dickens. The Dinsmoor mansion is fantastic in its excessive, back-to-nature grunge. The story maybe as old as Dickens, but director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n makes it a richly palatable experience. He jump-starts the action occasionally. For example, during a dancing scene between the young Finn and Estella, Cuar&oacute;n dissolves to the grown-up Finn and Estella without altering the scenery. Cuar&oacute;n is especially adept with the appropriate light touch in treating the erotic scenes with flair and ingenuity. Paltrow strips for Hawke in one scene (remind you of "Titanic") so he can draw her in the nude. Meantime, the only nudity shown appears on paper. A later erotic encounter tastefully skirts the issue by letting your imagination do the rest. See, it's a chick flick. If you want a good cry, "Great Expectations" will live up to your anticipations. It's not a "Great" movie, but it is a "Good" one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and dramatic piece of drama!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not read the novel "Great expectations" (written by Charles Dickens). It is the novel this movie is based on, but I did not even know this book, so my review is quite objective because I cannot make any comparisons between the movie and the novel. What I can say is that this movie is a very good drama. I will not say it is a top movie because the pace is sometimes too slow, however the movie is amusing enough and the twists near and in the end of the movie are great. The cast is composed by actors like Ethan Hawke, Robert De Niro, Gwyneth Paltrow and Chris Cooper, who are very good actors delivering very good performances in this movie. In my opinion, although De Niro is objectively the best actor nowadays, Ethan Hawke delivers the best performance in this movie. Gwyneth is great and beautiful while Cooper does a very good job, as well. Robert De Niro has a short but very relevant role with a very good acting. Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (the director) should have paid more attention to the movie's pace, but he has done a more than decent job with this film. As said before, the pace is its worse point while its cast, performances and final twists are the best thing in the film. In conclusion, "Great expectations" is a very recommendable drama that nearly everyone should watch. It talks about coincidences, love and shattered dreams I think. 7,5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some incredible scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rebecca Ziggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some obvious problems with the film, particularly towards the end, but overall it was great. It's one of those films where certain scenes are nailed to perfection while others seem underdeveloped. There's a fantastic scene where Patrick Doyle's 'Kissing in the Rain' plays in the background, and Finn, oblivious to everyone around him, runs disoriented out of an exhibition, through the streets, and into a Chinese restaurant Estella is eating at with her fianc&eacute;e and their friends. The surrealism of the scene starts with the fact that he happens to know exactly which restaurant they are in. He walks in and asks Estella to dance. In the background her fianc&eacute;e is trying to remain composed, keeping a politely bemused look on his face as this stranger starts dancing with his fianc&eacute;e, and then starts to walk her out of the restaurant. Kudos to Ethan Hawke in this moment, who captures perfectly someone whose impulses have overridden any sense of propriety, who in that moment takes control of their relationship for the first time. Estella watches him as she leads him out of the restaurant, slightly in awe of the new Finn. I can't think of any other film that has illustrated the attraction between two people more skilfully. Such an underrated film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dickens..Would..Not..Be..Amused
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The two lead actors are wrong for this...so were behind the 8 ball before we pick up the cue. Ethan Hawke does not have the screen presence for this, and he is exposed badly. The Estelle character needed to be sexy and beautiful....Gwyneth Paltrow is neither. Hank Azaria is the only actor here who gives a good performance. The script is painfully predictable, and quite simply the idea of making this Charles Dickens Classic in modern day America ..does not work on any level. When Hawke is frantically painting Paltrow (with absurd pop music playing) it becomes so bad.....its funny. There are no memorable moments in this, and when De Niro turns up near the end, farce is in the air. A movie to avoid....if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well made with a great score, Bancroft and DeNiro, but the story and the leads don't quite convince
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was not expecting a completely faithful adaptation of Dickens' book, it was made clear that this was a loose adaptation and I was expecting that. On its own terms, it is definitely worth the viewing, but I was a little underwhelmed considering the talent involved. Great Expectations(1998) is certainly not a bad movie. It looks amazing, with gorgeous scenery and some of the best cinematography I've seen recently. The music is haunting and sweeping, complimenting the film wonderfully. The script has its frothy moments, but also moments of tension and wit. The supporting cast really help to carry the film, especially Anne Bancroft's haunting, deranged Mrs Dinsmoor and Robert DeNiro's caring criminal-type character in the name of Lustig. However, I wasn't as convinced by the leads. Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow look handsome certainly and their chemistry is okay, but overall I did find Hawke too sensitive and Paltrow too shallow. The story is loose as anticipated but also a rather clich&eacute;d poor-to-rich sort of story with some elements of draggy pacing and preachy tone. Alfonso Cuaron's direction was stylish certainly but forgets to give the film much substance and if anybody is looking for any of the basic underlying themes of the book you won't find much here sadly. All in all, stunning and stylish visually with a great score and supporting cast but the direction I had mixed feelings about, the story is rather clich&eacute;d and doesn't have enough substance to make me forgive that and the two leads are unconvincing, in my opinion. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost Substace in Film. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mobeans03
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember reading this novel in middle school, however as an 8th grader I was not equipped well enough to perceive this story as Dickens might have intended. Fast forward a few years and I gave myself another shot at digesting this once confusing piece of literature. That being said I thoroughly enjoyed the book and would recommend it to anyone. Not only is the story line so unique for its time, but the characters are all so vividly described (as expected) at times it felt as if you were there filled with suspense, agony and the occasional comic relief. Honestly this movie fell monumentally short of my expectations and trust me, mine were not as "great" as Pips. The casting was one of the major disappointments in this film, Ethan Hawke never gave Fin a chance to progress in the movie looks wise he seemed as poor and tentative as when he was a fisherman in spite of the new found success. When I saw the little girl who played Estella I was pleasantly surprised to know that she fit the description on the book. Gwyneth Paltrow on the other hand might have ruined it for me, she is just not pretty but I speculate that there actors were the happening thing in the late 90's I cant remember. The movie was rushed with rightful reason but it lost a great deal of story and depth. I gave this movie a 4 due to the fact that it was rushed beyond reason and ultimately costing the movie depth and story. Casting was a failure, and acting was sub par. I hope the upcoming remake in November 2012 will do the book more justice. Thanks for reading. AC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far Exceeded My Expectations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read Charles Dickens's novel on which 'Great Expectations' is based thus I cannot comment on its accuracy. However, I was very pleasantly surprised by Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n's which is an enchanting cinematic experience. It's visually mesmerizing thanks to the amazing sets and art direction and perhaps mostly to the stunning cinematography. Cuar&oacute;n certainly has an eye for visuals and in my opinion, this is one of the finest examples of first-rate cinematography. I was especially drawn by the long shots. Then there's the wonderful soundtrack which contributes beautifully to the lyrical flow and the surreal feel the film creates. The sound effects and lighting are on par. In addition, the dialogues are eloquently written. A lot is said with a few words and the few words that are spoken are poetry. The pacing is smooth. There is not a single boring moment. 'Great Expectations' reminds me that Ethan Hawk is one of the finest actors today and unlike many of his contemporaries, he manages to keep a low profile and let his work speak. His performance is transcendent, unaffected by the visuals. Chris Cooper is equally good good as Fin's guardian who loves him no matter what. Gwyneth Paltrow looks alluring (albeit a little too thin). Anne Bancroft is haunting. Robert de Niro is awesome. I didn't know that Cuaron was the director and I wasn't expecting much from a cinematic adaptation of a Dickens novel but I got far more than what I has expected. It's been a while since a film has so wholly engaged and involved me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Impressie1!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherrie Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always going to be a challenge to take a classic novel and turn it into be a movie that will satisfy everyone, especially when the story is being changed and adapted to fit a modern setting. If what you want to find from this movie is an exact translation of the book you will be unimpressed. I personally loved this movie, it is completely stylish thanks to a brilliant soundtrack and the gorgeous leads Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow (who is cast perfectly as the beautiful ice queen). They are helped along by a strong supporting cast of Anne Bancroft (wonderfully eccentric as Ms. Nora Dinsmoor), Chris Cooper and Robert DiNero. The problem, however, is that in trying to fit a story as long and complicated as 'Great expectations' into a 90 minute movie you loose a lot of the development of the characters necessary to identify and have an emotional reaction to them. Rather than linger on these issues Alfonso Cuaron concentrated on the visual aspect of the movie and the result is a movie that is great to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My rating: 6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vihren Mitev
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic story as a whole, again the main theme - love and not love at all, but first love from childhood. She is rich and cold from little, but beautiful, and he is sensitive, closed, poor, but very talented artist. Once kindled love between them, the fate separates them at a distance from each other for a long period of time. Ultimately, it appears that fate has the whims of one man and one woman, which I define as fantastic in the plot of the film, which catches the eye with some very good acting or directing. Even the appearance of Robert De Niro failed to make the film one of "those movies." My opinion on the subject is this - what is there in the end? Sensitive and vulnerable man hardens with age and learns to achieve its objectives, to live among the people and to be strong. Meanwhile, the cold woman softens by the years, began to think and rethink her life and her inadequate behavior and softens. And at some point of intersection of these two processes they come together to live together. Well, yes but I do not think so! Such a situation is worthy only in a movie and a movie from that class. As much as I am a romantic, I can not find a place for such behavior (especially the male role) in life. The rest - about the talent that if you develop it, it'll make way in your life and you will meet people to go with you in one direction, for that I agree. About that you have never to forget where you're going and the people who lived with you, also making always good no matter what you receive in return, yes I agree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Movie that Could've Been Great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing Great Expectations has going for it is the breathtaking, inventive, beautiful cinematography. The look of the picture is unreal and unfortunately, ends up being the film's fault. It's such a good looking picture, when it comes to analytical thought, it ends up being a looky film, not a thoughtful one. It almost sleepwalks through scenes that were written with potential to scratch deep into character's minds, but decides not to take the extra mile. Great Expectations doesn't deliver the inside of the movie, just the outside. I enjoy the update of this old tale, the film's story is an interesting one. It intrigues the audience because we can all relate to wanting something that is "better" than us; we love the things that are unattainable. It tries to takes some profound stances on topics, but doesn't succeed, because the director, Alfonso Cuaron, and the actors have a problem communicating information of the character's thoughts to the audience. Everything we should get becomes obscure. Ethan Hawke doesn't row down the riverbank, nor does he sink, he just floats, not affecting any of the actors, not the director, he's just there to look nice and move the adaptation from scene to scene. Gwyneth Paltrow embodies the aspects of a first love nicely. Robert DeNiro has some great short scenes in the film, but the ultimate twist in the end ruins his character for me. I thought the twist was excessive and unnecessary. It cheapened the story and the solid ground the film built upon. Great Expectations sets out with great intentions, seeking to lecture the audience about kindness, love, and that in success comes tragedy, but the film is like looking through the glass windows of your favorite shopping store in the mall with an empty wallet. It's stunning to look at, but fails to psychologically tell the story. Great Expectations celebrates art as well, I wish Cuaron would've dug deeper into the thoughts, motivations, and intentions of the characters because the audience is left empty. A good movie that could've been great. Rating: 6/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it appropriates an immortal literary classic, Hollywood has no qualms about rewriting the original story. "A Little Princess" director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n and "Scrooged" scenarist Mitch Glazer maintain that venerable Tinsel Town tradition with the latest cinematic adaptation of "Great Expectations," a boy-meets-girl and boy-loses-girl tearjerker. Ethan Hawke, Gwyneth Paltrow, Robert De Niro, and Anne Bancroft topline this entertaining but offbeat social drama. Tony Burrough's elegant production designs, "Reality Bites" lenser Emmanuel Lubezki's lush cinematography, and Cuaron's own poetic vision bolster "Great Expectations" far above Glazer's loquacious as well as predictable screenplay. "Great Expectations" qualifies easily as either a chick flick or a date flick, unless you're going to compare it with the six previous versions produced either for the silver screen or the boob tube. Unless you have scanned the Cliff Notes for "Great Expectations" recently, you may find yourself swamped by this free-spirited adaptation. Hollywood has changed some things. Glazer uproots the plot from its original Victorian English setting and transplants it to contemporary Florida. Charles Dickens named his protagonist Pip, but Glazer gives him the name Finn. Undoubtedly, literary types are struggling to figure out what a Mark Twain nickname and an Ernst Hemingway setting can have in common with a Dickens tale. Me, too. My B.A. was in English Literature and I've never seen Dickens like this. Not only does Glazer rechristen his lead character, but also he rechristens Miss Havisham as Ms. Dinsmoor. The criminal Magwitch is now Arthur Lustig, a death-row inmate who killed a mob boss. Estella is still Estella. Of course, Cuar&oacute;n has altered several other things, too, but that will give you literature professors something to bitch about in class. Condensing a Dickens' epic in less than two hours in a film with names that you can pronounce might have something to do with this nonsense. Briefly, Finnegan Bell (Ethan Hawke of "Dead Poets Society") takes life easy in sunny coastal Florida, just the kind of lifestyle Huckleberry Finn would yearn for in his wildest dreams. Orphaned, Finn resides with Maggie, his weirdo sister (Kim Dickens of "Brazil"), and Joe, his lower class, brother-in-law, handyman (Chris Cooper of "Lone Star"). Joe has trouble keeping food on the table and money in his pocket, so Maggie bails on them. "Great Expectations" makes women look like kennel club members, while the men emerge as good people who take care of one other. Finn spends his time cruising around in his outboard when he is not drawing pictures. Francesco Clemente received credit for those drawings, but he must have been channeling Walter Anderson. One day, the vicious convict Lustig (Robert De Nero of "Goodfellas") surprises Finn and forces him to help him escape. The escape plan goes sour for Lusting, but Finn gets away. Finn fares far less lucky during his next encounter. He meets an eccentric unmarried woman, Ms. Dinsmoor (Anne Bancroft of "The Graduate"). She is a dotty old dame abandoned at the altar by a worthless suitor. Languishing away in a magnificent mansion that has gradually gone to seed since her disastrous wedding day, Dinsmoor has left things the way they had been set up for the wedding ceremony. "Great Expectations" looks like a feminine version of "Heart of Darkness," but let us not trash a great guy like Joseph Conrad. Ms. Dinsmoor, it seems, wants a playmate for her snotty niece Estella, so she pages and pays for Finn. Poor Finn is immediately entranced by the cold, haughty Estella. Estella shocks Finn with a surprise kiss at a water fountain, and the filmmakers make that a recurring scene. When Finn reveals that he cannot dance for her, Ms. Dinsmoor allows him to draw. Reluctant initially to pose, Estella finds herself forced to sit for his portrait. Finn thinks she is beautiful but snobbish. Ms. Dinsmoor lectures Finn about the incompatibility of the sexes and the irony of love. Every time Finn meets Estella, she treats him indifferently, leaving him before anything can happen. She is the stuck-up, ice maiden of all time until the ending, but until then Finn recklessly pursues her. The unhappy day comes when Estella leaves Florida and travels to France for her education. Meanwhile, Finn sticks around Florida, works with Joe as a commercial fisherman and gives up painting. Suddenly, fortune befriends inn. Not only does he learn a benefactor has paid his airfare to New York City, but also that an art show is scheduled for his work. Quickly, Finn pulls together some new works and becomes an overnight sensation. Nevertheless, he still has problems with Estella. She takes up with a well-heeled architect, Walter Plane (Hank Azaria), and Finn's dreams appear to elude him againalmost, but you will have to suffer through the sorrow to see what happens. "Great Expectations" is a sensational looking picture. Emmanuel Lubezki's postcard photography is so gorgeous that at times it distracts you from the story. Everything in "Great Expectations" has a soft, ethereal texture. Tony Burroughs' cluttered looking production designs come the closest to recapturing the Victorian spirit of Charles Dickens. The Dinsmoor mansion is fantastic in its excessive, back-to-nature grunge. The story maybe as old as Dickens, but director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n makes it a richly palatable experience. He jump-starts the action occasionally. For example, during a dancing scene between the young Finn and Estella, Cuar&oacute;n dissolves to the grown-up Finn and Estella without altering the scenery. Cuar&oacute;n is especially adept with the appropriate light touch in treating the erotic scenes with flair and ingenuity. Paltrow strips for Hawke in one scene (remind you of "Titanic") so he can draw her in the nude. Meantime, the only nudity shown appears on paper. A later erotic encounter tastefully skirts the issue by letting your imagination do the rest. See, it's a chick flick. If you want a good cry, "Great Expectations" will live up to your anticipations. It's not a "Great" movie, but it is a "Good" one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and dramatic piece of drama!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not read the novel "Great expectations" (written by Charles Dickens). It is the novel this movie is based on, but I did not even know this book, so my review is quite objective because I cannot make any comparisons between the movie and the novel. What I can say is that this movie is a very good drama. I will not say it is a top movie because the pace is sometimes too slow, however the movie is amusing enough and the twists near and in the end of the movie are great. The cast is composed by actors like Ethan Hawke, Robert De Niro, Gwyneth Paltrow and Chris Cooper, who are very good actors delivering very good performances in this movie. In my opinion, although De Niro is objectively the best actor nowadays, Ethan Hawke delivers the best performance in this movie. Gwyneth is great and beautiful while Cooper does a very good job, as well. Robert De Niro has a short but very relevant role with a very good acting. Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (the director) should have paid more attention to the movie's pace, but he has done a more than decent job with this film. As said before, the pace is its worse point while its cast, performances and final twists are the best thing in the film. In conclusion, "Great expectations" is a very recommendable drama that nearly everyone should watch. It talks about coincidences, love and shattered dreams I think. 7,5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some incredible scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rebecca Ziggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some obvious problems with the film, particularly towards the end, but overall it was great. It's one of those films where certain scenes are nailed to perfection while others seem underdeveloped. There's a fantastic scene where Patrick Doyle's 'Kissing in the Rain' plays in the background, and Finn, oblivious to everyone around him, runs disoriented out of an exhibition, through the streets, and into a Chinese restaurant Estella is eating at with her fianc&eacute;e and their friends. The surrealism of the scene starts with the fact that he happens to know exactly which restaurant they are in. He walks in and asks Estella to dance. In the background her fianc&eacute;e is trying to remain composed, keeping a politely bemused look on his face as this stranger starts dancing with his fianc&eacute;e, and then starts to walk her out of the restaurant. Kudos to Ethan Hawke in this moment, who captures perfectly someone whose impulses have overridden any sense of propriety, who in that moment takes control of their relationship for the first time. Estella watches him as she leads him out of the restaurant, slightly in awe of the new Finn. I can't think of any other film that has illustrated the attraction between two people more skilfully. Such an underrated film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dickens..Would..Not..Be..Amused
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The two lead actors are wrong for this...so were behind the 8 ball before we pick up the cue. Ethan Hawke does not have the screen presence for this, and he is exposed badly. The Estelle character needed to be sexy and beautiful....Gwyneth Paltrow is neither. Hank Azaria is the only actor here who gives a good performance. The script is painfully predictable, and quite simply the idea of making this Charles Dickens Classic in modern day America ..does not work on any level. When Hawke is frantically painting Paltrow (with absurd pop music playing) it becomes so bad.....its funny. There are no memorable moments in this, and when De Niro turns up near the end, farce is in the air. A movie to avoid....if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well made with a great score, Bancroft and DeNiro, but the story and the leads don't quite convince
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was not expecting a completely faithful adaptation of Dickens' book, it was made clear that this was a loose adaptation and I was expecting that. On its own terms, it is definitely worth the viewing, but I was a little underwhelmed considering the talent involved. Great Expectations(1998) is certainly not a bad movie. It looks amazing, with gorgeous scenery and some of the best cinematography I've seen recently. The music is haunting and sweeping, complimenting the film wonderfully. The script has its frothy moments, but also moments of tension and wit. The supporting cast really help to carry the film, especially Anne Bancroft's haunting, deranged Mrs Dinsmoor and Robert DeNiro's caring criminal-type character in the name of Lustig. However, I wasn't as convinced by the leads. Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow look handsome certainly and their chemistry is okay, but overall I did find Hawke too sensitive and Paltrow too shallow. The story is loose as anticipated but also a rather clich&eacute;d poor-to-rich sort of story with some elements of draggy pacing and preachy tone. Alfonso Cuaron's direction was stylish certainly but forgets to give the film much substance and if anybody is looking for any of the basic underlying themes of the book you won't find much here sadly. All in all, stunning and stylish visually with a great score and supporting cast but the direction I had mixed feelings about, the story is rather clich&eacute;d and doesn't have enough substance to make me forgive that and the two leads are unconvincing, in my opinion. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost Substace in Film. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mobeans03
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember reading this novel in middle school, however as an 8th grader I was not equipped well enough to perceive this story as Dickens might have intended. Fast forward a few years and I gave myself another shot at digesting this once confusing piece of literature. That being said I thoroughly enjoyed the book and would recommend it to anyone. Not only is the story line so unique for its time, but the characters are all so vividly described (as expected) at times it felt as if you were there filled with suspense, agony and the occasional comic relief. Honestly this movie fell monumentally short of my expectations and trust me, mine were not as "great" as Pips. The casting was one of the major disappointments in this film, Ethan Hawke never gave Fin a chance to progress in the movie looks wise he seemed as poor and tentative as when he was a fisherman in spite of the new found success. When I saw the little girl who played Estella I was pleasantly surprised to know that she fit the description on the book. Gwyneth Paltrow on the other hand might have ruined it for me, she is just not pretty but I speculate that there actors were the happening thing in the late 90's I cant remember. The movie was rushed with rightful reason but it lost a great deal of story and depth. I gave this movie a 4 due to the fact that it was rushed beyond reason and ultimately costing the movie depth and story. Casting was a failure, and acting was sub par. I hope the upcoming remake in November 2012 will do the book more justice. Thanks for reading. AC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far Exceeded My Expectations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read Charles Dickens's novel on which 'Great Expectations' is based thus I cannot comment on its accuracy. However, I was very pleasantly surprised by Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n's which is an enchanting cinematic experience. It's visually mesmerizing thanks to the amazing sets and art direction and perhaps mostly to the stunning cinematography. Cuar&oacute;n certainly has an eye for visuals and in my opinion, this is one of the finest examples of first-rate cinematography. I was especially drawn by the long shots. Then there's the wonderful soundtrack which contributes beautifully to the lyrical flow and the surreal feel the film creates. The sound effects and lighting are on par. In addition, the dialogues are eloquently written. A lot is said with a few words and the few words that are spoken are poetry. The pacing is smooth. There is not a single boring moment. 'Great Expectations' reminds me that Ethan Hawk is one of the finest actors today and unlike many of his contemporaries, he manages to keep a low profile and let his work speak. His performance is transcendent, unaffected by the visuals. Chris Cooper is equally good good as Fin's guardian who loves him no matter what. Gwyneth Paltrow looks alluring (albeit a little too thin). Anne Bancroft is haunting. Robert de Niro is awesome. I didn't know that Cuaron was the director and I wasn't expecting much from a cinematic adaptation of a Dickens novel but I got far more than what I has expected. It's been a while since a film has so wholly engaged and involved me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Impressie1!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherrie Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always going to be a challenge to take a classic novel and turn it into be a movie that will satisfy everyone, especially when the story is being changed and adapted to fit a modern setting. If what you want to find from this movie is an exact translation of the book you will be unimpressed. I personally loved this movie, it is completely stylish thanks to a brilliant soundtrack and the gorgeous leads Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow (who is cast perfectly as the beautiful ice queen). They are helped along by a strong supporting cast of Anne Bancroft (wonderfully eccentric as Ms. Nora Dinsmoor), Chris Cooper and Robert DiNero. The problem, however, is that in trying to fit a story as long and complicated as 'Great expectations' into a 90 minute movie you loose a lot of the development of the characters necessary to identify and have an emotional reaction to them. Rather than linger on these issues Alfonso Cuaron concentrated on the visual aspect of the movie and the result is a movie that is great to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My rating: 6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vihren Mitev
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic story as a whole, again the main theme - love and not love at all, but first love from childhood. She is rich and cold from little, but beautiful, and he is sensitive, closed, poor, but very talented artist. Once kindled love between them, the fate separates them at a distance from each other for a long period of time. Ultimately, it appears that fate has the whims of one man and one woman, which I define as fantastic in the plot of the film, which catches the eye with some very good acting or directing. Even the appearance of Robert De Niro failed to make the film one of "those movies." My opinion on the subject is this - what is there in the end? Sensitive and vulnerable man hardens with age and learns to achieve its objectives, to live among the people and to be strong. Meanwhile, the cold woman softens by the years, began to think and rethink her life and her inadequate behavior and softens. And at some point of intersection of these two processes they come together to live together. Well, yes but I do not think so! Such a situation is worthy only in a movie and a movie from that class. As much as I am a romantic, I can not find a place for such behavior (especially the male role) in life. The rest - about the talent that if you develop it, it'll make way in your life and you will meet people to go with you in one direction, for that I agree. About that you have never to forget where you're going and the people who lived with you, also making always good no matter what you receive in return, yes I agree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Movie that Could've Been Great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing Great Expectations has going for it is the breathtaking, inventive, beautiful cinematography. The look of the picture is unreal and unfortunately, ends up being the film's fault. It's such a good looking picture, when it comes to analytical thought, it ends up being a looky film, not a thoughtful one. It almost sleepwalks through scenes that were written with potential to scratch deep into character's minds, but decides not to take the extra mile. Great Expectations doesn't deliver the inside of the movie, just the outside. I enjoy the update of this old tale, the film's story is an interesting one. It intrigues the audience because we can all relate to wanting something that is "better" than us; we love the things that are unattainable. It tries to takes some profound stances on topics, but doesn't succeed, because the director, Alfonso Cuaron, and the actors have a problem communicating information of the character's thoughts to the audience. Everything we should get becomes obscure. Ethan Hawke doesn't row down the riverbank, nor does he sink, he just floats, not affecting any of the actors, not the director, he's just there to look nice and move the adaptation from scene to scene. Gwyneth Paltrow embodies the aspects of a first love nicely. Robert DeNiro has some great short scenes in the film, but the ultimate twist in the end ruins his character for me. I thought the twist was excessive and unnecessary. It cheapened the story and the solid ground the film built upon. Great Expectations sets out with great intentions, seeking to lecture the audience about kindness, love, and that in success comes tragedy, but the film is like looking through the glass windows of your favorite shopping store in the mall with an empty wallet. It's stunning to look at, but fails to psychologically tell the story. Great Expectations celebrates art as well, I wish Cuaron would've dug deeper into the thoughts, motivations, and intentions of the characters because the audience is left empty. A good movie that could've been great. Rating: 6/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it appropriates an immortal literary classic, Hollywood has no qualms about rewriting the original story. "A Little Princess" director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n and "Scrooged" scenarist Mitch Glazer maintain that venerable Tinsel Town tradition with the latest cinematic adaptation of "Great Expectations," a boy-meets-girl and boy-loses-girl tearjerker. Ethan Hawke, Gwyneth Paltrow, Robert De Niro, and Anne Bancroft topline this entertaining but offbeat social drama. Tony Burrough's elegant production designs, "Reality Bites" lenser Emmanuel Lubezki's lush cinematography, and Cuaron's own poetic vision bolster "Great Expectations" far above Glazer's loquacious as well as predictable screenplay. "Great Expectations" qualifies easily as either a chick flick or a date flick, unless you're going to compare it with the six previous versions produced either for the silver screen or the boob tube. Unless you have scanned the Cliff Notes for "Great Expectations" recently, you may find yourself swamped by this free-spirited adaptation. Hollywood has changed some things. Glazer uproots the plot from its original Victorian English setting and transplants it to contemporary Florida. Charles Dickens named his protagonist Pip, but Glazer gives him the name Finn. Undoubtedly, literary types are struggling to figure out what a Mark Twain nickname and an Ernst Hemingway setting can have in common with a Dickens tale. Me, too. My B.A. was in English Literature and I've never seen Dickens like this. Not only does Glazer rechristen his lead character, but also he rechristens Miss Havisham as Ms. Dinsmoor. The criminal Magwitch is now Arthur Lustig, a death-row inmate who killed a mob boss. Estella is still Estella. Of course, Cuar&oacute;n has altered several other things, too, but that will give you literature professors something to bitch about in class. Condensing a Dickens' epic in less than two hours in a film with names that you can pronounce might have something to do with this nonsense. Briefly, Finnegan Bell (Ethan Hawke of "Dead Poets Society") takes life easy in sunny coastal Florida, just the kind of lifestyle Huckleberry Finn would yearn for in his wildest dreams. Orphaned, Finn resides with Maggie, his weirdo sister (Kim Dickens of "Brazil"), and Joe, his lower class, brother-in-law, handyman (Chris Cooper of "Lone Star"). Joe has trouble keeping food on the table and money in his pocket, so Maggie bails on them. "Great Expectations" makes women look like kennel club members, while the men emerge as good people who take care of one other. Finn spends his time cruising around in his outboard when he is not drawing pictures. Francesco Clemente received credit for those drawings, but he must have been channeling Walter Anderson. One day, the vicious convict Lustig (Robert De Nero of "Goodfellas") surprises Finn and forces him to help him escape. The escape plan goes sour for Lusting, but Finn gets away. Finn fares far less lucky during his next encounter. He meets an eccentric unmarried woman, Ms. Dinsmoor (Anne Bancroft of "The Graduate"). She is a dotty old dame abandoned at the altar by a worthless suitor. Languishing away in a magnificent mansion that has gradually gone to seed since her disastrous wedding day, Dinsmoor has left things the way they had been set up for the wedding ceremony. "Great Expectations" looks like a feminine version of "Heart of Darkness," but let us not trash a great guy like Joseph Conrad. Ms. Dinsmoor, it seems, wants a playmate for her snotty niece Estella, so she pages and pays for Finn. Poor Finn is immediately entranced by the cold, haughty Estella. Estella shocks Finn with a surprise kiss at a water fountain, and the filmmakers make that a recurring scene. When Finn reveals that he cannot dance for her, Ms. Dinsmoor allows him to draw. Reluctant initially to pose, Estella finds herself forced to sit for his portrait. Finn thinks she is beautiful but snobbish. Ms. Dinsmoor lectures Finn about the incompatibility of the sexes and the irony of love. Every time Finn meets Estella, she treats him indifferently, leaving him before anything can happen. She is the stuck-up, ice maiden of all time until the ending, but until then Finn recklessly pursues her. The unhappy day comes when Estella leaves Florida and travels to France for her education. Meanwhile, Finn sticks around Florida, works with Joe as a commercial fisherman and gives up painting. Suddenly, fortune befriends inn. Not only does he learn a benefactor has paid his airfare to New York City, but also that an art show is scheduled for his work. Quickly, Finn pulls together some new works and becomes an overnight sensation. Nevertheless, he still has problems with Estella. She takes up with a well-heeled architect, Walter Plane (Hank Azaria), and Finn's dreams appear to elude him againalmost, but you will have to suffer through the sorrow to see what happens. "Great Expectations" is a sensational looking picture. Emmanuel Lubezki's postcard photography is so gorgeous that at times it distracts you from the story. Everything in "Great Expectations" has a soft, ethereal texture. Tony Burroughs' cluttered looking production designs come the closest to recapturing the Victorian spirit of Charles Dickens. The Dinsmoor mansion is fantastic in its excessive, back-to-nature grunge. The story maybe as old as Dickens, but director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n makes it a richly palatable experience. He jump-starts the action occasionally. For example, during a dancing scene between the young Finn and Estella, Cuar&oacute;n dissolves to the grown-up Finn and Estella without altering the scenery. Cuar&oacute;n is especially adept with the appropriate light touch in treating the erotic scenes with flair and ingenuity. Paltrow strips for Hawke in one scene (remind you of "Titanic") so he can draw her in the nude. Meantime, the only nudity shown appears on paper. A later erotic encounter tastefully skirts the issue by letting your imagination do the rest. See, it's a chick flick. If you want a good cry, "Great Expectations" will live up to your anticipations. It's not a "Great" movie, but it is a "Good" one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and dramatic piece of drama!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not read the novel "Great expectations" (written by Charles Dickens). It is the novel this movie is based on, but I did not even know this book, so my review is quite objective because I cannot make any comparisons between the movie and the novel. What I can say is that this movie is a very good drama. I will not say it is a top movie because the pace is sometimes too slow, however the movie is amusing enough and the twists near and in the end of the movie are great. The cast is composed by actors like Ethan Hawke, Robert De Niro, Gwyneth Paltrow and Chris Cooper, who are very good actors delivering very good performances in this movie. In my opinion, although De Niro is objectively the best actor nowadays, Ethan Hawke delivers the best performance in this movie. Gwyneth is great and beautiful while Cooper does a very good job, as well. Robert De Niro has a short but very relevant role with a very good acting. Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (the director) should have paid more attention to the movie's pace, but he has done a more than decent job with this film. As said before, the pace is its worse point while its cast, performances and final twists are the best thing in the film. In conclusion, "Great expectations" is a very recommendable drama that nearly everyone should watch. It talks about coincidences, love and shattered dreams I think. 7,5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some incredible scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rebecca Ziggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some obvious problems with the film, particularly towards the end, but overall it was great. It's one of those films where certain scenes are nailed to perfection while others seem underdeveloped. There's a fantastic scene where Patrick Doyle's 'Kissing in the Rain' plays in the background, and Finn, oblivious to everyone around him, runs disoriented out of an exhibition, through the streets, and into a Chinese restaurant Estella is eating at with her fianc&eacute;e and their friends. The surrealism of the scene starts with the fact that he happens to know exactly which restaurant they are in. He walks in and asks Estella to dance. In the background her fianc&eacute;e is trying to remain composed, keeping a politely bemused look on his face as this stranger starts dancing with his fianc&eacute;e, and then starts to walk her out of the restaurant. Kudos to Ethan Hawke in this moment, who captures perfectly someone whose impulses have overridden any sense of propriety, who in that moment takes control of their relationship for the first time. Estella watches him as she leads him out of the restaurant, slightly in awe of the new Finn. I can't think of any other film that has illustrated the attraction between two people more skilfully. Such an underrated film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dickens..Would..Not..Be..Amused
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The two lead actors are wrong for this...so were behind the 8 ball before we pick up the cue. Ethan Hawke does not have the screen presence for this, and he is exposed badly. The Estelle character needed to be sexy and beautiful....Gwyneth Paltrow is neither. Hank Azaria is the only actor here who gives a good performance. The script is painfully predictable, and quite simply the idea of making this Charles Dickens Classic in modern day America ..does not work on any level. When Hawke is frantically painting Paltrow (with absurd pop music playing) it becomes so bad.....its funny. There are no memorable moments in this, and when De Niro turns up near the end, farce is in the air. A movie to avoid....if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well made with a great score, Bancroft and DeNiro, but the story and the leads don't quite convince
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was not expecting a completely faithful adaptation of Dickens' book, it was made clear that this was a loose adaptation and I was expecting that. On its own terms, it is definitely worth the viewing, but I was a little underwhelmed considering the talent involved. Great Expectations(1998) is certainly not a bad movie. It looks amazing, with gorgeous scenery and some of the best cinematography I've seen recently. The music is haunting and sweeping, complimenting the film wonderfully. The script has its frothy moments, but also moments of tension and wit. The supporting cast really help to carry the film, especially Anne Bancroft's haunting, deranged Mrs Dinsmoor and Robert DeNiro's caring criminal-type character in the name of Lustig. However, I wasn't as convinced by the leads. Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow look handsome certainly and their chemistry is okay, but overall I did find Hawke too sensitive and Paltrow too shallow. The story is loose as anticipated but also a rather clich&eacute;d poor-to-rich sort of story with some elements of draggy pacing and preachy tone. Alfonso Cuaron's direction was stylish certainly but forgets to give the film much substance and if anybody is looking for any of the basic underlying themes of the book you won't find much here sadly. All in all, stunning and stylish visually with a great score and supporting cast but the direction I had mixed feelings about, the story is rather clich&eacute;d and doesn't have enough substance to make me forgive that and the two leads are unconvincing, in my opinion. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost Substace in Film. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mobeans03
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember reading this novel in middle school, however as an 8th grader I was not equipped well enough to perceive this story as Dickens might have intended. Fast forward a few years and I gave myself another shot at digesting this once confusing piece of literature. That being said I thoroughly enjoyed the book and would recommend it to anyone. Not only is the story line so unique for its time, but the characters are all so vividly described (as expected) at times it felt as if you were there filled with suspense, agony and the occasional comic relief. Honestly this movie fell monumentally short of my expectations and trust me, mine were not as "great" as Pips. The casting was one of the major disappointments in this film, Ethan Hawke never gave Fin a chance to progress in the movie looks wise he seemed as poor and tentative as when he was a fisherman in spite of the new found success. When I saw the little girl who played Estella I was pleasantly surprised to know that she fit the description on the book. Gwyneth Paltrow on the other hand might have ruined it for me, she is just not pretty but I speculate that there actors were the happening thing in the late 90's I cant remember. The movie was rushed with rightful reason but it lost a great deal of story and depth. I gave this movie a 4 due to the fact that it was rushed beyond reason and ultimately costing the movie depth and story. Casting was a failure, and acting was sub par. I hope the upcoming remake in November 2012 will do the book more justice. Thanks for reading. AC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far Exceeded My Expectations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read Charles Dickens's novel on which 'Great Expectations' is based thus I cannot comment on its accuracy. However, I was very pleasantly surprised by Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n's which is an enchanting cinematic experience. It's visually mesmerizing thanks to the amazing sets and art direction and perhaps mostly to the stunning cinematography. Cuar&oacute;n certainly has an eye for visuals and in my opinion, this is one of the finest examples of first-rate cinematography. I was especially drawn by the long shots. Then there's the wonderful soundtrack which contributes beautifully to the lyrical flow and the surreal feel the film creates. The sound effects and lighting are on par. In addition, the dialogues are eloquently written. A lot is said with a few words and the few words that are spoken are poetry. The pacing is smooth. There is not a single boring moment. 'Great Expectations' reminds me that Ethan Hawk is one of the finest actors today and unlike many of his contemporaries, he manages to keep a low profile and let his work speak. His performance is transcendent, unaffected by the visuals. Chris Cooper is equally good good as Fin's guardian who loves him no matter what. Gwyneth Paltrow looks alluring (albeit a little too thin). Anne Bancroft is haunting. Robert de Niro is awesome. I didn't know that Cuaron was the director and I wasn't expecting much from a cinematic adaptation of a Dickens novel but I got far more than what I has expected. It's been a while since a film has so wholly engaged and involved me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Impressie1!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherrie Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always going to be a challenge to take a classic novel and turn it into be a movie that will satisfy everyone, especially when the story is being changed and adapted to fit a modern setting. If what you want to find from this movie is an exact translation of the book you will be unimpressed. I personally loved this movie, it is completely stylish thanks to a brilliant soundtrack and the gorgeous leads Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow (who is cast perfectly as the beautiful ice queen). They are helped along by a strong supporting cast of Anne Bancroft (wonderfully eccentric as Ms. Nora Dinsmoor), Chris Cooper and Robert DiNero. The problem, however, is that in trying to fit a story as long and complicated as 'Great expectations' into a 90 minute movie you loose a lot of the development of the characters necessary to identify and have an emotional reaction to them. Rather than linger on these issues Alfonso Cuaron concentrated on the visual aspect of the movie and the result is a movie that is great to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My rating: 6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vihren Mitev
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic story as a whole, again the main theme - love and not love at all, but first love from childhood. She is rich and cold from little, but beautiful, and he is sensitive, closed, poor, but very talented artist. Once kindled love between them, the fate separates them at a distance from each other for a long period of time. Ultimately, it appears that fate has the whims of one man and one woman, which I define as fantastic in the plot of the film, which catches the eye with some very good acting or directing. Even the appearance of Robert De Niro failed to make the film one of "those movies." My opinion on the subject is this - what is there in the end? Sensitive and vulnerable man hardens with age and learns to achieve its objectives, to live among the people and to be strong. Meanwhile, the cold woman softens by the years, began to think and rethink her life and her inadequate behavior and softens. And at some point of intersection of these two processes they come together to live together. Well, yes but I do not think so! Such a situation is worthy only in a movie and a movie from that class. As much as I am a romantic, I can not find a place for such behavior (especially the male role) in life. The rest - about the talent that if you develop it, it'll make way in your life and you will meet people to go with you in one direction, for that I agree. About that you have never to forget where you're going and the people who lived with you, also making always good no matter what you receive in return, yes I agree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Movie that Could've Been Great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing Great Expectations has going for it is the breathtaking, inventive, beautiful cinematography. The look of the picture is unreal and unfortunately, ends up being the film's fault. It's such a good looking picture, when it comes to analytical thought, it ends up being a looky film, not a thoughtful one. It almost sleepwalks through scenes that were written with potential to scratch deep into character's minds, but decides not to take the extra mile. Great Expectations doesn't deliver the inside of the movie, just the outside. I enjoy the update of this old tale, the film's story is an interesting one. It intrigues the audience because we can all relate to wanting something that is "better" than us; we love the things that are unattainable. It tries to takes some profound stances on topics, but doesn't succeed, because the director, Alfonso Cuaron, and the actors have a problem communicating information of the character's thoughts to the audience. Everything we should get becomes obscure. Ethan Hawke doesn't row down the riverbank, nor does he sink, he just floats, not affecting any of the actors, not the director, he's just there to look nice and move the adaptation from scene to scene. Gwyneth Paltrow embodies the aspects of a first love nicely. Robert DeNiro has some great short scenes in the film, but the ultimate twist in the end ruins his character for me. I thought the twist was excessive and unnecessary. It cheapened the story and the solid ground the film built upon. Great Expectations sets out with great intentions, seeking to lecture the audience about kindness, love, and that in success comes tragedy, but the film is like looking through the glass windows of your favorite shopping store in the mall with an empty wallet. It's stunning to look at, but fails to psychologically tell the story. Great Expectations celebrates art as well, I wish Cuaron would've dug deeper into the thoughts, motivations, and intentions of the characters because the audience is left empty. A good movie that could've been great. Rating: 6/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it appropriates an immortal literary classic, Hollywood has no qualms about rewriting the original story. "A Little Princess" director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n and "Scrooged" scenarist Mitch Glazer maintain that venerable Tinsel Town tradition with the latest cinematic adaptation of "Great Expectations," a boy-meets-girl and boy-loses-girl tearjerker. Ethan Hawke, Gwyneth Paltrow, Robert De Niro, and Anne Bancroft topline this entertaining but offbeat social drama. Tony Burrough's elegant production designs, "Reality Bites" lenser Emmanuel Lubezki's lush cinematography, and Cuaron's own poetic vision bolster "Great Expectations" far above Glazer's loquacious as well as predictable screenplay. "Great Expectations" qualifies easily as either a chick flick or a date flick, unless you're going to compare it with the six previous versions produced either for the silver screen or the boob tube. Unless you have scanned the Cliff Notes for "Great Expectations" recently, you may find yourself swamped by this free-spirited adaptation. Hollywood has changed some things. Glazer uproots the plot from its original Victorian English setting and transplants it to contemporary Florida. Charles Dickens named his protagonist Pip, but Glazer gives him the name Finn. Undoubtedly, literary types are struggling to figure out what a Mark Twain nickname and an Ernst Hemingway setting can have in common with a Dickens tale. Me, too. My B.A. was in English Literature and I've never seen Dickens like this. Not only does Glazer rechristen his lead character, but also he rechristens Miss Havisham as Ms. Dinsmoor. The criminal Magwitch is now Arthur Lustig, a death-row inmate who killed a mob boss. Estella is still Estella. Of course, Cuar&oacute;n has altered several other things, too, but that will give you literature professors something to bitch about in class. Condensing a Dickens' epic in less than two hours in a film with names that you can pronounce might have something to do with this nonsense. Briefly, Finnegan Bell (Ethan Hawke of "Dead Poets Society") takes life easy in sunny coastal Florida, just the kind of lifestyle Huckleberry Finn would yearn for in his wildest dreams. Orphaned, Finn resides with Maggie, his weirdo sister (Kim Dickens of "Brazil"), and Joe, his lower class, brother-in-law, handyman (Chris Cooper of "Lone Star"). Joe has trouble keeping food on the table and money in his pocket, so Maggie bails on them. "Great Expectations" makes women look like kennel club members, while the men emerge as good people who take care of one other. Finn spends his time cruising around in his outboard when he is not drawing pictures. Francesco Clemente received credit for those drawings, but he must have been channeling Walter Anderson. One day, the vicious convict Lustig (Robert De Nero of "Goodfellas") surprises Finn and forces him to help him escape. The escape plan goes sour for Lusting, but Finn gets away. Finn fares far less lucky during his next encounter. He meets an eccentric unmarried woman, Ms. Dinsmoor (Anne Bancroft of "The Graduate"). She is a dotty old dame abandoned at the altar by a worthless suitor. Languishing away in a magnificent mansion that has gradually gone to seed since her disastrous wedding day, Dinsmoor has left things the way they had been set up for the wedding ceremony. "Great Expectations" looks like a feminine version of "Heart of Darkness," but let us not trash a great guy like Joseph Conrad. Ms. Dinsmoor, it seems, wants a playmate for her snotty niece Estella, so she pages and pays for Finn. Poor Finn is immediately entranced by the cold, haughty Estella. Estella shocks Finn with a surprise kiss at a water fountain, and the filmmakers make that a recurring scene. When Finn reveals that he cannot dance for her, Ms. Dinsmoor allows him to draw. Reluctant initially to pose, Estella finds herself forced to sit for his portrait. Finn thinks she is beautiful but snobbish. Ms. Dinsmoor lectures Finn about the incompatibility of the sexes and the irony of love. Every time Finn meets Estella, she treats him indifferently, leaving him before anything can happen. She is the stuck-up, ice maiden of all time until the ending, but until then Finn recklessly pursues her. The unhappy day comes when Estella leaves Florida and travels to France for her education. Meanwhile, Finn sticks around Florida, works with Joe as a commercial fisherman and gives up painting. Suddenly, fortune befriends inn. Not only does he learn a benefactor has paid his airfare to New York City, but also that an art show is scheduled for his work. Quickly, Finn pulls together some new works and becomes an overnight sensation. Nevertheless, he still has problems with Estella. She takes up with a well-heeled architect, Walter Plane (Hank Azaria), and Finn's dreams appear to elude him againalmost, but you will have to suffer through the sorrow to see what happens. "Great Expectations" is a sensational looking picture. Emmanuel Lubezki's postcard photography is so gorgeous that at times it distracts you from the story. Everything in "Great Expectations" has a soft, ethereal texture. Tony Burroughs' cluttered looking production designs come the closest to recapturing the Victorian spirit of Charles Dickens. The Dinsmoor mansion is fantastic in its excessive, back-to-nature grunge. The story maybe as old as Dickens, but director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n makes it a richly palatable experience. He jump-starts the action occasionally. For example, during a dancing scene between the young Finn and Estella, Cuar&oacute;n dissolves to the grown-up Finn and Estella without altering the scenery. Cuar&oacute;n is especially adept with the appropriate light touch in treating the erotic scenes with flair and ingenuity. Paltrow strips for Hawke in one scene (remind you of "Titanic") so he can draw her in the nude. Meantime, the only nudity shown appears on paper. A later erotic encounter tastefully skirts the issue by letting your imagination do the rest. See, it's a chick flick. If you want a good cry, "Great Expectations" will live up to your anticipations. It's not a "Great" movie, but it is a "Good" one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and dramatic piece of drama!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not read the novel "Great expectations" (written by Charles Dickens). It is the novel this movie is based on, but I did not even know this book, so my review is quite objective because I cannot make any comparisons between the movie and the novel. What I can say is that this movie is a very good drama. I will not say it is a top movie because the pace is sometimes too slow, however the movie is amusing enough and the twists near and in the end of the movie are great. The cast is composed by actors like Ethan Hawke, Robert De Niro, Gwyneth Paltrow and Chris Cooper, who are very good actors delivering very good performances in this movie. In my opinion, although De Niro is objectively the best actor nowadays, Ethan Hawke delivers the best performance in this movie. Gwyneth is great and beautiful while Cooper does a very good job, as well. Robert De Niro has a short but very relevant role with a very good acting. Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (the director) should have paid more attention to the movie's pace, but he has done a more than decent job with this film. As said before, the pace is its worse point while its cast, performances and final twists are the best thing in the film. In conclusion, "Great expectations" is a very recommendable drama that nearly everyone should watch. It talks about coincidences, love and shattered dreams I think. 7,5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some incredible scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rebecca Ziggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some obvious problems with the film, particularly towards the end, but overall it was great. It's one of those films where certain scenes are nailed to perfection while others seem underdeveloped. There's a fantastic scene where Patrick Doyle's 'Kissing in the Rain' plays in the background, and Finn, oblivious to everyone around him, runs disoriented out of an exhibition, through the streets, and into a Chinese restaurant Estella is eating at with her fianc&eacute;e and their friends. The surrealism of the scene starts with the fact that he happens to know exactly which restaurant they are in. He walks in and asks Estella to dance. In the background her fianc&eacute;e is trying to remain composed, keeping a politely bemused look on his face as this stranger starts dancing with his fianc&eacute;e, and then starts to walk her out of the restaurant. Kudos to Ethan Hawke in this moment, who captures perfectly someone whose impulses have overridden any sense of propriety, who in that moment takes control of their relationship for the first time. Estella watches him as she leads him out of the restaurant, slightly in awe of the new Finn. I can't think of any other film that has illustrated the attraction between two people more skilfully. Such an underrated film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dickens..Would..Not..Be..Amused
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The two lead actors are wrong for this...so were behind the 8 ball before we pick up the cue. Ethan Hawke does not have the screen presence for this, and he is exposed badly. The Estelle character needed to be sexy and beautiful....Gwyneth Paltrow is neither. Hank Azaria is the only actor here who gives a good performance. The script is painfully predictable, and quite simply the idea of making this Charles Dickens Classic in modern day America ..does not work on any level. When Hawke is frantically painting Paltrow (with absurd pop music playing) it becomes so bad.....its funny. There are no memorable moments in this, and when De Niro turns up near the end, farce is in the air. A movie to avoid....if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well made with a great score, Bancroft and DeNiro, but the story and the leads don't quite convince
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was not expecting a completely faithful adaptation of Dickens' book, it was made clear that this was a loose adaptation and I was expecting that. On its own terms, it is definitely worth the viewing, but I was a little underwhelmed considering the talent involved. Great Expectations(1998) is certainly not a bad movie. It looks amazing, with gorgeous scenery and some of the best cinematography I've seen recently. The music is haunting and sweeping, complimenting the film wonderfully. The script has its frothy moments, but also moments of tension and wit. The supporting cast really help to carry the film, especially Anne Bancroft's haunting, deranged Mrs Dinsmoor and Robert DeNiro's caring criminal-type character in the name of Lustig. However, I wasn't as convinced by the leads. Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow look handsome certainly and their chemistry is okay, but overall I did find Hawke too sensitive and Paltrow too shallow. The story is loose as anticipated but also a rather clich&eacute;d poor-to-rich sort of story with some elements of draggy pacing and preachy tone. Alfonso Cuaron's direction was stylish certainly but forgets to give the film much substance and if anybody is looking for any of the basic underlying themes of the book you won't find much here sadly. All in all, stunning and stylish visually with a great score and supporting cast but the direction I had mixed feelings about, the story is rather clich&eacute;d and doesn't have enough substance to make me forgive that and the two leads are unconvincing, in my opinion. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost Substace in Film. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mobeans03
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember reading this novel in middle school, however as an 8th grader I was not equipped well enough to perceive this story as Dickens might have intended. Fast forward a few years and I gave myself another shot at digesting this once confusing piece of literature. That being said I thoroughly enjoyed the book and would recommend it to anyone. Not only is the story line so unique for its time, but the characters are all so vividly described (as expected) at times it felt as if you were there filled with suspense, agony and the occasional comic relief. Honestly this movie fell monumentally short of my expectations and trust me, mine were not as "great" as Pips. The casting was one of the major disappointments in this film, Ethan Hawke never gave Fin a chance to progress in the movie looks wise he seemed as poor and tentative as when he was a fisherman in spite of the new found success. When I saw the little girl who played Estella I was pleasantly surprised to know that she fit the description on the book. Gwyneth Paltrow on the other hand might have ruined it for me, she is just not pretty but I speculate that there actors were the happening thing in the late 90's I cant remember. The movie was rushed with rightful reason but it lost a great deal of story and depth. I gave this movie a 4 due to the fact that it was rushed beyond reason and ultimately costing the movie depth and story. Casting was a failure, and acting was sub par. I hope the upcoming remake in November 2012 will do the book more justice. Thanks for reading. AC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far Exceeded My Expectations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read Charles Dickens's novel on which 'Great Expectations' is based thus I cannot comment on its accuracy. However, I was very pleasantly surprised by Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n's which is an enchanting cinematic experience. It's visually mesmerizing thanks to the amazing sets and art direction and perhaps mostly to the stunning cinematography. Cuar&oacute;n certainly has an eye for visuals and in my opinion, this is one of the finest examples of first-rate cinematography. I was especially drawn by the long shots. Then there's the wonderful soundtrack which contributes beautifully to the lyrical flow and the surreal feel the film creates. The sound effects and lighting are on par. In addition, the dialogues are eloquently written. A lot is said with a few words and the few words that are spoken are poetry. The pacing is smooth. There is not a single boring moment. 'Great Expectations' reminds me that Ethan Hawk is one of the finest actors today and unlike many of his contemporaries, he manages to keep a low profile and let his work speak. His performance is transcendent, unaffected by the visuals. Chris Cooper is equally good good as Fin's guardian who loves him no matter what. Gwyneth Paltrow looks alluring (albeit a little too thin). Anne Bancroft is haunting. Robert de Niro is awesome. I didn't know that Cuaron was the director and I wasn't expecting much from a cinematic adaptation of a Dickens novel but I got far more than what I has expected. It's been a while since a film has so wholly engaged and involved me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Impressie1!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherrie Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always going to be a challenge to take a classic novel and turn it into be a movie that will satisfy everyone, especially when the story is being changed and adapted to fit a modern setting. If what you want to find from this movie is an exact translation of the book you will be unimpressed. I personally loved this movie, it is completely stylish thanks to a brilliant soundtrack and the gorgeous leads Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow (who is cast perfectly as the beautiful ice queen). They are helped along by a strong supporting cast of Anne Bancroft (wonderfully eccentric as Ms. Nora Dinsmoor), Chris Cooper and Robert DiNero. The problem, however, is that in trying to fit a story as long and complicated as 'Great expectations' into a 90 minute movie you loose a lot of the development of the characters necessary to identify and have an emotional reaction to them. Rather than linger on these issues Alfonso Cuaron concentrated on the visual aspect of the movie and the result is a movie that is great to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My rating: 6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vihren Mitev
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic story as a whole, again the main theme - love and not love at all, but first love from childhood. She is rich and cold from little, but beautiful, and he is sensitive, closed, poor, but very talented artist. Once kindled love between them, the fate separates them at a distance from each other for a long period of time. Ultimately, it appears that fate has the whims of one man and one woman, which I define as fantastic in the plot of the film, which catches the eye with some very good acting or directing. Even the appearance of Robert De Niro failed to make the film one of "those movies." My opinion on the subject is this - what is there in the end? Sensitive and vulnerable man hardens with age and learns to achieve its objectives, to live among the people and to be strong. Meanwhile, the cold woman softens by the years, began to think and rethink her life and her inadequate behavior and softens. And at some point of intersection of these two processes they come together to live together. Well, yes but I do not think so! Such a situation is worthy only in a movie and a movie from that class. As much as I am a romantic, I can not find a place for such behavior (especially the male role) in life. The rest - about the talent that if you develop it, it'll make way in your life and you will meet people to go with you in one direction, for that I agree. About that you have never to forget where you're going and the people who lived with you, also making always good no matter what you receive in return, yes I agree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Movie that Could've Been Great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing Great Expectations has going for it is the breathtaking, inventive, beautiful cinematography. The look of the picture is unreal and unfortunately, ends up being the film's fault. It's such a good looking picture, when it comes to analytical thought, it ends up being a looky film, not a thoughtful one. It almost sleepwalks through scenes that were written with potential to scratch deep into character's minds, but decides not to take the extra mile. Great Expectations doesn't deliver the inside of the movie, just the outside. I enjoy the update of this old tale, the film's story is an interesting one. It intrigues the audience because we can all relate to wanting something that is "better" than us; we love the things that are unattainable. It tries to takes some profound stances on topics, but doesn't succeed, because the director, Alfonso Cuaron, and the actors have a problem communicating information of the character's thoughts to the audience. Everything we should get becomes obscure. Ethan Hawke doesn't row down the riverbank, nor does he sink, he just floats, not affecting any of the actors, not the director, he's just there to look nice and move the adaptation from scene to scene. Gwyneth Paltrow embodies the aspects of a first love nicely. Robert DeNiro has some great short scenes in the film, but the ultimate twist in the end ruins his character for me. I thought the twist was excessive and unnecessary. It cheapened the story and the solid ground the film built upon. Great Expectations sets out with great intentions, seeking to lecture the audience about kindness, love, and that in success comes tragedy, but the film is like looking through the glass windows of your favorite shopping store in the mall with an empty wallet. It's stunning to look at, but fails to psychologically tell the story. Great Expectations celebrates art as well, I wish Cuaron would've dug deeper into the thoughts, motivations, and intentions of the characters because the audience is left empty. A good movie that could've been great. Rating: 6/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it appropriates an immortal literary classic, Hollywood has no qualms about rewriting the original story. "A Little Princess" director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n and "Scrooged" scenarist Mitch Glazer maintain that venerable Tinsel Town tradition with the latest cinematic adaptation of "Great Expectations," a boy-meets-girl and boy-loses-girl tearjerker. Ethan Hawke, Gwyneth Paltrow, Robert De Niro, and Anne Bancroft topline this entertaining but offbeat social drama. Tony Burrough's elegant production designs, "Reality Bites" lenser Emmanuel Lubezki's lush cinematography, and Cuaron's own poetic vision bolster "Great Expectations" far above Glazer's loquacious as well as predictable screenplay. "Great Expectations" qualifies easily as either a chick flick or a date flick, unless you're going to compare it with the six previous versions produced either for the silver screen or the boob tube. Unless you have scanned the Cliff Notes for "Great Expectations" recently, you may find yourself swamped by this free-spirited adaptation. Hollywood has changed some things. Glazer uproots the plot from its original Victorian English setting and transplants it to contemporary Florida. Charles Dickens named his protagonist Pip, but Glazer gives him the name Finn. Undoubtedly, literary types are struggling to figure out what a Mark Twain nickname and an Ernst Hemingway setting can have in common with a Dickens tale. Me, too. My B.A. was in English Literature and I've never seen Dickens like this. Not only does Glazer rechristen his lead character, but also he rechristens Miss Havisham as Ms. Dinsmoor. The criminal Magwitch is now Arthur Lustig, a death-row inmate who killed a mob boss. Estella is still Estella. Of course, Cuar&oacute;n has altered several other things, too, but that will give you literature professors something to bitch about in class. Condensing a Dickens' epic in less than two hours in a film with names that you can pronounce might have something to do with this nonsense. Briefly, Finnegan Bell (Ethan Hawke of "Dead Poets Society") takes life easy in sunny coastal Florida, just the kind of lifestyle Huckleberry Finn would yearn for in his wildest dreams. Orphaned, Finn resides with Maggie, his weirdo sister (Kim Dickens of "Brazil"), and Joe, his lower class, brother-in-law, handyman (Chris Cooper of "Lone Star"). Joe has trouble keeping food on the table and money in his pocket, so Maggie bails on them. "Great Expectations" makes women look like kennel club members, while the men emerge as good people who take care of one other. Finn spends his time cruising around in his outboard when he is not drawing pictures. Francesco Clemente received credit for those drawings, but he must have been channeling Walter Anderson. One day, the vicious convict Lustig (Robert De Nero of "Goodfellas") surprises Finn and forces him to help him escape. The escape plan goes sour for Lusting, but Finn gets away. Finn fares far less lucky during his next encounter. He meets an eccentric unmarried woman, Ms. Dinsmoor (Anne Bancroft of "The Graduate"). She is a dotty old dame abandoned at the altar by a worthless suitor. Languishing away in a magnificent mansion that has gradually gone to seed since her disastrous wedding day, Dinsmoor has left things the way they had been set up for the wedding ceremony. "Great Expectations" looks like a feminine version of "Heart of Darkness," but let us not trash a great guy like Joseph Conrad. Ms. Dinsmoor, it seems, wants a playmate for her snotty niece Estella, so she pages and pays for Finn. Poor Finn is immediately entranced by the cold, haughty Estella. Estella shocks Finn with a surprise kiss at a water fountain, and the filmmakers make that a recurring scene. When Finn reveals that he cannot dance for her, Ms. Dinsmoor allows him to draw. Reluctant initially to pose, Estella finds herself forced to sit for his portrait. Finn thinks she is beautiful but snobbish. Ms. Dinsmoor lectures Finn about the incompatibility of the sexes and the irony of love. Every time Finn meets Estella, she treats him indifferently, leaving him before anything can happen. She is the stuck-up, ice maiden of all time until the ending, but until then Finn recklessly pursues her. The unhappy day comes when Estella leaves Florida and travels to France for her education. Meanwhile, Finn sticks around Florida, works with Joe as a commercial fisherman and gives up painting. Suddenly, fortune befriends inn. Not only does he learn a benefactor has paid his airfare to New York City, but also that an art show is scheduled for his work. Quickly, Finn pulls together some new works and becomes an overnight sensation. Nevertheless, he still has problems with Estella. She takes up with a well-heeled architect, Walter Plane (Hank Azaria), and Finn's dreams appear to elude him againalmost, but you will have to suffer through the sorrow to see what happens. "Great Expectations" is a sensational looking picture. Emmanuel Lubezki's postcard photography is so gorgeous that at times it distracts you from the story. Everything in "Great Expectations" has a soft, ethereal texture. Tony Burroughs' cluttered looking production designs come the closest to recapturing the Victorian spirit of Charles Dickens. The Dinsmoor mansion is fantastic in its excessive, back-to-nature grunge. The story maybe as old as Dickens, but director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n makes it a richly palatable experience. He jump-starts the action occasionally. For example, during a dancing scene between the young Finn and Estella, Cuar&oacute;n dissolves to the grown-up Finn and Estella without altering the scenery. Cuar&oacute;n is especially adept with the appropriate light touch in treating the erotic scenes with flair and ingenuity. Paltrow strips for Hawke in one scene (remind you of "Titanic") so he can draw her in the nude. Meantime, the only nudity shown appears on paper. A later erotic encounter tastefully skirts the issue by letting your imagination do the rest. See, it's a chick flick. If you want a good cry, "Great Expectations" will live up to your anticipations. It's not a "Great" movie, but it is a "Good" one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and dramatic piece of drama!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not read the novel "Great expectations" (written by Charles Dickens). It is the novel this movie is based on, but I did not even know this book, so my review is quite objective because I cannot make any comparisons between the movie and the novel. What I can say is that this movie is a very good drama. I will not say it is a top movie because the pace is sometimes too slow, however the movie is amusing enough and the twists near and in the end of the movie are great. The cast is composed by actors like Ethan Hawke, Robert De Niro, Gwyneth Paltrow and Chris Cooper, who are very good actors delivering very good performances in this movie. In my opinion, although De Niro is objectively the best actor nowadays, Ethan Hawke delivers the best performance in this movie. Gwyneth is great and beautiful while Cooper does a very good job, as well. Robert De Niro has a short but very relevant role with a very good acting. Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (the director) should have paid more attention to the movie's pace, but he has done a more than decent job with this film. As said before, the pace is its worse point while its cast, performances and final twists are the best thing in the film. In conclusion, "Great expectations" is a very recommendable drama that nearly everyone should watch. It talks about coincidences, love and shattered dreams I think. 7,5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some incredible scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rebecca Ziggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some obvious problems with the film, particularly towards the end, but overall it was great. It's one of those films where certain scenes are nailed to perfection while others seem underdeveloped. There's a fantastic scene where Patrick Doyle's 'Kissing in the Rain' plays in the background, and Finn, oblivious to everyone around him, runs disoriented out of an exhibition, through the streets, and into a Chinese restaurant Estella is eating at with her fianc&eacute;e and their friends. The surrealism of the scene starts with the fact that he happens to know exactly which restaurant they are in. He walks in and asks Estella to dance. In the background her fianc&eacute;e is trying to remain composed, keeping a politely bemused look on his face as this stranger starts dancing with his fianc&eacute;e, and then starts to walk her out of the restaurant. Kudos to Ethan Hawke in this moment, who captures perfectly someone whose impulses have overridden any sense of propriety, who in that moment takes control of their relationship for the first time. Estella watches him as she leads him out of the restaurant, slightly in awe of the new Finn. I can't think of any other film that has illustrated the attraction between two people more skilfully. Such an underrated film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dickens..Would..Not..Be..Amused
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The two lead actors are wrong for this...so were behind the 8 ball before we pick up the cue. Ethan Hawke does not have the screen presence for this, and he is exposed badly. The Estelle character needed to be sexy and beautiful....Gwyneth Paltrow is neither. Hank Azaria is the only actor here who gives a good performance. The script is painfully predictable, and quite simply the idea of making this Charles Dickens Classic in modern day America ..does not work on any level. When Hawke is frantically painting Paltrow (with absurd pop music playing) it becomes so bad.....its funny. There are no memorable moments in this, and when De Niro turns up near the end, farce is in the air. A movie to avoid....if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well made with a great score, Bancroft and DeNiro, but the story and the leads don't quite convince
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was not expecting a completely faithful adaptation of Dickens' book, it was made clear that this was a loose adaptation and I was expecting that. On its own terms, it is definitely worth the viewing, but I was a little underwhelmed considering the talent involved. Great Expectations(1998) is certainly not a bad movie. It looks amazing, with gorgeous scenery and some of the best cinematography I've seen recently. The music is haunting and sweeping, complimenting the film wonderfully. The script has its frothy moments, but also moments of tension and wit. The supporting cast really help to carry the film, especially Anne Bancroft's haunting, deranged Mrs Dinsmoor and Robert DeNiro's caring criminal-type character in the name of Lustig. However, I wasn't as convinced by the leads. Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow look handsome certainly and their chemistry is okay, but overall I did find Hawke too sensitive and Paltrow too shallow. The story is loose as anticipated but also a rather clich&eacute;d poor-to-rich sort of story with some elements of draggy pacing and preachy tone. Alfonso Cuaron's direction was stylish certainly but forgets to give the film much substance and if anybody is looking for any of the basic underlying themes of the book you won't find much here sadly. All in all, stunning and stylish visually with a great score and supporting cast but the direction I had mixed feelings about, the story is rather clich&eacute;d and doesn't have enough substance to make me forgive that and the two leads are unconvincing, in my opinion. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost Substace in Film. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mobeans03
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember reading this novel in middle school, however as an 8th grader I was not equipped well enough to perceive this story as Dickens might have intended. Fast forward a few years and I gave myself another shot at digesting this once confusing piece of literature. That being said I thoroughly enjoyed the book and would recommend it to anyone. Not only is the story line so unique for its time, but the characters are all so vividly described (as expected) at times it felt as if you were there filled with suspense, agony and the occasional comic relief. Honestly this movie fell monumentally short of my expectations and trust me, mine were not as "great" as Pips. The casting was one of the major disappointments in this film, Ethan Hawke never gave Fin a chance to progress in the movie looks wise he seemed as poor and tentative as when he was a fisherman in spite of the new found success. When I saw the little girl who played Estella I was pleasantly surprised to know that she fit the description on the book. Gwyneth Paltrow on the other hand might have ruined it for me, she is just not pretty but I speculate that there actors were the happening thing in the late 90's I cant remember. The movie was rushed with rightful reason but it lost a great deal of story and depth. I gave this movie a 4 due to the fact that it was rushed beyond reason and ultimately costing the movie depth and story. Casting was a failure, and acting was sub par. I hope the upcoming remake in November 2012 will do the book more justice. Thanks for reading. AC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far Exceeded My Expectations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read Charles Dickens's novel on which 'Great Expectations' is based thus I cannot comment on its accuracy. However, I was very pleasantly surprised by Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n's which is an enchanting cinematic experience. It's visually mesmerizing thanks to the amazing sets and art direction and perhaps mostly to the stunning cinematography. Cuar&oacute;n certainly has an eye for visuals and in my opinion, this is one of the finest examples of first-rate cinematography. I was especially drawn by the long shots. Then there's the wonderful soundtrack which contributes beautifully to the lyrical flow and the surreal feel the film creates. The sound effects and lighting are on par. In addition, the dialogues are eloquently written. A lot is said with a few words and the few words that are spoken are poetry. The pacing is smooth. There is not a single boring moment. 'Great Expectations' reminds me that Ethan Hawk is one of the finest actors today and unlike many of his contemporaries, he manages to keep a low profile and let his work speak. His performance is transcendent, unaffected by the visuals. Chris Cooper is equally good good as Fin's guardian who loves him no matter what. Gwyneth Paltrow looks alluring (albeit a little too thin). Anne Bancroft is haunting. Robert de Niro is awesome. I didn't know that Cuaron was the director and I wasn't expecting much from a cinematic adaptation of a Dickens novel but I got far more than what I has expected. It's been a while since a film has so wholly engaged and involved me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Impressie1!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherrie Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always going to be a challenge to take a classic novel and turn it into be a movie that will satisfy everyone, especially when the story is being changed and adapted to fit a modern setting. If what you want to find from this movie is an exact translation of the book you will be unimpressed. I personally loved this movie, it is completely stylish thanks to a brilliant soundtrack and the gorgeous leads Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow (who is cast perfectly as the beautiful ice queen). They are helped along by a strong supporting cast of Anne Bancroft (wonderfully eccentric as Ms. Nora Dinsmoor), Chris Cooper and Robert DiNero. The problem, however, is that in trying to fit a story as long and complicated as 'Great expectations' into a 90 minute movie you loose a lot of the development of the characters necessary to identify and have an emotional reaction to them. Rather than linger on these issues Alfonso Cuaron concentrated on the visual aspect of the movie and the result is a movie that is great to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My rating: 6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vihren Mitev
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic story as a whole, again the main theme - love and not love at all, but first love from childhood. She is rich and cold from little, but beautiful, and he is sensitive, closed, poor, but very talented artist. Once kindled love between them, the fate separates them at a distance from each other for a long period of time. Ultimately, it appears that fate has the whims of one man and one woman, which I define as fantastic in the plot of the film, which catches the eye with some very good acting or directing. Even the appearance of Robert De Niro failed to make the film one of "those movies." My opinion on the subject is this - what is there in the end? Sensitive and vulnerable man hardens with age and learns to achieve its objectives, to live among the people and to be strong. Meanwhile, the cold woman softens by the years, began to think and rethink her life and her inadequate behavior and softens. And at some point of intersection of these two processes they come together to live together. Well, yes but I do not think so! Such a situation is worthy only in a movie and a movie from that class. As much as I am a romantic, I can not find a place for such behavior (especially the male role) in life. The rest - about the talent that if you develop it, it'll make way in your life and you will meet people to go with you in one direction, for that I agree. About that you have never to forget where you're going and the people who lived with you, also making always good no matter what you receive in return, yes I agree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Movie that Could've Been Great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing Great Expectations has going for it is the breathtaking, inventive, beautiful cinematography. The look of the picture is unreal and unfortunately, ends up being the film's fault. It's such a good looking picture, when it comes to analytical thought, it ends up being a looky film, not a thoughtful one. It almost sleepwalks through scenes that were written with potential to scratch deep into character's minds, but decides not to take the extra mile. Great Expectations doesn't deliver the inside of the movie, just the outside. I enjoy the update of this old tale, the film's story is an interesting one. It intrigues the audience because we can all relate to wanting something that is "better" than us; we love the things that are unattainable. It tries to takes some profound stances on topics, but doesn't succeed, because the director, Alfonso Cuaron, and the actors have a problem communicating information of the character's thoughts to the audience. Everything we should get becomes obscure. Ethan Hawke doesn't row down the riverbank, nor does he sink, he just floats, not affecting any of the actors, not the director, he's just there to look nice and move the adaptation from scene to scene. Gwyneth Paltrow embodies the aspects of a first love nicely. Robert DeNiro has some great short scenes in the film, but the ultimate twist in the end ruins his character for me. I thought the twist was excessive and unnecessary. It cheapened the story and the solid ground the film built upon. Great Expectations sets out with great intentions, seeking to lecture the audience about kindness, love, and that in success comes tragedy, but the film is like looking through the glass windows of your favorite shopping store in the mall with an empty wallet. It's stunning to look at, but fails to psychologically tell the story. Great Expectations celebrates art as well, I wish Cuaron would've dug deeper into the thoughts, motivations, and intentions of the characters because the audience is left empty. A good movie that could've been great. Rating: 6/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it appropriates an immortal literary classic, Hollywood has no qualms about rewriting the original story. "A Little Princess" director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n and "Scrooged" scenarist Mitch Glazer maintain that venerable Tinsel Town tradition with the latest cinematic adaptation of "Great Expectations," a boy-meets-girl and boy-loses-girl tearjerker. Ethan Hawke, Gwyneth Paltrow, Robert De Niro, and Anne Bancroft topline this entertaining but offbeat social drama. Tony Burrough's elegant production designs, "Reality Bites" lenser Emmanuel Lubezki's lush cinematography, and Cuaron's own poetic vision bolster "Great Expectations" far above Glazer's loquacious as well as predictable screenplay. "Great Expectations" qualifies easily as either a chick flick or a date flick, unless you're going to compare it with the six previous versions produced either for the silver screen or the boob tube. Unless you have scanned the Cliff Notes for "Great Expectations" recently, you may find yourself swamped by this free-spirited adaptation. Hollywood has changed some things. Glazer uproots the plot from its original Victorian English setting and transplants it to contemporary Florida. Charles Dickens named his protagonist Pip, but Glazer gives him the name Finn. Undoubtedly, literary types are struggling to figure out what a Mark Twain nickname and an Ernst Hemingway setting can have in common with a Dickens tale. Me, too. My B.A. was in English Literature and I've never seen Dickens like this. Not only does Glazer rechristen his lead character, but also he rechristens Miss Havisham as Ms. Dinsmoor. The criminal Magwitch is now Arthur Lustig, a death-row inmate who killed a mob boss. Estella is still Estella. Of course, Cuar&oacute;n has altered several other things, too, but that will give you literature professors something to bitch about in class. Condensing a Dickens' epic in less than two hours in a film with names that you can pronounce might have something to do with this nonsense. Briefly, Finnegan Bell (Ethan Hawke of "Dead Poets Society") takes life easy in sunny coastal Florida, just the kind of lifestyle Huckleberry Finn would yearn for in his wildest dreams. Orphaned, Finn resides with Maggie, his weirdo sister (Kim Dickens of "Brazil"), and Joe, his lower class, brother-in-law, handyman (Chris Cooper of "Lone Star"). Joe has trouble keeping food on the table and money in his pocket, so Maggie bails on them. "Great Expectations" makes women look like kennel club members, while the men emerge as good people who take care of one other. Finn spends his time cruising around in his outboard when he is not drawing pictures. Francesco Clemente received credit for those drawings, but he must have been channeling Walter Anderson. One day, the vicious convict Lustig (Robert De Nero of "Goodfellas") surprises Finn and forces him to help him escape. The escape plan goes sour for Lusting, but Finn gets away. Finn fares far less lucky during his next encounter. He meets an eccentric unmarried woman, Ms. Dinsmoor (Anne Bancroft of "The Graduate"). She is a dotty old dame abandoned at the altar by a worthless suitor. Languishing away in a magnificent mansion that has gradually gone to seed since her disastrous wedding day, Dinsmoor has left things the way they had been set up for the wedding ceremony. "Great Expectations" looks like a feminine version of "Heart of Darkness," but let us not trash a great guy like Joseph Conrad. Ms. Dinsmoor, it seems, wants a playmate for her snotty niece Estella, so she pages and pays for Finn. Poor Finn is immediately entranced by the cold, haughty Estella. Estella shocks Finn with a surprise kiss at a water fountain, and the filmmakers make that a recurring scene. When Finn reveals that he cannot dance for her, Ms. Dinsmoor allows him to draw. Reluctant initially to pose, Estella finds herself forced to sit for his portrait. Finn thinks she is beautiful but snobbish. Ms. Dinsmoor lectures Finn about the incompatibility of the sexes and the irony of love. Every time Finn meets Estella, she treats him indifferently, leaving him before anything can happen. She is the stuck-up, ice maiden of all time until the ending, but until then Finn recklessly pursues her. The unhappy day comes when Estella leaves Florida and travels to France for her education. Meanwhile, Finn sticks around Florida, works with Joe as a commercial fisherman and gives up painting. Suddenly, fortune befriends inn. Not only does he learn a benefactor has paid his airfare to New York City, but also that an art show is scheduled for his work. Quickly, Finn pulls together some new works and becomes an overnight sensation. Nevertheless, he still has problems with Estella. She takes up with a well-heeled architect, Walter Plane (Hank Azaria), and Finn's dreams appear to elude him againalmost, but you will have to suffer through the sorrow to see what happens. "Great Expectations" is a sensational looking picture. Emmanuel Lubezki's postcard photography is so gorgeous that at times it distracts you from the story. Everything in "Great Expectations" has a soft, ethereal texture. Tony Burroughs' cluttered looking production designs come the closest to recapturing the Victorian spirit of Charles Dickens. The Dinsmoor mansion is fantastic in its excessive, back-to-nature grunge. The story maybe as old as Dickens, but director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n makes it a richly palatable experience. He jump-starts the action occasionally. For example, during a dancing scene between the young Finn and Estella, Cuar&oacute;n dissolves to the grown-up Finn and Estella without altering the scenery. Cuar&oacute;n is especially adept with the appropriate light touch in treating the erotic scenes with flair and ingenuity. Paltrow strips for Hawke in one scene (remind you of "Titanic") so he can draw her in the nude. Meantime, the only nudity shown appears on paper. A later erotic encounter tastefully skirts the issue by letting your imagination do the rest. See, it's a chick flick. If you want a good cry, "Great Expectations" will live up to your anticipations. It's not a "Great" movie, but it is a "Good" one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and dramatic piece of drama!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not read the novel "Great expectations" (written by Charles Dickens). It is the novel this movie is based on, but I did not even know this book, so my review is quite objective because I cannot make any comparisons between the movie and the novel. What I can say is that this movie is a very good drama. I will not say it is a top movie because the pace is sometimes too slow, however the movie is amusing enough and the twists near and in the end of the movie are great. The cast is composed by actors like Ethan Hawke, Robert De Niro, Gwyneth Paltrow and Chris Cooper, who are very good actors delivering very good performances in this movie. In my opinion, although De Niro is objectively the best actor nowadays, Ethan Hawke delivers the best performance in this movie. Gwyneth is great and beautiful while Cooper does a very good job, as well. Robert De Niro has a short but very relevant role with a very good acting. Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (the director) should have paid more attention to the movie's pace, but he has done a more than decent job with this film. As said before, the pace is its worse point while its cast, performances and final twists are the best thing in the film. In conclusion, "Great expectations" is a very recommendable drama that nearly everyone should watch. It talks about coincidences, love and shattered dreams I think. 7,5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some incredible scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rebecca Ziggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some obvious problems with the film, particularly towards the end, but overall it was great. It's one of those films where certain scenes are nailed to perfection while others seem underdeveloped. There's a fantastic scene where Patrick Doyle's 'Kissing in the Rain' plays in the background, and Finn, oblivious to everyone around him, runs disoriented out of an exhibition, through the streets, and into a Chinese restaurant Estella is eating at with her fianc&eacute;e and their friends. The surrealism of the scene starts with the fact that he happens to know exactly which restaurant they are in. He walks in and asks Estella to dance. In the background her fianc&eacute;e is trying to remain composed, keeping a politely bemused look on his face as this stranger starts dancing with his fianc&eacute;e, and then starts to walk her out of the restaurant. Kudos to Ethan Hawke in this moment, who captures perfectly someone whose impulses have overridden any sense of propriety, who in that moment takes control of their relationship for the first time. Estella watches him as she leads him out of the restaurant, slightly in awe of the new Finn. I can't think of any other film that has illustrated the attraction between two people more skilfully. Such an underrated film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dickens..Would..Not..Be..Amused
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The two lead actors are wrong for this...so were behind the 8 ball before we pick up the cue. Ethan Hawke does not have the screen presence for this, and he is exposed badly. The Estelle character needed to be sexy and beautiful....Gwyneth Paltrow is neither. Hank Azaria is the only actor here who gives a good performance. The script is painfully predictable, and quite simply the idea of making this Charles Dickens Classic in modern day America ..does not work on any level. When Hawke is frantically painting Paltrow (with absurd pop music playing) it becomes so bad.....its funny. There are no memorable moments in this, and when De Niro turns up near the end, farce is in the air. A movie to avoid....if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well made with a great score, Bancroft and DeNiro, but the story and the leads don't quite convince
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was not expecting a completely faithful adaptation of Dickens' book, it was made clear that this was a loose adaptation and I was expecting that. On its own terms, it is definitely worth the viewing, but I was a little underwhelmed considering the talent involved. Great Expectations(1998) is certainly not a bad movie. It looks amazing, with gorgeous scenery and some of the best cinematography I've seen recently. The music is haunting and sweeping, complimenting the film wonderfully. The script has its frothy moments, but also moments of tension and wit. The supporting cast really help to carry the film, especially Anne Bancroft's haunting, deranged Mrs Dinsmoor and Robert DeNiro's caring criminal-type character in the name of Lustig. However, I wasn't as convinced by the leads. Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow look handsome certainly and their chemistry is okay, but overall I did find Hawke too sensitive and Paltrow too shallow. The story is loose as anticipated but also a rather clich&eacute;d poor-to-rich sort of story with some elements of draggy pacing and preachy tone. Alfonso Cuaron's direction was stylish certainly but forgets to give the film much substance and if anybody is looking for any of the basic underlying themes of the book you won't find much here sadly. All in all, stunning and stylish visually with a great score and supporting cast but the direction I had mixed feelings about, the story is rather clich&eacute;d and doesn't have enough substance to make me forgive that and the two leads are unconvincing, in my opinion. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost Substace in Film. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mobeans03
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember reading this novel in middle school, however as an 8th grader I was not equipped well enough to perceive this story as Dickens might have intended. Fast forward a few years and I gave myself another shot at digesting this once confusing piece of literature. That being said I thoroughly enjoyed the book and would recommend it to anyone. Not only is the story line so unique for its time, but the characters are all so vividly described (as expected) at times it felt as if you were there filled with suspense, agony and the occasional comic relief. Honestly this movie fell monumentally short of my expectations and trust me, mine were not as "great" as Pips. The casting was one of the major disappointments in this film, Ethan Hawke never gave Fin a chance to progress in the movie looks wise he seemed as poor and tentative as when he was a fisherman in spite of the new found success. When I saw the little girl who played Estella I was pleasantly surprised to know that she fit the description on the book. Gwyneth Paltrow on the other hand might have ruined it for me, she is just not pretty but I speculate that there actors were the happening thing in the late 90's I cant remember. The movie was rushed with rightful reason but it lost a great deal of story and depth. I gave this movie a 4 due to the fact that it was rushed beyond reason and ultimately costing the movie depth and story. Casting was a failure, and acting was sub par. I hope the upcoming remake in November 2012 will do the book more justice. Thanks for reading. AC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far Exceeded My Expectations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read Charles Dickens's novel on which 'Great Expectations' is based thus I cannot comment on its accuracy. However, I was very pleasantly surprised by Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n's which is an enchanting cinematic experience. It's visually mesmerizing thanks to the amazing sets and art direction and perhaps mostly to the stunning cinematography. Cuar&oacute;n certainly has an eye for visuals and in my opinion, this is one of the finest examples of first-rate cinematography. I was especially drawn by the long shots. Then there's the wonderful soundtrack which contributes beautifully to the lyrical flow and the surreal feel the film creates. The sound effects and lighting are on par. In addition, the dialogues are eloquently written. A lot is said with a few words and the few words that are spoken are poetry. The pacing is smooth. There is not a single boring moment. 'Great Expectations' reminds me that Ethan Hawk is one of the finest actors today and unlike many of his contemporaries, he manages to keep a low profile and let his work speak. His performance is transcendent, unaffected by the visuals. Chris Cooper is equally good good as Fin's guardian who loves him no matter what. Gwyneth Paltrow looks alluring (albeit a little too thin). Anne Bancroft is haunting. Robert de Niro is awesome. I didn't know that Cuaron was the director and I wasn't expecting much from a cinematic adaptation of a Dickens novel but I got far more than what I has expected. It's been a while since a film has so wholly engaged and involved me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Impressie1!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherrie Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always going to be a challenge to take a classic novel and turn it into be a movie that will satisfy everyone, especially when the story is being changed and adapted to fit a modern setting. If what you want to find from this movie is an exact translation of the book you will be unimpressed. I personally loved this movie, it is completely stylish thanks to a brilliant soundtrack and the gorgeous leads Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow (who is cast perfectly as the beautiful ice queen). They are helped along by a strong supporting cast of Anne Bancroft (wonderfully eccentric as Ms. Nora Dinsmoor), Chris Cooper and Robert DiNero. The problem, however, is that in trying to fit a story as long and complicated as 'Great expectations' into a 90 minute movie you loose a lot of the development of the characters necessary to identify and have an emotional reaction to them. Rather than linger on these issues Alfonso Cuaron concentrated on the visual aspect of the movie and the result is a movie that is great to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My rating: 6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vihren Mitev
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic story as a whole, again the main theme - love and not love at all, but first love from childhood. She is rich and cold from little, but beautiful, and he is sensitive, closed, poor, but very talented artist. Once kindled love between them, the fate separates them at a distance from each other for a long period of time. Ultimately, it appears that fate has the whims of one man and one woman, which I define as fantastic in the plot of the film, which catches the eye with some very good acting or directing. Even the appearance of Robert De Niro failed to make the film one of "those movies." My opinion on the subject is this - what is there in the end? Sensitive and vulnerable man hardens with age and learns to achieve its objectives, to live among the people and to be strong. Meanwhile, the cold woman softens by the years, began to think and rethink her life and her inadequate behavior and softens. And at some point of intersection of these two processes they come together to live together. Well, yes but I do not think so! Such a situation is worthy only in a movie and a movie from that class. As much as I am a romantic, I can not find a place for such behavior (especially the male role) in life. The rest - about the talent that if you develop it, it'll make way in your life and you will meet people to go with you in one direction, for that I agree. About that you have never to forget where you're going and the people who lived with you, also making always good no matter what you receive in return, yes I agree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Good Movie that Could've Been Great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing Great Expectations has going for it is the breathtaking, inventive, beautiful cinematography. The look of the picture is unreal and unfortunately, ends up being the film's fault. It's such a good looking picture, when it comes to analytical thought, it ends up being a looky film, not a thoughtful one. It almost sleepwalks through scenes that were written with potential to scratch deep into character's minds, but decides not to take the extra mile. Great Expectations doesn't deliver the inside of the movie, just the outside. I enjoy the update of this old tale, the film's story is an interesting one. It intrigues the audience because we can all relate to wanting something that is "better" than us; we love the things that are unattainable. It tries to takes some profound stances on topics, but doesn't succeed, because the director, Alfonso Cuaron, and the actors have a problem communicating information of the character's thoughts to the audience. Everything we should get becomes obscure. Ethan Hawke doesn't row down the riverbank, nor does he sink, he just floats, not affecting any of the actors, not the director, he's just there to look nice and move the adaptation from scene to scene. Gwyneth Paltrow embodies the aspects of a first love nicely. Robert DeNiro has some great short scenes in the film, but the ultimate twist in the end ruins his character for me. I thought the twist was excessive and unnecessary. It cheapened the story and the solid ground the film built upon. Great Expectations sets out with great intentions, seeking to lecture the audience about kindness, love, and that in success comes tragedy, but the film is like looking through the glass windows of your favorite shopping store in the mall with an empty wallet. It's stunning to look at, but fails to psychologically tell the story. Great Expectations celebrates art as well, I wish Cuaron would've dug deeper into the thoughts, motivations, and intentions of the characters because the audience is left empty. A good movie that could've been great. Rating: 6/10 Grade: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good But Not Great
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zardoz-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When it appropriates an immortal literary classic, Hollywood has no qualms about rewriting the original story. "A Little Princess" director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n and "Scrooged" scenarist Mitch Glazer maintain that venerable Tinsel Town tradition with the latest cinematic adaptation of "Great Expectations," a boy-meets-girl and boy-loses-girl tearjerker. Ethan Hawke, Gwyneth Paltrow, Robert De Niro, and Anne Bancroft topline this entertaining but offbeat social drama. Tony Burrough's elegant production designs, "Reality Bites" lenser Emmanuel Lubezki's lush cinematography, and Cuaron's own poetic vision bolster "Great Expectations" far above Glazer's loquacious as well as predictable screenplay. "Great Expectations" qualifies easily as either a chick flick or a date flick, unless you're going to compare it with the six previous versions produced either for the silver screen or the boob tube. Unless you have scanned the Cliff Notes for "Great Expectations" recently, you may find yourself swamped by this free-spirited adaptation. Hollywood has changed some things. Glazer uproots the plot from its original Victorian English setting and transplants it to contemporary Florida. Charles Dickens named his protagonist Pip, but Glazer gives him the name Finn. Undoubtedly, literary types are struggling to figure out what a Mark Twain nickname and an Ernst Hemingway setting can have in common with a Dickens tale. Me, too. My B.A. was in English Literature and I've never seen Dickens like this. Not only does Glazer rechristen his lead character, but also he rechristens Miss Havisham as Ms. Dinsmoor. The criminal Magwitch is now Arthur Lustig, a death-row inmate who killed a mob boss. Estella is still Estella. Of course, Cuar&oacute;n has altered several other things, too, but that will give you literature professors something to bitch about in class. Condensing a Dickens' epic in less than two hours in a film with names that you can pronounce might have something to do with this nonsense. Briefly, Finnegan Bell (Ethan Hawke of "Dead Poets Society") takes life easy in sunny coastal Florida, just the kind of lifestyle Huckleberry Finn would yearn for in his wildest dreams. Orphaned, Finn resides with Maggie, his weirdo sister (Kim Dickens of "Brazil"), and Joe, his lower class, brother-in-law, handyman (Chris Cooper of "Lone Star"). Joe has trouble keeping food on the table and money in his pocket, so Maggie bails on them. "Great Expectations" makes women look like kennel club members, while the men emerge as good people who take care of one other. Finn spends his time cruising around in his outboard when he is not drawing pictures. Francesco Clemente received credit for those drawings, but he must have been channeling Walter Anderson. One day, the vicious convict Lustig (Robert De Nero of "Goodfellas") surprises Finn and forces him to help him escape. The escape plan goes sour for Lusting, but Finn gets away. Finn fares far less lucky during his next encounter. He meets an eccentric unmarried woman, Ms. Dinsmoor (Anne Bancroft of "The Graduate"). She is a dotty old dame abandoned at the altar by a worthless suitor. Languishing away in a magnificent mansion that has gradually gone to seed since her disastrous wedding day, Dinsmoor has left things the way they had been set up for the wedding ceremony. "Great Expectations" looks like a feminine version of "Heart of Darkness," but let us not trash a great guy like Joseph Conrad. Ms. Dinsmoor, it seems, wants a playmate for her snotty niece Estella, so she pages and pays for Finn. Poor Finn is immediately entranced by the cold, haughty Estella. Estella shocks Finn with a surprise kiss at a water fountain, and the filmmakers make that a recurring scene. When Finn reveals that he cannot dance for her, Ms. Dinsmoor allows him to draw. Reluctant initially to pose, Estella finds herself forced to sit for his portrait. Finn thinks she is beautiful but snobbish. Ms. Dinsmoor lectures Finn about the incompatibility of the sexes and the irony of love. Every time Finn meets Estella, she treats him indifferently, leaving him before anything can happen. She is the stuck-up, ice maiden of all time until the ending, but until then Finn recklessly pursues her. The unhappy day comes when Estella leaves Florida and travels to France for her education. Meanwhile, Finn sticks around Florida, works with Joe as a commercial fisherman and gives up painting. Suddenly, fortune befriends inn. Not only does he learn a benefactor has paid his airfare to New York City, but also that an art show is scheduled for his work. Quickly, Finn pulls together some new works and becomes an overnight sensation. Nevertheless, he still has problems with Estella. She takes up with a well-heeled architect, Walter Plane (Hank Azaria), and Finn's dreams appear to elude him againalmost, but you will have to suffer through the sorrow to see what happens. "Great Expectations" is a sensational looking picture. Emmanuel Lubezki's postcard photography is so gorgeous that at times it distracts you from the story. Everything in "Great Expectations" has a soft, ethereal texture. Tony Burroughs' cluttered looking production designs come the closest to recapturing the Victorian spirit of Charles Dickens. The Dinsmoor mansion is fantastic in its excessive, back-to-nature grunge. The story maybe as old as Dickens, but director Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n makes it a richly palatable experience. He jump-starts the action occasionally. For example, during a dancing scene between the young Finn and Estella, Cuar&oacute;n dissolves to the grown-up Finn and Estella without altering the scenery. Cuar&oacute;n is especially adept with the appropriate light touch in treating the erotic scenes with flair and ingenuity. Paltrow strips for Hawke in one scene (remind you of "Titanic") so he can draw her in the nude. Meantime, the only nudity shown appears on paper. A later erotic encounter tastefully skirts the issue by letting your imagination do the rest. See, it's a chick flick. If you want a good cry, "Great Expectations" will live up to your anticipations. It's not a "Great" movie, but it is a "Good" one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing and dramatic piece of drama!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manusanchez90
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have not read the novel "Great expectations" (written by Charles Dickens). It is the novel this movie is based on, but I did not even know this book, so my review is quite objective because I cannot make any comparisons between the movie and the novel. What I can say is that this movie is a very good drama. I will not say it is a top movie because the pace is sometimes too slow, however the movie is amusing enough and the twists near and in the end of the movie are great. The cast is composed by actors like Ethan Hawke, Robert De Niro, Gwyneth Paltrow and Chris Cooper, who are very good actors delivering very good performances in this movie. In my opinion, although De Niro is objectively the best actor nowadays, Ethan Hawke delivers the best performance in this movie. Gwyneth is great and beautiful while Cooper does a very good job, as well. Robert De Niro has a short but very relevant role with a very good acting. Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n (the director) should have paid more attention to the movie's pace, but he has done a more than decent job with this film. As said before, the pace is its worse point while its cast, performances and final twists are the best thing in the film. In conclusion, "Great expectations" is a very recommendable drama that nearly everyone should watch. It talks about coincidences, love and shattered dreams I think. 7,5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some incredible scenes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rebecca Ziggs
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are some obvious problems with the film, particularly towards the end, but overall it was great. It's one of those films where certain scenes are nailed to perfection while others seem underdeveloped. There's a fantastic scene where Patrick Doyle's 'Kissing in the Rain' plays in the background, and Finn, oblivious to everyone around him, runs disoriented out of an exhibition, through the streets, and into a Chinese restaurant Estella is eating at with her fianc&eacute;e and their friends. The surrealism of the scene starts with the fact that he happens to know exactly which restaurant they are in. He walks in and asks Estella to dance. In the background her fianc&eacute;e is trying to remain composed, keeping a politely bemused look on his face as this stranger starts dancing with his fianc&eacute;e, and then starts to walk her out of the restaurant. Kudos to Ethan Hawke in this moment, who captures perfectly someone whose impulses have overridden any sense of propriety, who in that moment takes control of their relationship for the first time. Estella watches him as she leads him out of the restaurant, slightly in awe of the new Finn. I can't think of any other film that has illustrated the attraction between two people more skilfully. Such an underrated film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dickens..Would..Not..Be..Amused
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The two lead actors are wrong for this...so were behind the 8 ball before we pick up the cue. Ethan Hawke does not have the screen presence for this, and he is exposed badly. The Estelle character needed to be sexy and beautiful....Gwyneth Paltrow is neither. Hank Azaria is the only actor here who gives a good performance. The script is painfully predictable, and quite simply the idea of making this Charles Dickens Classic in modern day America ..does not work on any level. When Hawke is frantically painting Paltrow (with absurd pop music playing) it becomes so bad.....its funny. There are no memorable moments in this, and when De Niro turns up near the end, farce is in the air. A movie to avoid....if you can.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well made with a great score, Bancroft and DeNiro, but the story and the leads don't quite convince
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was not expecting a completely faithful adaptation of Dickens' book, it was made clear that this was a loose adaptation and I was expecting that. On its own terms, it is definitely worth the viewing, but I was a little underwhelmed considering the talent involved. Great Expectations(1998) is certainly not a bad movie. It looks amazing, with gorgeous scenery and some of the best cinematography I've seen recently. The music is haunting and sweeping, complimenting the film wonderfully. The script has its frothy moments, but also moments of tension and wit. The supporting cast really help to carry the film, especially Anne Bancroft's haunting, deranged Mrs Dinsmoor and Robert DeNiro's caring criminal-type character in the name of Lustig. However, I wasn't as convinced by the leads. Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow look handsome certainly and their chemistry is okay, but overall I did find Hawke too sensitive and Paltrow too shallow. The story is loose as anticipated but also a rather clich&eacute;d poor-to-rich sort of story with some elements of draggy pacing and preachy tone. Alfonso Cuaron's direction was stylish certainly but forgets to give the film much substance and if anybody is looking for any of the basic underlying themes of the book you won't find much here sadly. All in all, stunning and stylish visually with a great score and supporting cast but the direction I had mixed feelings about, the story is rather clich&eacute;d and doesn't have enough substance to make me forgive that and the two leads are unconvincing, in my opinion. 6/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lost Substace in Film. . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mobeans03
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember reading this novel in middle school, however as an 8th grader I was not equipped well enough to perceive this story as Dickens might have intended. Fast forward a few years and I gave myself another shot at digesting this once confusing piece of literature. That being said I thoroughly enjoyed the book and would recommend it to anyone. Not only is the story line so unique for its time, but the characters are all so vividly described (as expected) at times it felt as if you were there filled with suspense, agony and the occasional comic relief. Honestly this movie fell monumentally short of my expectations and trust me, mine were not as "great" as Pips. The casting was one of the major disappointments in this film, Ethan Hawke never gave Fin a chance to progress in the movie looks wise he seemed as poor and tentative as when he was a fisherman in spite of the new found success. When I saw the little girl who played Estella I was pleasantly surprised to know that she fit the description on the book. Gwyneth Paltrow on the other hand might have ruined it for me, she is just not pretty but I speculate that there actors were the happening thing in the late 90's I cant remember. The movie was rushed with rightful reason but it lost a great deal of story and depth. I gave this movie a 4 due to the fact that it was rushed beyond reason and ultimately costing the movie depth and story. Casting was a failure, and acting was sub par. I hope the upcoming remake in November 2012 will do the book more justice. Thanks for reading. AC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Far Exceeded My Expectations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chrysanthepop
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't read Charles Dickens's novel on which 'Great Expectations' is based thus I cannot comment on its accuracy. However, I was very pleasantly surprised by Alfonso Cuar&oacute;n's which is an enchanting cinematic experience. It's visually mesmerizing thanks to the amazing sets and art direction and perhaps mostly to the stunning cinematography. Cuar&oacute;n certainly has an eye for visuals and in my opinion, this is one of the finest examples of first-rate cinematography. I was especially drawn by the long shots. Then there's the wonderful soundtrack which contributes beautifully to the lyrical flow and the surreal feel the film creates. The sound effects and lighting are on par. In addition, the dialogues are eloquently written. A lot is said with a few words and the few words that are spoken are poetry. The pacing is smooth. There is not a single boring moment. 'Great Expectations' reminds me that Ethan Hawk is one of the finest actors today and unlike many of his contemporaries, he manages to keep a low profile and let his work speak. His performance is transcendent, unaffected by the visuals. Chris Cooper is equally good good as Fin's guardian who loves him no matter what. Gwyneth Paltrow looks alluring (albeit a little too thin). Anne Bancroft is haunting. Robert de Niro is awesome. I didn't know that Cuaron was the director and I wasn't expecting much from a cinematic adaptation of a Dickens novel but I got far more than what I has expected. It's been a while since a film has so wholly engaged and involved me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Impressie1!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherrie Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always going to be a challenge to take a classic novel and turn it into be a movie that will satisfy everyone, especially when the story is being changed and adapted to fit a modern setting. If what you want to find from this movie is an exact translation of the book you will be unimpressed. I personally loved this movie, it is completely stylish thanks to a brilliant soundtrack and the gorgeous leads Ethan Hawke and Gwyneth Paltrow (who is cast perfectly as the beautiful ice queen). They are helped along by a strong supporting cast of Anne Bancroft (wonderfully eccentric as Ms. Nora Dinsmoor), Chris Cooper and Robert DiNero. The problem, however, is that in trying to fit a story as long and complicated as 'Great expectations' into a 90 minute movie you loose a lot of the development of the characters necessary to identify and have an emotional reaction to them. Rather than linger on these issues Alfonso Cuaron concentrated on the visual aspect of the movie and the result is a movie that is great to watch!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
