<filme>
 <id>
  914
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120890
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1998
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Garotas Selvagens
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A police detective uncovers a conspiracy behind a case involving a high school guidance counselor, when accusations of rape are made against him by two female students.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In south Florida, a high school counselor is accused of rape by a manipulative rich girl and her trailer trash classmate. The cop on the case begins to suspect a conspiracy and dives into an elaborate and devious web of greed and betrayal to find the truth.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   high school
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   florida
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   south florida
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   greed
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John McNaughton
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Stephen Peters
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kevin Bacon
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Matt Dillon
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Neve Campbell
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing, Humorous & Outrageously Twisted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This highly entertaining sleaze-fest features gratuitous nudity, bi-sexuality and a m&eacute;nage-a-trois which all seem to have been included purely to spice things up. It's also, however, a glossy thriller with an extremely well written plot that's intriguing, humorous and outrageously twisted. Remarkably, by the time all the explanatory flashbacks (which are included with the closing credits) have finished, it's also evident that the whole thing makes sense. Greed, betrayal and murder are the story's main ingredients but the sheer wickedness of its characters and the movie's satirical qualities also combine well to ensure that "Wild Things" compares favourably to most other crime-related mysteries that may be on offer. Kelly Van Ryan (Denise Richards) is a spoilt, 17-year-old rich girl who lives in Blue Bay, Florida. She's used to getting everything she wants but when she sets her sights on her High School guidance counsellor, Sam Lombardo (Matt Dillon), things don't fall into place as easily as she expects and she accuses him of rape. Local police detectives Ray Duquette (Kevin Bacon) and Gloria Perez (Daphne Rubin-Vega) are charged with the responsibility of investigating the alleged crime and Perez is certainly not convinced that there is any substance in Kelly's accusation. When another girl, Suzie Toller (Neve Campbell) also comes forward and makes a similar accusation, Sam Lombardo is arrested and hires lawyer Kenneth Bowden (Bill Murray) to defend him. Kelly's mother Sandra (Theresa Russell) is very wealthy and powerful and also one of Sam's ex-lovers. She's delighted to use the situation to try to ruin Sam but after the case against him collapses in bizarre circumstances and Lombardo is awarded a multi-million dollar settlement for defamation of character, Sandra Van Ryan is left furious and humiliated and looking for revenge. The course that the story takes from this point on is full of twists and double-crosses that keep on coming until the movie eventually ends with the most surprising development of them all. The characters in "Wild Things" include the very rich and the very poor as well as people who are employed in the legal profession, education and law enforcement. What they all have in common is that they're all morally bankrupt and most of them are criminals. The way in which they're represented on-screen is brilliant as the acting is pitched at just the right amount over-the-top to exploit the absurdity and humour of so many of the situations without allowing the impact of the more scandalous and wicked goings-on to be diminished in any way. In this respect, the entire cast is top-notch but Bill Murray does particularly well as a shyster lawyer who enjoys a good insurance scam but is also smarter than he first appears to be. "Wild Things" is beautifully filmed and some passages of the score wouldn't have seemed out of place in "Twin Peaks". It's tremendous fun to watch and very rewarding because it delivers so much more that it initially seems to promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sex is the only real reason to watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS "Wild things" is a trash entertainment , but an enjoyable entertainment . It isn't great on any kind of level . Still , it provides a quite decent entertainment for nearly 2 hours. It's better than most of the movies in its genre - erotic thriller (not that the genre has about 2 really good movies in it , while the rest is basically a straight-to-video/DVD crap. The best thing about "Wild things" is sex. We have three hot ladies here  Denise Richards , Neve Campbell and Theresa Russell . Not that the men are ugly , hell no , after all we have here Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon. I can assure you that at some point in the movie you will see everyone of them in some state of undress. "WD" also has some great sex scenes  the lesbian scene at the pool and great threesome between two ladies and one man . The threesome is one of my favorite and most arousing movie scenes EVER. The screenplay by Stephen Peters isn't exactly a brilliant one . It feels like a story from one of those pulp magazines that inspired Quentin Tarantino to make "Pulp fiction". I was able to figure out most of the twists and connections between characters before the movie presented them to the audience . Yet there was some inspired stuff here  the teeth , the lovely "behind the scenes" ending credits and Bill Murray's part in the story (!). John McNaughton directs the sex scenes very nicely . Atmospheric score by George S. Clinton certainly helps him. On the other hand he tries to hide the surprises from the audience in a too obvious way  for example if you didn't saw Dillon raping Richards or the fight between Bacon and Richards it means that the truth is completely different than what movie is trying to suggest you. Denise Richards is watchable here . Her body does most of the acting . Neve Campbell is really solid as the naughty girl , same as Kevin Bacon as FBI agent. Matt Dillon isn't bad , but the way he acts makes it obvious for the audience that he isn't exactly a good guy as the movie tries to present him . Theresa Russell is quite good as the rich and powerful Sandra Van Ryan. I was surprised by Bill Murray who gives a very funny performance as the tricky lawyer. It's obviously the best movie of the franchise . Not really a quality movie , but if you will low your expectations you probably will have fun with this popcorn thriller. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Thing, You Make My Heart Sing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The Squeerelist
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thriller has been one of my favorite movies as long as I can remember. As a kid, this was my go-to flick on any given Sunday. I know this is not a film for children, but what can I say... I was already unusual. A high school guidance counselor (Matt Dillon) is accused of rape by 2 of his students (Denise Richards & Neve Campbell)... The twisted storyline is set in the dreamy Floridian surroundings. For those who haven't been to Florida, it makes you want to discover this bit of paradise. For those who have, it just really makes you miss it. The lascivious original score smells like the Everglades and releases an intriguing scent wherever it infiltrates. Wild Things takes you out on a yacht, or makes you visit the gators (this film seriously makes me think of a typical Florida tourism brochure). The end will blow you away for sure. The cast is eclectic and brilliant (Kevin Bacon is an incredible dirty cop and the 2 main female leads are gorgeous and dangerously manipulative). The sex scenes are audacious and necessary to the plot. The film mixes humor (you can't escape it with Bill Murray in the cast) and seriousness which makes it a perfect combo. Wild Things is a great thriller, a sexy 90s classic! 1 reason to watch: the scene with Denise washing Matt's car to Lauren Christy's song I Want What I Want Read it here: http://squeerelist.blogspot.com/2013/06/wild-things- 1998.html
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things- Wild is the Wind? ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The classic tale of wealth, greed, conspiracy, mistrust and the eventual downfall of so many people all mark this 1998 thriller film. The problem with the movie is that there are too many plot twists here. Yes, they're very interesting, but after a while, it becomes who is doing what to whom. Honesty and integrity have all but fallen through the cracks here. Never underestimate the one most deviant. She or he may very well have a brain after-all. Robert Wagner is completely wasted here in a bit part of the rich girl's step-father. He is about the only one really not involved with what is going on here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twist-a-minute thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember when WILD THINGS came out on first release; for some reason, it never appealed to me. Back then I only cared about horror films like SCREAM, and this sleazy-looking thriller didn't have what it took to whet my appetite back then. Fourteen years later my tastes have broadened a great deal, so I decided to check it out. WILD THINGS turns out to be a real thrill-ride of a film, and that's all down to Stephen Peters' script, which is tremendous. It packs more genuinely surprising twists into its running time than half a dozen other Hollywood thrillers, and you can never predict where it's about to go next. An ensemble cast of actors known for appearances in sometimes-trashy cinema adds to the appeal. Matt Dillon does well balancing a difficult leading role, and Kevin Bacon has fun as a hard-ass cop, riffing on a role he must have played dozens of times during his career. Denise Richards, too, appears to be having a good time, trading on her cheerleader looks to decent effect, though Neve Campbell can't seem to shift her SCREAM-style goody two-shoes persona. Watch out for decent production values, slick direction from John McNaughton (HENRY: PORTRAIT OF A SERIAL KILLER) and a wicked supporting role for Bill Murray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men fare better than females
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guil fisher (guilfisher@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For certainly Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon walk off with the film. The two empty headed females in question are Neve Campbell and Denise Richards. Both of which I found boring and so predictable in their over acted performances. But then we are graced with some real professional women in the likes of Theresa Russell and Carrie Snodgress. Unfortunately they aren't in it long enough to count. Also Bill Murray in a cameo performance. I thought the plot was stupid and can't understand why no one caught on to Campbell's witchery. Or should I say bitchery. Wearing unflattering wigs, one wonders what her real hair was like. The author of this piece of junk (and I'm being polite) was out to lunch. The ending will find most viewers sick at the sight of the fem fa-tale (if you really want to call her that) sailing off into the sunset having killed someone and getting away with it. I guess the code of decency doesn't exist anymore and we continue to make films of violence letting the killers get away with their dirty deeds. Maybe that is why there is so much crime and violence in this world. I give it 2 and a half stars for Bacon, Dillon and supporting cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com - @tss5078
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For years, people have been talking to me about this smart, sexy thriller, that spawned three sequels. There is also something to be said for mysteries, with twists and turns, that make you think, but a half hour into this thing, it was easy to figure out why none of the stars came back for the sequels. This movie certainly plays up the eye candy angle, with two of the most beautiful women in Hollywood, and at first glance, it seems like it's going to be a pretty good film, but then the twists and turns kick in. Throwing in a twist can make an ordinary film spectacular, but when you do it every five minutes, it just confuses the hell out of the audience, and that's what happened here. By the end of Wild Things, I didn't know what the hell was going on anymore. As for the performances, they range from the brilliant Neve Campbell to the horrid Matt Dillon, and feature a ton of cameos in-between. I wanted to like this movie, there are some very good looking people, who like to take their cloths off, and that does tend to help you focus more, but the question is what are we focusing on? I concluded that there really isn't a reason to watch two hours of pure garbage, when you can find all the naked celebrity pictures you could ever want, in five minutes online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie but damn strange way to play it through.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really don't know what to think about this movie after watching it. On one hand I really enjoyed all the actors and actresses in it and it had a great story and beginning but as the movie went on and after about 300 twists later I find the movie to be just getting silly but it did come through in the end and wrap everything up nicely. This movie is about a teacher who is accused by two of his young students of rape. They take him to court and make a case agaisnt him but everything is not as it seems. This movie was really good I just feel it did not need to get so silly and overdone exspecially near the end. The twists were no longer a surprise because they happened so often all you expected was another one but other then that good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things, you make my heart sing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tawdry tale of sex, murder, money and betrayal, John McNaughton's neo-noir Wild Things comes across like a gloriously trashy blend of Body Heat and Cruel Intentions, only with bigger boobs and a greater degree of salacious Sapphic snogging. The film has more outrageous twists and turns than a worm at a zumba workoutno-one is who they seem to be, everyone is looking out for number one, and there are no depths to which the characters won't sink in order to achieve their goalsbut director McNaughton copes admirably with the movie's many Machiavellian machinations, adeptly juggling the complex script's many plot threads whilst still ensuring that matters move at a reasonably brisk pace. A superb ensemble cast also helps to make this a hugely entertaining time-waster, the acting talent including Matt Dillon, Kevin Bacon, Robert Wagner, Bill Murray, Theresa Russell, Neve Campbell and, last but not least, Denise Richards, who admittedly couldn't act her way out of a soggy paper bag, but who at least helps make good on the film's promise of some serious sexiness: she's soaked whilst washing a car, goes topless during a drunken threesome, flaunts herself in slow motion wearing a semi-translucent swimsuit, and gets it on with Campbell in a swimming pool. 7.5 out of 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Bacon, Matt Dillon, Neve Campbell, Denise Richards, Theresa Russell, Daphne Rubin-Vega, Robert Wagner and Bill Murray star in this 1998 thriller. A money-making plot erupts when a high school guidance counselor is accused of rape. This takes place in Blue Bay, Florida where we meet Sam Lombardo (Dillon), a mild-mannered guidance counselor and sailboat instructor who is soon accused of raping students, Kelly Van Ryan (Richards) and Suzie Toller (Campbell). Bacon plays police detective, Ray Duquette who investigates the case and learns there may be a plot to get money from Kelly's wealthy mother, Sandra Van Ryan (Russell). Vega plays Ray's partner, Gloria Perez, Wagner plays the Van Ryan's lawyer, Tom Baxter and Murray plays Sam's lawyer, Ken Bowden. This is a pretty good thriller with a good cast and some neat twists that I recommend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing, Humorous & Outrageously Twisted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This highly entertaining sleaze-fest features gratuitous nudity, bi-sexuality and a m&eacute;nage-a-trois which all seem to have been included purely to spice things up. It's also, however, a glossy thriller with an extremely well written plot that's intriguing, humorous and outrageously twisted. Remarkably, by the time all the explanatory flashbacks (which are included with the closing credits) have finished, it's also evident that the whole thing makes sense. Greed, betrayal and murder are the story's main ingredients but the sheer wickedness of its characters and the movie's satirical qualities also combine well to ensure that "Wild Things" compares favourably to most other crime-related mysteries that may be on offer. Kelly Van Ryan (Denise Richards) is a spoilt, 17-year-old rich girl who lives in Blue Bay, Florida. She's used to getting everything she wants but when she sets her sights on her High School guidance counsellor, Sam Lombardo (Matt Dillon), things don't fall into place as easily as she expects and she accuses him of rape. Local police detectives Ray Duquette (Kevin Bacon) and Gloria Perez (Daphne Rubin-Vega) are charged with the responsibility of investigating the alleged crime and Perez is certainly not convinced that there is any substance in Kelly's accusation. When another girl, Suzie Toller (Neve Campbell) also comes forward and makes a similar accusation, Sam Lombardo is arrested and hires lawyer Kenneth Bowden (Bill Murray) to defend him. Kelly's mother Sandra (Theresa Russell) is very wealthy and powerful and also one of Sam's ex-lovers. She's delighted to use the situation to try to ruin Sam but after the case against him collapses in bizarre circumstances and Lombardo is awarded a multi-million dollar settlement for defamation of character, Sandra Van Ryan is left furious and humiliated and looking for revenge. The course that the story takes from this point on is full of twists and double-crosses that keep on coming until the movie eventually ends with the most surprising development of them all. The characters in "Wild Things" include the very rich and the very poor as well as people who are employed in the legal profession, education and law enforcement. What they all have in common is that they're all morally bankrupt and most of them are criminals. The way in which they're represented on-screen is brilliant as the acting is pitched at just the right amount over-the-top to exploit the absurdity and humour of so many of the situations without allowing the impact of the more scandalous and wicked goings-on to be diminished in any way. In this respect, the entire cast is top-notch but Bill Murray does particularly well as a shyster lawyer who enjoys a good insurance scam but is also smarter than he first appears to be. "Wild Things" is beautifully filmed and some passages of the score wouldn't have seemed out of place in "Twin Peaks". It's tremendous fun to watch and very rewarding because it delivers so much more that it initially seems to promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sex is the only real reason to watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS "Wild things" is a trash entertainment , but an enjoyable entertainment . It isn't great on any kind of level . Still , it provides a quite decent entertainment for nearly 2 hours. It's better than most of the movies in its genre - erotic thriller (not that the genre has about 2 really good movies in it , while the rest is basically a straight-to-video/DVD crap. The best thing about "Wild things" is sex. We have three hot ladies here  Denise Richards , Neve Campbell and Theresa Russell . Not that the men are ugly , hell no , after all we have here Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon. I can assure you that at some point in the movie you will see everyone of them in some state of undress. "WD" also has some great sex scenes  the lesbian scene at the pool and great threesome between two ladies and one man . The threesome is one of my favorite and most arousing movie scenes EVER. The screenplay by Stephen Peters isn't exactly a brilliant one . It feels like a story from one of those pulp magazines that inspired Quentin Tarantino to make "Pulp fiction". I was able to figure out most of the twists and connections between characters before the movie presented them to the audience . Yet there was some inspired stuff here  the teeth , the lovely "behind the scenes" ending credits and Bill Murray's part in the story (!). John McNaughton directs the sex scenes very nicely . Atmospheric score by George S. Clinton certainly helps him. On the other hand he tries to hide the surprises from the audience in a too obvious way  for example if you didn't saw Dillon raping Richards or the fight between Bacon and Richards it means that the truth is completely different than what movie is trying to suggest you. Denise Richards is watchable here . Her body does most of the acting . Neve Campbell is really solid as the naughty girl , same as Kevin Bacon as FBI agent. Matt Dillon isn't bad , but the way he acts makes it obvious for the audience that he isn't exactly a good guy as the movie tries to present him . Theresa Russell is quite good as the rich and powerful Sandra Van Ryan. I was surprised by Bill Murray who gives a very funny performance as the tricky lawyer. It's obviously the best movie of the franchise . Not really a quality movie , but if you will low your expectations you probably will have fun with this popcorn thriller. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Thing, You Make My Heart Sing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The Squeerelist
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thriller has been one of my favorite movies as long as I can remember. As a kid, this was my go-to flick on any given Sunday. I know this is not a film for children, but what can I say... I was already unusual. A high school guidance counselor (Matt Dillon) is accused of rape by 2 of his students (Denise Richards & Neve Campbell)... The twisted storyline is set in the dreamy Floridian surroundings. For those who haven't been to Florida, it makes you want to discover this bit of paradise. For those who have, it just really makes you miss it. The lascivious original score smells like the Everglades and releases an intriguing scent wherever it infiltrates. Wild Things takes you out on a yacht, or makes you visit the gators (this film seriously makes me think of a typical Florida tourism brochure). The end will blow you away for sure. The cast is eclectic and brilliant (Kevin Bacon is an incredible dirty cop and the 2 main female leads are gorgeous and dangerously manipulative). The sex scenes are audacious and necessary to the plot. The film mixes humor (you can't escape it with Bill Murray in the cast) and seriousness which makes it a perfect combo. Wild Things is a great thriller, a sexy 90s classic! 1 reason to watch: the scene with Denise washing Matt's car to Lauren Christy's song I Want What I Want Read it here: http://squeerelist.blogspot.com/2013/06/wild-things- 1998.html
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things- Wild is the Wind? ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The classic tale of wealth, greed, conspiracy, mistrust and the eventual downfall of so many people all mark this 1998 thriller film. The problem with the movie is that there are too many plot twists here. Yes, they're very interesting, but after a while, it becomes who is doing what to whom. Honesty and integrity have all but fallen through the cracks here. Never underestimate the one most deviant. She or he may very well have a brain after-all. Robert Wagner is completely wasted here in a bit part of the rich girl's step-father. He is about the only one really not involved with what is going on here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twist-a-minute thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember when WILD THINGS came out on first release; for some reason, it never appealed to me. Back then I only cared about horror films like SCREAM, and this sleazy-looking thriller didn't have what it took to whet my appetite back then. Fourteen years later my tastes have broadened a great deal, so I decided to check it out. WILD THINGS turns out to be a real thrill-ride of a film, and that's all down to Stephen Peters' script, which is tremendous. It packs more genuinely surprising twists into its running time than half a dozen other Hollywood thrillers, and you can never predict where it's about to go next. An ensemble cast of actors known for appearances in sometimes-trashy cinema adds to the appeal. Matt Dillon does well balancing a difficult leading role, and Kevin Bacon has fun as a hard-ass cop, riffing on a role he must have played dozens of times during his career. Denise Richards, too, appears to be having a good time, trading on her cheerleader looks to decent effect, though Neve Campbell can't seem to shift her SCREAM-style goody two-shoes persona. Watch out for decent production values, slick direction from John McNaughton (HENRY: PORTRAIT OF A SERIAL KILLER) and a wicked supporting role for Bill Murray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men fare better than females
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guil fisher (guilfisher@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For certainly Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon walk off with the film. The two empty headed females in question are Neve Campbell and Denise Richards. Both of which I found boring and so predictable in their over acted performances. But then we are graced with some real professional women in the likes of Theresa Russell and Carrie Snodgress. Unfortunately they aren't in it long enough to count. Also Bill Murray in a cameo performance. I thought the plot was stupid and can't understand why no one caught on to Campbell's witchery. Or should I say bitchery. Wearing unflattering wigs, one wonders what her real hair was like. The author of this piece of junk (and I'm being polite) was out to lunch. The ending will find most viewers sick at the sight of the fem fa-tale (if you really want to call her that) sailing off into the sunset having killed someone and getting away with it. I guess the code of decency doesn't exist anymore and we continue to make films of violence letting the killers get away with their dirty deeds. Maybe that is why there is so much crime and violence in this world. I give it 2 and a half stars for Bacon, Dillon and supporting cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com - @tss5078
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For years, people have been talking to me about this smart, sexy thriller, that spawned three sequels. There is also something to be said for mysteries, with twists and turns, that make you think, but a half hour into this thing, it was easy to figure out why none of the stars came back for the sequels. This movie certainly plays up the eye candy angle, with two of the most beautiful women in Hollywood, and at first glance, it seems like it's going to be a pretty good film, but then the twists and turns kick in. Throwing in a twist can make an ordinary film spectacular, but when you do it every five minutes, it just confuses the hell out of the audience, and that's what happened here. By the end of Wild Things, I didn't know what the hell was going on anymore. As for the performances, they range from the brilliant Neve Campbell to the horrid Matt Dillon, and feature a ton of cameos in-between. I wanted to like this movie, there are some very good looking people, who like to take their cloths off, and that does tend to help you focus more, but the question is what are we focusing on? I concluded that there really isn't a reason to watch two hours of pure garbage, when you can find all the naked celebrity pictures you could ever want, in five minutes online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie but damn strange way to play it through.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really don't know what to think about this movie after watching it. On one hand I really enjoyed all the actors and actresses in it and it had a great story and beginning but as the movie went on and after about 300 twists later I find the movie to be just getting silly but it did come through in the end and wrap everything up nicely. This movie is about a teacher who is accused by two of his young students of rape. They take him to court and make a case agaisnt him but everything is not as it seems. This movie was really good I just feel it did not need to get so silly and overdone exspecially near the end. The twists were no longer a surprise because they happened so often all you expected was another one but other then that good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things, you make my heart sing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tawdry tale of sex, murder, money and betrayal, John McNaughton's neo-noir Wild Things comes across like a gloriously trashy blend of Body Heat and Cruel Intentions, only with bigger boobs and a greater degree of salacious Sapphic snogging. The film has more outrageous twists and turns than a worm at a zumba workoutno-one is who they seem to be, everyone is looking out for number one, and there are no depths to which the characters won't sink in order to achieve their goalsbut director McNaughton copes admirably with the movie's many Machiavellian machinations, adeptly juggling the complex script's many plot threads whilst still ensuring that matters move at a reasonably brisk pace. A superb ensemble cast also helps to make this a hugely entertaining time-waster, the acting talent including Matt Dillon, Kevin Bacon, Robert Wagner, Bill Murray, Theresa Russell, Neve Campbell and, last but not least, Denise Richards, who admittedly couldn't act her way out of a soggy paper bag, but who at least helps make good on the film's promise of some serious sexiness: she's soaked whilst washing a car, goes topless during a drunken threesome, flaunts herself in slow motion wearing a semi-translucent swimsuit, and gets it on with Campbell in a swimming pool. 7.5 out of 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Bacon, Matt Dillon, Neve Campbell, Denise Richards, Theresa Russell, Daphne Rubin-Vega, Robert Wagner and Bill Murray star in this 1998 thriller. A money-making plot erupts when a high school guidance counselor is accused of rape. This takes place in Blue Bay, Florida where we meet Sam Lombardo (Dillon), a mild-mannered guidance counselor and sailboat instructor who is soon accused of raping students, Kelly Van Ryan (Richards) and Suzie Toller (Campbell). Bacon plays police detective, Ray Duquette who investigates the case and learns there may be a plot to get money from Kelly's wealthy mother, Sandra Van Ryan (Russell). Vega plays Ray's partner, Gloria Perez, Wagner plays the Van Ryan's lawyer, Tom Baxter and Murray plays Sam's lawyer, Ken Bowden. This is a pretty good thriller with a good cast and some neat twists that I recommend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing, Humorous & Outrageously Twisted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This highly entertaining sleaze-fest features gratuitous nudity, bi-sexuality and a m&eacute;nage-a-trois which all seem to have been included purely to spice things up. It's also, however, a glossy thriller with an extremely well written plot that's intriguing, humorous and outrageously twisted. Remarkably, by the time all the explanatory flashbacks (which are included with the closing credits) have finished, it's also evident that the whole thing makes sense. Greed, betrayal and murder are the story's main ingredients but the sheer wickedness of its characters and the movie's satirical qualities also combine well to ensure that "Wild Things" compares favourably to most other crime-related mysteries that may be on offer. Kelly Van Ryan (Denise Richards) is a spoilt, 17-year-old rich girl who lives in Blue Bay, Florida. She's used to getting everything she wants but when she sets her sights on her High School guidance counsellor, Sam Lombardo (Matt Dillon), things don't fall into place as easily as she expects and she accuses him of rape. Local police detectives Ray Duquette (Kevin Bacon) and Gloria Perez (Daphne Rubin-Vega) are charged with the responsibility of investigating the alleged crime and Perez is certainly not convinced that there is any substance in Kelly's accusation. When another girl, Suzie Toller (Neve Campbell) also comes forward and makes a similar accusation, Sam Lombardo is arrested and hires lawyer Kenneth Bowden (Bill Murray) to defend him. Kelly's mother Sandra (Theresa Russell) is very wealthy and powerful and also one of Sam's ex-lovers. She's delighted to use the situation to try to ruin Sam but after the case against him collapses in bizarre circumstances and Lombardo is awarded a multi-million dollar settlement for defamation of character, Sandra Van Ryan is left furious and humiliated and looking for revenge. The course that the story takes from this point on is full of twists and double-crosses that keep on coming until the movie eventually ends with the most surprising development of them all. The characters in "Wild Things" include the very rich and the very poor as well as people who are employed in the legal profession, education and law enforcement. What they all have in common is that they're all morally bankrupt and most of them are criminals. The way in which they're represented on-screen is brilliant as the acting is pitched at just the right amount over-the-top to exploit the absurdity and humour of so many of the situations without allowing the impact of the more scandalous and wicked goings-on to be diminished in any way. In this respect, the entire cast is top-notch but Bill Murray does particularly well as a shyster lawyer who enjoys a good insurance scam but is also smarter than he first appears to be. "Wild Things" is beautifully filmed and some passages of the score wouldn't have seemed out of place in "Twin Peaks". It's tremendous fun to watch and very rewarding because it delivers so much more that it initially seems to promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sex is the only real reason to watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS "Wild things" is a trash entertainment , but an enjoyable entertainment . It isn't great on any kind of level . Still , it provides a quite decent entertainment for nearly 2 hours. It's better than most of the movies in its genre - erotic thriller (not that the genre has about 2 really good movies in it , while the rest is basically a straight-to-video/DVD crap. The best thing about "Wild things" is sex. We have three hot ladies here  Denise Richards , Neve Campbell and Theresa Russell . Not that the men are ugly , hell no , after all we have here Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon. I can assure you that at some point in the movie you will see everyone of them in some state of undress. "WD" also has some great sex scenes  the lesbian scene at the pool and great threesome between two ladies and one man . The threesome is one of my favorite and most arousing movie scenes EVER. The screenplay by Stephen Peters isn't exactly a brilliant one . It feels like a story from one of those pulp magazines that inspired Quentin Tarantino to make "Pulp fiction". I was able to figure out most of the twists and connections between characters before the movie presented them to the audience . Yet there was some inspired stuff here  the teeth , the lovely "behind the scenes" ending credits and Bill Murray's part in the story (!). John McNaughton directs the sex scenes very nicely . Atmospheric score by George S. Clinton certainly helps him. On the other hand he tries to hide the surprises from the audience in a too obvious way  for example if you didn't saw Dillon raping Richards or the fight between Bacon and Richards it means that the truth is completely different than what movie is trying to suggest you. Denise Richards is watchable here . Her body does most of the acting . Neve Campbell is really solid as the naughty girl , same as Kevin Bacon as FBI agent. Matt Dillon isn't bad , but the way he acts makes it obvious for the audience that he isn't exactly a good guy as the movie tries to present him . Theresa Russell is quite good as the rich and powerful Sandra Van Ryan. I was surprised by Bill Murray who gives a very funny performance as the tricky lawyer. It's obviously the best movie of the franchise . Not really a quality movie , but if you will low your expectations you probably will have fun with this popcorn thriller. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Thing, You Make My Heart Sing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The Squeerelist
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thriller has been one of my favorite movies as long as I can remember. As a kid, this was my go-to flick on any given Sunday. I know this is not a film for children, but what can I say... I was already unusual. A high school guidance counselor (Matt Dillon) is accused of rape by 2 of his students (Denise Richards & Neve Campbell)... The twisted storyline is set in the dreamy Floridian surroundings. For those who haven't been to Florida, it makes you want to discover this bit of paradise. For those who have, it just really makes you miss it. The lascivious original score smells like the Everglades and releases an intriguing scent wherever it infiltrates. Wild Things takes you out on a yacht, or makes you visit the gators (this film seriously makes me think of a typical Florida tourism brochure). The end will blow you away for sure. The cast is eclectic and brilliant (Kevin Bacon is an incredible dirty cop and the 2 main female leads are gorgeous and dangerously manipulative). The sex scenes are audacious and necessary to the plot. The film mixes humor (you can't escape it with Bill Murray in the cast) and seriousness which makes it a perfect combo. Wild Things is a great thriller, a sexy 90s classic! 1 reason to watch: the scene with Denise washing Matt's car to Lauren Christy's song I Want What I Want Read it here: http://squeerelist.blogspot.com/2013/06/wild-things- 1998.html
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things- Wild is the Wind? ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The classic tale of wealth, greed, conspiracy, mistrust and the eventual downfall of so many people all mark this 1998 thriller film. The problem with the movie is that there are too many plot twists here. Yes, they're very interesting, but after a while, it becomes who is doing what to whom. Honesty and integrity have all but fallen through the cracks here. Never underestimate the one most deviant. She or he may very well have a brain after-all. Robert Wagner is completely wasted here in a bit part of the rich girl's step-father. He is about the only one really not involved with what is going on here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twist-a-minute thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember when WILD THINGS came out on first release; for some reason, it never appealed to me. Back then I only cared about horror films like SCREAM, and this sleazy-looking thriller didn't have what it took to whet my appetite back then. Fourteen years later my tastes have broadened a great deal, so I decided to check it out. WILD THINGS turns out to be a real thrill-ride of a film, and that's all down to Stephen Peters' script, which is tremendous. It packs more genuinely surprising twists into its running time than half a dozen other Hollywood thrillers, and you can never predict where it's about to go next. An ensemble cast of actors known for appearances in sometimes-trashy cinema adds to the appeal. Matt Dillon does well balancing a difficult leading role, and Kevin Bacon has fun as a hard-ass cop, riffing on a role he must have played dozens of times during his career. Denise Richards, too, appears to be having a good time, trading on her cheerleader looks to decent effect, though Neve Campbell can't seem to shift her SCREAM-style goody two-shoes persona. Watch out for decent production values, slick direction from John McNaughton (HENRY: PORTRAIT OF A SERIAL KILLER) and a wicked supporting role for Bill Murray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men fare better than females
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guil fisher (guilfisher@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For certainly Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon walk off with the film. The two empty headed females in question are Neve Campbell and Denise Richards. Both of which I found boring and so predictable in their over acted performances. But then we are graced with some real professional women in the likes of Theresa Russell and Carrie Snodgress. Unfortunately they aren't in it long enough to count. Also Bill Murray in a cameo performance. I thought the plot was stupid and can't understand why no one caught on to Campbell's witchery. Or should I say bitchery. Wearing unflattering wigs, one wonders what her real hair was like. The author of this piece of junk (and I'm being polite) was out to lunch. The ending will find most viewers sick at the sight of the fem fa-tale (if you really want to call her that) sailing off into the sunset having killed someone and getting away with it. I guess the code of decency doesn't exist anymore and we continue to make films of violence letting the killers get away with their dirty deeds. Maybe that is why there is so much crime and violence in this world. I give it 2 and a half stars for Bacon, Dillon and supporting cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com - @tss5078
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For years, people have been talking to me about this smart, sexy thriller, that spawned three sequels. There is also something to be said for mysteries, with twists and turns, that make you think, but a half hour into this thing, it was easy to figure out why none of the stars came back for the sequels. This movie certainly plays up the eye candy angle, with two of the most beautiful women in Hollywood, and at first glance, it seems like it's going to be a pretty good film, but then the twists and turns kick in. Throwing in a twist can make an ordinary film spectacular, but when you do it every five minutes, it just confuses the hell out of the audience, and that's what happened here. By the end of Wild Things, I didn't know what the hell was going on anymore. As for the performances, they range from the brilliant Neve Campbell to the horrid Matt Dillon, and feature a ton of cameos in-between. I wanted to like this movie, there are some very good looking people, who like to take their cloths off, and that does tend to help you focus more, but the question is what are we focusing on? I concluded that there really isn't a reason to watch two hours of pure garbage, when you can find all the naked celebrity pictures you could ever want, in five minutes online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie but damn strange way to play it through.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really don't know what to think about this movie after watching it. On one hand I really enjoyed all the actors and actresses in it and it had a great story and beginning but as the movie went on and after about 300 twists later I find the movie to be just getting silly but it did come through in the end and wrap everything up nicely. This movie is about a teacher who is accused by two of his young students of rape. They take him to court and make a case agaisnt him but everything is not as it seems. This movie was really good I just feel it did not need to get so silly and overdone exspecially near the end. The twists were no longer a surprise because they happened so often all you expected was another one but other then that good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things, you make my heart sing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tawdry tale of sex, murder, money and betrayal, John McNaughton's neo-noir Wild Things comes across like a gloriously trashy blend of Body Heat and Cruel Intentions, only with bigger boobs and a greater degree of salacious Sapphic snogging. The film has more outrageous twists and turns than a worm at a zumba workoutno-one is who they seem to be, everyone is looking out for number one, and there are no depths to which the characters won't sink in order to achieve their goalsbut director McNaughton copes admirably with the movie's many Machiavellian machinations, adeptly juggling the complex script's many plot threads whilst still ensuring that matters move at a reasonably brisk pace. A superb ensemble cast also helps to make this a hugely entertaining time-waster, the acting talent including Matt Dillon, Kevin Bacon, Robert Wagner, Bill Murray, Theresa Russell, Neve Campbell and, last but not least, Denise Richards, who admittedly couldn't act her way out of a soggy paper bag, but who at least helps make good on the film's promise of some serious sexiness: she's soaked whilst washing a car, goes topless during a drunken threesome, flaunts herself in slow motion wearing a semi-translucent swimsuit, and gets it on with Campbell in a swimming pool. 7.5 out of 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Bacon, Matt Dillon, Neve Campbell, Denise Richards, Theresa Russell, Daphne Rubin-Vega, Robert Wagner and Bill Murray star in this 1998 thriller. A money-making plot erupts when a high school guidance counselor is accused of rape. This takes place in Blue Bay, Florida where we meet Sam Lombardo (Dillon), a mild-mannered guidance counselor and sailboat instructor who is soon accused of raping students, Kelly Van Ryan (Richards) and Suzie Toller (Campbell). Bacon plays police detective, Ray Duquette who investigates the case and learns there may be a plot to get money from Kelly's wealthy mother, Sandra Van Ryan (Russell). Vega plays Ray's partner, Gloria Perez, Wagner plays the Van Ryan's lawyer, Tom Baxter and Murray plays Sam's lawyer, Ken Bowden. This is a pretty good thriller with a good cast and some neat twists that I recommend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing, Humorous & Outrageously Twisted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This highly entertaining sleaze-fest features gratuitous nudity, bi-sexuality and a m&eacute;nage-a-trois which all seem to have been included purely to spice things up. It's also, however, a glossy thriller with an extremely well written plot that's intriguing, humorous and outrageously twisted. Remarkably, by the time all the explanatory flashbacks (which are included with the closing credits) have finished, it's also evident that the whole thing makes sense. Greed, betrayal and murder are the story's main ingredients but the sheer wickedness of its characters and the movie's satirical qualities also combine well to ensure that "Wild Things" compares favourably to most other crime-related mysteries that may be on offer. Kelly Van Ryan (Denise Richards) is a spoilt, 17-year-old rich girl who lives in Blue Bay, Florida. She's used to getting everything she wants but when she sets her sights on her High School guidance counsellor, Sam Lombardo (Matt Dillon), things don't fall into place as easily as she expects and she accuses him of rape. Local police detectives Ray Duquette (Kevin Bacon) and Gloria Perez (Daphne Rubin-Vega) are charged with the responsibility of investigating the alleged crime and Perez is certainly not convinced that there is any substance in Kelly's accusation. When another girl, Suzie Toller (Neve Campbell) also comes forward and makes a similar accusation, Sam Lombardo is arrested and hires lawyer Kenneth Bowden (Bill Murray) to defend him. Kelly's mother Sandra (Theresa Russell) is very wealthy and powerful and also one of Sam's ex-lovers. She's delighted to use the situation to try to ruin Sam but after the case against him collapses in bizarre circumstances and Lombardo is awarded a multi-million dollar settlement for defamation of character, Sandra Van Ryan is left furious and humiliated and looking for revenge. The course that the story takes from this point on is full of twists and double-crosses that keep on coming until the movie eventually ends with the most surprising development of them all. The characters in "Wild Things" include the very rich and the very poor as well as people who are employed in the legal profession, education and law enforcement. What they all have in common is that they're all morally bankrupt and most of them are criminals. The way in which they're represented on-screen is brilliant as the acting is pitched at just the right amount over-the-top to exploit the absurdity and humour of so many of the situations without allowing the impact of the more scandalous and wicked goings-on to be diminished in any way. In this respect, the entire cast is top-notch but Bill Murray does particularly well as a shyster lawyer who enjoys a good insurance scam but is also smarter than he first appears to be. "Wild Things" is beautifully filmed and some passages of the score wouldn't have seemed out of place in "Twin Peaks". It's tremendous fun to watch and very rewarding because it delivers so much more that it initially seems to promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sex is the only real reason to watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS "Wild things" is a trash entertainment , but an enjoyable entertainment . It isn't great on any kind of level . Still , it provides a quite decent entertainment for nearly 2 hours. It's better than most of the movies in its genre - erotic thriller (not that the genre has about 2 really good movies in it , while the rest is basically a straight-to-video/DVD crap. The best thing about "Wild things" is sex. We have three hot ladies here  Denise Richards , Neve Campbell and Theresa Russell . Not that the men are ugly , hell no , after all we have here Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon. I can assure you that at some point in the movie you will see everyone of them in some state of undress. "WD" also has some great sex scenes  the lesbian scene at the pool and great threesome between two ladies and one man . The threesome is one of my favorite and most arousing movie scenes EVER. The screenplay by Stephen Peters isn't exactly a brilliant one . It feels like a story from one of those pulp magazines that inspired Quentin Tarantino to make "Pulp fiction". I was able to figure out most of the twists and connections between characters before the movie presented them to the audience . Yet there was some inspired stuff here  the teeth , the lovely "behind the scenes" ending credits and Bill Murray's part in the story (!). John McNaughton directs the sex scenes very nicely . Atmospheric score by George S. Clinton certainly helps him. On the other hand he tries to hide the surprises from the audience in a too obvious way  for example if you didn't saw Dillon raping Richards or the fight between Bacon and Richards it means that the truth is completely different than what movie is trying to suggest you. Denise Richards is watchable here . Her body does most of the acting . Neve Campbell is really solid as the naughty girl , same as Kevin Bacon as FBI agent. Matt Dillon isn't bad , but the way he acts makes it obvious for the audience that he isn't exactly a good guy as the movie tries to present him . Theresa Russell is quite good as the rich and powerful Sandra Van Ryan. I was surprised by Bill Murray who gives a very funny performance as the tricky lawyer. It's obviously the best movie of the franchise . Not really a quality movie , but if you will low your expectations you probably will have fun with this popcorn thriller. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Thing, You Make My Heart Sing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The Squeerelist
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thriller has been one of my favorite movies as long as I can remember. As a kid, this was my go-to flick on any given Sunday. I know this is not a film for children, but what can I say... I was already unusual. A high school guidance counselor (Matt Dillon) is accused of rape by 2 of his students (Denise Richards & Neve Campbell)... The twisted storyline is set in the dreamy Floridian surroundings. For those who haven't been to Florida, it makes you want to discover this bit of paradise. For those who have, it just really makes you miss it. The lascivious original score smells like the Everglades and releases an intriguing scent wherever it infiltrates. Wild Things takes you out on a yacht, or makes you visit the gators (this film seriously makes me think of a typical Florida tourism brochure). The end will blow you away for sure. The cast is eclectic and brilliant (Kevin Bacon is an incredible dirty cop and the 2 main female leads are gorgeous and dangerously manipulative). The sex scenes are audacious and necessary to the plot. The film mixes humor (you can't escape it with Bill Murray in the cast) and seriousness which makes it a perfect combo. Wild Things is a great thriller, a sexy 90s classic! 1 reason to watch: the scene with Denise washing Matt's car to Lauren Christy's song I Want What I Want Read it here: http://squeerelist.blogspot.com/2013/06/wild-things- 1998.html
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things- Wild is the Wind? ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The classic tale of wealth, greed, conspiracy, mistrust and the eventual downfall of so many people all mark this 1998 thriller film. The problem with the movie is that there are too many plot twists here. Yes, they're very interesting, but after a while, it becomes who is doing what to whom. Honesty and integrity have all but fallen through the cracks here. Never underestimate the one most deviant. She or he may very well have a brain after-all. Robert Wagner is completely wasted here in a bit part of the rich girl's step-father. He is about the only one really not involved with what is going on here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twist-a-minute thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember when WILD THINGS came out on first release; for some reason, it never appealed to me. Back then I only cared about horror films like SCREAM, and this sleazy-looking thriller didn't have what it took to whet my appetite back then. Fourteen years later my tastes have broadened a great deal, so I decided to check it out. WILD THINGS turns out to be a real thrill-ride of a film, and that's all down to Stephen Peters' script, which is tremendous. It packs more genuinely surprising twists into its running time than half a dozen other Hollywood thrillers, and you can never predict where it's about to go next. An ensemble cast of actors known for appearances in sometimes-trashy cinema adds to the appeal. Matt Dillon does well balancing a difficult leading role, and Kevin Bacon has fun as a hard-ass cop, riffing on a role he must have played dozens of times during his career. Denise Richards, too, appears to be having a good time, trading on her cheerleader looks to decent effect, though Neve Campbell can't seem to shift her SCREAM-style goody two-shoes persona. Watch out for decent production values, slick direction from John McNaughton (HENRY: PORTRAIT OF A SERIAL KILLER) and a wicked supporting role for Bill Murray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men fare better than females
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guil fisher (guilfisher@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For certainly Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon walk off with the film. The two empty headed females in question are Neve Campbell and Denise Richards. Both of which I found boring and so predictable in their over acted performances. But then we are graced with some real professional women in the likes of Theresa Russell and Carrie Snodgress. Unfortunately they aren't in it long enough to count. Also Bill Murray in a cameo performance. I thought the plot was stupid and can't understand why no one caught on to Campbell's witchery. Or should I say bitchery. Wearing unflattering wigs, one wonders what her real hair was like. The author of this piece of junk (and I'm being polite) was out to lunch. The ending will find most viewers sick at the sight of the fem fa-tale (if you really want to call her that) sailing off into the sunset having killed someone and getting away with it. I guess the code of decency doesn't exist anymore and we continue to make films of violence letting the killers get away with their dirty deeds. Maybe that is why there is so much crime and violence in this world. I give it 2 and a half stars for Bacon, Dillon and supporting cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com - @tss5078
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For years, people have been talking to me about this smart, sexy thriller, that spawned three sequels. There is also something to be said for mysteries, with twists and turns, that make you think, but a half hour into this thing, it was easy to figure out why none of the stars came back for the sequels. This movie certainly plays up the eye candy angle, with two of the most beautiful women in Hollywood, and at first glance, it seems like it's going to be a pretty good film, but then the twists and turns kick in. Throwing in a twist can make an ordinary film spectacular, but when you do it every five minutes, it just confuses the hell out of the audience, and that's what happened here. By the end of Wild Things, I didn't know what the hell was going on anymore. As for the performances, they range from the brilliant Neve Campbell to the horrid Matt Dillon, and feature a ton of cameos in-between. I wanted to like this movie, there are some very good looking people, who like to take their cloths off, and that does tend to help you focus more, but the question is what are we focusing on? I concluded that there really isn't a reason to watch two hours of pure garbage, when you can find all the naked celebrity pictures you could ever want, in five minutes online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie but damn strange way to play it through.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really don't know what to think about this movie after watching it. On one hand I really enjoyed all the actors and actresses in it and it had a great story and beginning but as the movie went on and after about 300 twists later I find the movie to be just getting silly but it did come through in the end and wrap everything up nicely. This movie is about a teacher who is accused by two of his young students of rape. They take him to court and make a case agaisnt him but everything is not as it seems. This movie was really good I just feel it did not need to get so silly and overdone exspecially near the end. The twists were no longer a surprise because they happened so often all you expected was another one but other then that good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things, you make my heart sing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tawdry tale of sex, murder, money and betrayal, John McNaughton's neo-noir Wild Things comes across like a gloriously trashy blend of Body Heat and Cruel Intentions, only with bigger boobs and a greater degree of salacious Sapphic snogging. The film has more outrageous twists and turns than a worm at a zumba workoutno-one is who they seem to be, everyone is looking out for number one, and there are no depths to which the characters won't sink in order to achieve their goalsbut director McNaughton copes admirably with the movie's many Machiavellian machinations, adeptly juggling the complex script's many plot threads whilst still ensuring that matters move at a reasonably brisk pace. A superb ensemble cast also helps to make this a hugely entertaining time-waster, the acting talent including Matt Dillon, Kevin Bacon, Robert Wagner, Bill Murray, Theresa Russell, Neve Campbell and, last but not least, Denise Richards, who admittedly couldn't act her way out of a soggy paper bag, but who at least helps make good on the film's promise of some serious sexiness: she's soaked whilst washing a car, goes topless during a drunken threesome, flaunts herself in slow motion wearing a semi-translucent swimsuit, and gets it on with Campbell in a swimming pool. 7.5 out of 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Bacon, Matt Dillon, Neve Campbell, Denise Richards, Theresa Russell, Daphne Rubin-Vega, Robert Wagner and Bill Murray star in this 1998 thriller. A money-making plot erupts when a high school guidance counselor is accused of rape. This takes place in Blue Bay, Florida where we meet Sam Lombardo (Dillon), a mild-mannered guidance counselor and sailboat instructor who is soon accused of raping students, Kelly Van Ryan (Richards) and Suzie Toller (Campbell). Bacon plays police detective, Ray Duquette who investigates the case and learns there may be a plot to get money from Kelly's wealthy mother, Sandra Van Ryan (Russell). Vega plays Ray's partner, Gloria Perez, Wagner plays the Van Ryan's lawyer, Tom Baxter and Murray plays Sam's lawyer, Ken Bowden. This is a pretty good thriller with a good cast and some neat twists that I recommend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing, Humorous & Outrageously Twisted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This highly entertaining sleaze-fest features gratuitous nudity, bi-sexuality and a m&eacute;nage-a-trois which all seem to have been included purely to spice things up. It's also, however, a glossy thriller with an extremely well written plot that's intriguing, humorous and outrageously twisted. Remarkably, by the time all the explanatory flashbacks (which are included with the closing credits) have finished, it's also evident that the whole thing makes sense. Greed, betrayal and murder are the story's main ingredients but the sheer wickedness of its characters and the movie's satirical qualities also combine well to ensure that "Wild Things" compares favourably to most other crime-related mysteries that may be on offer. Kelly Van Ryan (Denise Richards) is a spoilt, 17-year-old rich girl who lives in Blue Bay, Florida. She's used to getting everything she wants but when she sets her sights on her High School guidance counsellor, Sam Lombardo (Matt Dillon), things don't fall into place as easily as she expects and she accuses him of rape. Local police detectives Ray Duquette (Kevin Bacon) and Gloria Perez (Daphne Rubin-Vega) are charged with the responsibility of investigating the alleged crime and Perez is certainly not convinced that there is any substance in Kelly's accusation. When another girl, Suzie Toller (Neve Campbell) also comes forward and makes a similar accusation, Sam Lombardo is arrested and hires lawyer Kenneth Bowden (Bill Murray) to defend him. Kelly's mother Sandra (Theresa Russell) is very wealthy and powerful and also one of Sam's ex-lovers. She's delighted to use the situation to try to ruin Sam but after the case against him collapses in bizarre circumstances and Lombardo is awarded a multi-million dollar settlement for defamation of character, Sandra Van Ryan is left furious and humiliated and looking for revenge. The course that the story takes from this point on is full of twists and double-crosses that keep on coming until the movie eventually ends with the most surprising development of them all. The characters in "Wild Things" include the very rich and the very poor as well as people who are employed in the legal profession, education and law enforcement. What they all have in common is that they're all morally bankrupt and most of them are criminals. The way in which they're represented on-screen is brilliant as the acting is pitched at just the right amount over-the-top to exploit the absurdity and humour of so many of the situations without allowing the impact of the more scandalous and wicked goings-on to be diminished in any way. In this respect, the entire cast is top-notch but Bill Murray does particularly well as a shyster lawyer who enjoys a good insurance scam but is also smarter than he first appears to be. "Wild Things" is beautifully filmed and some passages of the score wouldn't have seemed out of place in "Twin Peaks". It's tremendous fun to watch and very rewarding because it delivers so much more that it initially seems to promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sex is the only real reason to watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS "Wild things" is a trash entertainment , but an enjoyable entertainment . It isn't great on any kind of level . Still , it provides a quite decent entertainment for nearly 2 hours. It's better than most of the movies in its genre - erotic thriller (not that the genre has about 2 really good movies in it , while the rest is basically a straight-to-video/DVD crap. The best thing about "Wild things" is sex. We have three hot ladies here  Denise Richards , Neve Campbell and Theresa Russell . Not that the men are ugly , hell no , after all we have here Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon. I can assure you that at some point in the movie you will see everyone of them in some state of undress. "WD" also has some great sex scenes  the lesbian scene at the pool and great threesome between two ladies and one man . The threesome is one of my favorite and most arousing movie scenes EVER. The screenplay by Stephen Peters isn't exactly a brilliant one . It feels like a story from one of those pulp magazines that inspired Quentin Tarantino to make "Pulp fiction". I was able to figure out most of the twists and connections between characters before the movie presented them to the audience . Yet there was some inspired stuff here  the teeth , the lovely "behind the scenes" ending credits and Bill Murray's part in the story (!). John McNaughton directs the sex scenes very nicely . Atmospheric score by George S. Clinton certainly helps him. On the other hand he tries to hide the surprises from the audience in a too obvious way  for example if you didn't saw Dillon raping Richards or the fight between Bacon and Richards it means that the truth is completely different than what movie is trying to suggest you. Denise Richards is watchable here . Her body does most of the acting . Neve Campbell is really solid as the naughty girl , same as Kevin Bacon as FBI agent. Matt Dillon isn't bad , but the way he acts makes it obvious for the audience that he isn't exactly a good guy as the movie tries to present him . Theresa Russell is quite good as the rich and powerful Sandra Van Ryan. I was surprised by Bill Murray who gives a very funny performance as the tricky lawyer. It's obviously the best movie of the franchise . Not really a quality movie , but if you will low your expectations you probably will have fun with this popcorn thriller. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Thing, You Make My Heart Sing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The Squeerelist
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thriller has been one of my favorite movies as long as I can remember. As a kid, this was my go-to flick on any given Sunday. I know this is not a film for children, but what can I say... I was already unusual. A high school guidance counselor (Matt Dillon) is accused of rape by 2 of his students (Denise Richards & Neve Campbell)... The twisted storyline is set in the dreamy Floridian surroundings. For those who haven't been to Florida, it makes you want to discover this bit of paradise. For those who have, it just really makes you miss it. The lascivious original score smells like the Everglades and releases an intriguing scent wherever it infiltrates. Wild Things takes you out on a yacht, or makes you visit the gators (this film seriously makes me think of a typical Florida tourism brochure). The end will blow you away for sure. The cast is eclectic and brilliant (Kevin Bacon is an incredible dirty cop and the 2 main female leads are gorgeous and dangerously manipulative). The sex scenes are audacious and necessary to the plot. The film mixes humor (you can't escape it with Bill Murray in the cast) and seriousness which makes it a perfect combo. Wild Things is a great thriller, a sexy 90s classic! 1 reason to watch: the scene with Denise washing Matt's car to Lauren Christy's song I Want What I Want Read it here: http://squeerelist.blogspot.com/2013/06/wild-things- 1998.html
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things- Wild is the Wind? ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The classic tale of wealth, greed, conspiracy, mistrust and the eventual downfall of so many people all mark this 1998 thriller film. The problem with the movie is that there are too many plot twists here. Yes, they're very interesting, but after a while, it becomes who is doing what to whom. Honesty and integrity have all but fallen through the cracks here. Never underestimate the one most deviant. She or he may very well have a brain after-all. Robert Wagner is completely wasted here in a bit part of the rich girl's step-father. He is about the only one really not involved with what is going on here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twist-a-minute thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember when WILD THINGS came out on first release; for some reason, it never appealed to me. Back then I only cared about horror films like SCREAM, and this sleazy-looking thriller didn't have what it took to whet my appetite back then. Fourteen years later my tastes have broadened a great deal, so I decided to check it out. WILD THINGS turns out to be a real thrill-ride of a film, and that's all down to Stephen Peters' script, which is tremendous. It packs more genuinely surprising twists into its running time than half a dozen other Hollywood thrillers, and you can never predict where it's about to go next. An ensemble cast of actors known for appearances in sometimes-trashy cinema adds to the appeal. Matt Dillon does well balancing a difficult leading role, and Kevin Bacon has fun as a hard-ass cop, riffing on a role he must have played dozens of times during his career. Denise Richards, too, appears to be having a good time, trading on her cheerleader looks to decent effect, though Neve Campbell can't seem to shift her SCREAM-style goody two-shoes persona. Watch out for decent production values, slick direction from John McNaughton (HENRY: PORTRAIT OF A SERIAL KILLER) and a wicked supporting role for Bill Murray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men fare better than females
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guil fisher (guilfisher@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For certainly Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon walk off with the film. The two empty headed females in question are Neve Campbell and Denise Richards. Both of which I found boring and so predictable in their over acted performances. But then we are graced with some real professional women in the likes of Theresa Russell and Carrie Snodgress. Unfortunately they aren't in it long enough to count. Also Bill Murray in a cameo performance. I thought the plot was stupid and can't understand why no one caught on to Campbell's witchery. Or should I say bitchery. Wearing unflattering wigs, one wonders what her real hair was like. The author of this piece of junk (and I'm being polite) was out to lunch. The ending will find most viewers sick at the sight of the fem fa-tale (if you really want to call her that) sailing off into the sunset having killed someone and getting away with it. I guess the code of decency doesn't exist anymore and we continue to make films of violence letting the killers get away with their dirty deeds. Maybe that is why there is so much crime and violence in this world. I give it 2 and a half stars for Bacon, Dillon and supporting cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com - @tss5078
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For years, people have been talking to me about this smart, sexy thriller, that spawned three sequels. There is also something to be said for mysteries, with twists and turns, that make you think, but a half hour into this thing, it was easy to figure out why none of the stars came back for the sequels. This movie certainly plays up the eye candy angle, with two of the most beautiful women in Hollywood, and at first glance, it seems like it's going to be a pretty good film, but then the twists and turns kick in. Throwing in a twist can make an ordinary film spectacular, but when you do it every five minutes, it just confuses the hell out of the audience, and that's what happened here. By the end of Wild Things, I didn't know what the hell was going on anymore. As for the performances, they range from the brilliant Neve Campbell to the horrid Matt Dillon, and feature a ton of cameos in-between. I wanted to like this movie, there are some very good looking people, who like to take their cloths off, and that does tend to help you focus more, but the question is what are we focusing on? I concluded that there really isn't a reason to watch two hours of pure garbage, when you can find all the naked celebrity pictures you could ever want, in five minutes online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie but damn strange way to play it through.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really don't know what to think about this movie after watching it. On one hand I really enjoyed all the actors and actresses in it and it had a great story and beginning but as the movie went on and after about 300 twists later I find the movie to be just getting silly but it did come through in the end and wrap everything up nicely. This movie is about a teacher who is accused by two of his young students of rape. They take him to court and make a case agaisnt him but everything is not as it seems. This movie was really good I just feel it did not need to get so silly and overdone exspecially near the end. The twists were no longer a surprise because they happened so often all you expected was another one but other then that good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things, you make my heart sing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tawdry tale of sex, murder, money and betrayal, John McNaughton's neo-noir Wild Things comes across like a gloriously trashy blend of Body Heat and Cruel Intentions, only with bigger boobs and a greater degree of salacious Sapphic snogging. The film has more outrageous twists and turns than a worm at a zumba workoutno-one is who they seem to be, everyone is looking out for number one, and there are no depths to which the characters won't sink in order to achieve their goalsbut director McNaughton copes admirably with the movie's many Machiavellian machinations, adeptly juggling the complex script's many plot threads whilst still ensuring that matters move at a reasonably brisk pace. A superb ensemble cast also helps to make this a hugely entertaining time-waster, the acting talent including Matt Dillon, Kevin Bacon, Robert Wagner, Bill Murray, Theresa Russell, Neve Campbell and, last but not least, Denise Richards, who admittedly couldn't act her way out of a soggy paper bag, but who at least helps make good on the film's promise of some serious sexiness: she's soaked whilst washing a car, goes topless during a drunken threesome, flaunts herself in slow motion wearing a semi-translucent swimsuit, and gets it on with Campbell in a swimming pool. 7.5 out of 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Bacon, Matt Dillon, Neve Campbell, Denise Richards, Theresa Russell, Daphne Rubin-Vega, Robert Wagner and Bill Murray star in this 1998 thriller. A money-making plot erupts when a high school guidance counselor is accused of rape. This takes place in Blue Bay, Florida where we meet Sam Lombardo (Dillon), a mild-mannered guidance counselor and sailboat instructor who is soon accused of raping students, Kelly Van Ryan (Richards) and Suzie Toller (Campbell). Bacon plays police detective, Ray Duquette who investigates the case and learns there may be a plot to get money from Kelly's wealthy mother, Sandra Van Ryan (Russell). Vega plays Ray's partner, Gloria Perez, Wagner plays the Van Ryan's lawyer, Tom Baxter and Murray plays Sam's lawyer, Ken Bowden. This is a pretty good thriller with a good cast and some neat twists that I recommend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing, Humorous & Outrageously Twisted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This highly entertaining sleaze-fest features gratuitous nudity, bi-sexuality and a m&eacute;nage-a-trois which all seem to have been included purely to spice things up. It's also, however, a glossy thriller with an extremely well written plot that's intriguing, humorous and outrageously twisted. Remarkably, by the time all the explanatory flashbacks (which are included with the closing credits) have finished, it's also evident that the whole thing makes sense. Greed, betrayal and murder are the story's main ingredients but the sheer wickedness of its characters and the movie's satirical qualities also combine well to ensure that "Wild Things" compares favourably to most other crime-related mysteries that may be on offer. Kelly Van Ryan (Denise Richards) is a spoilt, 17-year-old rich girl who lives in Blue Bay, Florida. She's used to getting everything she wants but when she sets her sights on her High School guidance counsellor, Sam Lombardo (Matt Dillon), things don't fall into place as easily as she expects and she accuses him of rape. Local police detectives Ray Duquette (Kevin Bacon) and Gloria Perez (Daphne Rubin-Vega) are charged with the responsibility of investigating the alleged crime and Perez is certainly not convinced that there is any substance in Kelly's accusation. When another girl, Suzie Toller (Neve Campbell) also comes forward and makes a similar accusation, Sam Lombardo is arrested and hires lawyer Kenneth Bowden (Bill Murray) to defend him. Kelly's mother Sandra (Theresa Russell) is very wealthy and powerful and also one of Sam's ex-lovers. She's delighted to use the situation to try to ruin Sam but after the case against him collapses in bizarre circumstances and Lombardo is awarded a multi-million dollar settlement for defamation of character, Sandra Van Ryan is left furious and humiliated and looking for revenge. The course that the story takes from this point on is full of twists and double-crosses that keep on coming until the movie eventually ends with the most surprising development of them all. The characters in "Wild Things" include the very rich and the very poor as well as people who are employed in the legal profession, education and law enforcement. What they all have in common is that they're all morally bankrupt and most of them are criminals. The way in which they're represented on-screen is brilliant as the acting is pitched at just the right amount over-the-top to exploit the absurdity and humour of so many of the situations without allowing the impact of the more scandalous and wicked goings-on to be diminished in any way. In this respect, the entire cast is top-notch but Bill Murray does particularly well as a shyster lawyer who enjoys a good insurance scam but is also smarter than he first appears to be. "Wild Things" is beautifully filmed and some passages of the score wouldn't have seemed out of place in "Twin Peaks". It's tremendous fun to watch and very rewarding because it delivers so much more that it initially seems to promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sex is the only real reason to watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS "Wild things" is a trash entertainment , but an enjoyable entertainment . It isn't great on any kind of level . Still , it provides a quite decent entertainment for nearly 2 hours. It's better than most of the movies in its genre - erotic thriller (not that the genre has about 2 really good movies in it , while the rest is basically a straight-to-video/DVD crap. The best thing about "Wild things" is sex. We have three hot ladies here  Denise Richards , Neve Campbell and Theresa Russell . Not that the men are ugly , hell no , after all we have here Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon. I can assure you that at some point in the movie you will see everyone of them in some state of undress. "WD" also has some great sex scenes  the lesbian scene at the pool and great threesome between two ladies and one man . The threesome is one of my favorite and most arousing movie scenes EVER. The screenplay by Stephen Peters isn't exactly a brilliant one . It feels like a story from one of those pulp magazines that inspired Quentin Tarantino to make "Pulp fiction". I was able to figure out most of the twists and connections between characters before the movie presented them to the audience . Yet there was some inspired stuff here  the teeth , the lovely "behind the scenes" ending credits and Bill Murray's part in the story (!). John McNaughton directs the sex scenes very nicely . Atmospheric score by George S. Clinton certainly helps him. On the other hand he tries to hide the surprises from the audience in a too obvious way  for example if you didn't saw Dillon raping Richards or the fight between Bacon and Richards it means that the truth is completely different than what movie is trying to suggest you. Denise Richards is watchable here . Her body does most of the acting . Neve Campbell is really solid as the naughty girl , same as Kevin Bacon as FBI agent. Matt Dillon isn't bad , but the way he acts makes it obvious for the audience that he isn't exactly a good guy as the movie tries to present him . Theresa Russell is quite good as the rich and powerful Sandra Van Ryan. I was surprised by Bill Murray who gives a very funny performance as the tricky lawyer. It's obviously the best movie of the franchise . Not really a quality movie , but if you will low your expectations you probably will have fun with this popcorn thriller. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Thing, You Make My Heart Sing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The Squeerelist
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thriller has been one of my favorite movies as long as I can remember. As a kid, this was my go-to flick on any given Sunday. I know this is not a film for children, but what can I say... I was already unusual. A high school guidance counselor (Matt Dillon) is accused of rape by 2 of his students (Denise Richards & Neve Campbell)... The twisted storyline is set in the dreamy Floridian surroundings. For those who haven't been to Florida, it makes you want to discover this bit of paradise. For those who have, it just really makes you miss it. The lascivious original score smells like the Everglades and releases an intriguing scent wherever it infiltrates. Wild Things takes you out on a yacht, or makes you visit the gators (this film seriously makes me think of a typical Florida tourism brochure). The end will blow you away for sure. The cast is eclectic and brilliant (Kevin Bacon is an incredible dirty cop and the 2 main female leads are gorgeous and dangerously manipulative). The sex scenes are audacious and necessary to the plot. The film mixes humor (you can't escape it with Bill Murray in the cast) and seriousness which makes it a perfect combo. Wild Things is a great thriller, a sexy 90s classic! 1 reason to watch: the scene with Denise washing Matt's car to Lauren Christy's song I Want What I Want Read it here: http://squeerelist.blogspot.com/2013/06/wild-things- 1998.html
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things- Wild is the Wind? ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The classic tale of wealth, greed, conspiracy, mistrust and the eventual downfall of so many people all mark this 1998 thriller film. The problem with the movie is that there are too many plot twists here. Yes, they're very interesting, but after a while, it becomes who is doing what to whom. Honesty and integrity have all but fallen through the cracks here. Never underestimate the one most deviant. She or he may very well have a brain after-all. Robert Wagner is completely wasted here in a bit part of the rich girl's step-father. He is about the only one really not involved with what is going on here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twist-a-minute thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember when WILD THINGS came out on first release; for some reason, it never appealed to me. Back then I only cared about horror films like SCREAM, and this sleazy-looking thriller didn't have what it took to whet my appetite back then. Fourteen years later my tastes have broadened a great deal, so I decided to check it out. WILD THINGS turns out to be a real thrill-ride of a film, and that's all down to Stephen Peters' script, which is tremendous. It packs more genuinely surprising twists into its running time than half a dozen other Hollywood thrillers, and you can never predict where it's about to go next. An ensemble cast of actors known for appearances in sometimes-trashy cinema adds to the appeal. Matt Dillon does well balancing a difficult leading role, and Kevin Bacon has fun as a hard-ass cop, riffing on a role he must have played dozens of times during his career. Denise Richards, too, appears to be having a good time, trading on her cheerleader looks to decent effect, though Neve Campbell can't seem to shift her SCREAM-style goody two-shoes persona. Watch out for decent production values, slick direction from John McNaughton (HENRY: PORTRAIT OF A SERIAL KILLER) and a wicked supporting role for Bill Murray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men fare better than females
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guil fisher (guilfisher@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For certainly Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon walk off with the film. The two empty headed females in question are Neve Campbell and Denise Richards. Both of which I found boring and so predictable in their over acted performances. But then we are graced with some real professional women in the likes of Theresa Russell and Carrie Snodgress. Unfortunately they aren't in it long enough to count. Also Bill Murray in a cameo performance. I thought the plot was stupid and can't understand why no one caught on to Campbell's witchery. Or should I say bitchery. Wearing unflattering wigs, one wonders what her real hair was like. The author of this piece of junk (and I'm being polite) was out to lunch. The ending will find most viewers sick at the sight of the fem fa-tale (if you really want to call her that) sailing off into the sunset having killed someone and getting away with it. I guess the code of decency doesn't exist anymore and we continue to make films of violence letting the killers get away with their dirty deeds. Maybe that is why there is so much crime and violence in this world. I give it 2 and a half stars for Bacon, Dillon and supporting cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com - @tss5078
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For years, people have been talking to me about this smart, sexy thriller, that spawned three sequels. There is also something to be said for mysteries, with twists and turns, that make you think, but a half hour into this thing, it was easy to figure out why none of the stars came back for the sequels. This movie certainly plays up the eye candy angle, with two of the most beautiful women in Hollywood, and at first glance, it seems like it's going to be a pretty good film, but then the twists and turns kick in. Throwing in a twist can make an ordinary film spectacular, but when you do it every five minutes, it just confuses the hell out of the audience, and that's what happened here. By the end of Wild Things, I didn't know what the hell was going on anymore. As for the performances, they range from the brilliant Neve Campbell to the horrid Matt Dillon, and feature a ton of cameos in-between. I wanted to like this movie, there are some very good looking people, who like to take their cloths off, and that does tend to help you focus more, but the question is what are we focusing on? I concluded that there really isn't a reason to watch two hours of pure garbage, when you can find all the naked celebrity pictures you could ever want, in five minutes online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie but damn strange way to play it through.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really don't know what to think about this movie after watching it. On one hand I really enjoyed all the actors and actresses in it and it had a great story and beginning but as the movie went on and after about 300 twists later I find the movie to be just getting silly but it did come through in the end and wrap everything up nicely. This movie is about a teacher who is accused by two of his young students of rape. They take him to court and make a case agaisnt him but everything is not as it seems. This movie was really good I just feel it did not need to get so silly and overdone exspecially near the end. The twists were no longer a surprise because they happened so often all you expected was another one but other then that good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things, you make my heart sing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tawdry tale of sex, murder, money and betrayal, John McNaughton's neo-noir Wild Things comes across like a gloriously trashy blend of Body Heat and Cruel Intentions, only with bigger boobs and a greater degree of salacious Sapphic snogging. The film has more outrageous twists and turns than a worm at a zumba workoutno-one is who they seem to be, everyone is looking out for number one, and there are no depths to which the characters won't sink in order to achieve their goalsbut director McNaughton copes admirably with the movie's many Machiavellian machinations, adeptly juggling the complex script's many plot threads whilst still ensuring that matters move at a reasonably brisk pace. A superb ensemble cast also helps to make this a hugely entertaining time-waster, the acting talent including Matt Dillon, Kevin Bacon, Robert Wagner, Bill Murray, Theresa Russell, Neve Campbell and, last but not least, Denise Richards, who admittedly couldn't act her way out of a soggy paper bag, but who at least helps make good on the film's promise of some serious sexiness: she's soaked whilst washing a car, goes topless during a drunken threesome, flaunts herself in slow motion wearing a semi-translucent swimsuit, and gets it on with Campbell in a swimming pool. 7.5 out of 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Bacon, Matt Dillon, Neve Campbell, Denise Richards, Theresa Russell, Daphne Rubin-Vega, Robert Wagner and Bill Murray star in this 1998 thriller. A money-making plot erupts when a high school guidance counselor is accused of rape. This takes place in Blue Bay, Florida where we meet Sam Lombardo (Dillon), a mild-mannered guidance counselor and sailboat instructor who is soon accused of raping students, Kelly Van Ryan (Richards) and Suzie Toller (Campbell). Bacon plays police detective, Ray Duquette who investigates the case and learns there may be a plot to get money from Kelly's wealthy mother, Sandra Van Ryan (Russell). Vega plays Ray's partner, Gloria Perez, Wagner plays the Van Ryan's lawyer, Tom Baxter and Murray plays Sam's lawyer, Ken Bowden. This is a pretty good thriller with a good cast and some neat twists that I recommend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing, Humorous & Outrageously Twisted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This highly entertaining sleaze-fest features gratuitous nudity, bi-sexuality and a m&eacute;nage-a-trois which all seem to have been included purely to spice things up. It's also, however, a glossy thriller with an extremely well written plot that's intriguing, humorous and outrageously twisted. Remarkably, by the time all the explanatory flashbacks (which are included with the closing credits) have finished, it's also evident that the whole thing makes sense. Greed, betrayal and murder are the story's main ingredients but the sheer wickedness of its characters and the movie's satirical qualities also combine well to ensure that "Wild Things" compares favourably to most other crime-related mysteries that may be on offer. Kelly Van Ryan (Denise Richards) is a spoilt, 17-year-old rich girl who lives in Blue Bay, Florida. She's used to getting everything she wants but when she sets her sights on her High School guidance counsellor, Sam Lombardo (Matt Dillon), things don't fall into place as easily as she expects and she accuses him of rape. Local police detectives Ray Duquette (Kevin Bacon) and Gloria Perez (Daphne Rubin-Vega) are charged with the responsibility of investigating the alleged crime and Perez is certainly not convinced that there is any substance in Kelly's accusation. When another girl, Suzie Toller (Neve Campbell) also comes forward and makes a similar accusation, Sam Lombardo is arrested and hires lawyer Kenneth Bowden (Bill Murray) to defend him. Kelly's mother Sandra (Theresa Russell) is very wealthy and powerful and also one of Sam's ex-lovers. She's delighted to use the situation to try to ruin Sam but after the case against him collapses in bizarre circumstances and Lombardo is awarded a multi-million dollar settlement for defamation of character, Sandra Van Ryan is left furious and humiliated and looking for revenge. The course that the story takes from this point on is full of twists and double-crosses that keep on coming until the movie eventually ends with the most surprising development of them all. The characters in "Wild Things" include the very rich and the very poor as well as people who are employed in the legal profession, education and law enforcement. What they all have in common is that they're all morally bankrupt and most of them are criminals. The way in which they're represented on-screen is brilliant as the acting is pitched at just the right amount over-the-top to exploit the absurdity and humour of so many of the situations without allowing the impact of the more scandalous and wicked goings-on to be diminished in any way. In this respect, the entire cast is top-notch but Bill Murray does particularly well as a shyster lawyer who enjoys a good insurance scam but is also smarter than he first appears to be. "Wild Things" is beautifully filmed and some passages of the score wouldn't have seemed out of place in "Twin Peaks". It's tremendous fun to watch and very rewarding because it delivers so much more that it initially seems to promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sex is the only real reason to watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS "Wild things" is a trash entertainment , but an enjoyable entertainment . It isn't great on any kind of level . Still , it provides a quite decent entertainment for nearly 2 hours. It's better than most of the movies in its genre - erotic thriller (not that the genre has about 2 really good movies in it , while the rest is basically a straight-to-video/DVD crap. The best thing about "Wild things" is sex. We have three hot ladies here  Denise Richards , Neve Campbell and Theresa Russell . Not that the men are ugly , hell no , after all we have here Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon. I can assure you that at some point in the movie you will see everyone of them in some state of undress. "WD" also has some great sex scenes  the lesbian scene at the pool and great threesome between two ladies and one man . The threesome is one of my favorite and most arousing movie scenes EVER. The screenplay by Stephen Peters isn't exactly a brilliant one . It feels like a story from one of those pulp magazines that inspired Quentin Tarantino to make "Pulp fiction". I was able to figure out most of the twists and connections between characters before the movie presented them to the audience . Yet there was some inspired stuff here  the teeth , the lovely "behind the scenes" ending credits and Bill Murray's part in the story (!). John McNaughton directs the sex scenes very nicely . Atmospheric score by George S. Clinton certainly helps him. On the other hand he tries to hide the surprises from the audience in a too obvious way  for example if you didn't saw Dillon raping Richards or the fight between Bacon and Richards it means that the truth is completely different than what movie is trying to suggest you. Denise Richards is watchable here . Her body does most of the acting . Neve Campbell is really solid as the naughty girl , same as Kevin Bacon as FBI agent. Matt Dillon isn't bad , but the way he acts makes it obvious for the audience that he isn't exactly a good guy as the movie tries to present him . Theresa Russell is quite good as the rich and powerful Sandra Van Ryan. I was surprised by Bill Murray who gives a very funny performance as the tricky lawyer. It's obviously the best movie of the franchise . Not really a quality movie , but if you will low your expectations you probably will have fun with this popcorn thriller. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Thing, You Make My Heart Sing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The Squeerelist
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thriller has been one of my favorite movies as long as I can remember. As a kid, this was my go-to flick on any given Sunday. I know this is not a film for children, but what can I say... I was already unusual. A high school guidance counselor (Matt Dillon) is accused of rape by 2 of his students (Denise Richards & Neve Campbell)... The twisted storyline is set in the dreamy Floridian surroundings. For those who haven't been to Florida, it makes you want to discover this bit of paradise. For those who have, it just really makes you miss it. The lascivious original score smells like the Everglades and releases an intriguing scent wherever it infiltrates. Wild Things takes you out on a yacht, or makes you visit the gators (this film seriously makes me think of a typical Florida tourism brochure). The end will blow you away for sure. The cast is eclectic and brilliant (Kevin Bacon is an incredible dirty cop and the 2 main female leads are gorgeous and dangerously manipulative). The sex scenes are audacious and necessary to the plot. The film mixes humor (you can't escape it with Bill Murray in the cast) and seriousness which makes it a perfect combo. Wild Things is a great thriller, a sexy 90s classic! 1 reason to watch: the scene with Denise washing Matt's car to Lauren Christy's song I Want What I Want Read it here: http://squeerelist.blogspot.com/2013/06/wild-things- 1998.html
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things- Wild is the Wind? ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The classic tale of wealth, greed, conspiracy, mistrust and the eventual downfall of so many people all mark this 1998 thriller film. The problem with the movie is that there are too many plot twists here. Yes, they're very interesting, but after a while, it becomes who is doing what to whom. Honesty and integrity have all but fallen through the cracks here. Never underestimate the one most deviant. She or he may very well have a brain after-all. Robert Wagner is completely wasted here in a bit part of the rich girl's step-father. He is about the only one really not involved with what is going on here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twist-a-minute thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember when WILD THINGS came out on first release; for some reason, it never appealed to me. Back then I only cared about horror films like SCREAM, and this sleazy-looking thriller didn't have what it took to whet my appetite back then. Fourteen years later my tastes have broadened a great deal, so I decided to check it out. WILD THINGS turns out to be a real thrill-ride of a film, and that's all down to Stephen Peters' script, which is tremendous. It packs more genuinely surprising twists into its running time than half a dozen other Hollywood thrillers, and you can never predict where it's about to go next. An ensemble cast of actors known for appearances in sometimes-trashy cinema adds to the appeal. Matt Dillon does well balancing a difficult leading role, and Kevin Bacon has fun as a hard-ass cop, riffing on a role he must have played dozens of times during his career. Denise Richards, too, appears to be having a good time, trading on her cheerleader looks to decent effect, though Neve Campbell can't seem to shift her SCREAM-style goody two-shoes persona. Watch out for decent production values, slick direction from John McNaughton (HENRY: PORTRAIT OF A SERIAL KILLER) and a wicked supporting role for Bill Murray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men fare better than females
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guil fisher (guilfisher@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For certainly Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon walk off with the film. The two empty headed females in question are Neve Campbell and Denise Richards. Both of which I found boring and so predictable in their over acted performances. But then we are graced with some real professional women in the likes of Theresa Russell and Carrie Snodgress. Unfortunately they aren't in it long enough to count. Also Bill Murray in a cameo performance. I thought the plot was stupid and can't understand why no one caught on to Campbell's witchery. Or should I say bitchery. Wearing unflattering wigs, one wonders what her real hair was like. The author of this piece of junk (and I'm being polite) was out to lunch. The ending will find most viewers sick at the sight of the fem fa-tale (if you really want to call her that) sailing off into the sunset having killed someone and getting away with it. I guess the code of decency doesn't exist anymore and we continue to make films of violence letting the killers get away with their dirty deeds. Maybe that is why there is so much crime and violence in this world. I give it 2 and a half stars for Bacon, Dillon and supporting cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com - @tss5078
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For years, people have been talking to me about this smart, sexy thriller, that spawned three sequels. There is also something to be said for mysteries, with twists and turns, that make you think, but a half hour into this thing, it was easy to figure out why none of the stars came back for the sequels. This movie certainly plays up the eye candy angle, with two of the most beautiful women in Hollywood, and at first glance, it seems like it's going to be a pretty good film, but then the twists and turns kick in. Throwing in a twist can make an ordinary film spectacular, but when you do it every five minutes, it just confuses the hell out of the audience, and that's what happened here. By the end of Wild Things, I didn't know what the hell was going on anymore. As for the performances, they range from the brilliant Neve Campbell to the horrid Matt Dillon, and feature a ton of cameos in-between. I wanted to like this movie, there are some very good looking people, who like to take their cloths off, and that does tend to help you focus more, but the question is what are we focusing on? I concluded that there really isn't a reason to watch two hours of pure garbage, when you can find all the naked celebrity pictures you could ever want, in five minutes online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie but damn strange way to play it through.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really don't know what to think about this movie after watching it. On one hand I really enjoyed all the actors and actresses in it and it had a great story and beginning but as the movie went on and after about 300 twists later I find the movie to be just getting silly but it did come through in the end and wrap everything up nicely. This movie is about a teacher who is accused by two of his young students of rape. They take him to court and make a case agaisnt him but everything is not as it seems. This movie was really good I just feel it did not need to get so silly and overdone exspecially near the end. The twists were no longer a surprise because they happened so often all you expected was another one but other then that good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things, you make my heart sing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tawdry tale of sex, murder, money and betrayal, John McNaughton's neo-noir Wild Things comes across like a gloriously trashy blend of Body Heat and Cruel Intentions, only with bigger boobs and a greater degree of salacious Sapphic snogging. The film has more outrageous twists and turns than a worm at a zumba workoutno-one is who they seem to be, everyone is looking out for number one, and there are no depths to which the characters won't sink in order to achieve their goalsbut director McNaughton copes admirably with the movie's many Machiavellian machinations, adeptly juggling the complex script's many plot threads whilst still ensuring that matters move at a reasonably brisk pace. A superb ensemble cast also helps to make this a hugely entertaining time-waster, the acting talent including Matt Dillon, Kevin Bacon, Robert Wagner, Bill Murray, Theresa Russell, Neve Campbell and, last but not least, Denise Richards, who admittedly couldn't act her way out of a soggy paper bag, but who at least helps make good on the film's promise of some serious sexiness: she's soaked whilst washing a car, goes topless during a drunken threesome, flaunts herself in slow motion wearing a semi-translucent swimsuit, and gets it on with Campbell in a swimming pool. 7.5 out of 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Bacon, Matt Dillon, Neve Campbell, Denise Richards, Theresa Russell, Daphne Rubin-Vega, Robert Wagner and Bill Murray star in this 1998 thriller. A money-making plot erupts when a high school guidance counselor is accused of rape. This takes place in Blue Bay, Florida where we meet Sam Lombardo (Dillon), a mild-mannered guidance counselor and sailboat instructor who is soon accused of raping students, Kelly Van Ryan (Richards) and Suzie Toller (Campbell). Bacon plays police detective, Ray Duquette who investigates the case and learns there may be a plot to get money from Kelly's wealthy mother, Sandra Van Ryan (Russell). Vega plays Ray's partner, Gloria Perez, Wagner plays the Van Ryan's lawyer, Tom Baxter and Murray plays Sam's lawyer, Ken Bowden. This is a pretty good thriller with a good cast and some neat twists that I recommend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing, Humorous & Outrageously Twisted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This highly entertaining sleaze-fest features gratuitous nudity, bi-sexuality and a m&eacute;nage-a-trois which all seem to have been included purely to spice things up. It's also, however, a glossy thriller with an extremely well written plot that's intriguing, humorous and outrageously twisted. Remarkably, by the time all the explanatory flashbacks (which are included with the closing credits) have finished, it's also evident that the whole thing makes sense. Greed, betrayal and murder are the story's main ingredients but the sheer wickedness of its characters and the movie's satirical qualities also combine well to ensure that "Wild Things" compares favourably to most other crime-related mysteries that may be on offer. Kelly Van Ryan (Denise Richards) is a spoilt, 17-year-old rich girl who lives in Blue Bay, Florida. She's used to getting everything she wants but when she sets her sights on her High School guidance counsellor, Sam Lombardo (Matt Dillon), things don't fall into place as easily as she expects and she accuses him of rape. Local police detectives Ray Duquette (Kevin Bacon) and Gloria Perez (Daphne Rubin-Vega) are charged with the responsibility of investigating the alleged crime and Perez is certainly not convinced that there is any substance in Kelly's accusation. When another girl, Suzie Toller (Neve Campbell) also comes forward and makes a similar accusation, Sam Lombardo is arrested and hires lawyer Kenneth Bowden (Bill Murray) to defend him. Kelly's mother Sandra (Theresa Russell) is very wealthy and powerful and also one of Sam's ex-lovers. She's delighted to use the situation to try to ruin Sam but after the case against him collapses in bizarre circumstances and Lombardo is awarded a multi-million dollar settlement for defamation of character, Sandra Van Ryan is left furious and humiliated and looking for revenge. The course that the story takes from this point on is full of twists and double-crosses that keep on coming until the movie eventually ends with the most surprising development of them all. The characters in "Wild Things" include the very rich and the very poor as well as people who are employed in the legal profession, education and law enforcement. What they all have in common is that they're all morally bankrupt and most of them are criminals. The way in which they're represented on-screen is brilliant as the acting is pitched at just the right amount over-the-top to exploit the absurdity and humour of so many of the situations without allowing the impact of the more scandalous and wicked goings-on to be diminished in any way. In this respect, the entire cast is top-notch but Bill Murray does particularly well as a shyster lawyer who enjoys a good insurance scam but is also smarter than he first appears to be. "Wild Things" is beautifully filmed and some passages of the score wouldn't have seemed out of place in "Twin Peaks". It's tremendous fun to watch and very rewarding because it delivers so much more that it initially seems to promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sex is the only real reason to watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS "Wild things" is a trash entertainment , but an enjoyable entertainment . It isn't great on any kind of level . Still , it provides a quite decent entertainment for nearly 2 hours. It's better than most of the movies in its genre - erotic thriller (not that the genre has about 2 really good movies in it , while the rest is basically a straight-to-video/DVD crap. The best thing about "Wild things" is sex. We have three hot ladies here  Denise Richards , Neve Campbell and Theresa Russell . Not that the men are ugly , hell no , after all we have here Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon. I can assure you that at some point in the movie you will see everyone of them in some state of undress. "WD" also has some great sex scenes  the lesbian scene at the pool and great threesome between two ladies and one man . The threesome is one of my favorite and most arousing movie scenes EVER. The screenplay by Stephen Peters isn't exactly a brilliant one . It feels like a story from one of those pulp magazines that inspired Quentin Tarantino to make "Pulp fiction". I was able to figure out most of the twists and connections between characters before the movie presented them to the audience . Yet there was some inspired stuff here  the teeth , the lovely "behind the scenes" ending credits and Bill Murray's part in the story (!). John McNaughton directs the sex scenes very nicely . Atmospheric score by George S. Clinton certainly helps him. On the other hand he tries to hide the surprises from the audience in a too obvious way  for example if you didn't saw Dillon raping Richards or the fight between Bacon and Richards it means that the truth is completely different than what movie is trying to suggest you. Denise Richards is watchable here . Her body does most of the acting . Neve Campbell is really solid as the naughty girl , same as Kevin Bacon as FBI agent. Matt Dillon isn't bad , but the way he acts makes it obvious for the audience that he isn't exactly a good guy as the movie tries to present him . Theresa Russell is quite good as the rich and powerful Sandra Van Ryan. I was surprised by Bill Murray who gives a very funny performance as the tricky lawyer. It's obviously the best movie of the franchise . Not really a quality movie , but if you will low your expectations you probably will have fun with this popcorn thriller. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Thing, You Make My Heart Sing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The Squeerelist
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thriller has been one of my favorite movies as long as I can remember. As a kid, this was my go-to flick on any given Sunday. I know this is not a film for children, but what can I say... I was already unusual. A high school guidance counselor (Matt Dillon) is accused of rape by 2 of his students (Denise Richards & Neve Campbell)... The twisted storyline is set in the dreamy Floridian surroundings. For those who haven't been to Florida, it makes you want to discover this bit of paradise. For those who have, it just really makes you miss it. The lascivious original score smells like the Everglades and releases an intriguing scent wherever it infiltrates. Wild Things takes you out on a yacht, or makes you visit the gators (this film seriously makes me think of a typical Florida tourism brochure). The end will blow you away for sure. The cast is eclectic and brilliant (Kevin Bacon is an incredible dirty cop and the 2 main female leads are gorgeous and dangerously manipulative). The sex scenes are audacious and necessary to the plot. The film mixes humor (you can't escape it with Bill Murray in the cast) and seriousness which makes it a perfect combo. Wild Things is a great thriller, a sexy 90s classic! 1 reason to watch: the scene with Denise washing Matt's car to Lauren Christy's song I Want What I Want Read it here: http://squeerelist.blogspot.com/2013/06/wild-things- 1998.html
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things- Wild is the Wind? ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The classic tale of wealth, greed, conspiracy, mistrust and the eventual downfall of so many people all mark this 1998 thriller film. The problem with the movie is that there are too many plot twists here. Yes, they're very interesting, but after a while, it becomes who is doing what to whom. Honesty and integrity have all but fallen through the cracks here. Never underestimate the one most deviant. She or he may very well have a brain after-all. Robert Wagner is completely wasted here in a bit part of the rich girl's step-father. He is about the only one really not involved with what is going on here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twist-a-minute thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember when WILD THINGS came out on first release; for some reason, it never appealed to me. Back then I only cared about horror films like SCREAM, and this sleazy-looking thriller didn't have what it took to whet my appetite back then. Fourteen years later my tastes have broadened a great deal, so I decided to check it out. WILD THINGS turns out to be a real thrill-ride of a film, and that's all down to Stephen Peters' script, which is tremendous. It packs more genuinely surprising twists into its running time than half a dozen other Hollywood thrillers, and you can never predict where it's about to go next. An ensemble cast of actors known for appearances in sometimes-trashy cinema adds to the appeal. Matt Dillon does well balancing a difficult leading role, and Kevin Bacon has fun as a hard-ass cop, riffing on a role he must have played dozens of times during his career. Denise Richards, too, appears to be having a good time, trading on her cheerleader looks to decent effect, though Neve Campbell can't seem to shift her SCREAM-style goody two-shoes persona. Watch out for decent production values, slick direction from John McNaughton (HENRY: PORTRAIT OF A SERIAL KILLER) and a wicked supporting role for Bill Murray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men fare better than females
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guil fisher (guilfisher@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For certainly Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon walk off with the film. The two empty headed females in question are Neve Campbell and Denise Richards. Both of which I found boring and so predictable in their over acted performances. But then we are graced with some real professional women in the likes of Theresa Russell and Carrie Snodgress. Unfortunately they aren't in it long enough to count. Also Bill Murray in a cameo performance. I thought the plot was stupid and can't understand why no one caught on to Campbell's witchery. Or should I say bitchery. Wearing unflattering wigs, one wonders what her real hair was like. The author of this piece of junk (and I'm being polite) was out to lunch. The ending will find most viewers sick at the sight of the fem fa-tale (if you really want to call her that) sailing off into the sunset having killed someone and getting away with it. I guess the code of decency doesn't exist anymore and we continue to make films of violence letting the killers get away with their dirty deeds. Maybe that is why there is so much crime and violence in this world. I give it 2 and a half stars for Bacon, Dillon and supporting cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com - @tss5078
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For years, people have been talking to me about this smart, sexy thriller, that spawned three sequels. There is also something to be said for mysteries, with twists and turns, that make you think, but a half hour into this thing, it was easy to figure out why none of the stars came back for the sequels. This movie certainly plays up the eye candy angle, with two of the most beautiful women in Hollywood, and at first glance, it seems like it's going to be a pretty good film, but then the twists and turns kick in. Throwing in a twist can make an ordinary film spectacular, but when you do it every five minutes, it just confuses the hell out of the audience, and that's what happened here. By the end of Wild Things, I didn't know what the hell was going on anymore. As for the performances, they range from the brilliant Neve Campbell to the horrid Matt Dillon, and feature a ton of cameos in-between. I wanted to like this movie, there are some very good looking people, who like to take their cloths off, and that does tend to help you focus more, but the question is what are we focusing on? I concluded that there really isn't a reason to watch two hours of pure garbage, when you can find all the naked celebrity pictures you could ever want, in five minutes online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie but damn strange way to play it through.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really don't know what to think about this movie after watching it. On one hand I really enjoyed all the actors and actresses in it and it had a great story and beginning but as the movie went on and after about 300 twists later I find the movie to be just getting silly but it did come through in the end and wrap everything up nicely. This movie is about a teacher who is accused by two of his young students of rape. They take him to court and make a case agaisnt him but everything is not as it seems. This movie was really good I just feel it did not need to get so silly and overdone exspecially near the end. The twists were no longer a surprise because they happened so often all you expected was another one but other then that good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things, you make my heart sing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tawdry tale of sex, murder, money and betrayal, John McNaughton's neo-noir Wild Things comes across like a gloriously trashy blend of Body Heat and Cruel Intentions, only with bigger boobs and a greater degree of salacious Sapphic snogging. The film has more outrageous twists and turns than a worm at a zumba workoutno-one is who they seem to be, everyone is looking out for number one, and there are no depths to which the characters won't sink in order to achieve their goalsbut director McNaughton copes admirably with the movie's many Machiavellian machinations, adeptly juggling the complex script's many plot threads whilst still ensuring that matters move at a reasonably brisk pace. A superb ensemble cast also helps to make this a hugely entertaining time-waster, the acting talent including Matt Dillon, Kevin Bacon, Robert Wagner, Bill Murray, Theresa Russell, Neve Campbell and, last but not least, Denise Richards, who admittedly couldn't act her way out of a soggy paper bag, but who at least helps make good on the film's promise of some serious sexiness: she's soaked whilst washing a car, goes topless during a drunken threesome, flaunts herself in slow motion wearing a semi-translucent swimsuit, and gets it on with Campbell in a swimming pool. 7.5 out of 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Bacon, Matt Dillon, Neve Campbell, Denise Richards, Theresa Russell, Daphne Rubin-Vega, Robert Wagner and Bill Murray star in this 1998 thriller. A money-making plot erupts when a high school guidance counselor is accused of rape. This takes place in Blue Bay, Florida where we meet Sam Lombardo (Dillon), a mild-mannered guidance counselor and sailboat instructor who is soon accused of raping students, Kelly Van Ryan (Richards) and Suzie Toller (Campbell). Bacon plays police detective, Ray Duquette who investigates the case and learns there may be a plot to get money from Kelly's wealthy mother, Sandra Van Ryan (Russell). Vega plays Ray's partner, Gloria Perez, Wagner plays the Van Ryan's lawyer, Tom Baxter and Murray plays Sam's lawyer, Ken Bowden. This is a pretty good thriller with a good cast and some neat twists that I recommend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing, Humorous & Outrageously Twisted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This highly entertaining sleaze-fest features gratuitous nudity, bi-sexuality and a m&eacute;nage-a-trois which all seem to have been included purely to spice things up. It's also, however, a glossy thriller with an extremely well written plot that's intriguing, humorous and outrageously twisted. Remarkably, by the time all the explanatory flashbacks (which are included with the closing credits) have finished, it's also evident that the whole thing makes sense. Greed, betrayal and murder are the story's main ingredients but the sheer wickedness of its characters and the movie's satirical qualities also combine well to ensure that "Wild Things" compares favourably to most other crime-related mysteries that may be on offer. Kelly Van Ryan (Denise Richards) is a spoilt, 17-year-old rich girl who lives in Blue Bay, Florida. She's used to getting everything she wants but when she sets her sights on her High School guidance counsellor, Sam Lombardo (Matt Dillon), things don't fall into place as easily as she expects and she accuses him of rape. Local police detectives Ray Duquette (Kevin Bacon) and Gloria Perez (Daphne Rubin-Vega) are charged with the responsibility of investigating the alleged crime and Perez is certainly not convinced that there is any substance in Kelly's accusation. When another girl, Suzie Toller (Neve Campbell) also comes forward and makes a similar accusation, Sam Lombardo is arrested and hires lawyer Kenneth Bowden (Bill Murray) to defend him. Kelly's mother Sandra (Theresa Russell) is very wealthy and powerful and also one of Sam's ex-lovers. She's delighted to use the situation to try to ruin Sam but after the case against him collapses in bizarre circumstances and Lombardo is awarded a multi-million dollar settlement for defamation of character, Sandra Van Ryan is left furious and humiliated and looking for revenge. The course that the story takes from this point on is full of twists and double-crosses that keep on coming until the movie eventually ends with the most surprising development of them all. The characters in "Wild Things" include the very rich and the very poor as well as people who are employed in the legal profession, education and law enforcement. What they all have in common is that they're all morally bankrupt and most of them are criminals. The way in which they're represented on-screen is brilliant as the acting is pitched at just the right amount over-the-top to exploit the absurdity and humour of so many of the situations without allowing the impact of the more scandalous and wicked goings-on to be diminished in any way. In this respect, the entire cast is top-notch but Bill Murray does particularly well as a shyster lawyer who enjoys a good insurance scam but is also smarter than he first appears to be. "Wild Things" is beautifully filmed and some passages of the score wouldn't have seemed out of place in "Twin Peaks". It's tremendous fun to watch and very rewarding because it delivers so much more that it initially seems to promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sex is the only real reason to watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS "Wild things" is a trash entertainment , but an enjoyable entertainment . It isn't great on any kind of level . Still , it provides a quite decent entertainment for nearly 2 hours. It's better than most of the movies in its genre - erotic thriller (not that the genre has about 2 really good movies in it , while the rest is basically a straight-to-video/DVD crap. The best thing about "Wild things" is sex. We have three hot ladies here  Denise Richards , Neve Campbell and Theresa Russell . Not that the men are ugly , hell no , after all we have here Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon. I can assure you that at some point in the movie you will see everyone of them in some state of undress. "WD" also has some great sex scenes  the lesbian scene at the pool and great threesome between two ladies and one man . The threesome is one of my favorite and most arousing movie scenes EVER. The screenplay by Stephen Peters isn't exactly a brilliant one . It feels like a story from one of those pulp magazines that inspired Quentin Tarantino to make "Pulp fiction". I was able to figure out most of the twists and connections between characters before the movie presented them to the audience . Yet there was some inspired stuff here  the teeth , the lovely "behind the scenes" ending credits and Bill Murray's part in the story (!). John McNaughton directs the sex scenes very nicely . Atmospheric score by George S. Clinton certainly helps him. On the other hand he tries to hide the surprises from the audience in a too obvious way  for example if you didn't saw Dillon raping Richards or the fight between Bacon and Richards it means that the truth is completely different than what movie is trying to suggest you. Denise Richards is watchable here . Her body does most of the acting . Neve Campbell is really solid as the naughty girl , same as Kevin Bacon as FBI agent. Matt Dillon isn't bad , but the way he acts makes it obvious for the audience that he isn't exactly a good guy as the movie tries to present him . Theresa Russell is quite good as the rich and powerful Sandra Van Ryan. I was surprised by Bill Murray who gives a very funny performance as the tricky lawyer. It's obviously the best movie of the franchise . Not really a quality movie , but if you will low your expectations you probably will have fun with this popcorn thriller. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Thing, You Make My Heart Sing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The Squeerelist
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thriller has been one of my favorite movies as long as I can remember. As a kid, this was my go-to flick on any given Sunday. I know this is not a film for children, but what can I say... I was already unusual. A high school guidance counselor (Matt Dillon) is accused of rape by 2 of his students (Denise Richards & Neve Campbell)... The twisted storyline is set in the dreamy Floridian surroundings. For those who haven't been to Florida, it makes you want to discover this bit of paradise. For those who have, it just really makes you miss it. The lascivious original score smells like the Everglades and releases an intriguing scent wherever it infiltrates. Wild Things takes you out on a yacht, or makes you visit the gators (this film seriously makes me think of a typical Florida tourism brochure). The end will blow you away for sure. The cast is eclectic and brilliant (Kevin Bacon is an incredible dirty cop and the 2 main female leads are gorgeous and dangerously manipulative). The sex scenes are audacious and necessary to the plot. The film mixes humor (you can't escape it with Bill Murray in the cast) and seriousness which makes it a perfect combo. Wild Things is a great thriller, a sexy 90s classic! 1 reason to watch: the scene with Denise washing Matt's car to Lauren Christy's song I Want What I Want Read it here: http://squeerelist.blogspot.com/2013/06/wild-things- 1998.html
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things- Wild is the Wind? ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The classic tale of wealth, greed, conspiracy, mistrust and the eventual downfall of so many people all mark this 1998 thriller film. The problem with the movie is that there are too many plot twists here. Yes, they're very interesting, but after a while, it becomes who is doing what to whom. Honesty and integrity have all but fallen through the cracks here. Never underestimate the one most deviant. She or he may very well have a brain after-all. Robert Wagner is completely wasted here in a bit part of the rich girl's step-father. He is about the only one really not involved with what is going on here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twist-a-minute thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember when WILD THINGS came out on first release; for some reason, it never appealed to me. Back then I only cared about horror films like SCREAM, and this sleazy-looking thriller didn't have what it took to whet my appetite back then. Fourteen years later my tastes have broadened a great deal, so I decided to check it out. WILD THINGS turns out to be a real thrill-ride of a film, and that's all down to Stephen Peters' script, which is tremendous. It packs more genuinely surprising twists into its running time than half a dozen other Hollywood thrillers, and you can never predict where it's about to go next. An ensemble cast of actors known for appearances in sometimes-trashy cinema adds to the appeal. Matt Dillon does well balancing a difficult leading role, and Kevin Bacon has fun as a hard-ass cop, riffing on a role he must have played dozens of times during his career. Denise Richards, too, appears to be having a good time, trading on her cheerleader looks to decent effect, though Neve Campbell can't seem to shift her SCREAM-style goody two-shoes persona. Watch out for decent production values, slick direction from John McNaughton (HENRY: PORTRAIT OF A SERIAL KILLER) and a wicked supporting role for Bill Murray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men fare better than females
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guil fisher (guilfisher@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For certainly Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon walk off with the film. The two empty headed females in question are Neve Campbell and Denise Richards. Both of which I found boring and so predictable in their over acted performances. But then we are graced with some real professional women in the likes of Theresa Russell and Carrie Snodgress. Unfortunately they aren't in it long enough to count. Also Bill Murray in a cameo performance. I thought the plot was stupid and can't understand why no one caught on to Campbell's witchery. Or should I say bitchery. Wearing unflattering wigs, one wonders what her real hair was like. The author of this piece of junk (and I'm being polite) was out to lunch. The ending will find most viewers sick at the sight of the fem fa-tale (if you really want to call her that) sailing off into the sunset having killed someone and getting away with it. I guess the code of decency doesn't exist anymore and we continue to make films of violence letting the killers get away with their dirty deeds. Maybe that is why there is so much crime and violence in this world. I give it 2 and a half stars for Bacon, Dillon and supporting cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com - @tss5078
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For years, people have been talking to me about this smart, sexy thriller, that spawned three sequels. There is also something to be said for mysteries, with twists and turns, that make you think, but a half hour into this thing, it was easy to figure out why none of the stars came back for the sequels. This movie certainly plays up the eye candy angle, with two of the most beautiful women in Hollywood, and at first glance, it seems like it's going to be a pretty good film, but then the twists and turns kick in. Throwing in a twist can make an ordinary film spectacular, but when you do it every five minutes, it just confuses the hell out of the audience, and that's what happened here. By the end of Wild Things, I didn't know what the hell was going on anymore. As for the performances, they range from the brilliant Neve Campbell to the horrid Matt Dillon, and feature a ton of cameos in-between. I wanted to like this movie, there are some very good looking people, who like to take their cloths off, and that does tend to help you focus more, but the question is what are we focusing on? I concluded that there really isn't a reason to watch two hours of pure garbage, when you can find all the naked celebrity pictures you could ever want, in five minutes online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie but damn strange way to play it through.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really don't know what to think about this movie after watching it. On one hand I really enjoyed all the actors and actresses in it and it had a great story and beginning but as the movie went on and after about 300 twists later I find the movie to be just getting silly but it did come through in the end and wrap everything up nicely. This movie is about a teacher who is accused by two of his young students of rape. They take him to court and make a case agaisnt him but everything is not as it seems. This movie was really good I just feel it did not need to get so silly and overdone exspecially near the end. The twists were no longer a surprise because they happened so often all you expected was another one but other then that good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things, you make my heart sing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tawdry tale of sex, murder, money and betrayal, John McNaughton's neo-noir Wild Things comes across like a gloriously trashy blend of Body Heat and Cruel Intentions, only with bigger boobs and a greater degree of salacious Sapphic snogging. The film has more outrageous twists and turns than a worm at a zumba workoutno-one is who they seem to be, everyone is looking out for number one, and there are no depths to which the characters won't sink in order to achieve their goalsbut director McNaughton copes admirably with the movie's many Machiavellian machinations, adeptly juggling the complex script's many plot threads whilst still ensuring that matters move at a reasonably brisk pace. A superb ensemble cast also helps to make this a hugely entertaining time-waster, the acting talent including Matt Dillon, Kevin Bacon, Robert Wagner, Bill Murray, Theresa Russell, Neve Campbell and, last but not least, Denise Richards, who admittedly couldn't act her way out of a soggy paper bag, but who at least helps make good on the film's promise of some serious sexiness: she's soaked whilst washing a car, goes topless during a drunken threesome, flaunts herself in slow motion wearing a semi-translucent swimsuit, and gets it on with Campbell in a swimming pool. 7.5 out of 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Bacon, Matt Dillon, Neve Campbell, Denise Richards, Theresa Russell, Daphne Rubin-Vega, Robert Wagner and Bill Murray star in this 1998 thriller. A money-making plot erupts when a high school guidance counselor is accused of rape. This takes place in Blue Bay, Florida where we meet Sam Lombardo (Dillon), a mild-mannered guidance counselor and sailboat instructor who is soon accused of raping students, Kelly Van Ryan (Richards) and Suzie Toller (Campbell). Bacon plays police detective, Ray Duquette who investigates the case and learns there may be a plot to get money from Kelly's wealthy mother, Sandra Van Ryan (Russell). Vega plays Ray's partner, Gloria Perez, Wagner plays the Van Ryan's lawyer, Tom Baxter and Murray plays Sam's lawyer, Ken Bowden. This is a pretty good thriller with a good cast and some neat twists that I recommend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intriguing, Humorous & Outrageously Twisted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This highly entertaining sleaze-fest features gratuitous nudity, bi-sexuality and a m&eacute;nage-a-trois which all seem to have been included purely to spice things up. It's also, however, a glossy thriller with an extremely well written plot that's intriguing, humorous and outrageously twisted. Remarkably, by the time all the explanatory flashbacks (which are included with the closing credits) have finished, it's also evident that the whole thing makes sense. Greed, betrayal and murder are the story's main ingredients but the sheer wickedness of its characters and the movie's satirical qualities also combine well to ensure that "Wild Things" compares favourably to most other crime-related mysteries that may be on offer. Kelly Van Ryan (Denise Richards) is a spoilt, 17-year-old rich girl who lives in Blue Bay, Florida. She's used to getting everything she wants but when she sets her sights on her High School guidance counsellor, Sam Lombardo (Matt Dillon), things don't fall into place as easily as she expects and she accuses him of rape. Local police detectives Ray Duquette (Kevin Bacon) and Gloria Perez (Daphne Rubin-Vega) are charged with the responsibility of investigating the alleged crime and Perez is certainly not convinced that there is any substance in Kelly's accusation. When another girl, Suzie Toller (Neve Campbell) also comes forward and makes a similar accusation, Sam Lombardo is arrested and hires lawyer Kenneth Bowden (Bill Murray) to defend him. Kelly's mother Sandra (Theresa Russell) is very wealthy and powerful and also one of Sam's ex-lovers. She's delighted to use the situation to try to ruin Sam but after the case against him collapses in bizarre circumstances and Lombardo is awarded a multi-million dollar settlement for defamation of character, Sandra Van Ryan is left furious and humiliated and looking for revenge. The course that the story takes from this point on is full of twists and double-crosses that keep on coming until the movie eventually ends with the most surprising development of them all. The characters in "Wild Things" include the very rich and the very poor as well as people who are employed in the legal profession, education and law enforcement. What they all have in common is that they're all morally bankrupt and most of them are criminals. The way in which they're represented on-screen is brilliant as the acting is pitched at just the right amount over-the-top to exploit the absurdity and humour of so many of the situations without allowing the impact of the more scandalous and wicked goings-on to be diminished in any way. In this respect, the entire cast is top-notch but Bill Murray does particularly well as a shyster lawyer who enjoys a good insurance scam but is also smarter than he first appears to be. "Wild Things" is beautifully filmed and some passages of the score wouldn't have seemed out of place in "Twin Peaks". It's tremendous fun to watch and very rewarding because it delivers so much more that it initially seems to promise.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sex is the only real reason to watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maziun
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    *SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS*SPOILERS "Wild things" is a trash entertainment , but an enjoyable entertainment . It isn't great on any kind of level . Still , it provides a quite decent entertainment for nearly 2 hours. It's better than most of the movies in its genre - erotic thriller (not that the genre has about 2 really good movies in it , while the rest is basically a straight-to-video/DVD crap. The best thing about "Wild things" is sex. We have three hot ladies here  Denise Richards , Neve Campbell and Theresa Russell . Not that the men are ugly , hell no , after all we have here Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon. I can assure you that at some point in the movie you will see everyone of them in some state of undress. "WD" also has some great sex scenes  the lesbian scene at the pool and great threesome between two ladies and one man . The threesome is one of my favorite and most arousing movie scenes EVER. The screenplay by Stephen Peters isn't exactly a brilliant one . It feels like a story from one of those pulp magazines that inspired Quentin Tarantino to make "Pulp fiction". I was able to figure out most of the twists and connections between characters before the movie presented them to the audience . Yet there was some inspired stuff here  the teeth , the lovely "behind the scenes" ending credits and Bill Murray's part in the story (!). John McNaughton directs the sex scenes very nicely . Atmospheric score by George S. Clinton certainly helps him. On the other hand he tries to hide the surprises from the audience in a too obvious way  for example if you didn't saw Dillon raping Richards or the fight between Bacon and Richards it means that the truth is completely different than what movie is trying to suggest you. Denise Richards is watchable here . Her body does most of the acting . Neve Campbell is really solid as the naughty girl , same as Kevin Bacon as FBI agent. Matt Dillon isn't bad , but the way he acts makes it obvious for the audience that he isn't exactly a good guy as the movie tries to present him . Theresa Russell is quite good as the rich and powerful Sandra Van Ryan. I was surprised by Bill Murray who gives a very funny performance as the tricky lawyer. It's obviously the best movie of the franchise . Not really a quality movie , but if you will low your expectations you probably will have fun with this popcorn thriller. I give it 5/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Thing, You Make My Heart Sing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The Squeerelist
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This thriller has been one of my favorite movies as long as I can remember. As a kid, this was my go-to flick on any given Sunday. I know this is not a film for children, but what can I say... I was already unusual. A high school guidance counselor (Matt Dillon) is accused of rape by 2 of his students (Denise Richards & Neve Campbell)... The twisted storyline is set in the dreamy Floridian surroundings. For those who haven't been to Florida, it makes you want to discover this bit of paradise. For those who have, it just really makes you miss it. The lascivious original score smells like the Everglades and releases an intriguing scent wherever it infiltrates. Wild Things takes you out on a yacht, or makes you visit the gators (this film seriously makes me think of a typical Florida tourism brochure). The end will blow you away for sure. The cast is eclectic and brilliant (Kevin Bacon is an incredible dirty cop and the 2 main female leads are gorgeous and dangerously manipulative). The sex scenes are audacious and necessary to the plot. The film mixes humor (you can't escape it with Bill Murray in the cast) and seriousness which makes it a perfect combo. Wild Things is a great thriller, a sexy 90s classic! 1 reason to watch: the scene with Denise washing Matt's car to Lauren Christy's song I Want What I Want Read it here: http://squeerelist.blogspot.com/2013/06/wild-things- 1998.html
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things- Wild is the Wind? ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The classic tale of wealth, greed, conspiracy, mistrust and the eventual downfall of so many people all mark this 1998 thriller film. The problem with the movie is that there are too many plot twists here. Yes, they're very interesting, but after a while, it becomes who is doing what to whom. Honesty and integrity have all but fallen through the cracks here. Never underestimate the one most deviant. She or he may very well have a brain after-all. Robert Wagner is completely wasted here in a bit part of the rich girl's step-father. He is about the only one really not involved with what is going on here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twist-a-minute thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember when WILD THINGS came out on first release; for some reason, it never appealed to me. Back then I only cared about horror films like SCREAM, and this sleazy-looking thriller didn't have what it took to whet my appetite back then. Fourteen years later my tastes have broadened a great deal, so I decided to check it out. WILD THINGS turns out to be a real thrill-ride of a film, and that's all down to Stephen Peters' script, which is tremendous. It packs more genuinely surprising twists into its running time than half a dozen other Hollywood thrillers, and you can never predict where it's about to go next. An ensemble cast of actors known for appearances in sometimes-trashy cinema adds to the appeal. Matt Dillon does well balancing a difficult leading role, and Kevin Bacon has fun as a hard-ass cop, riffing on a role he must have played dozens of times during his career. Denise Richards, too, appears to be having a good time, trading on her cheerleader looks to decent effect, though Neve Campbell can't seem to shift her SCREAM-style goody two-shoes persona. Watch out for decent production values, slick direction from John McNaughton (HENRY: PORTRAIT OF A SERIAL KILLER) and a wicked supporting role for Bill Murray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Men fare better than females
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    guil fisher (guilfisher@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For certainly Kevin Bacon and Matt Dillon walk off with the film. The two empty headed females in question are Neve Campbell and Denise Richards. Both of which I found boring and so predictable in their over acted performances. But then we are graced with some real professional women in the likes of Theresa Russell and Carrie Snodgress. Unfortunately they aren't in it long enough to count. Also Bill Murray in a cameo performance. I thought the plot was stupid and can't understand why no one caught on to Campbell's witchery. Or should I say bitchery. Wearing unflattering wigs, one wonders what her real hair was like. The author of this piece of junk (and I'm being polite) was out to lunch. The ending will find most viewers sick at the sight of the fem fa-tale (if you really want to call her that) sailing off into the sunset having killed someone and getting away with it. I guess the code of decency doesn't exist anymore and we continue to make films of violence letting the killers get away with their dirty deeds. Maybe that is why there is so much crime and violence in this world. I give it 2 and a half stars for Bacon, Dillon and supporting cast.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Ultimate Movie Review! - http://tss5078.blogspot.com - @tss5078
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tss5078
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For years, people have been talking to me about this smart, sexy thriller, that spawned three sequels. There is also something to be said for mysteries, with twists and turns, that make you think, but a half hour into this thing, it was easy to figure out why none of the stars came back for the sequels. This movie certainly plays up the eye candy angle, with two of the most beautiful women in Hollywood, and at first glance, it seems like it's going to be a pretty good film, but then the twists and turns kick in. Throwing in a twist can make an ordinary film spectacular, but when you do it every five minutes, it just confuses the hell out of the audience, and that's what happened here. By the end of Wild Things, I didn't know what the hell was going on anymore. As for the performances, they range from the brilliant Neve Campbell to the horrid Matt Dillon, and feature a ton of cameos in-between. I wanted to like this movie, there are some very good looking people, who like to take their cloths off, and that does tend to help you focus more, but the question is what are we focusing on? I concluded that there really isn't a reason to watch two hours of pure garbage, when you can find all the naked celebrity pictures you could ever want, in five minutes online.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good movie but damn strange way to play it through.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really don't know what to think about this movie after watching it. On one hand I really enjoyed all the actors and actresses in it and it had a great story and beginning but as the movie went on and after about 300 twists later I find the movie to be just getting silly but it did come through in the end and wrap everything up nicely. This movie is about a teacher who is accused by two of his young students of rape. They take him to court and make a case agaisnt him but everything is not as it seems. This movie was really good I just feel it did not need to get so silly and overdone exspecially near the end. The twists were no longer a surprise because they happened so often all you expected was another one but other then that good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wild Things, you make my heart sing.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tawdry tale of sex, murder, money and betrayal, John McNaughton's neo-noir Wild Things comes across like a gloriously trashy blend of Body Heat and Cruel Intentions, only with bigger boobs and a greater degree of salacious Sapphic snogging. The film has more outrageous twists and turns than a worm at a zumba workoutno-one is who they seem to be, everyone is looking out for number one, and there are no depths to which the characters won't sink in order to achieve their goalsbut director McNaughton copes admirably with the movie's many Machiavellian machinations, adeptly juggling the complex script's many plot threads whilst still ensuring that matters move at a reasonably brisk pace. A superb ensemble cast also helps to make this a hugely entertaining time-waster, the acting talent including Matt Dillon, Kevin Bacon, Robert Wagner, Bill Murray, Theresa Russell, Neve Campbell and, last but not least, Denise Richards, who admittedly couldn't act her way out of a soggy paper bag, but who at least helps make good on the film's promise of some serious sexiness: she's soaked whilst washing a car, goes topless during a drunken threesome, flaunts herself in slow motion wearing a semi-translucent swimsuit, and gets it on with Campbell in a swimming pool. 7.5 out of 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Pretty Good!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Bacon, Matt Dillon, Neve Campbell, Denise Richards, Theresa Russell, Daphne Rubin-Vega, Robert Wagner and Bill Murray star in this 1998 thriller. A money-making plot erupts when a high school guidance counselor is accused of rape. This takes place in Blue Bay, Florida where we meet Sam Lombardo (Dillon), a mild-mannered guidance counselor and sailboat instructor who is soon accused of raping students, Kelly Van Ryan (Richards) and Suzie Toller (Campbell). Bacon plays police detective, Ray Duquette who investigates the case and learns there may be a plot to get money from Kelly's wealthy mother, Sandra Van Ryan (Russell). Vega plays Ray's partner, Gloria Perez, Wagner plays the Van Ryan's lawyer, Tom Baxter and Murray plays Sam's lawyer, Ken Bowden. This is a pretty good thriller with a good cast and some neat twists that I recommend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
