<filme>
 <id>
  917
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120749
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1998
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  C&oacute;digo Para o Inferno
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Shadowy elements in the NSA target a nine-year old autistic savant for death when he is able to decipher a top secret code.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Bruce Willis is an outcast FBI agent who is assigned to protect a 9 year old autistic boy who is the target for assassins after cracking a top secret government code.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   nsa
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fbi
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   puzzle
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   assassin
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   9 year old
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Harold Becker
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ryne Douglas Pearson
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Lawrence Konner
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Bruce Willis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Miko Hughes
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Alec Baldwin
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unrealistic, slow thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) is the best FBI undercover agent. But a bad shootout leaves him an outcast. Then he gets the case of a missing autistic boy. The boy is an amazing puzzle solver, and was able to decipher a new NSA top secret code. Before anybody else knows the code has been cracked, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) wants the boy killed to protect all the secrets. The NSA part is over the top unbelievable. Sad to say, the autistic boy is a little bit annoying at times. Also it's hard to see how the cops can't figure out what happened at the hospital. The whole thing is a little thin. It's a passable thriller, but it's just too slow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of the road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unremarkable but moderately suspenseful thriller that mistakenly underplays the relationship between rogue FBI agent Bruce Willis and autistic kiddie Miko Hughes, who has cracked a top secret code and is now the target of villainous Alec Baldwin. The plot seems as though it was more intelligent somewhere in the script's journey to the screen, while characterisation is on the shallow side - 'Is that him or you you're talking about?' asks Willis's best friend. Hmm. I wonder... Willis seems to have cottoned on to this lack of depth, as he hasn't switched off the autopilot. I could have done without the scene in which a hit man stares Willis in the eye just long enough for him to be recognised before legging it, and the computery sound effect that helpfully clues us in whenever Hughes cracks the code is just annoying. Still, the movie is low-key enough that it remains plausible, it's technically slick, and the villain's demise is impressively fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like my cooking skills, fast and tasteless.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The NSA has developed what they think is an unbreakable code. They ran a test to see if anyone can decipher it by putting it in a puzzle magazine. Simon Lynch, an autistic boy, deciphers it and calls the NSA. The men in charge call their boss Kudrow, who is worried what might happen if this gets out, and orders Simon to be killed. The man he sends kills his parents and leaves when the police arrive. The FBI send Art Jeffries to look for the boy. Art finds Simon, and they go on the run...... In the nineties, Willis lost his star power a little, and every now and again, he starred in your typical generic action thriller. And like Striking Distance, Last Man Standing, and The Jackal, it's nothing special, but its a must for Willis fans. As always in these types of movies, it starts with a set-up, this one leading to a bit of a meltdown for Art. He's involved in a robbery gone wrong and would you know it, it ends in a boy getting killed, thus Art will stop at nothing to protect Simon. The rest of the film involves Willis and Hughes (who is excellent) on the run from your atypical assassin, with supporting characters getting killed every now and again, with only Chi McBride as a friend, as the police are after him too. Baldwin is fine, but its little more than an extended cameo, with the two stars only meeting the once. The ending is silly, but its a nice little thriller which won't challenge the brain, with a nice ending. Plus, this film must hold the record for how many people actually duck when the Amin hero cries 'get down'. It won't win Willis any more fans, but it does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a great film but a great performance by Miko Hughes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Love
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two great acting performances in this film. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries, an FBI agent with attitude. Miko Hughes plays Simon Lynch, an autistic savant with a gift for codebreaking. Both are believable but Miko Hughes is astonishing  one of the best ever screen performances by a child. The scenes between the pair of them are really touching and you can believe that Willis really likes kids. Perhaps he does. The US government's pursuit of Lynch in this film may at first appear overly far-fetched and scaremongering. Then you remember the US attitude towards the British savant, Gary McKinnon, who was accused of perpetrating the biggest military computer hack of all time by hacking into 97 US military and NASA computers in 2002. Well, they didn't kill his mum and dad, and hunt him like an animal. But after 10 years of attempted extradition, and speculation of a 70-year jail term, maybe this story is just an exaggeration of reality, and not quite as ridiculous as some commentators have suggested. It's not really a downside but if you come to this film expecting a shoot-em-up action movie, you may be disappointed. It's much more than that and consequently slower  it's a touching drama with action scenes, and so we can forgive, just about, the pace through the middle of the film. The writing is actually very good and Pearson, Konner and Rosenthal all deserve credit. I did find the score a bit distracting. Sort of 'too big' and too 'James Bond' for the film. Scenes without music were better. Though the music being played at the club Jeffries visits was really good and I would have liked to have heard more of Koko Taylor (now no longer with us) belting out some blues. I was finding it difficult to see where this film was going. When Wills is with a kid, like in 16 blocks or Die Hard 4, you expect a visible end point, and there wasn't one. There was a sense of going around in circles. Until the last 5 minutes. Ultimately that cost it a couple of stars and the score lost another one. So seven out of ten for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    surely better then a 5.6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is nothing special but it surely worth more then a measly 5.6. The acting is good and the idea is new and original so I don't know why everyone hated it so much. It had a good story line and some decent action scenes so I was pleasantly surprised by this one. This movie is about a FBI agent who is sent to protect an autistic boy who is a target of assassins after accidentally cracking a top secret government code. I don't know why everybody hated this movie so much I actually thought it was pretty good. It was nothing special but in my eyes it was worth a watch no doubt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Gunston
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed this film and have found it equally watchable on repeated viewings. From the opening scene of a helicopter making its way towards a rural town accompanied by Barry's soulful music you just know that you are in for a rewarding movie experience. What elevates a routine and slightly clich&eacute;d thriller into a tense and emotionally satisfying film is the sensitive direction of Harold Becker, spot on casting, a story with emotional depth and John Barrys great score. Bruce Willis is ideally cast as the loner working against the system. The interaction between him and Miko Hughes as the autistic child Simon feels authentic. There is real chemistry in the exchanges between the 3 computer nerds who work for the NSA. And the scenes between Simon and his parents carry real emotional weight. This is not an action film. It is a film about story and character, and in some ways that makes it an old fashioned movie and all the better for it. It does, however, maintain tension through most of it's running time, a characteristic which is becoming rarer in modern films. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Your eyes see, but they do not observe, "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The novel 'Simple Simon' was written by Ryne Pearson and easily transferred to the silver screen, where it was directed expertly by Harold Becker. The movie tells the story of an autistic boy named Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who incredibly is able to decipher a top secret code created by the N.S.A. When the secret is uncovered, the top executive, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) believes his network of undercover agents and their identifies are in danger of being compromised and therefor orders a top assassin to execute Simon and his parents. The only defense for the boy is Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) a burned-out F.B.I agent who despite his short-comings is a tough-as-nails individual who learns Simon is a very special child and soon bonds with him. Along the way and amid the encroaching danger Jeffries receives help from Stacey a coffee shop patron (Kim Dickens) and fellow FBI agent Tommy B. Jordan (Chi McBride) The film is a combination of intrigue, murder and suspense with excitement filling in all the gaps. Willis and Hughes give a heartwarming and endearing performance. Recommended. ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really like this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsmemark47
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see the terrible reviews it got from some "important" reviewers. I'm watching it for at least the 4th time, just recorded it from satellite TV. Bruce Willis is really fine in this...I think few people appreciated how complex and skilled he is before this release, and I'm very glad they chose him for this role. Baldwin and the entire cast is very good and despite the not uncommon plot elements, the whole thing succeeds. Since the "Patriot Act" went into effect, I can give the actions of the government in this film a lot more credence...I rate it as an 8 out of 10, and I have seen extremely few 10's. mark
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was Bruce Willis at his finest. Although Mercury Rising was financially not well received, the film is a terrific thriller, solid acting, great story and just all around entertaining! One reviewer said this was more of a drama about autism and that's ludicrous. This is a thriller about a young boy who happens to have autism but to call this a drama or about autism at all is misleading. The film is part mystery, part thriller, part action and will entertain from beginning to end. Powerful performances from the lead cast make it worthwhile and riveting. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries and does a great job doing what he does best. No this isn't an award worthy performance or anything outstanding for Willis but he still carries the film well and Willis fans, like myself, will remember this. The star and stand out performance of this film is Miko Hughes who brilliantly plays autistic puzzle solver Simon. His performance is award worthy and I've always remembered it as one of my favorite performances. His chemistry with Willis is brilliant. Robert Stanton deserves mention in a small but pivotal role that I really enjoyed him in. Same could be said for Chi McBride who also does a good job. Alec Baldwin is good in his role as the villain. I would have liked a little more chemistry between him and Willis and I don't think he was outstanding in his role but he was definitely good. Kim Dickens is the female lead in the film and she does alright although I found her character very one dimensional for the most part. Harold Becker's direction is perhaps a little bland from time to time. It is true what some reviewers say that the film could have used just a little more action and some of the performances felt dry at times from Baldwin and Dickens, who are important to the entire film in many ways. Still the concept for the film is riveting and the story is delivered in a well paced, entertaining fashion. Anyone looking for a good thriller will not be steered wrong with this film. Its a movie that I watch from time to time again and again because I've always thought it was a great movie. Plenty of thrills, plenty of edge of your seat moments and a terrific performance from Hughes. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yet another disappointing action flick - 59%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For reasons that I can't explain, this has been on my "Must See" list for ages. I really don't know why - Bruce Willis action movies aren't exactly rare beasts and at some point, I figured that this had a plot that offered something a little different. Sadly, it turns out that it really wasn't worth the wait. It lacks the bluster of your usual Willis blockbuster and the story that I had high hopes for quickly finds itself becoming a gimmick. Willis plays FBI agent Art Jeffries, an undercover specialist who finds himself demoted to monitoring radio transmissions after a botched hostage assignment. However, he quickly finds himself assigned to look for a missing child - Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who is an autistic nine-year orphaned after his parents are murdered. But Art quickly finds threat there is more to it than that - Simon had accidentally cracked a top secret code after it inexplicably appeared in the pages of a puzzle magazine and was being sought by NSA operatives led by the gravel-voiced Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) and his murderous colleague Peter Burrell (Lindsey Ginter). Being an odd hybrid of espionage thriller and fugitive actioner, "Mercury Rising" successfully manages to be neither. The action is satisfying enough when it turns arrive in fits and starts but there is an awful lot of dialogue to get through in-between. Willis can pretty much sleepwalk through these kinda movies and sure enough, he simply doesn't engage you enough to care. He's also completely shown up by his young co-star as Hughes is brilliantly and genuinely heart-wrenching as the tortured savant. However, the worst actor by far is Baldwin who seems to be eerily foreshadowing his portrayal in "Team America: World Police". At times, he's simply appalling as he mumbles his way through his lines as though paying tribute to Michael Madsen. Maybe it was he who distracted me from the story which seemed confusing and never really explained what was happening. For example, imagine you are an experienced FBI agent looking after an infant suspect. Would you happily hand the care of the child over to a complete stranger in a caf&eacute; (played here by Kim Dickins) while you popped off to meet an informant because I'm not sure I would. "Mercury Rising" is annoyingly wasteful of its promising set-up, failing to deliver either a decent action movie or a gripping chase flick. It seems curiously restrained, as though it can't be bothered to be the nail-biting gripper it seems to aspire to. Maybe I'm being harsh on it given how long I've waited to watch it but for me, "Mercury Rising" is just as generic and forgettable as any other Nineties action flick. Shame, shame, shame.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unrealistic, slow thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) is the best FBI undercover agent. But a bad shootout leaves him an outcast. Then he gets the case of a missing autistic boy. The boy is an amazing puzzle solver, and was able to decipher a new NSA top secret code. Before anybody else knows the code has been cracked, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) wants the boy killed to protect all the secrets. The NSA part is over the top unbelievable. Sad to say, the autistic boy is a little bit annoying at times. Also it's hard to see how the cops can't figure out what happened at the hospital. The whole thing is a little thin. It's a passable thriller, but it's just too slow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of the road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unremarkable but moderately suspenseful thriller that mistakenly underplays the relationship between rogue FBI agent Bruce Willis and autistic kiddie Miko Hughes, who has cracked a top secret code and is now the target of villainous Alec Baldwin. The plot seems as though it was more intelligent somewhere in the script's journey to the screen, while characterisation is on the shallow side - 'Is that him or you you're talking about?' asks Willis's best friend. Hmm. I wonder... Willis seems to have cottoned on to this lack of depth, as he hasn't switched off the autopilot. I could have done without the scene in which a hit man stares Willis in the eye just long enough for him to be recognised before legging it, and the computery sound effect that helpfully clues us in whenever Hughes cracks the code is just annoying. Still, the movie is low-key enough that it remains plausible, it's technically slick, and the villain's demise is impressively fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like my cooking skills, fast and tasteless.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The NSA has developed what they think is an unbreakable code. They ran a test to see if anyone can decipher it by putting it in a puzzle magazine. Simon Lynch, an autistic boy, deciphers it and calls the NSA. The men in charge call their boss Kudrow, who is worried what might happen if this gets out, and orders Simon to be killed. The man he sends kills his parents and leaves when the police arrive. The FBI send Art Jeffries to look for the boy. Art finds Simon, and they go on the run...... In the nineties, Willis lost his star power a little, and every now and again, he starred in your typical generic action thriller. And like Striking Distance, Last Man Standing, and The Jackal, it's nothing special, but its a must for Willis fans. As always in these types of movies, it starts with a set-up, this one leading to a bit of a meltdown for Art. He's involved in a robbery gone wrong and would you know it, it ends in a boy getting killed, thus Art will stop at nothing to protect Simon. The rest of the film involves Willis and Hughes (who is excellent) on the run from your atypical assassin, with supporting characters getting killed every now and again, with only Chi McBride as a friend, as the police are after him too. Baldwin is fine, but its little more than an extended cameo, with the two stars only meeting the once. The ending is silly, but its a nice little thriller which won't challenge the brain, with a nice ending. Plus, this film must hold the record for how many people actually duck when the Amin hero cries 'get down'. It won't win Willis any more fans, but it does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a great film but a great performance by Miko Hughes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Love
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two great acting performances in this film. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries, an FBI agent with attitude. Miko Hughes plays Simon Lynch, an autistic savant with a gift for codebreaking. Both are believable but Miko Hughes is astonishing  one of the best ever screen performances by a child. The scenes between the pair of them are really touching and you can believe that Willis really likes kids. Perhaps he does. The US government's pursuit of Lynch in this film may at first appear overly far-fetched and scaremongering. Then you remember the US attitude towards the British savant, Gary McKinnon, who was accused of perpetrating the biggest military computer hack of all time by hacking into 97 US military and NASA computers in 2002. Well, they didn't kill his mum and dad, and hunt him like an animal. But after 10 years of attempted extradition, and speculation of a 70-year jail term, maybe this story is just an exaggeration of reality, and not quite as ridiculous as some commentators have suggested. It's not really a downside but if you come to this film expecting a shoot-em-up action movie, you may be disappointed. It's much more than that and consequently slower  it's a touching drama with action scenes, and so we can forgive, just about, the pace through the middle of the film. The writing is actually very good and Pearson, Konner and Rosenthal all deserve credit. I did find the score a bit distracting. Sort of 'too big' and too 'James Bond' for the film. Scenes without music were better. Though the music being played at the club Jeffries visits was really good and I would have liked to have heard more of Koko Taylor (now no longer with us) belting out some blues. I was finding it difficult to see where this film was going. When Wills is with a kid, like in 16 blocks or Die Hard 4, you expect a visible end point, and there wasn't one. There was a sense of going around in circles. Until the last 5 minutes. Ultimately that cost it a couple of stars and the score lost another one. So seven out of ten for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    surely better then a 5.6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is nothing special but it surely worth more then a measly 5.6. The acting is good and the idea is new and original so I don't know why everyone hated it so much. It had a good story line and some decent action scenes so I was pleasantly surprised by this one. This movie is about a FBI agent who is sent to protect an autistic boy who is a target of assassins after accidentally cracking a top secret government code. I don't know why everybody hated this movie so much I actually thought it was pretty good. It was nothing special but in my eyes it was worth a watch no doubt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Gunston
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed this film and have found it equally watchable on repeated viewings. From the opening scene of a helicopter making its way towards a rural town accompanied by Barry's soulful music you just know that you are in for a rewarding movie experience. What elevates a routine and slightly clich&eacute;d thriller into a tense and emotionally satisfying film is the sensitive direction of Harold Becker, spot on casting, a story with emotional depth and John Barrys great score. Bruce Willis is ideally cast as the loner working against the system. The interaction between him and Miko Hughes as the autistic child Simon feels authentic. There is real chemistry in the exchanges between the 3 computer nerds who work for the NSA. And the scenes between Simon and his parents carry real emotional weight. This is not an action film. It is a film about story and character, and in some ways that makes it an old fashioned movie and all the better for it. It does, however, maintain tension through most of it's running time, a characteristic which is becoming rarer in modern films. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Your eyes see, but they do not observe, "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The novel 'Simple Simon' was written by Ryne Pearson and easily transferred to the silver screen, where it was directed expertly by Harold Becker. The movie tells the story of an autistic boy named Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who incredibly is able to decipher a top secret code created by the N.S.A. When the secret is uncovered, the top executive, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) believes his network of undercover agents and their identifies are in danger of being compromised and therefor orders a top assassin to execute Simon and his parents. The only defense for the boy is Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) a burned-out F.B.I agent who despite his short-comings is a tough-as-nails individual who learns Simon is a very special child and soon bonds with him. Along the way and amid the encroaching danger Jeffries receives help from Stacey a coffee shop patron (Kim Dickens) and fellow FBI agent Tommy B. Jordan (Chi McBride) The film is a combination of intrigue, murder and suspense with excitement filling in all the gaps. Willis and Hughes give a heartwarming and endearing performance. Recommended. ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really like this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsmemark47
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see the terrible reviews it got from some "important" reviewers. I'm watching it for at least the 4th time, just recorded it from satellite TV. Bruce Willis is really fine in this...I think few people appreciated how complex and skilled he is before this release, and I'm very glad they chose him for this role. Baldwin and the entire cast is very good and despite the not uncommon plot elements, the whole thing succeeds. Since the "Patriot Act" went into effect, I can give the actions of the government in this film a lot more credence...I rate it as an 8 out of 10, and I have seen extremely few 10's. mark
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was Bruce Willis at his finest. Although Mercury Rising was financially not well received, the film is a terrific thriller, solid acting, great story and just all around entertaining! One reviewer said this was more of a drama about autism and that's ludicrous. This is a thriller about a young boy who happens to have autism but to call this a drama or about autism at all is misleading. The film is part mystery, part thriller, part action and will entertain from beginning to end. Powerful performances from the lead cast make it worthwhile and riveting. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries and does a great job doing what he does best. No this isn't an award worthy performance or anything outstanding for Willis but he still carries the film well and Willis fans, like myself, will remember this. The star and stand out performance of this film is Miko Hughes who brilliantly plays autistic puzzle solver Simon. His performance is award worthy and I've always remembered it as one of my favorite performances. His chemistry with Willis is brilliant. Robert Stanton deserves mention in a small but pivotal role that I really enjoyed him in. Same could be said for Chi McBride who also does a good job. Alec Baldwin is good in his role as the villain. I would have liked a little more chemistry between him and Willis and I don't think he was outstanding in his role but he was definitely good. Kim Dickens is the female lead in the film and she does alright although I found her character very one dimensional for the most part. Harold Becker's direction is perhaps a little bland from time to time. It is true what some reviewers say that the film could have used just a little more action and some of the performances felt dry at times from Baldwin and Dickens, who are important to the entire film in many ways. Still the concept for the film is riveting and the story is delivered in a well paced, entertaining fashion. Anyone looking for a good thriller will not be steered wrong with this film. Its a movie that I watch from time to time again and again because I've always thought it was a great movie. Plenty of thrills, plenty of edge of your seat moments and a terrific performance from Hughes. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yet another disappointing action flick - 59%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For reasons that I can't explain, this has been on my "Must See" list for ages. I really don't know why - Bruce Willis action movies aren't exactly rare beasts and at some point, I figured that this had a plot that offered something a little different. Sadly, it turns out that it really wasn't worth the wait. It lacks the bluster of your usual Willis blockbuster and the story that I had high hopes for quickly finds itself becoming a gimmick. Willis plays FBI agent Art Jeffries, an undercover specialist who finds himself demoted to monitoring radio transmissions after a botched hostage assignment. However, he quickly finds himself assigned to look for a missing child - Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who is an autistic nine-year orphaned after his parents are murdered. But Art quickly finds threat there is more to it than that - Simon had accidentally cracked a top secret code after it inexplicably appeared in the pages of a puzzle magazine and was being sought by NSA operatives led by the gravel-voiced Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) and his murderous colleague Peter Burrell (Lindsey Ginter). Being an odd hybrid of espionage thriller and fugitive actioner, "Mercury Rising" successfully manages to be neither. The action is satisfying enough when it turns arrive in fits and starts but there is an awful lot of dialogue to get through in-between. Willis can pretty much sleepwalk through these kinda movies and sure enough, he simply doesn't engage you enough to care. He's also completely shown up by his young co-star as Hughes is brilliantly and genuinely heart-wrenching as the tortured savant. However, the worst actor by far is Baldwin who seems to be eerily foreshadowing his portrayal in "Team America: World Police". At times, he's simply appalling as he mumbles his way through his lines as though paying tribute to Michael Madsen. Maybe it was he who distracted me from the story which seemed confusing and never really explained what was happening. For example, imagine you are an experienced FBI agent looking after an infant suspect. Would you happily hand the care of the child over to a complete stranger in a caf&eacute; (played here by Kim Dickins) while you popped off to meet an informant because I'm not sure I would. "Mercury Rising" is annoyingly wasteful of its promising set-up, failing to deliver either a decent action movie or a gripping chase flick. It seems curiously restrained, as though it can't be bothered to be the nail-biting gripper it seems to aspire to. Maybe I'm being harsh on it given how long I've waited to watch it but for me, "Mercury Rising" is just as generic and forgettable as any other Nineties action flick. Shame, shame, shame.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unrealistic, slow thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) is the best FBI undercover agent. But a bad shootout leaves him an outcast. Then he gets the case of a missing autistic boy. The boy is an amazing puzzle solver, and was able to decipher a new NSA top secret code. Before anybody else knows the code has been cracked, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) wants the boy killed to protect all the secrets. The NSA part is over the top unbelievable. Sad to say, the autistic boy is a little bit annoying at times. Also it's hard to see how the cops can't figure out what happened at the hospital. The whole thing is a little thin. It's a passable thriller, but it's just too slow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of the road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unremarkable but moderately suspenseful thriller that mistakenly underplays the relationship between rogue FBI agent Bruce Willis and autistic kiddie Miko Hughes, who has cracked a top secret code and is now the target of villainous Alec Baldwin. The plot seems as though it was more intelligent somewhere in the script's journey to the screen, while characterisation is on the shallow side - 'Is that him or you you're talking about?' asks Willis's best friend. Hmm. I wonder... Willis seems to have cottoned on to this lack of depth, as he hasn't switched off the autopilot. I could have done without the scene in which a hit man stares Willis in the eye just long enough for him to be recognised before legging it, and the computery sound effect that helpfully clues us in whenever Hughes cracks the code is just annoying. Still, the movie is low-key enough that it remains plausible, it's technically slick, and the villain's demise is impressively fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like my cooking skills, fast and tasteless.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The NSA has developed what they think is an unbreakable code. They ran a test to see if anyone can decipher it by putting it in a puzzle magazine. Simon Lynch, an autistic boy, deciphers it and calls the NSA. The men in charge call their boss Kudrow, who is worried what might happen if this gets out, and orders Simon to be killed. The man he sends kills his parents and leaves when the police arrive. The FBI send Art Jeffries to look for the boy. Art finds Simon, and they go on the run...... In the nineties, Willis lost his star power a little, and every now and again, he starred in your typical generic action thriller. And like Striking Distance, Last Man Standing, and The Jackal, it's nothing special, but its a must for Willis fans. As always in these types of movies, it starts with a set-up, this one leading to a bit of a meltdown for Art. He's involved in a robbery gone wrong and would you know it, it ends in a boy getting killed, thus Art will stop at nothing to protect Simon. The rest of the film involves Willis and Hughes (who is excellent) on the run from your atypical assassin, with supporting characters getting killed every now and again, with only Chi McBride as a friend, as the police are after him too. Baldwin is fine, but its little more than an extended cameo, with the two stars only meeting the once. The ending is silly, but its a nice little thriller which won't challenge the brain, with a nice ending. Plus, this film must hold the record for how many people actually duck when the Amin hero cries 'get down'. It won't win Willis any more fans, but it does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a great film but a great performance by Miko Hughes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Love
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two great acting performances in this film. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries, an FBI agent with attitude. Miko Hughes plays Simon Lynch, an autistic savant with a gift for codebreaking. Both are believable but Miko Hughes is astonishing  one of the best ever screen performances by a child. The scenes between the pair of them are really touching and you can believe that Willis really likes kids. Perhaps he does. The US government's pursuit of Lynch in this film may at first appear overly far-fetched and scaremongering. Then you remember the US attitude towards the British savant, Gary McKinnon, who was accused of perpetrating the biggest military computer hack of all time by hacking into 97 US military and NASA computers in 2002. Well, they didn't kill his mum and dad, and hunt him like an animal. But after 10 years of attempted extradition, and speculation of a 70-year jail term, maybe this story is just an exaggeration of reality, and not quite as ridiculous as some commentators have suggested. It's not really a downside but if you come to this film expecting a shoot-em-up action movie, you may be disappointed. It's much more than that and consequently slower  it's a touching drama with action scenes, and so we can forgive, just about, the pace through the middle of the film. The writing is actually very good and Pearson, Konner and Rosenthal all deserve credit. I did find the score a bit distracting. Sort of 'too big' and too 'James Bond' for the film. Scenes without music were better. Though the music being played at the club Jeffries visits was really good and I would have liked to have heard more of Koko Taylor (now no longer with us) belting out some blues. I was finding it difficult to see where this film was going. When Wills is with a kid, like in 16 blocks or Die Hard 4, you expect a visible end point, and there wasn't one. There was a sense of going around in circles. Until the last 5 minutes. Ultimately that cost it a couple of stars and the score lost another one. So seven out of ten for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    surely better then a 5.6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is nothing special but it surely worth more then a measly 5.6. The acting is good and the idea is new and original so I don't know why everyone hated it so much. It had a good story line and some decent action scenes so I was pleasantly surprised by this one. This movie is about a FBI agent who is sent to protect an autistic boy who is a target of assassins after accidentally cracking a top secret government code. I don't know why everybody hated this movie so much I actually thought it was pretty good. It was nothing special but in my eyes it was worth a watch no doubt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Gunston
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed this film and have found it equally watchable on repeated viewings. From the opening scene of a helicopter making its way towards a rural town accompanied by Barry's soulful music you just know that you are in for a rewarding movie experience. What elevates a routine and slightly clich&eacute;d thriller into a tense and emotionally satisfying film is the sensitive direction of Harold Becker, spot on casting, a story with emotional depth and John Barrys great score. Bruce Willis is ideally cast as the loner working against the system. The interaction between him and Miko Hughes as the autistic child Simon feels authentic. There is real chemistry in the exchanges between the 3 computer nerds who work for the NSA. And the scenes between Simon and his parents carry real emotional weight. This is not an action film. It is a film about story and character, and in some ways that makes it an old fashioned movie and all the better for it. It does, however, maintain tension through most of it's running time, a characteristic which is becoming rarer in modern films. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Your eyes see, but they do not observe, "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The novel 'Simple Simon' was written by Ryne Pearson and easily transferred to the silver screen, where it was directed expertly by Harold Becker. The movie tells the story of an autistic boy named Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who incredibly is able to decipher a top secret code created by the N.S.A. When the secret is uncovered, the top executive, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) believes his network of undercover agents and their identifies are in danger of being compromised and therefor orders a top assassin to execute Simon and his parents. The only defense for the boy is Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) a burned-out F.B.I agent who despite his short-comings is a tough-as-nails individual who learns Simon is a very special child and soon bonds with him. Along the way and amid the encroaching danger Jeffries receives help from Stacey a coffee shop patron (Kim Dickens) and fellow FBI agent Tommy B. Jordan (Chi McBride) The film is a combination of intrigue, murder and suspense with excitement filling in all the gaps. Willis and Hughes give a heartwarming and endearing performance. Recommended. ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really like this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsmemark47
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see the terrible reviews it got from some "important" reviewers. I'm watching it for at least the 4th time, just recorded it from satellite TV. Bruce Willis is really fine in this...I think few people appreciated how complex and skilled he is before this release, and I'm very glad they chose him for this role. Baldwin and the entire cast is very good and despite the not uncommon plot elements, the whole thing succeeds. Since the "Patriot Act" went into effect, I can give the actions of the government in this film a lot more credence...I rate it as an 8 out of 10, and I have seen extremely few 10's. mark
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was Bruce Willis at his finest. Although Mercury Rising was financially not well received, the film is a terrific thriller, solid acting, great story and just all around entertaining! One reviewer said this was more of a drama about autism and that's ludicrous. This is a thriller about a young boy who happens to have autism but to call this a drama or about autism at all is misleading. The film is part mystery, part thriller, part action and will entertain from beginning to end. Powerful performances from the lead cast make it worthwhile and riveting. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries and does a great job doing what he does best. No this isn't an award worthy performance or anything outstanding for Willis but he still carries the film well and Willis fans, like myself, will remember this. The star and stand out performance of this film is Miko Hughes who brilliantly plays autistic puzzle solver Simon. His performance is award worthy and I've always remembered it as one of my favorite performances. His chemistry with Willis is brilliant. Robert Stanton deserves mention in a small but pivotal role that I really enjoyed him in. Same could be said for Chi McBride who also does a good job. Alec Baldwin is good in his role as the villain. I would have liked a little more chemistry between him and Willis and I don't think he was outstanding in his role but he was definitely good. Kim Dickens is the female lead in the film and she does alright although I found her character very one dimensional for the most part. Harold Becker's direction is perhaps a little bland from time to time. It is true what some reviewers say that the film could have used just a little more action and some of the performances felt dry at times from Baldwin and Dickens, who are important to the entire film in many ways. Still the concept for the film is riveting and the story is delivered in a well paced, entertaining fashion. Anyone looking for a good thriller will not be steered wrong with this film. Its a movie that I watch from time to time again and again because I've always thought it was a great movie. Plenty of thrills, plenty of edge of your seat moments and a terrific performance from Hughes. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yet another disappointing action flick - 59%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For reasons that I can't explain, this has been on my "Must See" list for ages. I really don't know why - Bruce Willis action movies aren't exactly rare beasts and at some point, I figured that this had a plot that offered something a little different. Sadly, it turns out that it really wasn't worth the wait. It lacks the bluster of your usual Willis blockbuster and the story that I had high hopes for quickly finds itself becoming a gimmick. Willis plays FBI agent Art Jeffries, an undercover specialist who finds himself demoted to monitoring radio transmissions after a botched hostage assignment. However, he quickly finds himself assigned to look for a missing child - Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who is an autistic nine-year orphaned after his parents are murdered. But Art quickly finds threat there is more to it than that - Simon had accidentally cracked a top secret code after it inexplicably appeared in the pages of a puzzle magazine and was being sought by NSA operatives led by the gravel-voiced Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) and his murderous colleague Peter Burrell (Lindsey Ginter). Being an odd hybrid of espionage thriller and fugitive actioner, "Mercury Rising" successfully manages to be neither. The action is satisfying enough when it turns arrive in fits and starts but there is an awful lot of dialogue to get through in-between. Willis can pretty much sleepwalk through these kinda movies and sure enough, he simply doesn't engage you enough to care. He's also completely shown up by his young co-star as Hughes is brilliantly and genuinely heart-wrenching as the tortured savant. However, the worst actor by far is Baldwin who seems to be eerily foreshadowing his portrayal in "Team America: World Police". At times, he's simply appalling as he mumbles his way through his lines as though paying tribute to Michael Madsen. Maybe it was he who distracted me from the story which seemed confusing and never really explained what was happening. For example, imagine you are an experienced FBI agent looking after an infant suspect. Would you happily hand the care of the child over to a complete stranger in a caf&eacute; (played here by Kim Dickins) while you popped off to meet an informant because I'm not sure I would. "Mercury Rising" is annoyingly wasteful of its promising set-up, failing to deliver either a decent action movie or a gripping chase flick. It seems curiously restrained, as though it can't be bothered to be the nail-biting gripper it seems to aspire to. Maybe I'm being harsh on it given how long I've waited to watch it but for me, "Mercury Rising" is just as generic and forgettable as any other Nineties action flick. Shame, shame, shame.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unrealistic, slow thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) is the best FBI undercover agent. But a bad shootout leaves him an outcast. Then he gets the case of a missing autistic boy. The boy is an amazing puzzle solver, and was able to decipher a new NSA top secret code. Before anybody else knows the code has been cracked, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) wants the boy killed to protect all the secrets. The NSA part is over the top unbelievable. Sad to say, the autistic boy is a little bit annoying at times. Also it's hard to see how the cops can't figure out what happened at the hospital. The whole thing is a little thin. It's a passable thriller, but it's just too slow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of the road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unremarkable but moderately suspenseful thriller that mistakenly underplays the relationship between rogue FBI agent Bruce Willis and autistic kiddie Miko Hughes, who has cracked a top secret code and is now the target of villainous Alec Baldwin. The plot seems as though it was more intelligent somewhere in the script's journey to the screen, while characterisation is on the shallow side - 'Is that him or you you're talking about?' asks Willis's best friend. Hmm. I wonder... Willis seems to have cottoned on to this lack of depth, as he hasn't switched off the autopilot. I could have done without the scene in which a hit man stares Willis in the eye just long enough for him to be recognised before legging it, and the computery sound effect that helpfully clues us in whenever Hughes cracks the code is just annoying. Still, the movie is low-key enough that it remains plausible, it's technically slick, and the villain's demise is impressively fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like my cooking skills, fast and tasteless.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The NSA has developed what they think is an unbreakable code. They ran a test to see if anyone can decipher it by putting it in a puzzle magazine. Simon Lynch, an autistic boy, deciphers it and calls the NSA. The men in charge call their boss Kudrow, who is worried what might happen if this gets out, and orders Simon to be killed. The man he sends kills his parents and leaves when the police arrive. The FBI send Art Jeffries to look for the boy. Art finds Simon, and they go on the run...... In the nineties, Willis lost his star power a little, and every now and again, he starred in your typical generic action thriller. And like Striking Distance, Last Man Standing, and The Jackal, it's nothing special, but its a must for Willis fans. As always in these types of movies, it starts with a set-up, this one leading to a bit of a meltdown for Art. He's involved in a robbery gone wrong and would you know it, it ends in a boy getting killed, thus Art will stop at nothing to protect Simon. The rest of the film involves Willis and Hughes (who is excellent) on the run from your atypical assassin, with supporting characters getting killed every now and again, with only Chi McBride as a friend, as the police are after him too. Baldwin is fine, but its little more than an extended cameo, with the two stars only meeting the once. The ending is silly, but its a nice little thriller which won't challenge the brain, with a nice ending. Plus, this film must hold the record for how many people actually duck when the Amin hero cries 'get down'. It won't win Willis any more fans, but it does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a great film but a great performance by Miko Hughes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Love
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two great acting performances in this film. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries, an FBI agent with attitude. Miko Hughes plays Simon Lynch, an autistic savant with a gift for codebreaking. Both are believable but Miko Hughes is astonishing  one of the best ever screen performances by a child. The scenes between the pair of them are really touching and you can believe that Willis really likes kids. Perhaps he does. The US government's pursuit of Lynch in this film may at first appear overly far-fetched and scaremongering. Then you remember the US attitude towards the British savant, Gary McKinnon, who was accused of perpetrating the biggest military computer hack of all time by hacking into 97 US military and NASA computers in 2002. Well, they didn't kill his mum and dad, and hunt him like an animal. But after 10 years of attempted extradition, and speculation of a 70-year jail term, maybe this story is just an exaggeration of reality, and not quite as ridiculous as some commentators have suggested. It's not really a downside but if you come to this film expecting a shoot-em-up action movie, you may be disappointed. It's much more than that and consequently slower  it's a touching drama with action scenes, and so we can forgive, just about, the pace through the middle of the film. The writing is actually very good and Pearson, Konner and Rosenthal all deserve credit. I did find the score a bit distracting. Sort of 'too big' and too 'James Bond' for the film. Scenes without music were better. Though the music being played at the club Jeffries visits was really good and I would have liked to have heard more of Koko Taylor (now no longer with us) belting out some blues. I was finding it difficult to see where this film was going. When Wills is with a kid, like in 16 blocks or Die Hard 4, you expect a visible end point, and there wasn't one. There was a sense of going around in circles. Until the last 5 minutes. Ultimately that cost it a couple of stars and the score lost another one. So seven out of ten for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    surely better then a 5.6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is nothing special but it surely worth more then a measly 5.6. The acting is good and the idea is new and original so I don't know why everyone hated it so much. It had a good story line and some decent action scenes so I was pleasantly surprised by this one. This movie is about a FBI agent who is sent to protect an autistic boy who is a target of assassins after accidentally cracking a top secret government code. I don't know why everybody hated this movie so much I actually thought it was pretty good. It was nothing special but in my eyes it was worth a watch no doubt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Gunston
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed this film and have found it equally watchable on repeated viewings. From the opening scene of a helicopter making its way towards a rural town accompanied by Barry's soulful music you just know that you are in for a rewarding movie experience. What elevates a routine and slightly clich&eacute;d thriller into a tense and emotionally satisfying film is the sensitive direction of Harold Becker, spot on casting, a story with emotional depth and John Barrys great score. Bruce Willis is ideally cast as the loner working against the system. The interaction between him and Miko Hughes as the autistic child Simon feels authentic. There is real chemistry in the exchanges between the 3 computer nerds who work for the NSA. And the scenes between Simon and his parents carry real emotional weight. This is not an action film. It is a film about story and character, and in some ways that makes it an old fashioned movie and all the better for it. It does, however, maintain tension through most of it's running time, a characteristic which is becoming rarer in modern films. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Your eyes see, but they do not observe, "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The novel 'Simple Simon' was written by Ryne Pearson and easily transferred to the silver screen, where it was directed expertly by Harold Becker. The movie tells the story of an autistic boy named Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who incredibly is able to decipher a top secret code created by the N.S.A. When the secret is uncovered, the top executive, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) believes his network of undercover agents and their identifies are in danger of being compromised and therefor orders a top assassin to execute Simon and his parents. The only defense for the boy is Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) a burned-out F.B.I agent who despite his short-comings is a tough-as-nails individual who learns Simon is a very special child and soon bonds with him. Along the way and amid the encroaching danger Jeffries receives help from Stacey a coffee shop patron (Kim Dickens) and fellow FBI agent Tommy B. Jordan (Chi McBride) The film is a combination of intrigue, murder and suspense with excitement filling in all the gaps. Willis and Hughes give a heartwarming and endearing performance. Recommended. ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really like this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsmemark47
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see the terrible reviews it got from some "important" reviewers. I'm watching it for at least the 4th time, just recorded it from satellite TV. Bruce Willis is really fine in this...I think few people appreciated how complex and skilled he is before this release, and I'm very glad they chose him for this role. Baldwin and the entire cast is very good and despite the not uncommon plot elements, the whole thing succeeds. Since the "Patriot Act" went into effect, I can give the actions of the government in this film a lot more credence...I rate it as an 8 out of 10, and I have seen extremely few 10's. mark
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was Bruce Willis at his finest. Although Mercury Rising was financially not well received, the film is a terrific thriller, solid acting, great story and just all around entertaining! One reviewer said this was more of a drama about autism and that's ludicrous. This is a thriller about a young boy who happens to have autism but to call this a drama or about autism at all is misleading. The film is part mystery, part thriller, part action and will entertain from beginning to end. Powerful performances from the lead cast make it worthwhile and riveting. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries and does a great job doing what he does best. No this isn't an award worthy performance or anything outstanding for Willis but he still carries the film well and Willis fans, like myself, will remember this. The star and stand out performance of this film is Miko Hughes who brilliantly plays autistic puzzle solver Simon. His performance is award worthy and I've always remembered it as one of my favorite performances. His chemistry with Willis is brilliant. Robert Stanton deserves mention in a small but pivotal role that I really enjoyed him in. Same could be said for Chi McBride who also does a good job. Alec Baldwin is good in his role as the villain. I would have liked a little more chemistry between him and Willis and I don't think he was outstanding in his role but he was definitely good. Kim Dickens is the female lead in the film and she does alright although I found her character very one dimensional for the most part. Harold Becker's direction is perhaps a little bland from time to time. It is true what some reviewers say that the film could have used just a little more action and some of the performances felt dry at times from Baldwin and Dickens, who are important to the entire film in many ways. Still the concept for the film is riveting and the story is delivered in a well paced, entertaining fashion. Anyone looking for a good thriller will not be steered wrong with this film. Its a movie that I watch from time to time again and again because I've always thought it was a great movie. Plenty of thrills, plenty of edge of your seat moments and a terrific performance from Hughes. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yet another disappointing action flick - 59%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For reasons that I can't explain, this has been on my "Must See" list for ages. I really don't know why - Bruce Willis action movies aren't exactly rare beasts and at some point, I figured that this had a plot that offered something a little different. Sadly, it turns out that it really wasn't worth the wait. It lacks the bluster of your usual Willis blockbuster and the story that I had high hopes for quickly finds itself becoming a gimmick. Willis plays FBI agent Art Jeffries, an undercover specialist who finds himself demoted to monitoring radio transmissions after a botched hostage assignment. However, he quickly finds himself assigned to look for a missing child - Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who is an autistic nine-year orphaned after his parents are murdered. But Art quickly finds threat there is more to it than that - Simon had accidentally cracked a top secret code after it inexplicably appeared in the pages of a puzzle magazine and was being sought by NSA operatives led by the gravel-voiced Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) and his murderous colleague Peter Burrell (Lindsey Ginter). Being an odd hybrid of espionage thriller and fugitive actioner, "Mercury Rising" successfully manages to be neither. The action is satisfying enough when it turns arrive in fits and starts but there is an awful lot of dialogue to get through in-between. Willis can pretty much sleepwalk through these kinda movies and sure enough, he simply doesn't engage you enough to care. He's also completely shown up by his young co-star as Hughes is brilliantly and genuinely heart-wrenching as the tortured savant. However, the worst actor by far is Baldwin who seems to be eerily foreshadowing his portrayal in "Team America: World Police". At times, he's simply appalling as he mumbles his way through his lines as though paying tribute to Michael Madsen. Maybe it was he who distracted me from the story which seemed confusing and never really explained what was happening. For example, imagine you are an experienced FBI agent looking after an infant suspect. Would you happily hand the care of the child over to a complete stranger in a caf&eacute; (played here by Kim Dickins) while you popped off to meet an informant because I'm not sure I would. "Mercury Rising" is annoyingly wasteful of its promising set-up, failing to deliver either a decent action movie or a gripping chase flick. It seems curiously restrained, as though it can't be bothered to be the nail-biting gripper it seems to aspire to. Maybe I'm being harsh on it given how long I've waited to watch it but for me, "Mercury Rising" is just as generic and forgettable as any other Nineties action flick. Shame, shame, shame.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unrealistic, slow thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) is the best FBI undercover agent. But a bad shootout leaves him an outcast. Then he gets the case of a missing autistic boy. The boy is an amazing puzzle solver, and was able to decipher a new NSA top secret code. Before anybody else knows the code has been cracked, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) wants the boy killed to protect all the secrets. The NSA part is over the top unbelievable. Sad to say, the autistic boy is a little bit annoying at times. Also it's hard to see how the cops can't figure out what happened at the hospital. The whole thing is a little thin. It's a passable thriller, but it's just too slow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of the road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unremarkable but moderately suspenseful thriller that mistakenly underplays the relationship between rogue FBI agent Bruce Willis and autistic kiddie Miko Hughes, who has cracked a top secret code and is now the target of villainous Alec Baldwin. The plot seems as though it was more intelligent somewhere in the script's journey to the screen, while characterisation is on the shallow side - 'Is that him or you you're talking about?' asks Willis's best friend. Hmm. I wonder... Willis seems to have cottoned on to this lack of depth, as he hasn't switched off the autopilot. I could have done without the scene in which a hit man stares Willis in the eye just long enough for him to be recognised before legging it, and the computery sound effect that helpfully clues us in whenever Hughes cracks the code is just annoying. Still, the movie is low-key enough that it remains plausible, it's technically slick, and the villain's demise is impressively fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like my cooking skills, fast and tasteless.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The NSA has developed what they think is an unbreakable code. They ran a test to see if anyone can decipher it by putting it in a puzzle magazine. Simon Lynch, an autistic boy, deciphers it and calls the NSA. The men in charge call their boss Kudrow, who is worried what might happen if this gets out, and orders Simon to be killed. The man he sends kills his parents and leaves when the police arrive. The FBI send Art Jeffries to look for the boy. Art finds Simon, and they go on the run...... In the nineties, Willis lost his star power a little, and every now and again, he starred in your typical generic action thriller. And like Striking Distance, Last Man Standing, and The Jackal, it's nothing special, but its a must for Willis fans. As always in these types of movies, it starts with a set-up, this one leading to a bit of a meltdown for Art. He's involved in a robbery gone wrong and would you know it, it ends in a boy getting killed, thus Art will stop at nothing to protect Simon. The rest of the film involves Willis and Hughes (who is excellent) on the run from your atypical assassin, with supporting characters getting killed every now and again, with only Chi McBride as a friend, as the police are after him too. Baldwin is fine, but its little more than an extended cameo, with the two stars only meeting the once. The ending is silly, but its a nice little thriller which won't challenge the brain, with a nice ending. Plus, this film must hold the record for how many people actually duck when the Amin hero cries 'get down'. It won't win Willis any more fans, but it does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a great film but a great performance by Miko Hughes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Love
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two great acting performances in this film. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries, an FBI agent with attitude. Miko Hughes plays Simon Lynch, an autistic savant with a gift for codebreaking. Both are believable but Miko Hughes is astonishing  one of the best ever screen performances by a child. The scenes between the pair of them are really touching and you can believe that Willis really likes kids. Perhaps he does. The US government's pursuit of Lynch in this film may at first appear overly far-fetched and scaremongering. Then you remember the US attitude towards the British savant, Gary McKinnon, who was accused of perpetrating the biggest military computer hack of all time by hacking into 97 US military and NASA computers in 2002. Well, they didn't kill his mum and dad, and hunt him like an animal. But after 10 years of attempted extradition, and speculation of a 70-year jail term, maybe this story is just an exaggeration of reality, and not quite as ridiculous as some commentators have suggested. It's not really a downside but if you come to this film expecting a shoot-em-up action movie, you may be disappointed. It's much more than that and consequently slower  it's a touching drama with action scenes, and so we can forgive, just about, the pace through the middle of the film. The writing is actually very good and Pearson, Konner and Rosenthal all deserve credit. I did find the score a bit distracting. Sort of 'too big' and too 'James Bond' for the film. Scenes without music were better. Though the music being played at the club Jeffries visits was really good and I would have liked to have heard more of Koko Taylor (now no longer with us) belting out some blues. I was finding it difficult to see where this film was going. When Wills is with a kid, like in 16 blocks or Die Hard 4, you expect a visible end point, and there wasn't one. There was a sense of going around in circles. Until the last 5 minutes. Ultimately that cost it a couple of stars and the score lost another one. So seven out of ten for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    surely better then a 5.6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is nothing special but it surely worth more then a measly 5.6. The acting is good and the idea is new and original so I don't know why everyone hated it so much. It had a good story line and some decent action scenes so I was pleasantly surprised by this one. This movie is about a FBI agent who is sent to protect an autistic boy who is a target of assassins after accidentally cracking a top secret government code. I don't know why everybody hated this movie so much I actually thought it was pretty good. It was nothing special but in my eyes it was worth a watch no doubt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Gunston
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed this film and have found it equally watchable on repeated viewings. From the opening scene of a helicopter making its way towards a rural town accompanied by Barry's soulful music you just know that you are in for a rewarding movie experience. What elevates a routine and slightly clich&eacute;d thriller into a tense and emotionally satisfying film is the sensitive direction of Harold Becker, spot on casting, a story with emotional depth and John Barrys great score. Bruce Willis is ideally cast as the loner working against the system. The interaction between him and Miko Hughes as the autistic child Simon feels authentic. There is real chemistry in the exchanges between the 3 computer nerds who work for the NSA. And the scenes between Simon and his parents carry real emotional weight. This is not an action film. It is a film about story and character, and in some ways that makes it an old fashioned movie and all the better for it. It does, however, maintain tension through most of it's running time, a characteristic which is becoming rarer in modern films. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Your eyes see, but they do not observe, "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The novel 'Simple Simon' was written by Ryne Pearson and easily transferred to the silver screen, where it was directed expertly by Harold Becker. The movie tells the story of an autistic boy named Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who incredibly is able to decipher a top secret code created by the N.S.A. When the secret is uncovered, the top executive, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) believes his network of undercover agents and their identifies are in danger of being compromised and therefor orders a top assassin to execute Simon and his parents. The only defense for the boy is Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) a burned-out F.B.I agent who despite his short-comings is a tough-as-nails individual who learns Simon is a very special child and soon bonds with him. Along the way and amid the encroaching danger Jeffries receives help from Stacey a coffee shop patron (Kim Dickens) and fellow FBI agent Tommy B. Jordan (Chi McBride) The film is a combination of intrigue, murder and suspense with excitement filling in all the gaps. Willis and Hughes give a heartwarming and endearing performance. Recommended. ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really like this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsmemark47
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see the terrible reviews it got from some "important" reviewers. I'm watching it for at least the 4th time, just recorded it from satellite TV. Bruce Willis is really fine in this...I think few people appreciated how complex and skilled he is before this release, and I'm very glad they chose him for this role. Baldwin and the entire cast is very good and despite the not uncommon plot elements, the whole thing succeeds. Since the "Patriot Act" went into effect, I can give the actions of the government in this film a lot more credence...I rate it as an 8 out of 10, and I have seen extremely few 10's. mark
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was Bruce Willis at his finest. Although Mercury Rising was financially not well received, the film is a terrific thriller, solid acting, great story and just all around entertaining! One reviewer said this was more of a drama about autism and that's ludicrous. This is a thriller about a young boy who happens to have autism but to call this a drama or about autism at all is misleading. The film is part mystery, part thriller, part action and will entertain from beginning to end. Powerful performances from the lead cast make it worthwhile and riveting. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries and does a great job doing what he does best. No this isn't an award worthy performance or anything outstanding for Willis but he still carries the film well and Willis fans, like myself, will remember this. The star and stand out performance of this film is Miko Hughes who brilliantly plays autistic puzzle solver Simon. His performance is award worthy and I've always remembered it as one of my favorite performances. His chemistry with Willis is brilliant. Robert Stanton deserves mention in a small but pivotal role that I really enjoyed him in. Same could be said for Chi McBride who also does a good job. Alec Baldwin is good in his role as the villain. I would have liked a little more chemistry between him and Willis and I don't think he was outstanding in his role but he was definitely good. Kim Dickens is the female lead in the film and she does alright although I found her character very one dimensional for the most part. Harold Becker's direction is perhaps a little bland from time to time. It is true what some reviewers say that the film could have used just a little more action and some of the performances felt dry at times from Baldwin and Dickens, who are important to the entire film in many ways. Still the concept for the film is riveting and the story is delivered in a well paced, entertaining fashion. Anyone looking for a good thriller will not be steered wrong with this film. Its a movie that I watch from time to time again and again because I've always thought it was a great movie. Plenty of thrills, plenty of edge of your seat moments and a terrific performance from Hughes. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yet another disappointing action flick - 59%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For reasons that I can't explain, this has been on my "Must See" list for ages. I really don't know why - Bruce Willis action movies aren't exactly rare beasts and at some point, I figured that this had a plot that offered something a little different. Sadly, it turns out that it really wasn't worth the wait. It lacks the bluster of your usual Willis blockbuster and the story that I had high hopes for quickly finds itself becoming a gimmick. Willis plays FBI agent Art Jeffries, an undercover specialist who finds himself demoted to monitoring radio transmissions after a botched hostage assignment. However, he quickly finds himself assigned to look for a missing child - Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who is an autistic nine-year orphaned after his parents are murdered. But Art quickly finds threat there is more to it than that - Simon had accidentally cracked a top secret code after it inexplicably appeared in the pages of a puzzle magazine and was being sought by NSA operatives led by the gravel-voiced Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) and his murderous colleague Peter Burrell (Lindsey Ginter). Being an odd hybrid of espionage thriller and fugitive actioner, "Mercury Rising" successfully manages to be neither. The action is satisfying enough when it turns arrive in fits and starts but there is an awful lot of dialogue to get through in-between. Willis can pretty much sleepwalk through these kinda movies and sure enough, he simply doesn't engage you enough to care. He's also completely shown up by his young co-star as Hughes is brilliantly and genuinely heart-wrenching as the tortured savant. However, the worst actor by far is Baldwin who seems to be eerily foreshadowing his portrayal in "Team America: World Police". At times, he's simply appalling as he mumbles his way through his lines as though paying tribute to Michael Madsen. Maybe it was he who distracted me from the story which seemed confusing and never really explained what was happening. For example, imagine you are an experienced FBI agent looking after an infant suspect. Would you happily hand the care of the child over to a complete stranger in a caf&eacute; (played here by Kim Dickins) while you popped off to meet an informant because I'm not sure I would. "Mercury Rising" is annoyingly wasteful of its promising set-up, failing to deliver either a decent action movie or a gripping chase flick. It seems curiously restrained, as though it can't be bothered to be the nail-biting gripper it seems to aspire to. Maybe I'm being harsh on it given how long I've waited to watch it but for me, "Mercury Rising" is just as generic and forgettable as any other Nineties action flick. Shame, shame, shame.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unrealistic, slow thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) is the best FBI undercover agent. But a bad shootout leaves him an outcast. Then he gets the case of a missing autistic boy. The boy is an amazing puzzle solver, and was able to decipher a new NSA top secret code. Before anybody else knows the code has been cracked, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) wants the boy killed to protect all the secrets. The NSA part is over the top unbelievable. Sad to say, the autistic boy is a little bit annoying at times. Also it's hard to see how the cops can't figure out what happened at the hospital. The whole thing is a little thin. It's a passable thriller, but it's just too slow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of the road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unremarkable but moderately suspenseful thriller that mistakenly underplays the relationship between rogue FBI agent Bruce Willis and autistic kiddie Miko Hughes, who has cracked a top secret code and is now the target of villainous Alec Baldwin. The plot seems as though it was more intelligent somewhere in the script's journey to the screen, while characterisation is on the shallow side - 'Is that him or you you're talking about?' asks Willis's best friend. Hmm. I wonder... Willis seems to have cottoned on to this lack of depth, as he hasn't switched off the autopilot. I could have done without the scene in which a hit man stares Willis in the eye just long enough for him to be recognised before legging it, and the computery sound effect that helpfully clues us in whenever Hughes cracks the code is just annoying. Still, the movie is low-key enough that it remains plausible, it's technically slick, and the villain's demise is impressively fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like my cooking skills, fast and tasteless.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The NSA has developed what they think is an unbreakable code. They ran a test to see if anyone can decipher it by putting it in a puzzle magazine. Simon Lynch, an autistic boy, deciphers it and calls the NSA. The men in charge call their boss Kudrow, who is worried what might happen if this gets out, and orders Simon to be killed. The man he sends kills his parents and leaves when the police arrive. The FBI send Art Jeffries to look for the boy. Art finds Simon, and they go on the run...... In the nineties, Willis lost his star power a little, and every now and again, he starred in your typical generic action thriller. And like Striking Distance, Last Man Standing, and The Jackal, it's nothing special, but its a must for Willis fans. As always in these types of movies, it starts with a set-up, this one leading to a bit of a meltdown for Art. He's involved in a robbery gone wrong and would you know it, it ends in a boy getting killed, thus Art will stop at nothing to protect Simon. The rest of the film involves Willis and Hughes (who is excellent) on the run from your atypical assassin, with supporting characters getting killed every now and again, with only Chi McBride as a friend, as the police are after him too. Baldwin is fine, but its little more than an extended cameo, with the two stars only meeting the once. The ending is silly, but its a nice little thriller which won't challenge the brain, with a nice ending. Plus, this film must hold the record for how many people actually duck when the Amin hero cries 'get down'. It won't win Willis any more fans, but it does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a great film but a great performance by Miko Hughes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Love
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two great acting performances in this film. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries, an FBI agent with attitude. Miko Hughes plays Simon Lynch, an autistic savant with a gift for codebreaking. Both are believable but Miko Hughes is astonishing  one of the best ever screen performances by a child. The scenes between the pair of them are really touching and you can believe that Willis really likes kids. Perhaps he does. The US government's pursuit of Lynch in this film may at first appear overly far-fetched and scaremongering. Then you remember the US attitude towards the British savant, Gary McKinnon, who was accused of perpetrating the biggest military computer hack of all time by hacking into 97 US military and NASA computers in 2002. Well, they didn't kill his mum and dad, and hunt him like an animal. But after 10 years of attempted extradition, and speculation of a 70-year jail term, maybe this story is just an exaggeration of reality, and not quite as ridiculous as some commentators have suggested. It's not really a downside but if you come to this film expecting a shoot-em-up action movie, you may be disappointed. It's much more than that and consequently slower  it's a touching drama with action scenes, and so we can forgive, just about, the pace through the middle of the film. The writing is actually very good and Pearson, Konner and Rosenthal all deserve credit. I did find the score a bit distracting. Sort of 'too big' and too 'James Bond' for the film. Scenes without music were better. Though the music being played at the club Jeffries visits was really good and I would have liked to have heard more of Koko Taylor (now no longer with us) belting out some blues. I was finding it difficult to see where this film was going. When Wills is with a kid, like in 16 blocks or Die Hard 4, you expect a visible end point, and there wasn't one. There was a sense of going around in circles. Until the last 5 minutes. Ultimately that cost it a couple of stars and the score lost another one. So seven out of ten for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    surely better then a 5.6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is nothing special but it surely worth more then a measly 5.6. The acting is good and the idea is new and original so I don't know why everyone hated it so much. It had a good story line and some decent action scenes so I was pleasantly surprised by this one. This movie is about a FBI agent who is sent to protect an autistic boy who is a target of assassins after accidentally cracking a top secret government code. I don't know why everybody hated this movie so much I actually thought it was pretty good. It was nothing special but in my eyes it was worth a watch no doubt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Gunston
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed this film and have found it equally watchable on repeated viewings. From the opening scene of a helicopter making its way towards a rural town accompanied by Barry's soulful music you just know that you are in for a rewarding movie experience. What elevates a routine and slightly clich&eacute;d thriller into a tense and emotionally satisfying film is the sensitive direction of Harold Becker, spot on casting, a story with emotional depth and John Barrys great score. Bruce Willis is ideally cast as the loner working against the system. The interaction between him and Miko Hughes as the autistic child Simon feels authentic. There is real chemistry in the exchanges between the 3 computer nerds who work for the NSA. And the scenes between Simon and his parents carry real emotional weight. This is not an action film. It is a film about story and character, and in some ways that makes it an old fashioned movie and all the better for it. It does, however, maintain tension through most of it's running time, a characteristic which is becoming rarer in modern films. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Your eyes see, but they do not observe, "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The novel 'Simple Simon' was written by Ryne Pearson and easily transferred to the silver screen, where it was directed expertly by Harold Becker. The movie tells the story of an autistic boy named Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who incredibly is able to decipher a top secret code created by the N.S.A. When the secret is uncovered, the top executive, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) believes his network of undercover agents and their identifies are in danger of being compromised and therefor orders a top assassin to execute Simon and his parents. The only defense for the boy is Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) a burned-out F.B.I agent who despite his short-comings is a tough-as-nails individual who learns Simon is a very special child and soon bonds with him. Along the way and amid the encroaching danger Jeffries receives help from Stacey a coffee shop patron (Kim Dickens) and fellow FBI agent Tommy B. Jordan (Chi McBride) The film is a combination of intrigue, murder and suspense with excitement filling in all the gaps. Willis and Hughes give a heartwarming and endearing performance. Recommended. ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really like this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsmemark47
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see the terrible reviews it got from some "important" reviewers. I'm watching it for at least the 4th time, just recorded it from satellite TV. Bruce Willis is really fine in this...I think few people appreciated how complex and skilled he is before this release, and I'm very glad they chose him for this role. Baldwin and the entire cast is very good and despite the not uncommon plot elements, the whole thing succeeds. Since the "Patriot Act" went into effect, I can give the actions of the government in this film a lot more credence...I rate it as an 8 out of 10, and I have seen extremely few 10's. mark
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was Bruce Willis at his finest. Although Mercury Rising was financially not well received, the film is a terrific thriller, solid acting, great story and just all around entertaining! One reviewer said this was more of a drama about autism and that's ludicrous. This is a thriller about a young boy who happens to have autism but to call this a drama or about autism at all is misleading. The film is part mystery, part thriller, part action and will entertain from beginning to end. Powerful performances from the lead cast make it worthwhile and riveting. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries and does a great job doing what he does best. No this isn't an award worthy performance or anything outstanding for Willis but he still carries the film well and Willis fans, like myself, will remember this. The star and stand out performance of this film is Miko Hughes who brilliantly plays autistic puzzle solver Simon. His performance is award worthy and I've always remembered it as one of my favorite performances. His chemistry with Willis is brilliant. Robert Stanton deserves mention in a small but pivotal role that I really enjoyed him in. Same could be said for Chi McBride who also does a good job. Alec Baldwin is good in his role as the villain. I would have liked a little more chemistry between him and Willis and I don't think he was outstanding in his role but he was definitely good. Kim Dickens is the female lead in the film and she does alright although I found her character very one dimensional for the most part. Harold Becker's direction is perhaps a little bland from time to time. It is true what some reviewers say that the film could have used just a little more action and some of the performances felt dry at times from Baldwin and Dickens, who are important to the entire film in many ways. Still the concept for the film is riveting and the story is delivered in a well paced, entertaining fashion. Anyone looking for a good thriller will not be steered wrong with this film. Its a movie that I watch from time to time again and again because I've always thought it was a great movie. Plenty of thrills, plenty of edge of your seat moments and a terrific performance from Hughes. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yet another disappointing action flick - 59%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For reasons that I can't explain, this has been on my "Must See" list for ages. I really don't know why - Bruce Willis action movies aren't exactly rare beasts and at some point, I figured that this had a plot that offered something a little different. Sadly, it turns out that it really wasn't worth the wait. It lacks the bluster of your usual Willis blockbuster and the story that I had high hopes for quickly finds itself becoming a gimmick. Willis plays FBI agent Art Jeffries, an undercover specialist who finds himself demoted to monitoring radio transmissions after a botched hostage assignment. However, he quickly finds himself assigned to look for a missing child - Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who is an autistic nine-year orphaned after his parents are murdered. But Art quickly finds threat there is more to it than that - Simon had accidentally cracked a top secret code after it inexplicably appeared in the pages of a puzzle magazine and was being sought by NSA operatives led by the gravel-voiced Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) and his murderous colleague Peter Burrell (Lindsey Ginter). Being an odd hybrid of espionage thriller and fugitive actioner, "Mercury Rising" successfully manages to be neither. The action is satisfying enough when it turns arrive in fits and starts but there is an awful lot of dialogue to get through in-between. Willis can pretty much sleepwalk through these kinda movies and sure enough, he simply doesn't engage you enough to care. He's also completely shown up by his young co-star as Hughes is brilliantly and genuinely heart-wrenching as the tortured savant. However, the worst actor by far is Baldwin who seems to be eerily foreshadowing his portrayal in "Team America: World Police". At times, he's simply appalling as he mumbles his way through his lines as though paying tribute to Michael Madsen. Maybe it was he who distracted me from the story which seemed confusing and never really explained what was happening. For example, imagine you are an experienced FBI agent looking after an infant suspect. Would you happily hand the care of the child over to a complete stranger in a caf&eacute; (played here by Kim Dickins) while you popped off to meet an informant because I'm not sure I would. "Mercury Rising" is annoyingly wasteful of its promising set-up, failing to deliver either a decent action movie or a gripping chase flick. It seems curiously restrained, as though it can't be bothered to be the nail-biting gripper it seems to aspire to. Maybe I'm being harsh on it given how long I've waited to watch it but for me, "Mercury Rising" is just as generic and forgettable as any other Nineties action flick. Shame, shame, shame.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unrealistic, slow thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) is the best FBI undercover agent. But a bad shootout leaves him an outcast. Then he gets the case of a missing autistic boy. The boy is an amazing puzzle solver, and was able to decipher a new NSA top secret code. Before anybody else knows the code has been cracked, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) wants the boy killed to protect all the secrets. The NSA part is over the top unbelievable. Sad to say, the autistic boy is a little bit annoying at times. Also it's hard to see how the cops can't figure out what happened at the hospital. The whole thing is a little thin. It's a passable thriller, but it's just too slow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of the road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unremarkable but moderately suspenseful thriller that mistakenly underplays the relationship between rogue FBI agent Bruce Willis and autistic kiddie Miko Hughes, who has cracked a top secret code and is now the target of villainous Alec Baldwin. The plot seems as though it was more intelligent somewhere in the script's journey to the screen, while characterisation is on the shallow side - 'Is that him or you you're talking about?' asks Willis's best friend. Hmm. I wonder... Willis seems to have cottoned on to this lack of depth, as he hasn't switched off the autopilot. I could have done without the scene in which a hit man stares Willis in the eye just long enough for him to be recognised before legging it, and the computery sound effect that helpfully clues us in whenever Hughes cracks the code is just annoying. Still, the movie is low-key enough that it remains plausible, it's technically slick, and the villain's demise is impressively fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like my cooking skills, fast and tasteless.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The NSA has developed what they think is an unbreakable code. They ran a test to see if anyone can decipher it by putting it in a puzzle magazine. Simon Lynch, an autistic boy, deciphers it and calls the NSA. The men in charge call their boss Kudrow, who is worried what might happen if this gets out, and orders Simon to be killed. The man he sends kills his parents and leaves when the police arrive. The FBI send Art Jeffries to look for the boy. Art finds Simon, and they go on the run...... In the nineties, Willis lost his star power a little, and every now and again, he starred in your typical generic action thriller. And like Striking Distance, Last Man Standing, and The Jackal, it's nothing special, but its a must for Willis fans. As always in these types of movies, it starts with a set-up, this one leading to a bit of a meltdown for Art. He's involved in a robbery gone wrong and would you know it, it ends in a boy getting killed, thus Art will stop at nothing to protect Simon. The rest of the film involves Willis and Hughes (who is excellent) on the run from your atypical assassin, with supporting characters getting killed every now and again, with only Chi McBride as a friend, as the police are after him too. Baldwin is fine, but its little more than an extended cameo, with the two stars only meeting the once. The ending is silly, but its a nice little thriller which won't challenge the brain, with a nice ending. Plus, this film must hold the record for how many people actually duck when the Amin hero cries 'get down'. It won't win Willis any more fans, but it does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a great film but a great performance by Miko Hughes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Love
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two great acting performances in this film. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries, an FBI agent with attitude. Miko Hughes plays Simon Lynch, an autistic savant with a gift for codebreaking. Both are believable but Miko Hughes is astonishing  one of the best ever screen performances by a child. The scenes between the pair of them are really touching and you can believe that Willis really likes kids. Perhaps he does. The US government's pursuit of Lynch in this film may at first appear overly far-fetched and scaremongering. Then you remember the US attitude towards the British savant, Gary McKinnon, who was accused of perpetrating the biggest military computer hack of all time by hacking into 97 US military and NASA computers in 2002. Well, they didn't kill his mum and dad, and hunt him like an animal. But after 10 years of attempted extradition, and speculation of a 70-year jail term, maybe this story is just an exaggeration of reality, and not quite as ridiculous as some commentators have suggested. It's not really a downside but if you come to this film expecting a shoot-em-up action movie, you may be disappointed. It's much more than that and consequently slower  it's a touching drama with action scenes, and so we can forgive, just about, the pace through the middle of the film. The writing is actually very good and Pearson, Konner and Rosenthal all deserve credit. I did find the score a bit distracting. Sort of 'too big' and too 'James Bond' for the film. Scenes without music were better. Though the music being played at the club Jeffries visits was really good and I would have liked to have heard more of Koko Taylor (now no longer with us) belting out some blues. I was finding it difficult to see where this film was going. When Wills is with a kid, like in 16 blocks or Die Hard 4, you expect a visible end point, and there wasn't one. There was a sense of going around in circles. Until the last 5 minutes. Ultimately that cost it a couple of stars and the score lost another one. So seven out of ten for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    surely better then a 5.6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is nothing special but it surely worth more then a measly 5.6. The acting is good and the idea is new and original so I don't know why everyone hated it so much. It had a good story line and some decent action scenes so I was pleasantly surprised by this one. This movie is about a FBI agent who is sent to protect an autistic boy who is a target of assassins after accidentally cracking a top secret government code. I don't know why everybody hated this movie so much I actually thought it was pretty good. It was nothing special but in my eyes it was worth a watch no doubt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Gunston
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed this film and have found it equally watchable on repeated viewings. From the opening scene of a helicopter making its way towards a rural town accompanied by Barry's soulful music you just know that you are in for a rewarding movie experience. What elevates a routine and slightly clich&eacute;d thriller into a tense and emotionally satisfying film is the sensitive direction of Harold Becker, spot on casting, a story with emotional depth and John Barrys great score. Bruce Willis is ideally cast as the loner working against the system. The interaction between him and Miko Hughes as the autistic child Simon feels authentic. There is real chemistry in the exchanges between the 3 computer nerds who work for the NSA. And the scenes between Simon and his parents carry real emotional weight. This is not an action film. It is a film about story and character, and in some ways that makes it an old fashioned movie and all the better for it. It does, however, maintain tension through most of it's running time, a characteristic which is becoming rarer in modern films. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Your eyes see, but they do not observe, "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The novel 'Simple Simon' was written by Ryne Pearson and easily transferred to the silver screen, where it was directed expertly by Harold Becker. The movie tells the story of an autistic boy named Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who incredibly is able to decipher a top secret code created by the N.S.A. When the secret is uncovered, the top executive, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) believes his network of undercover agents and their identifies are in danger of being compromised and therefor orders a top assassin to execute Simon and his parents. The only defense for the boy is Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) a burned-out F.B.I agent who despite his short-comings is a tough-as-nails individual who learns Simon is a very special child and soon bonds with him. Along the way and amid the encroaching danger Jeffries receives help from Stacey a coffee shop patron (Kim Dickens) and fellow FBI agent Tommy B. Jordan (Chi McBride) The film is a combination of intrigue, murder and suspense with excitement filling in all the gaps. Willis and Hughes give a heartwarming and endearing performance. Recommended. ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really like this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsmemark47
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see the terrible reviews it got from some "important" reviewers. I'm watching it for at least the 4th time, just recorded it from satellite TV. Bruce Willis is really fine in this...I think few people appreciated how complex and skilled he is before this release, and I'm very glad they chose him for this role. Baldwin and the entire cast is very good and despite the not uncommon plot elements, the whole thing succeeds. Since the "Patriot Act" went into effect, I can give the actions of the government in this film a lot more credence...I rate it as an 8 out of 10, and I have seen extremely few 10's. mark
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was Bruce Willis at his finest. Although Mercury Rising was financially not well received, the film is a terrific thriller, solid acting, great story and just all around entertaining! One reviewer said this was more of a drama about autism and that's ludicrous. This is a thriller about a young boy who happens to have autism but to call this a drama or about autism at all is misleading. The film is part mystery, part thriller, part action and will entertain from beginning to end. Powerful performances from the lead cast make it worthwhile and riveting. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries and does a great job doing what he does best. No this isn't an award worthy performance or anything outstanding for Willis but he still carries the film well and Willis fans, like myself, will remember this. The star and stand out performance of this film is Miko Hughes who brilliantly plays autistic puzzle solver Simon. His performance is award worthy and I've always remembered it as one of my favorite performances. His chemistry with Willis is brilliant. Robert Stanton deserves mention in a small but pivotal role that I really enjoyed him in. Same could be said for Chi McBride who also does a good job. Alec Baldwin is good in his role as the villain. I would have liked a little more chemistry between him and Willis and I don't think he was outstanding in his role but he was definitely good. Kim Dickens is the female lead in the film and she does alright although I found her character very one dimensional for the most part. Harold Becker's direction is perhaps a little bland from time to time. It is true what some reviewers say that the film could have used just a little more action and some of the performances felt dry at times from Baldwin and Dickens, who are important to the entire film in many ways. Still the concept for the film is riveting and the story is delivered in a well paced, entertaining fashion. Anyone looking for a good thriller will not be steered wrong with this film. Its a movie that I watch from time to time again and again because I've always thought it was a great movie. Plenty of thrills, plenty of edge of your seat moments and a terrific performance from Hughes. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yet another disappointing action flick - 59%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For reasons that I can't explain, this has been on my "Must See" list for ages. I really don't know why - Bruce Willis action movies aren't exactly rare beasts and at some point, I figured that this had a plot that offered something a little different. Sadly, it turns out that it really wasn't worth the wait. It lacks the bluster of your usual Willis blockbuster and the story that I had high hopes for quickly finds itself becoming a gimmick. Willis plays FBI agent Art Jeffries, an undercover specialist who finds himself demoted to monitoring radio transmissions after a botched hostage assignment. However, he quickly finds himself assigned to look for a missing child - Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who is an autistic nine-year orphaned after his parents are murdered. But Art quickly finds threat there is more to it than that - Simon had accidentally cracked a top secret code after it inexplicably appeared in the pages of a puzzle magazine and was being sought by NSA operatives led by the gravel-voiced Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) and his murderous colleague Peter Burrell (Lindsey Ginter). Being an odd hybrid of espionage thriller and fugitive actioner, "Mercury Rising" successfully manages to be neither. The action is satisfying enough when it turns arrive in fits and starts but there is an awful lot of dialogue to get through in-between. Willis can pretty much sleepwalk through these kinda movies and sure enough, he simply doesn't engage you enough to care. He's also completely shown up by his young co-star as Hughes is brilliantly and genuinely heart-wrenching as the tortured savant. However, the worst actor by far is Baldwin who seems to be eerily foreshadowing his portrayal in "Team America: World Police". At times, he's simply appalling as he mumbles his way through his lines as though paying tribute to Michael Madsen. Maybe it was he who distracted me from the story which seemed confusing and never really explained what was happening. For example, imagine you are an experienced FBI agent looking after an infant suspect. Would you happily hand the care of the child over to a complete stranger in a caf&eacute; (played here by Kim Dickins) while you popped off to meet an informant because I'm not sure I would. "Mercury Rising" is annoyingly wasteful of its promising set-up, failing to deliver either a decent action movie or a gripping chase flick. It seems curiously restrained, as though it can't be bothered to be the nail-biting gripper it seems to aspire to. Maybe I'm being harsh on it given how long I've waited to watch it but for me, "Mercury Rising" is just as generic and forgettable as any other Nineties action flick. Shame, shame, shame.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unrealistic, slow thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) is the best FBI undercover agent. But a bad shootout leaves him an outcast. Then he gets the case of a missing autistic boy. The boy is an amazing puzzle solver, and was able to decipher a new NSA top secret code. Before anybody else knows the code has been cracked, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) wants the boy killed to protect all the secrets. The NSA part is over the top unbelievable. Sad to say, the autistic boy is a little bit annoying at times. Also it's hard to see how the cops can't figure out what happened at the hospital. The whole thing is a little thin. It's a passable thriller, but it's just too slow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of the road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unremarkable but moderately suspenseful thriller that mistakenly underplays the relationship between rogue FBI agent Bruce Willis and autistic kiddie Miko Hughes, who has cracked a top secret code and is now the target of villainous Alec Baldwin. The plot seems as though it was more intelligent somewhere in the script's journey to the screen, while characterisation is on the shallow side - 'Is that him or you you're talking about?' asks Willis's best friend. Hmm. I wonder... Willis seems to have cottoned on to this lack of depth, as he hasn't switched off the autopilot. I could have done without the scene in which a hit man stares Willis in the eye just long enough for him to be recognised before legging it, and the computery sound effect that helpfully clues us in whenever Hughes cracks the code is just annoying. Still, the movie is low-key enough that it remains plausible, it's technically slick, and the villain's demise is impressively fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like my cooking skills, fast and tasteless.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The NSA has developed what they think is an unbreakable code. They ran a test to see if anyone can decipher it by putting it in a puzzle magazine. Simon Lynch, an autistic boy, deciphers it and calls the NSA. The men in charge call their boss Kudrow, who is worried what might happen if this gets out, and orders Simon to be killed. The man he sends kills his parents and leaves when the police arrive. The FBI send Art Jeffries to look for the boy. Art finds Simon, and they go on the run...... In the nineties, Willis lost his star power a little, and every now and again, he starred in your typical generic action thriller. And like Striking Distance, Last Man Standing, and The Jackal, it's nothing special, but its a must for Willis fans. As always in these types of movies, it starts with a set-up, this one leading to a bit of a meltdown for Art. He's involved in a robbery gone wrong and would you know it, it ends in a boy getting killed, thus Art will stop at nothing to protect Simon. The rest of the film involves Willis and Hughes (who is excellent) on the run from your atypical assassin, with supporting characters getting killed every now and again, with only Chi McBride as a friend, as the police are after him too. Baldwin is fine, but its little more than an extended cameo, with the two stars only meeting the once. The ending is silly, but its a nice little thriller which won't challenge the brain, with a nice ending. Plus, this film must hold the record for how many people actually duck when the Amin hero cries 'get down'. It won't win Willis any more fans, but it does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a great film but a great performance by Miko Hughes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Love
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two great acting performances in this film. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries, an FBI agent with attitude. Miko Hughes plays Simon Lynch, an autistic savant with a gift for codebreaking. Both are believable but Miko Hughes is astonishing  one of the best ever screen performances by a child. The scenes between the pair of them are really touching and you can believe that Willis really likes kids. Perhaps he does. The US government's pursuit of Lynch in this film may at first appear overly far-fetched and scaremongering. Then you remember the US attitude towards the British savant, Gary McKinnon, who was accused of perpetrating the biggest military computer hack of all time by hacking into 97 US military and NASA computers in 2002. Well, they didn't kill his mum and dad, and hunt him like an animal. But after 10 years of attempted extradition, and speculation of a 70-year jail term, maybe this story is just an exaggeration of reality, and not quite as ridiculous as some commentators have suggested. It's not really a downside but if you come to this film expecting a shoot-em-up action movie, you may be disappointed. It's much more than that and consequently slower  it's a touching drama with action scenes, and so we can forgive, just about, the pace through the middle of the film. The writing is actually very good and Pearson, Konner and Rosenthal all deserve credit. I did find the score a bit distracting. Sort of 'too big' and too 'James Bond' for the film. Scenes without music were better. Though the music being played at the club Jeffries visits was really good and I would have liked to have heard more of Koko Taylor (now no longer with us) belting out some blues. I was finding it difficult to see where this film was going. When Wills is with a kid, like in 16 blocks or Die Hard 4, you expect a visible end point, and there wasn't one. There was a sense of going around in circles. Until the last 5 minutes. Ultimately that cost it a couple of stars and the score lost another one. So seven out of ten for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    surely better then a 5.6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is nothing special but it surely worth more then a measly 5.6. The acting is good and the idea is new and original so I don't know why everyone hated it so much. It had a good story line and some decent action scenes so I was pleasantly surprised by this one. This movie is about a FBI agent who is sent to protect an autistic boy who is a target of assassins after accidentally cracking a top secret government code. I don't know why everybody hated this movie so much I actually thought it was pretty good. It was nothing special but in my eyes it was worth a watch no doubt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Gunston
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed this film and have found it equally watchable on repeated viewings. From the opening scene of a helicopter making its way towards a rural town accompanied by Barry's soulful music you just know that you are in for a rewarding movie experience. What elevates a routine and slightly clich&eacute;d thriller into a tense and emotionally satisfying film is the sensitive direction of Harold Becker, spot on casting, a story with emotional depth and John Barrys great score. Bruce Willis is ideally cast as the loner working against the system. The interaction between him and Miko Hughes as the autistic child Simon feels authentic. There is real chemistry in the exchanges between the 3 computer nerds who work for the NSA. And the scenes between Simon and his parents carry real emotional weight. This is not an action film. It is a film about story and character, and in some ways that makes it an old fashioned movie and all the better for it. It does, however, maintain tension through most of it's running time, a characteristic which is becoming rarer in modern films. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Your eyes see, but they do not observe, "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The novel 'Simple Simon' was written by Ryne Pearson and easily transferred to the silver screen, where it was directed expertly by Harold Becker. The movie tells the story of an autistic boy named Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who incredibly is able to decipher a top secret code created by the N.S.A. When the secret is uncovered, the top executive, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) believes his network of undercover agents and their identifies are in danger of being compromised and therefor orders a top assassin to execute Simon and his parents. The only defense for the boy is Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) a burned-out F.B.I agent who despite his short-comings is a tough-as-nails individual who learns Simon is a very special child and soon bonds with him. Along the way and amid the encroaching danger Jeffries receives help from Stacey a coffee shop patron (Kim Dickens) and fellow FBI agent Tommy B. Jordan (Chi McBride) The film is a combination of intrigue, murder and suspense with excitement filling in all the gaps. Willis and Hughes give a heartwarming and endearing performance. Recommended. ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really like this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsmemark47
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see the terrible reviews it got from some "important" reviewers. I'm watching it for at least the 4th time, just recorded it from satellite TV. Bruce Willis is really fine in this...I think few people appreciated how complex and skilled he is before this release, and I'm very glad they chose him for this role. Baldwin and the entire cast is very good and despite the not uncommon plot elements, the whole thing succeeds. Since the "Patriot Act" went into effect, I can give the actions of the government in this film a lot more credence...I rate it as an 8 out of 10, and I have seen extremely few 10's. mark
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was Bruce Willis at his finest. Although Mercury Rising was financially not well received, the film is a terrific thriller, solid acting, great story and just all around entertaining! One reviewer said this was more of a drama about autism and that's ludicrous. This is a thriller about a young boy who happens to have autism but to call this a drama or about autism at all is misleading. The film is part mystery, part thriller, part action and will entertain from beginning to end. Powerful performances from the lead cast make it worthwhile and riveting. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries and does a great job doing what he does best. No this isn't an award worthy performance or anything outstanding for Willis but he still carries the film well and Willis fans, like myself, will remember this. The star and stand out performance of this film is Miko Hughes who brilliantly plays autistic puzzle solver Simon. His performance is award worthy and I've always remembered it as one of my favorite performances. His chemistry with Willis is brilliant. Robert Stanton deserves mention in a small but pivotal role that I really enjoyed him in. Same could be said for Chi McBride who also does a good job. Alec Baldwin is good in his role as the villain. I would have liked a little more chemistry between him and Willis and I don't think he was outstanding in his role but he was definitely good. Kim Dickens is the female lead in the film and she does alright although I found her character very one dimensional for the most part. Harold Becker's direction is perhaps a little bland from time to time. It is true what some reviewers say that the film could have used just a little more action and some of the performances felt dry at times from Baldwin and Dickens, who are important to the entire film in many ways. Still the concept for the film is riveting and the story is delivered in a well paced, entertaining fashion. Anyone looking for a good thriller will not be steered wrong with this film. Its a movie that I watch from time to time again and again because I've always thought it was a great movie. Plenty of thrills, plenty of edge of your seat moments and a terrific performance from Hughes. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yet another disappointing action flick - 59%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For reasons that I can't explain, this has been on my "Must See" list for ages. I really don't know why - Bruce Willis action movies aren't exactly rare beasts and at some point, I figured that this had a plot that offered something a little different. Sadly, it turns out that it really wasn't worth the wait. It lacks the bluster of your usual Willis blockbuster and the story that I had high hopes for quickly finds itself becoming a gimmick. Willis plays FBI agent Art Jeffries, an undercover specialist who finds himself demoted to monitoring radio transmissions after a botched hostage assignment. However, he quickly finds himself assigned to look for a missing child - Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who is an autistic nine-year orphaned after his parents are murdered. But Art quickly finds threat there is more to it than that - Simon had accidentally cracked a top secret code after it inexplicably appeared in the pages of a puzzle magazine and was being sought by NSA operatives led by the gravel-voiced Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) and his murderous colleague Peter Burrell (Lindsey Ginter). Being an odd hybrid of espionage thriller and fugitive actioner, "Mercury Rising" successfully manages to be neither. The action is satisfying enough when it turns arrive in fits and starts but there is an awful lot of dialogue to get through in-between. Willis can pretty much sleepwalk through these kinda movies and sure enough, he simply doesn't engage you enough to care. He's also completely shown up by his young co-star as Hughes is brilliantly and genuinely heart-wrenching as the tortured savant. However, the worst actor by far is Baldwin who seems to be eerily foreshadowing his portrayal in "Team America: World Police". At times, he's simply appalling as he mumbles his way through his lines as though paying tribute to Michael Madsen. Maybe it was he who distracted me from the story which seemed confusing and never really explained what was happening. For example, imagine you are an experienced FBI agent looking after an infant suspect. Would you happily hand the care of the child over to a complete stranger in a caf&eacute; (played here by Kim Dickins) while you popped off to meet an informant because I'm not sure I would. "Mercury Rising" is annoyingly wasteful of its promising set-up, failing to deliver either a decent action movie or a gripping chase flick. It seems curiously restrained, as though it can't be bothered to be the nail-biting gripper it seems to aspire to. Maybe I'm being harsh on it given how long I've waited to watch it but for me, "Mercury Rising" is just as generic and forgettable as any other Nineties action flick. Shame, shame, shame.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unrealistic, slow thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) is the best FBI undercover agent. But a bad shootout leaves him an outcast. Then he gets the case of a missing autistic boy. The boy is an amazing puzzle solver, and was able to decipher a new NSA top secret code. Before anybody else knows the code has been cracked, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) wants the boy killed to protect all the secrets. The NSA part is over the top unbelievable. Sad to say, the autistic boy is a little bit annoying at times. Also it's hard to see how the cops can't figure out what happened at the hospital. The whole thing is a little thin. It's a passable thriller, but it's just too slow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of the road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unremarkable but moderately suspenseful thriller that mistakenly underplays the relationship between rogue FBI agent Bruce Willis and autistic kiddie Miko Hughes, who has cracked a top secret code and is now the target of villainous Alec Baldwin. The plot seems as though it was more intelligent somewhere in the script's journey to the screen, while characterisation is on the shallow side - 'Is that him or you you're talking about?' asks Willis's best friend. Hmm. I wonder... Willis seems to have cottoned on to this lack of depth, as he hasn't switched off the autopilot. I could have done without the scene in which a hit man stares Willis in the eye just long enough for him to be recognised before legging it, and the computery sound effect that helpfully clues us in whenever Hughes cracks the code is just annoying. Still, the movie is low-key enough that it remains plausible, it's technically slick, and the villain's demise is impressively fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like my cooking skills, fast and tasteless.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The NSA has developed what they think is an unbreakable code. They ran a test to see if anyone can decipher it by putting it in a puzzle magazine. Simon Lynch, an autistic boy, deciphers it and calls the NSA. The men in charge call their boss Kudrow, who is worried what might happen if this gets out, and orders Simon to be killed. The man he sends kills his parents and leaves when the police arrive. The FBI send Art Jeffries to look for the boy. Art finds Simon, and they go on the run...... In the nineties, Willis lost his star power a little, and every now and again, he starred in your typical generic action thriller. And like Striking Distance, Last Man Standing, and The Jackal, it's nothing special, but its a must for Willis fans. As always in these types of movies, it starts with a set-up, this one leading to a bit of a meltdown for Art. He's involved in a robbery gone wrong and would you know it, it ends in a boy getting killed, thus Art will stop at nothing to protect Simon. The rest of the film involves Willis and Hughes (who is excellent) on the run from your atypical assassin, with supporting characters getting killed every now and again, with only Chi McBride as a friend, as the police are after him too. Baldwin is fine, but its little more than an extended cameo, with the two stars only meeting the once. The ending is silly, but its a nice little thriller which won't challenge the brain, with a nice ending. Plus, this film must hold the record for how many people actually duck when the Amin hero cries 'get down'. It won't win Willis any more fans, but it does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a great film but a great performance by Miko Hughes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Love
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two great acting performances in this film. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries, an FBI agent with attitude. Miko Hughes plays Simon Lynch, an autistic savant with a gift for codebreaking. Both are believable but Miko Hughes is astonishing  one of the best ever screen performances by a child. The scenes between the pair of them are really touching and you can believe that Willis really likes kids. Perhaps he does. The US government's pursuit of Lynch in this film may at first appear overly far-fetched and scaremongering. Then you remember the US attitude towards the British savant, Gary McKinnon, who was accused of perpetrating the biggest military computer hack of all time by hacking into 97 US military and NASA computers in 2002. Well, they didn't kill his mum and dad, and hunt him like an animal. But after 10 years of attempted extradition, and speculation of a 70-year jail term, maybe this story is just an exaggeration of reality, and not quite as ridiculous as some commentators have suggested. It's not really a downside but if you come to this film expecting a shoot-em-up action movie, you may be disappointed. It's much more than that and consequently slower  it's a touching drama with action scenes, and so we can forgive, just about, the pace through the middle of the film. The writing is actually very good and Pearson, Konner and Rosenthal all deserve credit. I did find the score a bit distracting. Sort of 'too big' and too 'James Bond' for the film. Scenes without music were better. Though the music being played at the club Jeffries visits was really good and I would have liked to have heard more of Koko Taylor (now no longer with us) belting out some blues. I was finding it difficult to see where this film was going. When Wills is with a kid, like in 16 blocks or Die Hard 4, you expect a visible end point, and there wasn't one. There was a sense of going around in circles. Until the last 5 minutes. Ultimately that cost it a couple of stars and the score lost another one. So seven out of ten for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    surely better then a 5.6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is nothing special but it surely worth more then a measly 5.6. The acting is good and the idea is new and original so I don't know why everyone hated it so much. It had a good story line and some decent action scenes so I was pleasantly surprised by this one. This movie is about a FBI agent who is sent to protect an autistic boy who is a target of assassins after accidentally cracking a top secret government code. I don't know why everybody hated this movie so much I actually thought it was pretty good. It was nothing special but in my eyes it was worth a watch no doubt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Gunston
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed this film and have found it equally watchable on repeated viewings. From the opening scene of a helicopter making its way towards a rural town accompanied by Barry's soulful music you just know that you are in for a rewarding movie experience. What elevates a routine and slightly clich&eacute;d thriller into a tense and emotionally satisfying film is the sensitive direction of Harold Becker, spot on casting, a story with emotional depth and John Barrys great score. Bruce Willis is ideally cast as the loner working against the system. The interaction between him and Miko Hughes as the autistic child Simon feels authentic. There is real chemistry in the exchanges between the 3 computer nerds who work for the NSA. And the scenes between Simon and his parents carry real emotional weight. This is not an action film. It is a film about story and character, and in some ways that makes it an old fashioned movie and all the better for it. It does, however, maintain tension through most of it's running time, a characteristic which is becoming rarer in modern films. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Your eyes see, but they do not observe, "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The novel 'Simple Simon' was written by Ryne Pearson and easily transferred to the silver screen, where it was directed expertly by Harold Becker. The movie tells the story of an autistic boy named Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who incredibly is able to decipher a top secret code created by the N.S.A. When the secret is uncovered, the top executive, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) believes his network of undercover agents and their identifies are in danger of being compromised and therefor orders a top assassin to execute Simon and his parents. The only defense for the boy is Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) a burned-out F.B.I agent who despite his short-comings is a tough-as-nails individual who learns Simon is a very special child and soon bonds with him. Along the way and amid the encroaching danger Jeffries receives help from Stacey a coffee shop patron (Kim Dickens) and fellow FBI agent Tommy B. Jordan (Chi McBride) The film is a combination of intrigue, murder and suspense with excitement filling in all the gaps. Willis and Hughes give a heartwarming and endearing performance. Recommended. ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really like this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsmemark47
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see the terrible reviews it got from some "important" reviewers. I'm watching it for at least the 4th time, just recorded it from satellite TV. Bruce Willis is really fine in this...I think few people appreciated how complex and skilled he is before this release, and I'm very glad they chose him for this role. Baldwin and the entire cast is very good and despite the not uncommon plot elements, the whole thing succeeds. Since the "Patriot Act" went into effect, I can give the actions of the government in this film a lot more credence...I rate it as an 8 out of 10, and I have seen extremely few 10's. mark
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was Bruce Willis at his finest. Although Mercury Rising was financially not well received, the film is a terrific thriller, solid acting, great story and just all around entertaining! One reviewer said this was more of a drama about autism and that's ludicrous. This is a thriller about a young boy who happens to have autism but to call this a drama or about autism at all is misleading. The film is part mystery, part thriller, part action and will entertain from beginning to end. Powerful performances from the lead cast make it worthwhile and riveting. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries and does a great job doing what he does best. No this isn't an award worthy performance or anything outstanding for Willis but he still carries the film well and Willis fans, like myself, will remember this. The star and stand out performance of this film is Miko Hughes who brilliantly plays autistic puzzle solver Simon. His performance is award worthy and I've always remembered it as one of my favorite performances. His chemistry with Willis is brilliant. Robert Stanton deserves mention in a small but pivotal role that I really enjoyed him in. Same could be said for Chi McBride who also does a good job. Alec Baldwin is good in his role as the villain. I would have liked a little more chemistry between him and Willis and I don't think he was outstanding in his role but he was definitely good. Kim Dickens is the female lead in the film and she does alright although I found her character very one dimensional for the most part. Harold Becker's direction is perhaps a little bland from time to time. It is true what some reviewers say that the film could have used just a little more action and some of the performances felt dry at times from Baldwin and Dickens, who are important to the entire film in many ways. Still the concept for the film is riveting and the story is delivered in a well paced, entertaining fashion. Anyone looking for a good thriller will not be steered wrong with this film. Its a movie that I watch from time to time again and again because I've always thought it was a great movie. Plenty of thrills, plenty of edge of your seat moments and a terrific performance from Hughes. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yet another disappointing action flick - 59%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For reasons that I can't explain, this has been on my "Must See" list for ages. I really don't know why - Bruce Willis action movies aren't exactly rare beasts and at some point, I figured that this had a plot that offered something a little different. Sadly, it turns out that it really wasn't worth the wait. It lacks the bluster of your usual Willis blockbuster and the story that I had high hopes for quickly finds itself becoming a gimmick. Willis plays FBI agent Art Jeffries, an undercover specialist who finds himself demoted to monitoring radio transmissions after a botched hostage assignment. However, he quickly finds himself assigned to look for a missing child - Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who is an autistic nine-year orphaned after his parents are murdered. But Art quickly finds threat there is more to it than that - Simon had accidentally cracked a top secret code after it inexplicably appeared in the pages of a puzzle magazine and was being sought by NSA operatives led by the gravel-voiced Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) and his murderous colleague Peter Burrell (Lindsey Ginter). Being an odd hybrid of espionage thriller and fugitive actioner, "Mercury Rising" successfully manages to be neither. The action is satisfying enough when it turns arrive in fits and starts but there is an awful lot of dialogue to get through in-between. Willis can pretty much sleepwalk through these kinda movies and sure enough, he simply doesn't engage you enough to care. He's also completely shown up by his young co-star as Hughes is brilliantly and genuinely heart-wrenching as the tortured savant. However, the worst actor by far is Baldwin who seems to be eerily foreshadowing his portrayal in "Team America: World Police". At times, he's simply appalling as he mumbles his way through his lines as though paying tribute to Michael Madsen. Maybe it was he who distracted me from the story which seemed confusing and never really explained what was happening. For example, imagine you are an experienced FBI agent looking after an infant suspect. Would you happily hand the care of the child over to a complete stranger in a caf&eacute; (played here by Kim Dickins) while you popped off to meet an informant because I'm not sure I would. "Mercury Rising" is annoyingly wasteful of its promising set-up, failing to deliver either a decent action movie or a gripping chase flick. It seems curiously restrained, as though it can't be bothered to be the nail-biting gripper it seems to aspire to. Maybe I'm being harsh on it given how long I've waited to watch it but for me, "Mercury Rising" is just as generic and forgettable as any other Nineties action flick. Shame, shame, shame.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unrealistic, slow thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) is the best FBI undercover agent. But a bad shootout leaves him an outcast. Then he gets the case of a missing autistic boy. The boy is an amazing puzzle solver, and was able to decipher a new NSA top secret code. Before anybody else knows the code has been cracked, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) wants the boy killed to protect all the secrets. The NSA part is over the top unbelievable. Sad to say, the autistic boy is a little bit annoying at times. Also it's hard to see how the cops can't figure out what happened at the hospital. The whole thing is a little thin. It's a passable thriller, but it's just too slow.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of the road
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unremarkable but moderately suspenseful thriller that mistakenly underplays the relationship between rogue FBI agent Bruce Willis and autistic kiddie Miko Hughes, who has cracked a top secret code and is now the target of villainous Alec Baldwin. The plot seems as though it was more intelligent somewhere in the script's journey to the screen, while characterisation is on the shallow side - 'Is that him or you you're talking about?' asks Willis's best friend. Hmm. I wonder... Willis seems to have cottoned on to this lack of depth, as he hasn't switched off the autopilot. I could have done without the scene in which a hit man stares Willis in the eye just long enough for him to be recognised before legging it, and the computery sound effect that helpfully clues us in whenever Hughes cracks the code is just annoying. Still, the movie is low-key enough that it remains plausible, it's technically slick, and the villain's demise is impressively fresh.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like my cooking skills, fast and tasteless.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The NSA has developed what they think is an unbreakable code. They ran a test to see if anyone can decipher it by putting it in a puzzle magazine. Simon Lynch, an autistic boy, deciphers it and calls the NSA. The men in charge call their boss Kudrow, who is worried what might happen if this gets out, and orders Simon to be killed. The man he sends kills his parents and leaves when the police arrive. The FBI send Art Jeffries to look for the boy. Art finds Simon, and they go on the run...... In the nineties, Willis lost his star power a little, and every now and again, he starred in your typical generic action thriller. And like Striking Distance, Last Man Standing, and The Jackal, it's nothing special, but its a must for Willis fans. As always in these types of movies, it starts with a set-up, this one leading to a bit of a meltdown for Art. He's involved in a robbery gone wrong and would you know it, it ends in a boy getting killed, thus Art will stop at nothing to protect Simon. The rest of the film involves Willis and Hughes (who is excellent) on the run from your atypical assassin, with supporting characters getting killed every now and again, with only Chi McBride as a friend, as the police are after him too. Baldwin is fine, but its little more than an extended cameo, with the two stars only meeting the once. The ending is silly, but its a nice little thriller which won't challenge the brain, with a nice ending. Plus, this film must hold the record for how many people actually duck when the Amin hero cries 'get down'. It won't win Willis any more fans, but it does its job.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a great film but a great performance by Miko Hughes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Love
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two great acting performances in this film. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries, an FBI agent with attitude. Miko Hughes plays Simon Lynch, an autistic savant with a gift for codebreaking. Both are believable but Miko Hughes is astonishing  one of the best ever screen performances by a child. The scenes between the pair of them are really touching and you can believe that Willis really likes kids. Perhaps he does. The US government's pursuit of Lynch in this film may at first appear overly far-fetched and scaremongering. Then you remember the US attitude towards the British savant, Gary McKinnon, who was accused of perpetrating the biggest military computer hack of all time by hacking into 97 US military and NASA computers in 2002. Well, they didn't kill his mum and dad, and hunt him like an animal. But after 10 years of attempted extradition, and speculation of a 70-year jail term, maybe this story is just an exaggeration of reality, and not quite as ridiculous as some commentators have suggested. It's not really a downside but if you come to this film expecting a shoot-em-up action movie, you may be disappointed. It's much more than that and consequently slower  it's a touching drama with action scenes, and so we can forgive, just about, the pace through the middle of the film. The writing is actually very good and Pearson, Konner and Rosenthal all deserve credit. I did find the score a bit distracting. Sort of 'too big' and too 'James Bond' for the film. Scenes without music were better. Though the music being played at the club Jeffries visits was really good and I would have liked to have heard more of Koko Taylor (now no longer with us) belting out some blues. I was finding it difficult to see where this film was going. When Wills is with a kid, like in 16 blocks or Die Hard 4, you expect a visible end point, and there wasn't one. There was a sense of going around in circles. Until the last 5 minutes. Ultimately that cost it a couple of stars and the score lost another one. So seven out of ten for this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    surely better then a 5.6
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deatman9
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is nothing special but it surely worth more then a measly 5.6. The acting is good and the idea is new and original so I don't know why everyone hated it so much. It had a good story line and some decent action scenes so I was pleasantly surprised by this one. This movie is about a FBI agent who is sent to protect an autistic boy who is a target of assassins after accidentally cracking a top secret government code. I don't know why everybody hated this movie so much I actually thought it was pretty good. It was nothing special but in my eyes it was worth a watch no doubt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mark Gunston
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed this film and have found it equally watchable on repeated viewings. From the opening scene of a helicopter making its way towards a rural town accompanied by Barry's soulful music you just know that you are in for a rewarding movie experience. What elevates a routine and slightly clich&eacute;d thriller into a tense and emotionally satisfying film is the sensitive direction of Harold Becker, spot on casting, a story with emotional depth and John Barrys great score. Bruce Willis is ideally cast as the loner working against the system. The interaction between him and Miko Hughes as the autistic child Simon feels authentic. There is real chemistry in the exchanges between the 3 computer nerds who work for the NSA. And the scenes between Simon and his parents carry real emotional weight. This is not an action film. It is a film about story and character, and in some ways that makes it an old fashioned movie and all the better for it. It does, however, maintain tension through most of it's running time, a characteristic which is becoming rarer in modern films. Definitely recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " Your eyes see, but they do not observe, "
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The novel 'Simple Simon' was written by Ryne Pearson and easily transferred to the silver screen, where it was directed expertly by Harold Becker. The movie tells the story of an autistic boy named Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who incredibly is able to decipher a top secret code created by the N.S.A. When the secret is uncovered, the top executive, Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) believes his network of undercover agents and their identifies are in danger of being compromised and therefor orders a top assassin to execute Simon and his parents. The only defense for the boy is Art Jeffries (Bruce Willis) a burned-out F.B.I agent who despite his short-comings is a tough-as-nails individual who learns Simon is a very special child and soon bonds with him. Along the way and amid the encroaching danger Jeffries receives help from Stacey a coffee shop patron (Kim Dickens) and fellow FBI agent Tommy B. Jordan (Chi McBride) The film is a combination of intrigue, murder and suspense with excitement filling in all the gaps. Willis and Hughes give a heartwarming and endearing performance. Recommended. ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I really like this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itsmemark47
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was surprised to see the terrible reviews it got from some "important" reviewers. I'm watching it for at least the 4th time, just recorded it from satellite TV. Bruce Willis is really fine in this...I think few people appreciated how complex and skilled he is before this release, and I'm very glad they chose him for this role. Baldwin and the entire cast is very good and despite the not uncommon plot elements, the whole thing succeeds. Since the "Patriot Act" went into effect, I can give the actions of the government in this film a lot more credence...I rate it as an 8 out of 10, and I have seen extremely few 10's. mark
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A terrific action thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was Bruce Willis at his finest. Although Mercury Rising was financially not well received, the film is a terrific thriller, solid acting, great story and just all around entertaining! One reviewer said this was more of a drama about autism and that's ludicrous. This is a thriller about a young boy who happens to have autism but to call this a drama or about autism at all is misleading. The film is part mystery, part thriller, part action and will entertain from beginning to end. Powerful performances from the lead cast make it worthwhile and riveting. Bruce Willis plays Art Jeffries and does a great job doing what he does best. No this isn't an award worthy performance or anything outstanding for Willis but he still carries the film well and Willis fans, like myself, will remember this. The star and stand out performance of this film is Miko Hughes who brilliantly plays autistic puzzle solver Simon. His performance is award worthy and I've always remembered it as one of my favorite performances. His chemistry with Willis is brilliant. Robert Stanton deserves mention in a small but pivotal role that I really enjoyed him in. Same could be said for Chi McBride who also does a good job. Alec Baldwin is good in his role as the villain. I would have liked a little more chemistry between him and Willis and I don't think he was outstanding in his role but he was definitely good. Kim Dickens is the female lead in the film and she does alright although I found her character very one dimensional for the most part. Harold Becker's direction is perhaps a little bland from time to time. It is true what some reviewers say that the film could have used just a little more action and some of the performances felt dry at times from Baldwin and Dickens, who are important to the entire film in many ways. Still the concept for the film is riveting and the story is delivered in a well paced, entertaining fashion. Anyone looking for a good thriller will not be steered wrong with this film. Its a movie that I watch from time to time again and again because I've always thought it was a great movie. Plenty of thrills, plenty of edge of your seat moments and a terrific performance from Hughes. 8.5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yet another disappointing action flick - 59%
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Benjamin Cox
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For reasons that I can't explain, this has been on my "Must See" list for ages. I really don't know why - Bruce Willis action movies aren't exactly rare beasts and at some point, I figured that this had a plot that offered something a little different. Sadly, it turns out that it really wasn't worth the wait. It lacks the bluster of your usual Willis blockbuster and the story that I had high hopes for quickly finds itself becoming a gimmick. Willis plays FBI agent Art Jeffries, an undercover specialist who finds himself demoted to monitoring radio transmissions after a botched hostage assignment. However, he quickly finds himself assigned to look for a missing child - Simon Lynch (Miko Hughes) who is an autistic nine-year orphaned after his parents are murdered. But Art quickly finds threat there is more to it than that - Simon had accidentally cracked a top secret code after it inexplicably appeared in the pages of a puzzle magazine and was being sought by NSA operatives led by the gravel-voiced Nick Kudrow (Alec Baldwin) and his murderous colleague Peter Burrell (Lindsey Ginter). Being an odd hybrid of espionage thriller and fugitive actioner, "Mercury Rising" successfully manages to be neither. The action is satisfying enough when it turns arrive in fits and starts but there is an awful lot of dialogue to get through in-between. Willis can pretty much sleepwalk through these kinda movies and sure enough, he simply doesn't engage you enough to care. He's also completely shown up by his young co-star as Hughes is brilliantly and genuinely heart-wrenching as the tortured savant. However, the worst actor by far is Baldwin who seems to be eerily foreshadowing his portrayal in "Team America: World Police". At times, he's simply appalling as he mumbles his way through his lines as though paying tribute to Michael Madsen. Maybe it was he who distracted me from the story which seemed confusing and never really explained what was happening. For example, imagine you are an experienced FBI agent looking after an infant suspect. Would you happily hand the care of the child over to a complete stranger in a caf&eacute; (played here by Kim Dickins) while you popped off to meet an informant because I'm not sure I would. "Mercury Rising" is annoyingly wasteful of its promising set-up, failing to deliver either a decent action movie or a gripping chase flick. It seems curiously restrained, as though it can't be bothered to be the nail-biting gripper it seems to aspire to. Maybe I'm being harsh on it given how long I've waited to watch it but for me, "Mercury Rising" is just as generic and forgettable as any other Nineties action flick. Shame, shame, shame.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
