<filme>
 <id>
  918
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120632
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1998
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Cidade dos Anjos
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Inspired by the modern classic, Wings of Desire, City involves an angel (Cage) who is spotted by a doctor in an operating room. Franz plays Cage's buddy who somehow knows a lot about angels.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Seth is an angel who accompanies the spirits of the recently dead to the ever after. Seth has never been human and so has has never experienced touch or taste. When in the hospital however he comes across Dr. Maggie Rice, a brilliant young heart surgeon who is devoted to her profession and her patients. Seth has the power to let himself be seen but Maggie finds him far too mysterious. Seth also meets a patient, Nathaniel Messinger, who has news for him - he too was once an angel like Seth but chose to fall to Earth and become human. Seth makes a decision on his future, which does not turn out as he had expected.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   angel
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fall
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   doctor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hospital
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Brad Silberling
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Wim Wenders
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Peter Handke
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Nicolas Cage
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Meg Ryan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Andre Braugher
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need more life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the German film "Wings of Desire" (1987), Seth (Nicolas Cage) is an angel. They can't feel, taste, be touched, or seen. Their job is to bring the dead to the afterlife. Dr. Maggie Rice (Meg Ryan) is a sharp young heart surgeon who feels there's something more going on after the death of her last patient. One day, Maggie sees Seth. At first she thinks he's simply a patient at the hospital. But soon she realizes that he is much more mysterious than that, and she quickly falls for him. Nathaniel Messinger (Dennis Franz) is Maggie's patient, and surprisingly a former angel. He tells Seth his choice to fall to Earth. This is a very slow movie. Nicolas Cage is doing his empty look, and his tired speaking voice. Meg Ryan does her best to inject chemistry into this film. It's a very slow romance and it works on that level. When he finally falls to Earth, he does a complete 180. Subtlety has never been Cage's strong point. It's too jarring, and too late. The problem is the lack of humor. I think a few well placed jokes early can enliven the whole film. For a movie about life and death, they need more life in it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    City of Somnambulance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want to make it clear that I'm not against representing the concept of angels in movies... It's just laughable the way it's done in this instance - Cage walking around, perma-brooding, dressed all in black, acting stoned to convey his 'otherworldliness' and constantly speaking in hushed tones... and then, to contrast, you cast Dennis Franz as the 'happy' angel who's crossed over into human existence (See? He must be happy because of his ruddy complexion and physique... so we'll make sure that he's eating when the viewer sees him, just so we can hammer home the point... ) The crisis that provokes the climax of the movie is utterly ridiculous, in the way that it's shown. I mean, what do you expect when you're riding the bike with your eyes closed, and a "Look ma, no hands!" expression?! ... and why would you do this? Joy is not an excuse for stupidity. When you've seen movies such as "The Seventh Seal", which contemplates the realities of human existence, then movies like "City of Angels" just seem manipulative, you know? I have yet to see it, but I have no doubt that "Wings of Desire" (of which this is apparently a pandering remake) will bear this out, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible, terrible movie *contains minor spoilers*
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thejeenius
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh, look! It's one of those typical Hollywood remakes that no one actually cares about! Who would've thought? To sum it up: your time will be better spent doing something else. This movie reeks of tear-jerking, prototypical love scenes and particularly cheesy effects. Even when Nicholas (that stupid angel) takes off his shoes at the beach you can tell something's not right. You really have to wonder if anyone's supposed to take this seriously with all the flaws that it has. Also, if you're not in on the whole "angel" thing this movie won't do for you. There's really nothing else to say here. It's the epitome of blandness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some things are true whether you believe them or not.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    catherinemccutcheon100
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece just like the movie that it's based on 'Wings of Desire'. A lot of people think this movie is rubbish, it's plot is unbelievable, acting is wooden blah blah blah. People (myself included) love a film where an alien is left on earth and befriends a young boy!!!! why can't angels exist all around us listening to our thoughts, our fears and help us through our day simply just being around us? This to me is what makes this film work, what if? as the film states, some things are true whether you believe them or not. The acting is first class, Meg Ryan in a change to her normal comedy plays Maggie Rice perfectly, (the whole science and faith question is what she struggles with the most)Nicholas Cage plays he angel Seth to perfection as well so i really don't see how people can't like this film?! The main with this film is you really just have to trust where it's going to, believe me the end of this film angers me to no end but hey i'm a romantic and I weep like a child always have and always have.One of my all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Meg Ryan is Pure Magic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can say more about Amazing Love story movie blended by Meg Ryan's massive sensuality, beauty and priceless screenplay? Meg captives and shine just for her appearance. from this movie definitely I falled in love for Meg. I Was 17 aged when i watched nominated and recommended by my brother-in- law. I was in total constant Meg Ryan Amazement cause some her currently movies as already followed and watched in middle-late 1998. I just loved and adored this movie and already I cried a lot of ocean for Tears, Nowadays,I became a Meg Ryan's Unconditional Fan. MEG RYAN IS AMAZING PURE EMOTION,FANTASY AND INSPIRATION AND PASSION.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ole' Yeller might just choke up on this one.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryan mcdaniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First off Im a straight guy who prefers movies like Die-hard, Star Wars and Pulp fiction but I have to say, this movie really knocked me back. Yeah, its a chick-flick, but its a perfect movie to curl up on the couch with your significant other. Make sure you watch this with someone you really like, otherwise you could be sending the wrong message and be in real trouble. As for the movie, I thought it was Cages best role aside from Leaving Las Vegas and Meg Ryan was her typical adorable self. The first scene is really disturbing but sets the mood for the rest of the film. As a Christian there were a few things that bothered me about the "angel" aspect of the movie but it was of little consequence to the overall strength of the movie. This is not a party movie, you will not walk away felling particularly happy but there is a contentment it portrays that will stay with you for a long time. This is a movie you will probably want to watch more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grey Jane
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No words can describe the awfulness of this film. I watched with a friend, loaded with cups of coffee, and yet within thirty minutes we were out from the numerous awkward silences that lulled us to sleep. We snoozed until near to the end, but honestly think we didn't miss much. Nicholas Cage acts like a pre-Twilight Robert Pattinson. Creepy. He is so creepy. The way he obsesses over Maggie is quite unnerving and uncomfortable. He acts like a dumb puppy. The story line is predictable and disappointing, with the 'angels' always looking rather awkward and out-of-place. The characters were for the most part unlikable, though it has to be said that Meg Ryan was okay. She pretty. Overall, if you're the sort of person who likes soppy, lame romance or Twilight, watch it. If not, STAY AWAY. GOT IT? >:)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joni-h
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is worth falling for ,when u really want to hold the hands of Magi,feel her,touch her and really leave the eternity to just be with her. The theme was so wonderful that u really want to live with the characters and just hope to be one of them, that proves why man is afraid to die ,because he know that he will lose all the sensations for what human being is really crafted by the god, to live in pain leaving the eternity,but to feel love.The characters are excellently played,even the scores following were just letting you feel the theme and live with the characters. I really can't understand the harsh notes of critics and there sharp views but I can feel that this movie is worth falling for, even if you have to loose your eternity.This is my first comment on this site but I feel may be I delayed it only to give my first one to this one only.(24-12-05)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie touches my heart - favorite of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jax_lady2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much. It's a favorite and I rarely watch a movie more than once, because you know what will happen. This movie I've seen several times. It touches my soul. This is Nicholas Casge's best movie in my opinion. He and Meg Ryan are such a perfect match in this movie. I also love how the angels listen to people think. The connection these two characters have is so amazing. I want to find a love like that in my lifetime. It exemplifies how a love can touch your soul and no matter how much or how little time you have together it's worth it. When you see the comparison of how empty the Dr's eye are (Meg's boyfriend) in comparison to the way Seth look at her, you can see the love there. I think this movie was so under-appreciated and I felt compelled to write a review. I've never written one before, but this is well worth a great review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yeeeehhh, Hollywood ripped off another foreign movie!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ricardopthomaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just had to see, folks, how much Hollywood would drag this to it's complete sappiness. I was fortunate enough to being able to see "Der Himmel &Uuml;ber Berlin" (Wings of Desire) from 1987 and it's sequel, "In Weiter Ferne, so nah!" (Faraway, So Close!) from 1993, both wonderful films by German director Wim Wenders, and believe me, when you see them you just don't see the time passing, they are very, very slow, but these movies keeps you so focused that you just feels like flying over Berlin with those angels. With this Hollywood mock up, it's the other way around. There's so much clich&eacute;s and so much cheesiness, that you keep looking on your watch how much time is left for the movie to end. Seth is a complete sappy version from Damiel, the angel from the Wenders films. It just angers me thinking why Hollywood feels the need of having their own version of foreign movies, why they can't just let these movies alone? Despite some remakes that really respects the original flick and sometimes even tends to pay homage to them, this one is a total flop. It drains all the philosophical and elaborate lines from the original Wenders films and tries to get to our emotions with gratuitous cheesy lines and dialogs. Avoid this film. Watch Wenders masterpieces instead. Damiel and Cassiel in the originals are much better pals than Cage and Braugher. Plus in the original films we have Peter Falk, the Columbo to make us good company as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need more life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the German film "Wings of Desire" (1987), Seth (Nicolas Cage) is an angel. They can't feel, taste, be touched, or seen. Their job is to bring the dead to the afterlife. Dr. Maggie Rice (Meg Ryan) is a sharp young heart surgeon who feels there's something more going on after the death of her last patient. One day, Maggie sees Seth. At first she thinks he's simply a patient at the hospital. But soon she realizes that he is much more mysterious than that, and she quickly falls for him. Nathaniel Messinger (Dennis Franz) is Maggie's patient, and surprisingly a former angel. He tells Seth his choice to fall to Earth. This is a very slow movie. Nicolas Cage is doing his empty look, and his tired speaking voice. Meg Ryan does her best to inject chemistry into this film. It's a very slow romance and it works on that level. When he finally falls to Earth, he does a complete 180. Subtlety has never been Cage's strong point. It's too jarring, and too late. The problem is the lack of humor. I think a few well placed jokes early can enliven the whole film. For a movie about life and death, they need more life in it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    City of Somnambulance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want to make it clear that I'm not against representing the concept of angels in movies... It's just laughable the way it's done in this instance - Cage walking around, perma-brooding, dressed all in black, acting stoned to convey his 'otherworldliness' and constantly speaking in hushed tones... and then, to contrast, you cast Dennis Franz as the 'happy' angel who's crossed over into human existence (See? He must be happy because of his ruddy complexion and physique... so we'll make sure that he's eating when the viewer sees him, just so we can hammer home the point... ) The crisis that provokes the climax of the movie is utterly ridiculous, in the way that it's shown. I mean, what do you expect when you're riding the bike with your eyes closed, and a "Look ma, no hands!" expression?! ... and why would you do this? Joy is not an excuse for stupidity. When you've seen movies such as "The Seventh Seal", which contemplates the realities of human existence, then movies like "City of Angels" just seem manipulative, you know? I have yet to see it, but I have no doubt that "Wings of Desire" (of which this is apparently a pandering remake) will bear this out, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible, terrible movie *contains minor spoilers*
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thejeenius
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh, look! It's one of those typical Hollywood remakes that no one actually cares about! Who would've thought? To sum it up: your time will be better spent doing something else. This movie reeks of tear-jerking, prototypical love scenes and particularly cheesy effects. Even when Nicholas (that stupid angel) takes off his shoes at the beach you can tell something's not right. You really have to wonder if anyone's supposed to take this seriously with all the flaws that it has. Also, if you're not in on the whole "angel" thing this movie won't do for you. There's really nothing else to say here. It's the epitome of blandness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some things are true whether you believe them or not.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    catherinemccutcheon100
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece just like the movie that it's based on 'Wings of Desire'. A lot of people think this movie is rubbish, it's plot is unbelievable, acting is wooden blah blah blah. People (myself included) love a film where an alien is left on earth and befriends a young boy!!!! why can't angels exist all around us listening to our thoughts, our fears and help us through our day simply just being around us? This to me is what makes this film work, what if? as the film states, some things are true whether you believe them or not. The acting is first class, Meg Ryan in a change to her normal comedy plays Maggie Rice perfectly, (the whole science and faith question is what she struggles with the most)Nicholas Cage plays he angel Seth to perfection as well so i really don't see how people can't like this film?! The main with this film is you really just have to trust where it's going to, believe me the end of this film angers me to no end but hey i'm a romantic and I weep like a child always have and always have.One of my all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Meg Ryan is Pure Magic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can say more about Amazing Love story movie blended by Meg Ryan's massive sensuality, beauty and priceless screenplay? Meg captives and shine just for her appearance. from this movie definitely I falled in love for Meg. I Was 17 aged when i watched nominated and recommended by my brother-in- law. I was in total constant Meg Ryan Amazement cause some her currently movies as already followed and watched in middle-late 1998. I just loved and adored this movie and already I cried a lot of ocean for Tears, Nowadays,I became a Meg Ryan's Unconditional Fan. MEG RYAN IS AMAZING PURE EMOTION,FANTASY AND INSPIRATION AND PASSION.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ole' Yeller might just choke up on this one.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryan mcdaniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First off Im a straight guy who prefers movies like Die-hard, Star Wars and Pulp fiction but I have to say, this movie really knocked me back. Yeah, its a chick-flick, but its a perfect movie to curl up on the couch with your significant other. Make sure you watch this with someone you really like, otherwise you could be sending the wrong message and be in real trouble. As for the movie, I thought it was Cages best role aside from Leaving Las Vegas and Meg Ryan was her typical adorable self. The first scene is really disturbing but sets the mood for the rest of the film. As a Christian there were a few things that bothered me about the "angel" aspect of the movie but it was of little consequence to the overall strength of the movie. This is not a party movie, you will not walk away felling particularly happy but there is a contentment it portrays that will stay with you for a long time. This is a movie you will probably want to watch more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grey Jane
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No words can describe the awfulness of this film. I watched with a friend, loaded with cups of coffee, and yet within thirty minutes we were out from the numerous awkward silences that lulled us to sleep. We snoozed until near to the end, but honestly think we didn't miss much. Nicholas Cage acts like a pre-Twilight Robert Pattinson. Creepy. He is so creepy. The way he obsesses over Maggie is quite unnerving and uncomfortable. He acts like a dumb puppy. The story line is predictable and disappointing, with the 'angels' always looking rather awkward and out-of-place. The characters were for the most part unlikable, though it has to be said that Meg Ryan was okay. She pretty. Overall, if you're the sort of person who likes soppy, lame romance or Twilight, watch it. If not, STAY AWAY. GOT IT? >:)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joni-h
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is worth falling for ,when u really want to hold the hands of Magi,feel her,touch her and really leave the eternity to just be with her. The theme was so wonderful that u really want to live with the characters and just hope to be one of them, that proves why man is afraid to die ,because he know that he will lose all the sensations for what human being is really crafted by the god, to live in pain leaving the eternity,but to feel love.The characters are excellently played,even the scores following were just letting you feel the theme and live with the characters. I really can't understand the harsh notes of critics and there sharp views but I can feel that this movie is worth falling for, even if you have to loose your eternity.This is my first comment on this site but I feel may be I delayed it only to give my first one to this one only.(24-12-05)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie touches my heart - favorite of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jax_lady2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much. It's a favorite and I rarely watch a movie more than once, because you know what will happen. This movie I've seen several times. It touches my soul. This is Nicholas Casge's best movie in my opinion. He and Meg Ryan are such a perfect match in this movie. I also love how the angels listen to people think. The connection these two characters have is so amazing. I want to find a love like that in my lifetime. It exemplifies how a love can touch your soul and no matter how much or how little time you have together it's worth it. When you see the comparison of how empty the Dr's eye are (Meg's boyfriend) in comparison to the way Seth look at her, you can see the love there. I think this movie was so under-appreciated and I felt compelled to write a review. I've never written one before, but this is well worth a great review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yeeeehhh, Hollywood ripped off another foreign movie!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ricardopthomaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just had to see, folks, how much Hollywood would drag this to it's complete sappiness. I was fortunate enough to being able to see "Der Himmel &Uuml;ber Berlin" (Wings of Desire) from 1987 and it's sequel, "In Weiter Ferne, so nah!" (Faraway, So Close!) from 1993, both wonderful films by German director Wim Wenders, and believe me, when you see them you just don't see the time passing, they are very, very slow, but these movies keeps you so focused that you just feels like flying over Berlin with those angels. With this Hollywood mock up, it's the other way around. There's so much clich&eacute;s and so much cheesiness, that you keep looking on your watch how much time is left for the movie to end. Seth is a complete sappy version from Damiel, the angel from the Wenders films. It just angers me thinking why Hollywood feels the need of having their own version of foreign movies, why they can't just let these movies alone? Despite some remakes that really respects the original flick and sometimes even tends to pay homage to them, this one is a total flop. It drains all the philosophical and elaborate lines from the original Wenders films and tries to get to our emotions with gratuitous cheesy lines and dialogs. Avoid this film. Watch Wenders masterpieces instead. Damiel and Cassiel in the originals are much better pals than Cage and Braugher. Plus in the original films we have Peter Falk, the Columbo to make us good company as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need more life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the German film "Wings of Desire" (1987), Seth (Nicolas Cage) is an angel. They can't feel, taste, be touched, or seen. Their job is to bring the dead to the afterlife. Dr. Maggie Rice (Meg Ryan) is a sharp young heart surgeon who feels there's something more going on after the death of her last patient. One day, Maggie sees Seth. At first she thinks he's simply a patient at the hospital. But soon she realizes that he is much more mysterious than that, and she quickly falls for him. Nathaniel Messinger (Dennis Franz) is Maggie's patient, and surprisingly a former angel. He tells Seth his choice to fall to Earth. This is a very slow movie. Nicolas Cage is doing his empty look, and his tired speaking voice. Meg Ryan does her best to inject chemistry into this film. It's a very slow romance and it works on that level. When he finally falls to Earth, he does a complete 180. Subtlety has never been Cage's strong point. It's too jarring, and too late. The problem is the lack of humor. I think a few well placed jokes early can enliven the whole film. For a movie about life and death, they need more life in it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    City of Somnambulance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want to make it clear that I'm not against representing the concept of angels in movies... It's just laughable the way it's done in this instance - Cage walking around, perma-brooding, dressed all in black, acting stoned to convey his 'otherworldliness' and constantly speaking in hushed tones... and then, to contrast, you cast Dennis Franz as the 'happy' angel who's crossed over into human existence (See? He must be happy because of his ruddy complexion and physique... so we'll make sure that he's eating when the viewer sees him, just so we can hammer home the point... ) The crisis that provokes the climax of the movie is utterly ridiculous, in the way that it's shown. I mean, what do you expect when you're riding the bike with your eyes closed, and a "Look ma, no hands!" expression?! ... and why would you do this? Joy is not an excuse for stupidity. When you've seen movies such as "The Seventh Seal", which contemplates the realities of human existence, then movies like "City of Angels" just seem manipulative, you know? I have yet to see it, but I have no doubt that "Wings of Desire" (of which this is apparently a pandering remake) will bear this out, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible, terrible movie *contains minor spoilers*
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thejeenius
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh, look! It's one of those typical Hollywood remakes that no one actually cares about! Who would've thought? To sum it up: your time will be better spent doing something else. This movie reeks of tear-jerking, prototypical love scenes and particularly cheesy effects. Even when Nicholas (that stupid angel) takes off his shoes at the beach you can tell something's not right. You really have to wonder if anyone's supposed to take this seriously with all the flaws that it has. Also, if you're not in on the whole "angel" thing this movie won't do for you. There's really nothing else to say here. It's the epitome of blandness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some things are true whether you believe them or not.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    catherinemccutcheon100
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece just like the movie that it's based on 'Wings of Desire'. A lot of people think this movie is rubbish, it's plot is unbelievable, acting is wooden blah blah blah. People (myself included) love a film where an alien is left on earth and befriends a young boy!!!! why can't angels exist all around us listening to our thoughts, our fears and help us through our day simply just being around us? This to me is what makes this film work, what if? as the film states, some things are true whether you believe them or not. The acting is first class, Meg Ryan in a change to her normal comedy plays Maggie Rice perfectly, (the whole science and faith question is what she struggles with the most)Nicholas Cage plays he angel Seth to perfection as well so i really don't see how people can't like this film?! The main with this film is you really just have to trust where it's going to, believe me the end of this film angers me to no end but hey i'm a romantic and I weep like a child always have and always have.One of my all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Meg Ryan is Pure Magic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can say more about Amazing Love story movie blended by Meg Ryan's massive sensuality, beauty and priceless screenplay? Meg captives and shine just for her appearance. from this movie definitely I falled in love for Meg. I Was 17 aged when i watched nominated and recommended by my brother-in- law. I was in total constant Meg Ryan Amazement cause some her currently movies as already followed and watched in middle-late 1998. I just loved and adored this movie and already I cried a lot of ocean for Tears, Nowadays,I became a Meg Ryan's Unconditional Fan. MEG RYAN IS AMAZING PURE EMOTION,FANTASY AND INSPIRATION AND PASSION.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ole' Yeller might just choke up on this one.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryan mcdaniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First off Im a straight guy who prefers movies like Die-hard, Star Wars and Pulp fiction but I have to say, this movie really knocked me back. Yeah, its a chick-flick, but its a perfect movie to curl up on the couch with your significant other. Make sure you watch this with someone you really like, otherwise you could be sending the wrong message and be in real trouble. As for the movie, I thought it was Cages best role aside from Leaving Las Vegas and Meg Ryan was her typical adorable self. The first scene is really disturbing but sets the mood for the rest of the film. As a Christian there were a few things that bothered me about the "angel" aspect of the movie but it was of little consequence to the overall strength of the movie. This is not a party movie, you will not walk away felling particularly happy but there is a contentment it portrays that will stay with you for a long time. This is a movie you will probably want to watch more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grey Jane
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No words can describe the awfulness of this film. I watched with a friend, loaded with cups of coffee, and yet within thirty minutes we were out from the numerous awkward silences that lulled us to sleep. We snoozed until near to the end, but honestly think we didn't miss much. Nicholas Cage acts like a pre-Twilight Robert Pattinson. Creepy. He is so creepy. The way he obsesses over Maggie is quite unnerving and uncomfortable. He acts like a dumb puppy. The story line is predictable and disappointing, with the 'angels' always looking rather awkward and out-of-place. The characters were for the most part unlikable, though it has to be said that Meg Ryan was okay. She pretty. Overall, if you're the sort of person who likes soppy, lame romance or Twilight, watch it. If not, STAY AWAY. GOT IT? >:)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joni-h
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is worth falling for ,when u really want to hold the hands of Magi,feel her,touch her and really leave the eternity to just be with her. The theme was so wonderful that u really want to live with the characters and just hope to be one of them, that proves why man is afraid to die ,because he know that he will lose all the sensations for what human being is really crafted by the god, to live in pain leaving the eternity,but to feel love.The characters are excellently played,even the scores following were just letting you feel the theme and live with the characters. I really can't understand the harsh notes of critics and there sharp views but I can feel that this movie is worth falling for, even if you have to loose your eternity.This is my first comment on this site but I feel may be I delayed it only to give my first one to this one only.(24-12-05)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie touches my heart - favorite of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jax_lady2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much. It's a favorite and I rarely watch a movie more than once, because you know what will happen. This movie I've seen several times. It touches my soul. This is Nicholas Casge's best movie in my opinion. He and Meg Ryan are such a perfect match in this movie. I also love how the angels listen to people think. The connection these two characters have is so amazing. I want to find a love like that in my lifetime. It exemplifies how a love can touch your soul and no matter how much or how little time you have together it's worth it. When you see the comparison of how empty the Dr's eye are (Meg's boyfriend) in comparison to the way Seth look at her, you can see the love there. I think this movie was so under-appreciated and I felt compelled to write a review. I've never written one before, but this is well worth a great review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yeeeehhh, Hollywood ripped off another foreign movie!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ricardopthomaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just had to see, folks, how much Hollywood would drag this to it's complete sappiness. I was fortunate enough to being able to see "Der Himmel &Uuml;ber Berlin" (Wings of Desire) from 1987 and it's sequel, "In Weiter Ferne, so nah!" (Faraway, So Close!) from 1993, both wonderful films by German director Wim Wenders, and believe me, when you see them you just don't see the time passing, they are very, very slow, but these movies keeps you so focused that you just feels like flying over Berlin with those angels. With this Hollywood mock up, it's the other way around. There's so much clich&eacute;s and so much cheesiness, that you keep looking on your watch how much time is left for the movie to end. Seth is a complete sappy version from Damiel, the angel from the Wenders films. It just angers me thinking why Hollywood feels the need of having their own version of foreign movies, why they can't just let these movies alone? Despite some remakes that really respects the original flick and sometimes even tends to pay homage to them, this one is a total flop. It drains all the philosophical and elaborate lines from the original Wenders films and tries to get to our emotions with gratuitous cheesy lines and dialogs. Avoid this film. Watch Wenders masterpieces instead. Damiel and Cassiel in the originals are much better pals than Cage and Braugher. Plus in the original films we have Peter Falk, the Columbo to make us good company as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need more life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the German film "Wings of Desire" (1987), Seth (Nicolas Cage) is an angel. They can't feel, taste, be touched, or seen. Their job is to bring the dead to the afterlife. Dr. Maggie Rice (Meg Ryan) is a sharp young heart surgeon who feels there's something more going on after the death of her last patient. One day, Maggie sees Seth. At first she thinks he's simply a patient at the hospital. But soon she realizes that he is much more mysterious than that, and she quickly falls for him. Nathaniel Messinger (Dennis Franz) is Maggie's patient, and surprisingly a former angel. He tells Seth his choice to fall to Earth. This is a very slow movie. Nicolas Cage is doing his empty look, and his tired speaking voice. Meg Ryan does her best to inject chemistry into this film. It's a very slow romance and it works on that level. When he finally falls to Earth, he does a complete 180. Subtlety has never been Cage's strong point. It's too jarring, and too late. The problem is the lack of humor. I think a few well placed jokes early can enliven the whole film. For a movie about life and death, they need more life in it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    City of Somnambulance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want to make it clear that I'm not against representing the concept of angels in movies... It's just laughable the way it's done in this instance - Cage walking around, perma-brooding, dressed all in black, acting stoned to convey his 'otherworldliness' and constantly speaking in hushed tones... and then, to contrast, you cast Dennis Franz as the 'happy' angel who's crossed over into human existence (See? He must be happy because of his ruddy complexion and physique... so we'll make sure that he's eating when the viewer sees him, just so we can hammer home the point... ) The crisis that provokes the climax of the movie is utterly ridiculous, in the way that it's shown. I mean, what do you expect when you're riding the bike with your eyes closed, and a "Look ma, no hands!" expression?! ... and why would you do this? Joy is not an excuse for stupidity. When you've seen movies such as "The Seventh Seal", which contemplates the realities of human existence, then movies like "City of Angels" just seem manipulative, you know? I have yet to see it, but I have no doubt that "Wings of Desire" (of which this is apparently a pandering remake) will bear this out, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible, terrible movie *contains minor spoilers*
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thejeenius
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh, look! It's one of those typical Hollywood remakes that no one actually cares about! Who would've thought? To sum it up: your time will be better spent doing something else. This movie reeks of tear-jerking, prototypical love scenes and particularly cheesy effects. Even when Nicholas (that stupid angel) takes off his shoes at the beach you can tell something's not right. You really have to wonder if anyone's supposed to take this seriously with all the flaws that it has. Also, if you're not in on the whole "angel" thing this movie won't do for you. There's really nothing else to say here. It's the epitome of blandness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some things are true whether you believe them or not.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    catherinemccutcheon100
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece just like the movie that it's based on 'Wings of Desire'. A lot of people think this movie is rubbish, it's plot is unbelievable, acting is wooden blah blah blah. People (myself included) love a film where an alien is left on earth and befriends a young boy!!!! why can't angels exist all around us listening to our thoughts, our fears and help us through our day simply just being around us? This to me is what makes this film work, what if? as the film states, some things are true whether you believe them or not. The acting is first class, Meg Ryan in a change to her normal comedy plays Maggie Rice perfectly, (the whole science and faith question is what she struggles with the most)Nicholas Cage plays he angel Seth to perfection as well so i really don't see how people can't like this film?! The main with this film is you really just have to trust where it's going to, believe me the end of this film angers me to no end but hey i'm a romantic and I weep like a child always have and always have.One of my all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Meg Ryan is Pure Magic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can say more about Amazing Love story movie blended by Meg Ryan's massive sensuality, beauty and priceless screenplay? Meg captives and shine just for her appearance. from this movie definitely I falled in love for Meg. I Was 17 aged when i watched nominated and recommended by my brother-in- law. I was in total constant Meg Ryan Amazement cause some her currently movies as already followed and watched in middle-late 1998. I just loved and adored this movie and already I cried a lot of ocean for Tears, Nowadays,I became a Meg Ryan's Unconditional Fan. MEG RYAN IS AMAZING PURE EMOTION,FANTASY AND INSPIRATION AND PASSION.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ole' Yeller might just choke up on this one.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryan mcdaniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First off Im a straight guy who prefers movies like Die-hard, Star Wars and Pulp fiction but I have to say, this movie really knocked me back. Yeah, its a chick-flick, but its a perfect movie to curl up on the couch with your significant other. Make sure you watch this with someone you really like, otherwise you could be sending the wrong message and be in real trouble. As for the movie, I thought it was Cages best role aside from Leaving Las Vegas and Meg Ryan was her typical adorable self. The first scene is really disturbing but sets the mood for the rest of the film. As a Christian there were a few things that bothered me about the "angel" aspect of the movie but it was of little consequence to the overall strength of the movie. This is not a party movie, you will not walk away felling particularly happy but there is a contentment it portrays that will stay with you for a long time. This is a movie you will probably want to watch more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grey Jane
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No words can describe the awfulness of this film. I watched with a friend, loaded with cups of coffee, and yet within thirty minutes we were out from the numerous awkward silences that lulled us to sleep. We snoozed until near to the end, but honestly think we didn't miss much. Nicholas Cage acts like a pre-Twilight Robert Pattinson. Creepy. He is so creepy. The way he obsesses over Maggie is quite unnerving and uncomfortable. He acts like a dumb puppy. The story line is predictable and disappointing, with the 'angels' always looking rather awkward and out-of-place. The characters were for the most part unlikable, though it has to be said that Meg Ryan was okay. She pretty. Overall, if you're the sort of person who likes soppy, lame romance or Twilight, watch it. If not, STAY AWAY. GOT IT? >:)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joni-h
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is worth falling for ,when u really want to hold the hands of Magi,feel her,touch her and really leave the eternity to just be with her. The theme was so wonderful that u really want to live with the characters and just hope to be one of them, that proves why man is afraid to die ,because he know that he will lose all the sensations for what human being is really crafted by the god, to live in pain leaving the eternity,but to feel love.The characters are excellently played,even the scores following were just letting you feel the theme and live with the characters. I really can't understand the harsh notes of critics and there sharp views but I can feel that this movie is worth falling for, even if you have to loose your eternity.This is my first comment on this site but I feel may be I delayed it only to give my first one to this one only.(24-12-05)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie touches my heart - favorite of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jax_lady2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much. It's a favorite and I rarely watch a movie more than once, because you know what will happen. This movie I've seen several times. It touches my soul. This is Nicholas Casge's best movie in my opinion. He and Meg Ryan are such a perfect match in this movie. I also love how the angels listen to people think. The connection these two characters have is so amazing. I want to find a love like that in my lifetime. It exemplifies how a love can touch your soul and no matter how much or how little time you have together it's worth it. When you see the comparison of how empty the Dr's eye are (Meg's boyfriend) in comparison to the way Seth look at her, you can see the love there. I think this movie was so under-appreciated and I felt compelled to write a review. I've never written one before, but this is well worth a great review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yeeeehhh, Hollywood ripped off another foreign movie!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ricardopthomaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just had to see, folks, how much Hollywood would drag this to it's complete sappiness. I was fortunate enough to being able to see "Der Himmel &Uuml;ber Berlin" (Wings of Desire) from 1987 and it's sequel, "In Weiter Ferne, so nah!" (Faraway, So Close!) from 1993, both wonderful films by German director Wim Wenders, and believe me, when you see them you just don't see the time passing, they are very, very slow, but these movies keeps you so focused that you just feels like flying over Berlin with those angels. With this Hollywood mock up, it's the other way around. There's so much clich&eacute;s and so much cheesiness, that you keep looking on your watch how much time is left for the movie to end. Seth is a complete sappy version from Damiel, the angel from the Wenders films. It just angers me thinking why Hollywood feels the need of having their own version of foreign movies, why they can't just let these movies alone? Despite some remakes that really respects the original flick and sometimes even tends to pay homage to them, this one is a total flop. It drains all the philosophical and elaborate lines from the original Wenders films and tries to get to our emotions with gratuitous cheesy lines and dialogs. Avoid this film. Watch Wenders masterpieces instead. Damiel and Cassiel in the originals are much better pals than Cage and Braugher. Plus in the original films we have Peter Falk, the Columbo to make us good company as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need more life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the German film "Wings of Desire" (1987), Seth (Nicolas Cage) is an angel. They can't feel, taste, be touched, or seen. Their job is to bring the dead to the afterlife. Dr. Maggie Rice (Meg Ryan) is a sharp young heart surgeon who feels there's something more going on after the death of her last patient. One day, Maggie sees Seth. At first she thinks he's simply a patient at the hospital. But soon she realizes that he is much more mysterious than that, and she quickly falls for him. Nathaniel Messinger (Dennis Franz) is Maggie's patient, and surprisingly a former angel. He tells Seth his choice to fall to Earth. This is a very slow movie. Nicolas Cage is doing his empty look, and his tired speaking voice. Meg Ryan does her best to inject chemistry into this film. It's a very slow romance and it works on that level. When he finally falls to Earth, he does a complete 180. Subtlety has never been Cage's strong point. It's too jarring, and too late. The problem is the lack of humor. I think a few well placed jokes early can enliven the whole film. For a movie about life and death, they need more life in it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    City of Somnambulance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want to make it clear that I'm not against representing the concept of angels in movies... It's just laughable the way it's done in this instance - Cage walking around, perma-brooding, dressed all in black, acting stoned to convey his 'otherworldliness' and constantly speaking in hushed tones... and then, to contrast, you cast Dennis Franz as the 'happy' angel who's crossed over into human existence (See? He must be happy because of his ruddy complexion and physique... so we'll make sure that he's eating when the viewer sees him, just so we can hammer home the point... ) The crisis that provokes the climax of the movie is utterly ridiculous, in the way that it's shown. I mean, what do you expect when you're riding the bike with your eyes closed, and a "Look ma, no hands!" expression?! ... and why would you do this? Joy is not an excuse for stupidity. When you've seen movies such as "The Seventh Seal", which contemplates the realities of human existence, then movies like "City of Angels" just seem manipulative, you know? I have yet to see it, but I have no doubt that "Wings of Desire" (of which this is apparently a pandering remake) will bear this out, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible, terrible movie *contains minor spoilers*
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thejeenius
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh, look! It's one of those typical Hollywood remakes that no one actually cares about! Who would've thought? To sum it up: your time will be better spent doing something else. This movie reeks of tear-jerking, prototypical love scenes and particularly cheesy effects. Even when Nicholas (that stupid angel) takes off his shoes at the beach you can tell something's not right. You really have to wonder if anyone's supposed to take this seriously with all the flaws that it has. Also, if you're not in on the whole "angel" thing this movie won't do for you. There's really nothing else to say here. It's the epitome of blandness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some things are true whether you believe them or not.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    catherinemccutcheon100
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece just like the movie that it's based on 'Wings of Desire'. A lot of people think this movie is rubbish, it's plot is unbelievable, acting is wooden blah blah blah. People (myself included) love a film where an alien is left on earth and befriends a young boy!!!! why can't angels exist all around us listening to our thoughts, our fears and help us through our day simply just being around us? This to me is what makes this film work, what if? as the film states, some things are true whether you believe them or not. The acting is first class, Meg Ryan in a change to her normal comedy plays Maggie Rice perfectly, (the whole science and faith question is what she struggles with the most)Nicholas Cage plays he angel Seth to perfection as well so i really don't see how people can't like this film?! The main with this film is you really just have to trust where it's going to, believe me the end of this film angers me to no end but hey i'm a romantic and I weep like a child always have and always have.One of my all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Meg Ryan is Pure Magic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can say more about Amazing Love story movie blended by Meg Ryan's massive sensuality, beauty and priceless screenplay? Meg captives and shine just for her appearance. from this movie definitely I falled in love for Meg. I Was 17 aged when i watched nominated and recommended by my brother-in- law. I was in total constant Meg Ryan Amazement cause some her currently movies as already followed and watched in middle-late 1998. I just loved and adored this movie and already I cried a lot of ocean for Tears, Nowadays,I became a Meg Ryan's Unconditional Fan. MEG RYAN IS AMAZING PURE EMOTION,FANTASY AND INSPIRATION AND PASSION.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ole' Yeller might just choke up on this one.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryan mcdaniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First off Im a straight guy who prefers movies like Die-hard, Star Wars and Pulp fiction but I have to say, this movie really knocked me back. Yeah, its a chick-flick, but its a perfect movie to curl up on the couch with your significant other. Make sure you watch this with someone you really like, otherwise you could be sending the wrong message and be in real trouble. As for the movie, I thought it was Cages best role aside from Leaving Las Vegas and Meg Ryan was her typical adorable self. The first scene is really disturbing but sets the mood for the rest of the film. As a Christian there were a few things that bothered me about the "angel" aspect of the movie but it was of little consequence to the overall strength of the movie. This is not a party movie, you will not walk away felling particularly happy but there is a contentment it portrays that will stay with you for a long time. This is a movie you will probably want to watch more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grey Jane
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No words can describe the awfulness of this film. I watched with a friend, loaded with cups of coffee, and yet within thirty minutes we were out from the numerous awkward silences that lulled us to sleep. We snoozed until near to the end, but honestly think we didn't miss much. Nicholas Cage acts like a pre-Twilight Robert Pattinson. Creepy. He is so creepy. The way he obsesses over Maggie is quite unnerving and uncomfortable. He acts like a dumb puppy. The story line is predictable and disappointing, with the 'angels' always looking rather awkward and out-of-place. The characters were for the most part unlikable, though it has to be said that Meg Ryan was okay. She pretty. Overall, if you're the sort of person who likes soppy, lame romance or Twilight, watch it. If not, STAY AWAY. GOT IT? >:)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joni-h
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is worth falling for ,when u really want to hold the hands of Magi,feel her,touch her and really leave the eternity to just be with her. The theme was so wonderful that u really want to live with the characters and just hope to be one of them, that proves why man is afraid to die ,because he know that he will lose all the sensations for what human being is really crafted by the god, to live in pain leaving the eternity,but to feel love.The characters are excellently played,even the scores following were just letting you feel the theme and live with the characters. I really can't understand the harsh notes of critics and there sharp views but I can feel that this movie is worth falling for, even if you have to loose your eternity.This is my first comment on this site but I feel may be I delayed it only to give my first one to this one only.(24-12-05)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie touches my heart - favorite of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jax_lady2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much. It's a favorite and I rarely watch a movie more than once, because you know what will happen. This movie I've seen several times. It touches my soul. This is Nicholas Casge's best movie in my opinion. He and Meg Ryan are such a perfect match in this movie. I also love how the angels listen to people think. The connection these two characters have is so amazing. I want to find a love like that in my lifetime. It exemplifies how a love can touch your soul and no matter how much or how little time you have together it's worth it. When you see the comparison of how empty the Dr's eye are (Meg's boyfriend) in comparison to the way Seth look at her, you can see the love there. I think this movie was so under-appreciated and I felt compelled to write a review. I've never written one before, but this is well worth a great review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yeeeehhh, Hollywood ripped off another foreign movie!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ricardopthomaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just had to see, folks, how much Hollywood would drag this to it's complete sappiness. I was fortunate enough to being able to see "Der Himmel &Uuml;ber Berlin" (Wings of Desire) from 1987 and it's sequel, "In Weiter Ferne, so nah!" (Faraway, So Close!) from 1993, both wonderful films by German director Wim Wenders, and believe me, when you see them you just don't see the time passing, they are very, very slow, but these movies keeps you so focused that you just feels like flying over Berlin with those angels. With this Hollywood mock up, it's the other way around. There's so much clich&eacute;s and so much cheesiness, that you keep looking on your watch how much time is left for the movie to end. Seth is a complete sappy version from Damiel, the angel from the Wenders films. It just angers me thinking why Hollywood feels the need of having their own version of foreign movies, why they can't just let these movies alone? Despite some remakes that really respects the original flick and sometimes even tends to pay homage to them, this one is a total flop. It drains all the philosophical and elaborate lines from the original Wenders films and tries to get to our emotions with gratuitous cheesy lines and dialogs. Avoid this film. Watch Wenders masterpieces instead. Damiel and Cassiel in the originals are much better pals than Cage and Braugher. Plus in the original films we have Peter Falk, the Columbo to make us good company as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need more life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the German film "Wings of Desire" (1987), Seth (Nicolas Cage) is an angel. They can't feel, taste, be touched, or seen. Their job is to bring the dead to the afterlife. Dr. Maggie Rice (Meg Ryan) is a sharp young heart surgeon who feels there's something more going on after the death of her last patient. One day, Maggie sees Seth. At first she thinks he's simply a patient at the hospital. But soon she realizes that he is much more mysterious than that, and she quickly falls for him. Nathaniel Messinger (Dennis Franz) is Maggie's patient, and surprisingly a former angel. He tells Seth his choice to fall to Earth. This is a very slow movie. Nicolas Cage is doing his empty look, and his tired speaking voice. Meg Ryan does her best to inject chemistry into this film. It's a very slow romance and it works on that level. When he finally falls to Earth, he does a complete 180. Subtlety has never been Cage's strong point. It's too jarring, and too late. The problem is the lack of humor. I think a few well placed jokes early can enliven the whole film. For a movie about life and death, they need more life in it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    City of Somnambulance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want to make it clear that I'm not against representing the concept of angels in movies... It's just laughable the way it's done in this instance - Cage walking around, perma-brooding, dressed all in black, acting stoned to convey his 'otherworldliness' and constantly speaking in hushed tones... and then, to contrast, you cast Dennis Franz as the 'happy' angel who's crossed over into human existence (See? He must be happy because of his ruddy complexion and physique... so we'll make sure that he's eating when the viewer sees him, just so we can hammer home the point... ) The crisis that provokes the climax of the movie is utterly ridiculous, in the way that it's shown. I mean, what do you expect when you're riding the bike with your eyes closed, and a "Look ma, no hands!" expression?! ... and why would you do this? Joy is not an excuse for stupidity. When you've seen movies such as "The Seventh Seal", which contemplates the realities of human existence, then movies like "City of Angels" just seem manipulative, you know? I have yet to see it, but I have no doubt that "Wings of Desire" (of which this is apparently a pandering remake) will bear this out, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible, terrible movie *contains minor spoilers*
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thejeenius
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh, look! It's one of those typical Hollywood remakes that no one actually cares about! Who would've thought? To sum it up: your time will be better spent doing something else. This movie reeks of tear-jerking, prototypical love scenes and particularly cheesy effects. Even when Nicholas (that stupid angel) takes off his shoes at the beach you can tell something's not right. You really have to wonder if anyone's supposed to take this seriously with all the flaws that it has. Also, if you're not in on the whole "angel" thing this movie won't do for you. There's really nothing else to say here. It's the epitome of blandness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some things are true whether you believe them or not.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    catherinemccutcheon100
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece just like the movie that it's based on 'Wings of Desire'. A lot of people think this movie is rubbish, it's plot is unbelievable, acting is wooden blah blah blah. People (myself included) love a film where an alien is left on earth and befriends a young boy!!!! why can't angels exist all around us listening to our thoughts, our fears and help us through our day simply just being around us? This to me is what makes this film work, what if? as the film states, some things are true whether you believe them or not. The acting is first class, Meg Ryan in a change to her normal comedy plays Maggie Rice perfectly, (the whole science and faith question is what she struggles with the most)Nicholas Cage plays he angel Seth to perfection as well so i really don't see how people can't like this film?! The main with this film is you really just have to trust where it's going to, believe me the end of this film angers me to no end but hey i'm a romantic and I weep like a child always have and always have.One of my all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Meg Ryan is Pure Magic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can say more about Amazing Love story movie blended by Meg Ryan's massive sensuality, beauty and priceless screenplay? Meg captives and shine just for her appearance. from this movie definitely I falled in love for Meg. I Was 17 aged when i watched nominated and recommended by my brother-in- law. I was in total constant Meg Ryan Amazement cause some her currently movies as already followed and watched in middle-late 1998. I just loved and adored this movie and already I cried a lot of ocean for Tears, Nowadays,I became a Meg Ryan's Unconditional Fan. MEG RYAN IS AMAZING PURE EMOTION,FANTASY AND INSPIRATION AND PASSION.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ole' Yeller might just choke up on this one.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryan mcdaniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First off Im a straight guy who prefers movies like Die-hard, Star Wars and Pulp fiction but I have to say, this movie really knocked me back. Yeah, its a chick-flick, but its a perfect movie to curl up on the couch with your significant other. Make sure you watch this with someone you really like, otherwise you could be sending the wrong message and be in real trouble. As for the movie, I thought it was Cages best role aside from Leaving Las Vegas and Meg Ryan was her typical adorable self. The first scene is really disturbing but sets the mood for the rest of the film. As a Christian there were a few things that bothered me about the "angel" aspect of the movie but it was of little consequence to the overall strength of the movie. This is not a party movie, you will not walk away felling particularly happy but there is a contentment it portrays that will stay with you for a long time. This is a movie you will probably want to watch more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grey Jane
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No words can describe the awfulness of this film. I watched with a friend, loaded with cups of coffee, and yet within thirty minutes we were out from the numerous awkward silences that lulled us to sleep. We snoozed until near to the end, but honestly think we didn't miss much. Nicholas Cage acts like a pre-Twilight Robert Pattinson. Creepy. He is so creepy. The way he obsesses over Maggie is quite unnerving and uncomfortable. He acts like a dumb puppy. The story line is predictable and disappointing, with the 'angels' always looking rather awkward and out-of-place. The characters were for the most part unlikable, though it has to be said that Meg Ryan was okay. She pretty. Overall, if you're the sort of person who likes soppy, lame romance or Twilight, watch it. If not, STAY AWAY. GOT IT? >:)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joni-h
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is worth falling for ,when u really want to hold the hands of Magi,feel her,touch her and really leave the eternity to just be with her. The theme was so wonderful that u really want to live with the characters and just hope to be one of them, that proves why man is afraid to die ,because he know that he will lose all the sensations for what human being is really crafted by the god, to live in pain leaving the eternity,but to feel love.The characters are excellently played,even the scores following were just letting you feel the theme and live with the characters. I really can't understand the harsh notes of critics and there sharp views but I can feel that this movie is worth falling for, even if you have to loose your eternity.This is my first comment on this site but I feel may be I delayed it only to give my first one to this one only.(24-12-05)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie touches my heart - favorite of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jax_lady2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much. It's a favorite and I rarely watch a movie more than once, because you know what will happen. This movie I've seen several times. It touches my soul. This is Nicholas Casge's best movie in my opinion. He and Meg Ryan are such a perfect match in this movie. I also love how the angels listen to people think. The connection these two characters have is so amazing. I want to find a love like that in my lifetime. It exemplifies how a love can touch your soul and no matter how much or how little time you have together it's worth it. When you see the comparison of how empty the Dr's eye are (Meg's boyfriend) in comparison to the way Seth look at her, you can see the love there. I think this movie was so under-appreciated and I felt compelled to write a review. I've never written one before, but this is well worth a great review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yeeeehhh, Hollywood ripped off another foreign movie!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ricardopthomaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just had to see, folks, how much Hollywood would drag this to it's complete sappiness. I was fortunate enough to being able to see "Der Himmel &Uuml;ber Berlin" (Wings of Desire) from 1987 and it's sequel, "In Weiter Ferne, so nah!" (Faraway, So Close!) from 1993, both wonderful films by German director Wim Wenders, and believe me, when you see them you just don't see the time passing, they are very, very slow, but these movies keeps you so focused that you just feels like flying over Berlin with those angels. With this Hollywood mock up, it's the other way around. There's so much clich&eacute;s and so much cheesiness, that you keep looking on your watch how much time is left for the movie to end. Seth is a complete sappy version from Damiel, the angel from the Wenders films. It just angers me thinking why Hollywood feels the need of having their own version of foreign movies, why they can't just let these movies alone? Despite some remakes that really respects the original flick and sometimes even tends to pay homage to them, this one is a total flop. It drains all the philosophical and elaborate lines from the original Wenders films and tries to get to our emotions with gratuitous cheesy lines and dialogs. Avoid this film. Watch Wenders masterpieces instead. Damiel and Cassiel in the originals are much better pals than Cage and Braugher. Plus in the original films we have Peter Falk, the Columbo to make us good company as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need more life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the German film "Wings of Desire" (1987), Seth (Nicolas Cage) is an angel. They can't feel, taste, be touched, or seen. Their job is to bring the dead to the afterlife. Dr. Maggie Rice (Meg Ryan) is a sharp young heart surgeon who feels there's something more going on after the death of her last patient. One day, Maggie sees Seth. At first she thinks he's simply a patient at the hospital. But soon she realizes that he is much more mysterious than that, and she quickly falls for him. Nathaniel Messinger (Dennis Franz) is Maggie's patient, and surprisingly a former angel. He tells Seth his choice to fall to Earth. This is a very slow movie. Nicolas Cage is doing his empty look, and his tired speaking voice. Meg Ryan does her best to inject chemistry into this film. It's a very slow romance and it works on that level. When he finally falls to Earth, he does a complete 180. Subtlety has never been Cage's strong point. It's too jarring, and too late. The problem is the lack of humor. I think a few well placed jokes early can enliven the whole film. For a movie about life and death, they need more life in it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    City of Somnambulance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want to make it clear that I'm not against representing the concept of angels in movies... It's just laughable the way it's done in this instance - Cage walking around, perma-brooding, dressed all in black, acting stoned to convey his 'otherworldliness' and constantly speaking in hushed tones... and then, to contrast, you cast Dennis Franz as the 'happy' angel who's crossed over into human existence (See? He must be happy because of his ruddy complexion and physique... so we'll make sure that he's eating when the viewer sees him, just so we can hammer home the point... ) The crisis that provokes the climax of the movie is utterly ridiculous, in the way that it's shown. I mean, what do you expect when you're riding the bike with your eyes closed, and a "Look ma, no hands!" expression?! ... and why would you do this? Joy is not an excuse for stupidity. When you've seen movies such as "The Seventh Seal", which contemplates the realities of human existence, then movies like "City of Angels" just seem manipulative, you know? I have yet to see it, but I have no doubt that "Wings of Desire" (of which this is apparently a pandering remake) will bear this out, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible, terrible movie *contains minor spoilers*
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thejeenius
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh, look! It's one of those typical Hollywood remakes that no one actually cares about! Who would've thought? To sum it up: your time will be better spent doing something else. This movie reeks of tear-jerking, prototypical love scenes and particularly cheesy effects. Even when Nicholas (that stupid angel) takes off his shoes at the beach you can tell something's not right. You really have to wonder if anyone's supposed to take this seriously with all the flaws that it has. Also, if you're not in on the whole "angel" thing this movie won't do for you. There's really nothing else to say here. It's the epitome of blandness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some things are true whether you believe them or not.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    catherinemccutcheon100
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece just like the movie that it's based on 'Wings of Desire'. A lot of people think this movie is rubbish, it's plot is unbelievable, acting is wooden blah blah blah. People (myself included) love a film where an alien is left on earth and befriends a young boy!!!! why can't angels exist all around us listening to our thoughts, our fears and help us through our day simply just being around us? This to me is what makes this film work, what if? as the film states, some things are true whether you believe them or not. The acting is first class, Meg Ryan in a change to her normal comedy plays Maggie Rice perfectly, (the whole science and faith question is what she struggles with the most)Nicholas Cage plays he angel Seth to perfection as well so i really don't see how people can't like this film?! The main with this film is you really just have to trust where it's going to, believe me the end of this film angers me to no end but hey i'm a romantic and I weep like a child always have and always have.One of my all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Meg Ryan is Pure Magic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can say more about Amazing Love story movie blended by Meg Ryan's massive sensuality, beauty and priceless screenplay? Meg captives and shine just for her appearance. from this movie definitely I falled in love for Meg. I Was 17 aged when i watched nominated and recommended by my brother-in- law. I was in total constant Meg Ryan Amazement cause some her currently movies as already followed and watched in middle-late 1998. I just loved and adored this movie and already I cried a lot of ocean for Tears, Nowadays,I became a Meg Ryan's Unconditional Fan. MEG RYAN IS AMAZING PURE EMOTION,FANTASY AND INSPIRATION AND PASSION.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ole' Yeller might just choke up on this one.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryan mcdaniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First off Im a straight guy who prefers movies like Die-hard, Star Wars and Pulp fiction but I have to say, this movie really knocked me back. Yeah, its a chick-flick, but its a perfect movie to curl up on the couch with your significant other. Make sure you watch this with someone you really like, otherwise you could be sending the wrong message and be in real trouble. As for the movie, I thought it was Cages best role aside from Leaving Las Vegas and Meg Ryan was her typical adorable self. The first scene is really disturbing but sets the mood for the rest of the film. As a Christian there were a few things that bothered me about the "angel" aspect of the movie but it was of little consequence to the overall strength of the movie. This is not a party movie, you will not walk away felling particularly happy but there is a contentment it portrays that will stay with you for a long time. This is a movie you will probably want to watch more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grey Jane
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No words can describe the awfulness of this film. I watched with a friend, loaded with cups of coffee, and yet within thirty minutes we were out from the numerous awkward silences that lulled us to sleep. We snoozed until near to the end, but honestly think we didn't miss much. Nicholas Cage acts like a pre-Twilight Robert Pattinson. Creepy. He is so creepy. The way he obsesses over Maggie is quite unnerving and uncomfortable. He acts like a dumb puppy. The story line is predictable and disappointing, with the 'angels' always looking rather awkward and out-of-place. The characters were for the most part unlikable, though it has to be said that Meg Ryan was okay. She pretty. Overall, if you're the sort of person who likes soppy, lame romance or Twilight, watch it. If not, STAY AWAY. GOT IT? >:)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joni-h
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is worth falling for ,when u really want to hold the hands of Magi,feel her,touch her and really leave the eternity to just be with her. The theme was so wonderful that u really want to live with the characters and just hope to be one of them, that proves why man is afraid to die ,because he know that he will lose all the sensations for what human being is really crafted by the god, to live in pain leaving the eternity,but to feel love.The characters are excellently played,even the scores following were just letting you feel the theme and live with the characters. I really can't understand the harsh notes of critics and there sharp views but I can feel that this movie is worth falling for, even if you have to loose your eternity.This is my first comment on this site but I feel may be I delayed it only to give my first one to this one only.(24-12-05)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie touches my heart - favorite of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jax_lady2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much. It's a favorite and I rarely watch a movie more than once, because you know what will happen. This movie I've seen several times. It touches my soul. This is Nicholas Casge's best movie in my opinion. He and Meg Ryan are such a perfect match in this movie. I also love how the angels listen to people think. The connection these two characters have is so amazing. I want to find a love like that in my lifetime. It exemplifies how a love can touch your soul and no matter how much or how little time you have together it's worth it. When you see the comparison of how empty the Dr's eye are (Meg's boyfriend) in comparison to the way Seth look at her, you can see the love there. I think this movie was so under-appreciated and I felt compelled to write a review. I've never written one before, but this is well worth a great review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yeeeehhh, Hollywood ripped off another foreign movie!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ricardopthomaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just had to see, folks, how much Hollywood would drag this to it's complete sappiness. I was fortunate enough to being able to see "Der Himmel &Uuml;ber Berlin" (Wings of Desire) from 1987 and it's sequel, "In Weiter Ferne, so nah!" (Faraway, So Close!) from 1993, both wonderful films by German director Wim Wenders, and believe me, when you see them you just don't see the time passing, they are very, very slow, but these movies keeps you so focused that you just feels like flying over Berlin with those angels. With this Hollywood mock up, it's the other way around. There's so much clich&eacute;s and so much cheesiness, that you keep looking on your watch how much time is left for the movie to end. Seth is a complete sappy version from Damiel, the angel from the Wenders films. It just angers me thinking why Hollywood feels the need of having their own version of foreign movies, why they can't just let these movies alone? Despite some remakes that really respects the original flick and sometimes even tends to pay homage to them, this one is a total flop. It drains all the philosophical and elaborate lines from the original Wenders films and tries to get to our emotions with gratuitous cheesy lines and dialogs. Avoid this film. Watch Wenders masterpieces instead. Damiel and Cassiel in the originals are much better pals than Cage and Braugher. Plus in the original films we have Peter Falk, the Columbo to make us good company as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need more life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the German film "Wings of Desire" (1987), Seth (Nicolas Cage) is an angel. They can't feel, taste, be touched, or seen. Their job is to bring the dead to the afterlife. Dr. Maggie Rice (Meg Ryan) is a sharp young heart surgeon who feels there's something more going on after the death of her last patient. One day, Maggie sees Seth. At first she thinks he's simply a patient at the hospital. But soon she realizes that he is much more mysterious than that, and she quickly falls for him. Nathaniel Messinger (Dennis Franz) is Maggie's patient, and surprisingly a former angel. He tells Seth his choice to fall to Earth. This is a very slow movie. Nicolas Cage is doing his empty look, and his tired speaking voice. Meg Ryan does her best to inject chemistry into this film. It's a very slow romance and it works on that level. When he finally falls to Earth, he does a complete 180. Subtlety has never been Cage's strong point. It's too jarring, and too late. The problem is the lack of humor. I think a few well placed jokes early can enliven the whole film. For a movie about life and death, they need more life in it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    City of Somnambulance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want to make it clear that I'm not against representing the concept of angels in movies... It's just laughable the way it's done in this instance - Cage walking around, perma-brooding, dressed all in black, acting stoned to convey his 'otherworldliness' and constantly speaking in hushed tones... and then, to contrast, you cast Dennis Franz as the 'happy' angel who's crossed over into human existence (See? He must be happy because of his ruddy complexion and physique... so we'll make sure that he's eating when the viewer sees him, just so we can hammer home the point... ) The crisis that provokes the climax of the movie is utterly ridiculous, in the way that it's shown. I mean, what do you expect when you're riding the bike with your eyes closed, and a "Look ma, no hands!" expression?! ... and why would you do this? Joy is not an excuse for stupidity. When you've seen movies such as "The Seventh Seal", which contemplates the realities of human existence, then movies like "City of Angels" just seem manipulative, you know? I have yet to see it, but I have no doubt that "Wings of Desire" (of which this is apparently a pandering remake) will bear this out, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible, terrible movie *contains minor spoilers*
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thejeenius
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh, look! It's one of those typical Hollywood remakes that no one actually cares about! Who would've thought? To sum it up: your time will be better spent doing something else. This movie reeks of tear-jerking, prototypical love scenes and particularly cheesy effects. Even when Nicholas (that stupid angel) takes off his shoes at the beach you can tell something's not right. You really have to wonder if anyone's supposed to take this seriously with all the flaws that it has. Also, if you're not in on the whole "angel" thing this movie won't do for you. There's really nothing else to say here. It's the epitome of blandness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some things are true whether you believe them or not.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    catherinemccutcheon100
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece just like the movie that it's based on 'Wings of Desire'. A lot of people think this movie is rubbish, it's plot is unbelievable, acting is wooden blah blah blah. People (myself included) love a film where an alien is left on earth and befriends a young boy!!!! why can't angels exist all around us listening to our thoughts, our fears and help us through our day simply just being around us? This to me is what makes this film work, what if? as the film states, some things are true whether you believe them or not. The acting is first class, Meg Ryan in a change to her normal comedy plays Maggie Rice perfectly, (the whole science and faith question is what she struggles with the most)Nicholas Cage plays he angel Seth to perfection as well so i really don't see how people can't like this film?! The main with this film is you really just have to trust where it's going to, believe me the end of this film angers me to no end but hey i'm a romantic and I weep like a child always have and always have.One of my all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Meg Ryan is Pure Magic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can say more about Amazing Love story movie blended by Meg Ryan's massive sensuality, beauty and priceless screenplay? Meg captives and shine just for her appearance. from this movie definitely I falled in love for Meg. I Was 17 aged when i watched nominated and recommended by my brother-in- law. I was in total constant Meg Ryan Amazement cause some her currently movies as already followed and watched in middle-late 1998. I just loved and adored this movie and already I cried a lot of ocean for Tears, Nowadays,I became a Meg Ryan's Unconditional Fan. MEG RYAN IS AMAZING PURE EMOTION,FANTASY AND INSPIRATION AND PASSION.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ole' Yeller might just choke up on this one.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryan mcdaniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First off Im a straight guy who prefers movies like Die-hard, Star Wars and Pulp fiction but I have to say, this movie really knocked me back. Yeah, its a chick-flick, but its a perfect movie to curl up on the couch with your significant other. Make sure you watch this with someone you really like, otherwise you could be sending the wrong message and be in real trouble. As for the movie, I thought it was Cages best role aside from Leaving Las Vegas and Meg Ryan was her typical adorable self. The first scene is really disturbing but sets the mood for the rest of the film. As a Christian there were a few things that bothered me about the "angel" aspect of the movie but it was of little consequence to the overall strength of the movie. This is not a party movie, you will not walk away felling particularly happy but there is a contentment it portrays that will stay with you for a long time. This is a movie you will probably want to watch more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grey Jane
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No words can describe the awfulness of this film. I watched with a friend, loaded with cups of coffee, and yet within thirty minutes we were out from the numerous awkward silences that lulled us to sleep. We snoozed until near to the end, but honestly think we didn't miss much. Nicholas Cage acts like a pre-Twilight Robert Pattinson. Creepy. He is so creepy. The way he obsesses over Maggie is quite unnerving and uncomfortable. He acts like a dumb puppy. The story line is predictable and disappointing, with the 'angels' always looking rather awkward and out-of-place. The characters were for the most part unlikable, though it has to be said that Meg Ryan was okay. She pretty. Overall, if you're the sort of person who likes soppy, lame romance or Twilight, watch it. If not, STAY AWAY. GOT IT? >:)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joni-h
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is worth falling for ,when u really want to hold the hands of Magi,feel her,touch her and really leave the eternity to just be with her. The theme was so wonderful that u really want to live with the characters and just hope to be one of them, that proves why man is afraid to die ,because he know that he will lose all the sensations for what human being is really crafted by the god, to live in pain leaving the eternity,but to feel love.The characters are excellently played,even the scores following were just letting you feel the theme and live with the characters. I really can't understand the harsh notes of critics and there sharp views but I can feel that this movie is worth falling for, even if you have to loose your eternity.This is my first comment on this site but I feel may be I delayed it only to give my first one to this one only.(24-12-05)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie touches my heart - favorite of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jax_lady2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much. It's a favorite and I rarely watch a movie more than once, because you know what will happen. This movie I've seen several times. It touches my soul. This is Nicholas Casge's best movie in my opinion. He and Meg Ryan are such a perfect match in this movie. I also love how the angels listen to people think. The connection these two characters have is so amazing. I want to find a love like that in my lifetime. It exemplifies how a love can touch your soul and no matter how much or how little time you have together it's worth it. When you see the comparison of how empty the Dr's eye are (Meg's boyfriend) in comparison to the way Seth look at her, you can see the love there. I think this movie was so under-appreciated and I felt compelled to write a review. I've never written one before, but this is well worth a great review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yeeeehhh, Hollywood ripped off another foreign movie!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ricardopthomaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just had to see, folks, how much Hollywood would drag this to it's complete sappiness. I was fortunate enough to being able to see "Der Himmel &Uuml;ber Berlin" (Wings of Desire) from 1987 and it's sequel, "In Weiter Ferne, so nah!" (Faraway, So Close!) from 1993, both wonderful films by German director Wim Wenders, and believe me, when you see them you just don't see the time passing, they are very, very slow, but these movies keeps you so focused that you just feels like flying over Berlin with those angels. With this Hollywood mock up, it's the other way around. There's so much clich&eacute;s and so much cheesiness, that you keep looking on your watch how much time is left for the movie to end. Seth is a complete sappy version from Damiel, the angel from the Wenders films. It just angers me thinking why Hollywood feels the need of having their own version of foreign movies, why they can't just let these movies alone? Despite some remakes that really respects the original flick and sometimes even tends to pay homage to them, this one is a total flop. It drains all the philosophical and elaborate lines from the original Wenders films and tries to get to our emotions with gratuitous cheesy lines and dialogs. Avoid this film. Watch Wenders masterpieces instead. Damiel and Cassiel in the originals are much better pals than Cage and Braugher. Plus in the original films we have Peter Falk, the Columbo to make us good company as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need more life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the German film "Wings of Desire" (1987), Seth (Nicolas Cage) is an angel. They can't feel, taste, be touched, or seen. Their job is to bring the dead to the afterlife. Dr. Maggie Rice (Meg Ryan) is a sharp young heart surgeon who feels there's something more going on after the death of her last patient. One day, Maggie sees Seth. At first she thinks he's simply a patient at the hospital. But soon she realizes that he is much more mysterious than that, and she quickly falls for him. Nathaniel Messinger (Dennis Franz) is Maggie's patient, and surprisingly a former angel. He tells Seth his choice to fall to Earth. This is a very slow movie. Nicolas Cage is doing his empty look, and his tired speaking voice. Meg Ryan does her best to inject chemistry into this film. It's a very slow romance and it works on that level. When he finally falls to Earth, he does a complete 180. Subtlety has never been Cage's strong point. It's too jarring, and too late. The problem is the lack of humor. I think a few well placed jokes early can enliven the whole film. For a movie about life and death, they need more life in it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    City of Somnambulance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want to make it clear that I'm not against representing the concept of angels in movies... It's just laughable the way it's done in this instance - Cage walking around, perma-brooding, dressed all in black, acting stoned to convey his 'otherworldliness' and constantly speaking in hushed tones... and then, to contrast, you cast Dennis Franz as the 'happy' angel who's crossed over into human existence (See? He must be happy because of his ruddy complexion and physique... so we'll make sure that he's eating when the viewer sees him, just so we can hammer home the point... ) The crisis that provokes the climax of the movie is utterly ridiculous, in the way that it's shown. I mean, what do you expect when you're riding the bike with your eyes closed, and a "Look ma, no hands!" expression?! ... and why would you do this? Joy is not an excuse for stupidity. When you've seen movies such as "The Seventh Seal", which contemplates the realities of human existence, then movies like "City of Angels" just seem manipulative, you know? I have yet to see it, but I have no doubt that "Wings of Desire" (of which this is apparently a pandering remake) will bear this out, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible, terrible movie *contains minor spoilers*
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thejeenius
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh, look! It's one of those typical Hollywood remakes that no one actually cares about! Who would've thought? To sum it up: your time will be better spent doing something else. This movie reeks of tear-jerking, prototypical love scenes and particularly cheesy effects. Even when Nicholas (that stupid angel) takes off his shoes at the beach you can tell something's not right. You really have to wonder if anyone's supposed to take this seriously with all the flaws that it has. Also, if you're not in on the whole "angel" thing this movie won't do for you. There's really nothing else to say here. It's the epitome of blandness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some things are true whether you believe them or not.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    catherinemccutcheon100
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece just like the movie that it's based on 'Wings of Desire'. A lot of people think this movie is rubbish, it's plot is unbelievable, acting is wooden blah blah blah. People (myself included) love a film where an alien is left on earth and befriends a young boy!!!! why can't angels exist all around us listening to our thoughts, our fears and help us through our day simply just being around us? This to me is what makes this film work, what if? as the film states, some things are true whether you believe them or not. The acting is first class, Meg Ryan in a change to her normal comedy plays Maggie Rice perfectly, (the whole science and faith question is what she struggles with the most)Nicholas Cage plays he angel Seth to perfection as well so i really don't see how people can't like this film?! The main with this film is you really just have to trust where it's going to, believe me the end of this film angers me to no end but hey i'm a romantic and I weep like a child always have and always have.One of my all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Meg Ryan is Pure Magic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can say more about Amazing Love story movie blended by Meg Ryan's massive sensuality, beauty and priceless screenplay? Meg captives and shine just for her appearance. from this movie definitely I falled in love for Meg. I Was 17 aged when i watched nominated and recommended by my brother-in- law. I was in total constant Meg Ryan Amazement cause some her currently movies as already followed and watched in middle-late 1998. I just loved and adored this movie and already I cried a lot of ocean for Tears, Nowadays,I became a Meg Ryan's Unconditional Fan. MEG RYAN IS AMAZING PURE EMOTION,FANTASY AND INSPIRATION AND PASSION.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ole' Yeller might just choke up on this one.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryan mcdaniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First off Im a straight guy who prefers movies like Die-hard, Star Wars and Pulp fiction but I have to say, this movie really knocked me back. Yeah, its a chick-flick, but its a perfect movie to curl up on the couch with your significant other. Make sure you watch this with someone you really like, otherwise you could be sending the wrong message and be in real trouble. As for the movie, I thought it was Cages best role aside from Leaving Las Vegas and Meg Ryan was her typical adorable self. The first scene is really disturbing but sets the mood for the rest of the film. As a Christian there were a few things that bothered me about the "angel" aspect of the movie but it was of little consequence to the overall strength of the movie. This is not a party movie, you will not walk away felling particularly happy but there is a contentment it portrays that will stay with you for a long time. This is a movie you will probably want to watch more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grey Jane
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No words can describe the awfulness of this film. I watched with a friend, loaded with cups of coffee, and yet within thirty minutes we were out from the numerous awkward silences that lulled us to sleep. We snoozed until near to the end, but honestly think we didn't miss much. Nicholas Cage acts like a pre-Twilight Robert Pattinson. Creepy. He is so creepy. The way he obsesses over Maggie is quite unnerving and uncomfortable. He acts like a dumb puppy. The story line is predictable and disappointing, with the 'angels' always looking rather awkward and out-of-place. The characters were for the most part unlikable, though it has to be said that Meg Ryan was okay. She pretty. Overall, if you're the sort of person who likes soppy, lame romance or Twilight, watch it. If not, STAY AWAY. GOT IT? >:)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joni-h
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is worth falling for ,when u really want to hold the hands of Magi,feel her,touch her and really leave the eternity to just be with her. The theme was so wonderful that u really want to live with the characters and just hope to be one of them, that proves why man is afraid to die ,because he know that he will lose all the sensations for what human being is really crafted by the god, to live in pain leaving the eternity,but to feel love.The characters are excellently played,even the scores following were just letting you feel the theme and live with the characters. I really can't understand the harsh notes of critics and there sharp views but I can feel that this movie is worth falling for, even if you have to loose your eternity.This is my first comment on this site but I feel may be I delayed it only to give my first one to this one only.(24-12-05)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie touches my heart - favorite of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jax_lady2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much. It's a favorite and I rarely watch a movie more than once, because you know what will happen. This movie I've seen several times. It touches my soul. This is Nicholas Casge's best movie in my opinion. He and Meg Ryan are such a perfect match in this movie. I also love how the angels listen to people think. The connection these two characters have is so amazing. I want to find a love like that in my lifetime. It exemplifies how a love can touch your soul and no matter how much or how little time you have together it's worth it. When you see the comparison of how empty the Dr's eye are (Meg's boyfriend) in comparison to the way Seth look at her, you can see the love there. I think this movie was so under-appreciated and I felt compelled to write a review. I've never written one before, but this is well worth a great review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yeeeehhh, Hollywood ripped off another foreign movie!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ricardopthomaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just had to see, folks, how much Hollywood would drag this to it's complete sappiness. I was fortunate enough to being able to see "Der Himmel &Uuml;ber Berlin" (Wings of Desire) from 1987 and it's sequel, "In Weiter Ferne, so nah!" (Faraway, So Close!) from 1993, both wonderful films by German director Wim Wenders, and believe me, when you see them you just don't see the time passing, they are very, very slow, but these movies keeps you so focused that you just feels like flying over Berlin with those angels. With this Hollywood mock up, it's the other way around. There's so much clich&eacute;s and so much cheesiness, that you keep looking on your watch how much time is left for the movie to end. Seth is a complete sappy version from Damiel, the angel from the Wenders films. It just angers me thinking why Hollywood feels the need of having their own version of foreign movies, why they can't just let these movies alone? Despite some remakes that really respects the original flick and sometimes even tends to pay homage to them, this one is a total flop. It drains all the philosophical and elaborate lines from the original Wenders films and tries to get to our emotions with gratuitous cheesy lines and dialogs. Avoid this film. Watch Wenders masterpieces instead. Damiel and Cassiel in the originals are much better pals than Cage and Braugher. Plus in the original films we have Peter Falk, the Columbo to make us good company as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Need more life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the German film "Wings of Desire" (1987), Seth (Nicolas Cage) is an angel. They can't feel, taste, be touched, or seen. Their job is to bring the dead to the afterlife. Dr. Maggie Rice (Meg Ryan) is a sharp young heart surgeon who feels there's something more going on after the death of her last patient. One day, Maggie sees Seth. At first she thinks he's simply a patient at the hospital. But soon she realizes that he is much more mysterious than that, and she quickly falls for him. Nathaniel Messinger (Dennis Franz) is Maggie's patient, and surprisingly a former angel. He tells Seth his choice to fall to Earth. This is a very slow movie. Nicolas Cage is doing his empty look, and his tired speaking voice. Meg Ryan does her best to inject chemistry into this film. It's a very slow romance and it works on that level. When he finally falls to Earth, he does a complete 180. Subtlety has never been Cage's strong point. It's too jarring, and too late. The problem is the lack of humor. I think a few well placed jokes early can enliven the whole film. For a movie about life and death, they need more life in it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    City of Somnambulance...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Howlin Wolf
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I want to make it clear that I'm not against representing the concept of angels in movies... It's just laughable the way it's done in this instance - Cage walking around, perma-brooding, dressed all in black, acting stoned to convey his 'otherworldliness' and constantly speaking in hushed tones... and then, to contrast, you cast Dennis Franz as the 'happy' angel who's crossed over into human existence (See? He must be happy because of his ruddy complexion and physique... so we'll make sure that he's eating when the viewer sees him, just so we can hammer home the point... ) The crisis that provokes the climax of the movie is utterly ridiculous, in the way that it's shown. I mean, what do you expect when you're riding the bike with your eyes closed, and a "Look ma, no hands!" expression?! ... and why would you do this? Joy is not an excuse for stupidity. When you've seen movies such as "The Seventh Seal", which contemplates the realities of human existence, then movies like "City of Angels" just seem manipulative, you know? I have yet to see it, but I have no doubt that "Wings of Desire" (of which this is apparently a pandering remake) will bear this out, too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible, terrible movie *contains minor spoilers*
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thejeenius
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oh, look! It's one of those typical Hollywood remakes that no one actually cares about! Who would've thought? To sum it up: your time will be better spent doing something else. This movie reeks of tear-jerking, prototypical love scenes and particularly cheesy effects. Even when Nicholas (that stupid angel) takes off his shoes at the beach you can tell something's not right. You really have to wonder if anyone's supposed to take this seriously with all the flaws that it has. Also, if you're not in on the whole "angel" thing this movie won't do for you. There's really nothing else to say here. It's the epitome of blandness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some things are true whether you believe them or not.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    catherinemccutcheon100
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a masterpiece just like the movie that it's based on 'Wings of Desire'. A lot of people think this movie is rubbish, it's plot is unbelievable, acting is wooden blah blah blah. People (myself included) love a film where an alien is left on earth and befriends a young boy!!!! why can't angels exist all around us listening to our thoughts, our fears and help us through our day simply just being around us? This to me is what makes this film work, what if? as the film states, some things are true whether you believe them or not. The acting is first class, Meg Ryan in a change to her normal comedy plays Maggie Rice perfectly, (the whole science and faith question is what she struggles with the most)Nicholas Cage plays he angel Seth to perfection as well so i really don't see how people can't like this film?! The main with this film is you really just have to trust where it's going to, believe me the end of this film angers me to no end but hey i'm a romantic and I weep like a child always have and always have.One of my all time favourite films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Meg Ryan is Pure Magic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eban1981
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can say more about Amazing Love story movie blended by Meg Ryan's massive sensuality, beauty and priceless screenplay? Meg captives and shine just for her appearance. from this movie definitely I falled in love for Meg. I Was 17 aged when i watched nominated and recommended by my brother-in- law. I was in total constant Meg Ryan Amazement cause some her currently movies as already followed and watched in middle-late 1998. I just loved and adored this movie and already I cried a lot of ocean for Tears, Nowadays,I became a Meg Ryan's Unconditional Fan. MEG RYAN IS AMAZING PURE EMOTION,FANTASY AND INSPIRATION AND PASSION.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ole' Yeller might just choke up on this one.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ryan mcdaniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First off Im a straight guy who prefers movies like Die-hard, Star Wars and Pulp fiction but I have to say, this movie really knocked me back. Yeah, its a chick-flick, but its a perfect movie to curl up on the couch with your significant other. Make sure you watch this with someone you really like, otherwise you could be sending the wrong message and be in real trouble. As for the movie, I thought it was Cages best role aside from Leaving Las Vegas and Meg Ryan was her typical adorable self. The first scene is really disturbing but sets the mood for the rest of the film. As a Christian there were a few things that bothered me about the "angel" aspect of the movie but it was of little consequence to the overall strength of the movie. This is not a party movie, you will not walk away felling particularly happy but there is a contentment it portrays that will stay with you for a long time. This is a movie you will probably want to watch more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grey Jane
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No words can describe the awfulness of this film. I watched with a friend, loaded with cups of coffee, and yet within thirty minutes we were out from the numerous awkward silences that lulled us to sleep. We snoozed until near to the end, but honestly think we didn't miss much. Nicholas Cage acts like a pre-Twilight Robert Pattinson. Creepy. He is so creepy. The way he obsesses over Maggie is quite unnerving and uncomfortable. He acts like a dumb puppy. The story line is predictable and disappointing, with the 'angels' always looking rather awkward and out-of-place. The characters were for the most part unlikable, though it has to be said that Meg Ryan was okay. She pretty. Overall, if you're the sort of person who likes soppy, lame romance or Twilight, watch it. If not, STAY AWAY. GOT IT? >:)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth it all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    joni-h
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is worth falling for ,when u really want to hold the hands of Magi,feel her,touch her and really leave the eternity to just be with her. The theme was so wonderful that u really want to live with the characters and just hope to be one of them, that proves why man is afraid to die ,because he know that he will lose all the sensations for what human being is really crafted by the god, to live in pain leaving the eternity,but to feel love.The characters are excellently played,even the scores following were just letting you feel the theme and live with the characters. I really can't understand the harsh notes of critics and there sharp views but I can feel that this movie is worth falling for, even if you have to loose your eternity.This is my first comment on this site but I feel may be I delayed it only to give my first one to this one only.(24-12-05)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie touches my heart - favorite of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jax_lady2002
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much. It's a favorite and I rarely watch a movie more than once, because you know what will happen. This movie I've seen several times. It touches my soul. This is Nicholas Casge's best movie in my opinion. He and Meg Ryan are such a perfect match in this movie. I also love how the angels listen to people think. The connection these two characters have is so amazing. I want to find a love like that in my lifetime. It exemplifies how a love can touch your soul and no matter how much or how little time you have together it's worth it. When you see the comparison of how empty the Dr's eye are (Meg's boyfriend) in comparison to the way Seth look at her, you can see the love there. I think this movie was so under-appreciated and I felt compelled to write a review. I've never written one before, but this is well worth a great review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yeeeehhh, Hollywood ripped off another foreign movie!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ricardopthomaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just had to see, folks, how much Hollywood would drag this to it's complete sappiness. I was fortunate enough to being able to see "Der Himmel &Uuml;ber Berlin" (Wings of Desire) from 1987 and it's sequel, "In Weiter Ferne, so nah!" (Faraway, So Close!) from 1993, both wonderful films by German director Wim Wenders, and believe me, when you see them you just don't see the time passing, they are very, very slow, but these movies keeps you so focused that you just feels like flying over Berlin with those angels. With this Hollywood mock up, it's the other way around. There's so much clich&eacute;s and so much cheesiness, that you keep looking on your watch how much time is left for the movie to end. Seth is a complete sappy version from Damiel, the angel from the Wenders films. It just angers me thinking why Hollywood feels the need of having their own version of foreign movies, why they can't just let these movies alone? Despite some remakes that really respects the original flick and sometimes even tends to pay homage to them, this one is a total flop. It drains all the philosophical and elaborate lines from the original Wenders films and tries to get to our emotions with gratuitous cheesy lines and dialogs. Avoid this film. Watch Wenders masterpieces instead. Damiel and Cassiel in the originals are much better pals than Cage and Braugher. Plus in the original films we have Peter Falk, the Columbo to make us good company as well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
