<filme>
 <id>
  93
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114906
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Bem-Vindo &agrave; Casa de Bonecas
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Insightful look at an unattractive 7th grader as she struggles to cope with un-attentive parents, snobbish classmates, a smart older brother, an attractive younger sister, and her own insecurities.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Seventh-grade is no fun. Especially for Dawn Weiner when everyone at school calls you 'Dog-Face' or 'Wiener-Dog.' Not to mention if your older brother is 'King of the Nerds' and your younger sister is a cutesy ballerina who gets you in trouble but is your parents' favorite. And that's just the beginning--her life seems to be falling apart when she faces rejection from the older guy in her brother's band that she has a crush on, her parents want to tear down her 'Special People's Club' clubhouse, and her sister is abducted....
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   school
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ballerina
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   social outcast
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   outcast
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nerd
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Todd Solondz
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Todd Solondz
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Heather Matarazzo
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Christina Brucato
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Victoria Davis
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmGuy34567
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse-***1/2 (out of 4): Junior high can be tough and it is especially tough for little Dawn, who suffers from her abusive classmates, less than satisfactory home life, and her own discomfort with the problems of adolescence. Perhaps one of the most raw and unsentimental coming of age pictures ever made, though the tone is purely original. We are in many ways touched and even heartbroken by the central character and her troubles, but often catch ourselves laughing at the sheer misery and misfortune encountered by her. Half black comic and half drama, but completely insightful: this film is definitely one for the books. It also is the first display of the humorous misery of writer-director's Todd Solondz's imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to watch... But brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rich Wright
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'd think, with all the humiliations that pile up on our mousy heroine over the course of this unbearably cruel film, the scene is set for a big revenge moment... A huge climax where she finally sticks it to all her enemies and proves her worth. You would be completely wrong. This is no 'triumph of the underdog' tale, just a survival story about the spirit of a kid who must endure almost consistent harassment everyday, whether she's at school or home... And we wonder, how does she avoid cracking up? Her family don't want anything to do with her, preferring to lavish their affections on her 'perfect' younger sister, while in class she's the target of bullies, and the teachers seem to consist of a bunch of patronising jerks. Even the few chinks of light that occasionally shine through the gloom of her existence are quickly snuffed out, so if you're looking for a movie to put you in a good mood you're better off watching Bambi's mother get shot on an endless loop. BUT... (and this is a massive BUT) it also happens to be one of the finest films I've seen in years. I had it on DVD but guess what... a massive scratch on the disc stopped it after half an hour. Even with that small taste, I knew it was something special. So I waited... And FINALLY the whole thing has been uploaded to Youtube... And may I just say, it fulfilled my initial reaction to it, and then some. A huge part of it's success lies squarely at the feet of Heather Matarazzo, who cuts a sympathetic (or perhaps just pathetic) figure as she shuffles through life, being abused and hated by all. It's a role which could easily have descended into caricature, but her breathtaking performance as a bright girl doomed by circumstance to eke out this rubbish existence makes her plight evermore tragic. The supporting parts hit the bullseye too, as everyone from her nerdy best (and only) friend to her tutu-wearing, sickly-sweet younger sibling infuse proceedings with a quality which is rarely seen. This is a great film... Not a happy one, but I guarantee a far more relatable flick than half the homogenised coming-of-age motion pictures out there. You know, the ones where everyone is beautiful, most of your fellow students are wealthy minorities and you burst into the chorus of a cheesy song every few minutes. Hmm, what could I possibly be talking about... 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennsouthwest
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ha ha ha. Her friends make her poop on the floor of the school bathroom. Her little sister gets kidnapped by a pedophile and is kept prisoner in sub-floor space. Isn't that funny? I didn't think so. I can enjoy very dark humor. I can laugh about things that others find offensive, so it takes something really cruel and raw to turn my stomach. This was not done in a satirical way. It looked dead serious, but they added little tidbits here and there to let you know it was supposed to be a comedy. I wasn't sure in the movie theater whether I was more disturbed by the movie, or by the fact that other viewers were laughing! If you aren't disturbed by pedophilia, excrement-related bullying and other such themes, and in fact, you find all of those topics very funny, this may be just the movie for you. The actors were very talented and certainly convincing in their roles. The director made it all seem very real. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kind of misanthropic but fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Adam Thirwell
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing about watching a film like this at a time when the American high school genre has moved on to the much rosier visions of Napoleon Dynamite and Glee is that it strikes you how almost every character is a flawed, unlikeable person. Sure, you feel sorry and empathise with Dawn, the main character, but she's equally willing to bully, and doesn't have saving graces like the standard US school film geek - she's no brainbox. The guys in the film are portrayed as far less vindictive than the girls - bad boy Brandon has a sort of rogue honour, and the main fault of the other males in Dawn's life is that they are obsessed with doing their own thing or else following expectations laid down for them. It's a very watchable film - more so than Todd Solondz's later works. It looks like the work of an embittered outsider, but at least an outsider who, like the main character, tries to do their own thing against the odds.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbie and the Beast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like Woody Allen, Todd Solondz spends his time poking fun at man's foibles, whilst perhaps simultaneously wishing he weren't part of the very social fabric he condemns. It's your classic ego trap: "I'm better and above you, but worthless and wish I were with you." Solondz made "Fear, Anxiety and Depression" in 1989. He wrote and directed that film and, like Woody Allen, also cast himself as the film's neurotic hero. Like Allen's alter ego in "Annie Hall", the geeky looking Solondz spent the entire film bumbling about, venting his various dissaffections. Solondz was never happy with "Fear", however, and promptly disowned the film when his producers re-edited it behind his back. Burnt by the film industry, Solondz slipped into depression. He withdrew into isolation and became a teacher and writer. During these years his approach to art changed drastically. His screenplays became more formal, more precise, more caustic, and his visual style became cold. Ice cold. Solondz's first film when he emerged from his depression was "Welcome to the Dollhouse". Drawing upon his own unhappy school years, "Dollhouse" is about Dawn Weiner, a girl whom the universe seems to have condemned. More sinister than similar teen movies, "Dollhouse's" Dawn is so insecure she's happy to let a kid at school rape her if it means validating her own self worth. This would be rapist is himself marginalized, insecure and so reliant on sexual threats for self validation. Dawn is so filled with rage she even saws off the heads of her sister's dolls, fantasises about bashing people with a hammer and deliberately causes her sibling to be kidnapped by a local paedophile. Meanwhile, all the abuses people hurl at the geeky Dawn, Dawn hurls down at her little sister, a girl whom she unfairly despises. The result is that Dawn is shown to be capable of the same kind of brutality that she's subjected to. Social bullying is internalised, becomes self-hatred, and is then redirected violently back out at others. "Dollhouse" was a cosy film compared to Solondz's next three flicks. In "Happiness" he portrays a web of characters, all of whom harbour different problems and neuroses, and all of whom are linked by their desire for absolute contentment. And so we have a paedophile who is only happy around kids, a successful writer who is only happy if she writes something of substance, a musician (who ironically writes songs of substance) who can't find success and is so discontent, an elderly couple who no longer have the will to live, a fat man who fantasises about raping women, a fat woman who is disgusted by sex and a dopey housewife who is blissfully unaware of the disturbing truths that exist beneath her sweet suburban facade. Forget "American Beauty" and "Blue Velvet". Solondz ends his film with a Norman Rockwell kid ejaculating on his front balcony. Solondz's point is almost classically psychoanalytic: Lack breeds Desire breeds Suffering. Peel away the emotional baggage and happiness is a stain that oft amounts to nothing more than a fleeting moment of biological bliss. "Happiness" doesn't broadening its horizons to tackle the wider social and structural issues that better directors align to their existential musings, but it does offer more than Sam Mendes' "American Beauty". Indeed, Solondz's next film, "Storytelling", seemed designed to address those critics who pointed out the similarities between "Happiness" and "American Beauty". Mendes has himself slammed Solondz on numerous occasions, and so perhaps "Storytelling" is best viewed as a sort of intellectual assault on Solondz's critics. "Storytelling" is divided into two segments, the first called "fiction" the second called "non-fiction". "Fiction" is about a creative writing student who has "sympathy sex" with a mentally disabled kid and later lets her African American teacher "rape" her. She then turns her experiences into a work of fiction which purports to be "truthfully" based on these factual encounters. "Storytelling's" second segment then focuses on a documentary director who makes a documentary called "American Scooby" (a parody of "American Beauty") in which he follows a high school student around campus. The documentary director hopes to uncover the "truth" of growing up in suburbia, but in reality is merely transposing his own "deep thoughts", self-analysis and existential hang-ups onto a modern teen who is actually a dopey airhead. The end result is that film-maker and child enter a sort of exploitative relationship. The kid gets fame and is portrayed as being "deeper" than he is, while the film-maker gets prestige for nothing. End result: Solondz essentially advocates the sort of "truthful" sensationalism present in the non-fiction segment of the film, whilst aligning human delusions (love, romantic illusions, family etc) with the fictions of the second half. Other themes abound - the power games and domination/exploitatin reversals of "Dollhouse" are reworked here with subplots about a vengeful maid and a black teacher - but it's the "American Beauty" angle that's most interesting. "Palindromes" is thus far the weakest of Solondz's films. The first and last words in the movie are "Mom", a pair of palindromes through which Solondz implies that "nothing ever changes". Indeed, Solondz makes the film a palindrome at every level, his Schopenhaueran point being that we are paradoxically always changing and never changing (hence different actors play the same character), every desire and addiction merely supplanting another. It's an extremely bleak film, depending how much trust the audience puts in its final monologue. This bleakness has led to critics labelling Solondz a misanthrope, but he's no more colder than both Allen and the Coens, two other contemporary critical darlings who've spent their careers reworking similar material. 7.9/10  "Welcome to the Dollhouse", "Palindromes" 8/10  "Storytelling", "Happiness"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sketch of adolescent alienation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse is about a girl named Dawn who fails to find a place anywhere in society. She seems to be the victim of middle child syndrome as her parents are too worried about their other two children to bother much with her. Dawn's brother is already established as the brainy oldest child and her sister is the cute one, leaving her without an easy way to establish her own identity. At school she is is unable to fit in at least partially because her parents don't care enough about her to help her dress normally for her age. Because she isn't nurtured at home, she also fails to develop socially and her personality is too thin to make her sympathetic to the other students. Predictably, she is treated as poorly at school as she is at home. Welcome to the Dollhouse is full of these devastating scenes in which Dawn get her hopes up only to have them knocked down again. Her parents and classmates are oblivious to her suffering; no matter how bad things are for her nobody ever seems to think about her feelings. Things also tend to go against her as a matter of course. She is frequently unlucky as when she attempts to get revenge on her tormentors and accidentally targets an unsuspecting adult. Welcome to the Dollhouse does a fairly good job of capturing an unfortunate girl at a particularly awkward time of life. It suffers from a lack of realism at times, however, since it's unlikely that every teacher and student would hate a person that is more bland than offensive. Even more detrimental than the film's lack of realism in establishing Dawn's situation is the film's lack of style. The visuals are unremarkable and the only memorable aesthetic choice is the tacky design in Dawn's home. The plot takes a detour into absurdity when Dawn's sister is kidnapped but surprisingly this isn't really played for laughs in spite of some humorous elements. I was surprised to learn that this wasn't director Todd Solondz's first feature as it felt like the work of a film-maker looking to gain enough confidence to do the things he really wanted to. Welcome to the Dollhouse does an adequate job of establishing a single character but it feels like it's missing some crucial elements that could have made it truly memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Todd Solondz initiates a world of downers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never heard of Todd Solondz, then I should explain that "Welcome to the Dollhouse" is probably the most watchable. His movies - at least the few that I've seen - are always complete downers, containing characters who are either sickos, helpless, or something similar. His first notable movie concerns Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo), a New Jersey middle school girl ostracized by everyone around her. The only boy who gives her any good advice is totally pitiful himself. Dawn's entire life is one big FML. I recommend "WTTD", but with the caution that it IS a total downer. Hell, you might not even end up liking it. But it is worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the horrors of middle school
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film well encapsulates the horrors of middle school, perhaps more than was your experience, but the point is well taken. This unfortunately-named girl (Dawn Wiener), whose plight is not helped by her gawky looks, nerdiness, and refusal to take her punishment lying down, brings the pain of middle school into sharp relief. Having read a lot of the comments on IMDb, it's clear that this movie resonates with many. Landmark director Todd Solondz doesn't shrink from depicting the most cringe-inducing, skin-peeling, soul-destroying tortures inflicted by kids on their peers during those difficult tweener/teen years. Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo) lives with a mother who has no idea of the pain in which her daughter is in and with a father with no guts to intervene to his wife on his daughter's behalf. Her older brother is an academic success, although also very nerdy and her younger sister is the belle of the ball who can do no wrong in her mother's eyes. Solondz has constructed a very plausible hell in which his young protagonist suffers. She has no friends save for one boy who is the only other member of her "Special People Club". Her locker is the site of some particularly vitriolic abuse (although, having worked at schools, I found it implausible to believe that no teacher would have intervened to have the abuse removed), she is called "lesbo" and one girl who is particularly nasty will not let her leave the restroom without taking a crap. I liked the fact that this protagonist does not take the abuse lying down. Solondz creates such a good movie that he does not make Wiener into a wallflower. Indeed, she reacts in sometimes callous ways, taking out the anger she feels on someone less powerful than her. It's not necessarily pretty, but it's human nature. She reacts in anger to several things and I found this refreshing. She is not depicted as an ineffectual person. She fights back against her treatment-which people do, in real life-and Solondz deserves credit for this characterization of his protagonist. This really is a tough film to watch but I think this is one many young teens and tweeners would do well to watch and discuss with their parents because it could be a jumping-off point for a discussion about bullying and cruelty at this very difficult age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At three o'clock today, I'm going to rape you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dawn is bullied in her middle school. She is insecure, wears unflattering clothes and doesn't feel attractive. Her inattentive parents care far more about her smart and nerdy older brother and her spoilt, elegant little sister(that she actually has to share a room with, in spite of being 11) than her, leaving her the overlooked middle child. She falls in love with a guy five years her senior. But could that possibly work out? This is one of the most brutally honest(it admits that teenagers actually think about sex), painful(the cake scene is torture), and difficult to watch films I've ever seen. I knew that it would be, because this is not my first exposure to the immensely talented Solondz... I own a copy of the quite good Storytelling, and I had heard that this was much harder on the viewer. This really doesn't let up(there are those that will use the word "nihilistic"), it's pure bared nerve endings, and it shows with no pretense the kind of cruelty some of us experience, and what effect it has on us. Everyone lashes out at someone weaker than them when they're in agony. While some of the actions do encourage headscratching, the characters in this are entirely realistic(I would say almost everything in this is), credible and well-developed. No one is a hero or a villain(don't expect to like everything about any of them). The acting is amazing. Matarazzo(who I can barely believe was willing to play the role) is impossibly perfect. Her body language, voice, eyes, everything is spot-on. Everyone is convincing in this. The tension is present and thick right from the beginning. I suppose one could argue that this doesn't have all that much genuine plot... we get a string of scenes in chronological order, and several things aren't followed up on. A ton does happen; I think this is mainly meant to show a small portion of the girl's life. Don't expect a lot of growth or change, or for this to have a conclusion(it kind of just stops... one can interpret the last image to mean something, though, and it certainly isn't randomly chosen). I'm not sure I understand classifying this as a comedy... if so, definitely note that it's black and sardonic humor. You can really *feel* the setting. The lunch-room, class-room and the suburban home... you're *there*, and you feel as suffocated and trapped as our lead does. This is filmed and edited impeccably well. There is disturbing content and strong language throughout this. The DVD comes with a trailer. I recommend this to anyone who wants an uncompromising look at what for many are the worst years of their life. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On trying to find DVDs, v1.10
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    annevejb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A prime quality that the DVD had for me was a price much higher than I usually can pay. Used to be that when I browsed IMDb details I sometimes looked at the tag at the top that showed availability in the different Amazon countries, availability as disk or tape or whatever. Way back then I purchased from local low cost shops, but it was interesting to browse. Then I progressed to purchases from the local, UK, Amazon but only for what I could pay for by cheque. Then I got to be able to pay electronically and it was suddenly possible to purchase low cost disks from second hand sources in the UK, Germany, USA and Canada, etc, via Amazon UK. The disk availability box at the top of an IMDb page was starting to have potential for real value, though I tended to search just in Amazon UK. Some of the really interesting disks were not available, some needed access to paying to a different country's Amazon, especially for low cost disks, but this was a massive start for being able to search for disks by title rather than from the more restricted range of what was available locally. Locally is still really useful, but it is more a serendipity sort of thing. Then the IMDb system changed. The disk availability button was not there. Then it was there but not showing the range of countries or versions of disks, if UK Amazon had the title in a variety of versions then either only one would be shown or an Amazon USA version would be shown. So, there was a basic indicator of availability, which is useful knowledge, just the way of searching the different stores was gone and at August 2009 this was still gone. So things were okay and unless an Amazon other than UK became the sole outlet for such as The Adventures Of Pete And Pete Season 3, some have a hunger for that Trachtenberg series, then things were tolerable. What happened instead was that Amazon USA became the sole outlet for Unfabulous Seasons 1 and 2. Also Zoey 101 seasons 3 and 4. While the prices are nothing like my ideal it was suddenly essential for me to get a payment method that Amazon USA accepts and in August 2009 I managed. Dollhouse. When I got to make my first order there was a copy of this at USA at a much lower price than I had ever noticed at Amazon UK or any other outlet. Except that order failed, it was not available for a delivery address in the UK. Two other items went through, though. It looks as if some traders are able to export, but not others. Later experiences told me that I still have a problem re availability of difficult to find titles. The outlook can seem bleak. The stuff that I had been noticing will mostly have not been available for export. * Dollhouse is from the year when season 3 of Pete, Pete appears and is a couple of years after Heather Matarazzo appeared in an episode of each of seasons 0 and 1. It is weaker than Pete, but in some ways it is as strong. I find that it echoes My Girl and Tideland, but from a different culture and in a more down to earth way. All have the main actor as of an appropriate age, scary but sense when musing on these sort of aspects. Dollhouse is bound to feel offensive to some who can accept My Girl. To me it has a reality that I can relate to more than with My Girl, though both stories are alien at the same time. Napoleon Dynamite, about a different age range and a different subset of symptoms, I now have to wonder how those characters would appear if that story was set at age eleven. Mysterious Skin and The Quiet expand on the range of faces of this. I found Dollhouse difficult to get into, but I vastly prefer this to Princess Diaries as that falls flat for me as soon as Mia gets the makeover, the point where one is supposed to gain empathy with Mia? Much is said of Dollhouse being a story about the difficulties that an ugly girl can face at age 12, but watch this with any care at all and it is obvious that this is a rather nice looking girl who is badly damaged by the ugly ways of those around her. One needs the right sort of helps to be able to get around that sort of thing and this story makes a loud comment about how real those helps can be. I have to like this feature a lot. The message board hints of some considering the three bad boys to be pure criminal types, but the strongest hint put in a criminal way. For me, Dollhouse gives a context that puts such into perspective. What this shows of their back to front reality, criminal seems an inappropriate label. That is the real strength of this feature. This is not about the apex of the pyramid of society, it shows a dunghill. Dawn comes out with some really putrid behaviour and there are some reviews here that consider that to be a reflection of her personality. To me, she is just showing some effects that can happen when one is blowing in the wind, chaff that does not have enough free will to escape being blown in that way. Rather than Dawn being horror I consider that she is blown into a horrifying and damaging situation, but one has had to have been in that sort of situation oneself to accept that is an aspect of her being a victim of horror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmGuy34567
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse-***1/2 (out of 4): Junior high can be tough and it is especially tough for little Dawn, who suffers from her abusive classmates, less than satisfactory home life, and her own discomfort with the problems of adolescence. Perhaps one of the most raw and unsentimental coming of age pictures ever made, though the tone is purely original. We are in many ways touched and even heartbroken by the central character and her troubles, but often catch ourselves laughing at the sheer misery and misfortune encountered by her. Half black comic and half drama, but completely insightful: this film is definitely one for the books. It also is the first display of the humorous misery of writer-director's Todd Solondz's imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to watch... But brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rich Wright
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'd think, with all the humiliations that pile up on our mousy heroine over the course of this unbearably cruel film, the scene is set for a big revenge moment... A huge climax where she finally sticks it to all her enemies and proves her worth. You would be completely wrong. This is no 'triumph of the underdog' tale, just a survival story about the spirit of a kid who must endure almost consistent harassment everyday, whether she's at school or home... And we wonder, how does she avoid cracking up? Her family don't want anything to do with her, preferring to lavish their affections on her 'perfect' younger sister, while in class she's the target of bullies, and the teachers seem to consist of a bunch of patronising jerks. Even the few chinks of light that occasionally shine through the gloom of her existence are quickly snuffed out, so if you're looking for a movie to put you in a good mood you're better off watching Bambi's mother get shot on an endless loop. BUT... (and this is a massive BUT) it also happens to be one of the finest films I've seen in years. I had it on DVD but guess what... a massive scratch on the disc stopped it after half an hour. Even with that small taste, I knew it was something special. So I waited... And FINALLY the whole thing has been uploaded to Youtube... And may I just say, it fulfilled my initial reaction to it, and then some. A huge part of it's success lies squarely at the feet of Heather Matarazzo, who cuts a sympathetic (or perhaps just pathetic) figure as she shuffles through life, being abused and hated by all. It's a role which could easily have descended into caricature, but her breathtaking performance as a bright girl doomed by circumstance to eke out this rubbish existence makes her plight evermore tragic. The supporting parts hit the bullseye too, as everyone from her nerdy best (and only) friend to her tutu-wearing, sickly-sweet younger sibling infuse proceedings with a quality which is rarely seen. This is a great film... Not a happy one, but I guarantee a far more relatable flick than half the homogenised coming-of-age motion pictures out there. You know, the ones where everyone is beautiful, most of your fellow students are wealthy minorities and you burst into the chorus of a cheesy song every few minutes. Hmm, what could I possibly be talking about... 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennsouthwest
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ha ha ha. Her friends make her poop on the floor of the school bathroom. Her little sister gets kidnapped by a pedophile and is kept prisoner in sub-floor space. Isn't that funny? I didn't think so. I can enjoy very dark humor. I can laugh about things that others find offensive, so it takes something really cruel and raw to turn my stomach. This was not done in a satirical way. It looked dead serious, but they added little tidbits here and there to let you know it was supposed to be a comedy. I wasn't sure in the movie theater whether I was more disturbed by the movie, or by the fact that other viewers were laughing! If you aren't disturbed by pedophilia, excrement-related bullying and other such themes, and in fact, you find all of those topics very funny, this may be just the movie for you. The actors were very talented and certainly convincing in their roles. The director made it all seem very real. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kind of misanthropic but fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Adam Thirwell
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing about watching a film like this at a time when the American high school genre has moved on to the much rosier visions of Napoleon Dynamite and Glee is that it strikes you how almost every character is a flawed, unlikeable person. Sure, you feel sorry and empathise with Dawn, the main character, but she's equally willing to bully, and doesn't have saving graces like the standard US school film geek - she's no brainbox. The guys in the film are portrayed as far less vindictive than the girls - bad boy Brandon has a sort of rogue honour, and the main fault of the other males in Dawn's life is that they are obsessed with doing their own thing or else following expectations laid down for them. It's a very watchable film - more so than Todd Solondz's later works. It looks like the work of an embittered outsider, but at least an outsider who, like the main character, tries to do their own thing against the odds.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbie and the Beast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like Woody Allen, Todd Solondz spends his time poking fun at man's foibles, whilst perhaps simultaneously wishing he weren't part of the very social fabric he condemns. It's your classic ego trap: "I'm better and above you, but worthless and wish I were with you." Solondz made "Fear, Anxiety and Depression" in 1989. He wrote and directed that film and, like Woody Allen, also cast himself as the film's neurotic hero. Like Allen's alter ego in "Annie Hall", the geeky looking Solondz spent the entire film bumbling about, venting his various dissaffections. Solondz was never happy with "Fear", however, and promptly disowned the film when his producers re-edited it behind his back. Burnt by the film industry, Solondz slipped into depression. He withdrew into isolation and became a teacher and writer. During these years his approach to art changed drastically. His screenplays became more formal, more precise, more caustic, and his visual style became cold. Ice cold. Solondz's first film when he emerged from his depression was "Welcome to the Dollhouse". Drawing upon his own unhappy school years, "Dollhouse" is about Dawn Weiner, a girl whom the universe seems to have condemned. More sinister than similar teen movies, "Dollhouse's" Dawn is so insecure she's happy to let a kid at school rape her if it means validating her own self worth. This would be rapist is himself marginalized, insecure and so reliant on sexual threats for self validation. Dawn is so filled with rage she even saws off the heads of her sister's dolls, fantasises about bashing people with a hammer and deliberately causes her sibling to be kidnapped by a local paedophile. Meanwhile, all the abuses people hurl at the geeky Dawn, Dawn hurls down at her little sister, a girl whom she unfairly despises. The result is that Dawn is shown to be capable of the same kind of brutality that she's subjected to. Social bullying is internalised, becomes self-hatred, and is then redirected violently back out at others. "Dollhouse" was a cosy film compared to Solondz's next three flicks. In "Happiness" he portrays a web of characters, all of whom harbour different problems and neuroses, and all of whom are linked by their desire for absolute contentment. And so we have a paedophile who is only happy around kids, a successful writer who is only happy if she writes something of substance, a musician (who ironically writes songs of substance) who can't find success and is so discontent, an elderly couple who no longer have the will to live, a fat man who fantasises about raping women, a fat woman who is disgusted by sex and a dopey housewife who is blissfully unaware of the disturbing truths that exist beneath her sweet suburban facade. Forget "American Beauty" and "Blue Velvet". Solondz ends his film with a Norman Rockwell kid ejaculating on his front balcony. Solondz's point is almost classically psychoanalytic: Lack breeds Desire breeds Suffering. Peel away the emotional baggage and happiness is a stain that oft amounts to nothing more than a fleeting moment of biological bliss. "Happiness" doesn't broadening its horizons to tackle the wider social and structural issues that better directors align to their existential musings, but it does offer more than Sam Mendes' "American Beauty". Indeed, Solondz's next film, "Storytelling", seemed designed to address those critics who pointed out the similarities between "Happiness" and "American Beauty". Mendes has himself slammed Solondz on numerous occasions, and so perhaps "Storytelling" is best viewed as a sort of intellectual assault on Solondz's critics. "Storytelling" is divided into two segments, the first called "fiction" the second called "non-fiction". "Fiction" is about a creative writing student who has "sympathy sex" with a mentally disabled kid and later lets her African American teacher "rape" her. She then turns her experiences into a work of fiction which purports to be "truthfully" based on these factual encounters. "Storytelling's" second segment then focuses on a documentary director who makes a documentary called "American Scooby" (a parody of "American Beauty") in which he follows a high school student around campus. The documentary director hopes to uncover the "truth" of growing up in suburbia, but in reality is merely transposing his own "deep thoughts", self-analysis and existential hang-ups onto a modern teen who is actually a dopey airhead. The end result is that film-maker and child enter a sort of exploitative relationship. The kid gets fame and is portrayed as being "deeper" than he is, while the film-maker gets prestige for nothing. End result: Solondz essentially advocates the sort of "truthful" sensationalism present in the non-fiction segment of the film, whilst aligning human delusions (love, romantic illusions, family etc) with the fictions of the second half. Other themes abound - the power games and domination/exploitatin reversals of "Dollhouse" are reworked here with subplots about a vengeful maid and a black teacher - but it's the "American Beauty" angle that's most interesting. "Palindromes" is thus far the weakest of Solondz's films. The first and last words in the movie are "Mom", a pair of palindromes through which Solondz implies that "nothing ever changes". Indeed, Solondz makes the film a palindrome at every level, his Schopenhaueran point being that we are paradoxically always changing and never changing (hence different actors play the same character), every desire and addiction merely supplanting another. It's an extremely bleak film, depending how much trust the audience puts in its final monologue. This bleakness has led to critics labelling Solondz a misanthrope, but he's no more colder than both Allen and the Coens, two other contemporary critical darlings who've spent their careers reworking similar material. 7.9/10  "Welcome to the Dollhouse", "Palindromes" 8/10  "Storytelling", "Happiness"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sketch of adolescent alienation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse is about a girl named Dawn who fails to find a place anywhere in society. She seems to be the victim of middle child syndrome as her parents are too worried about their other two children to bother much with her. Dawn's brother is already established as the brainy oldest child and her sister is the cute one, leaving her without an easy way to establish her own identity. At school she is is unable to fit in at least partially because her parents don't care enough about her to help her dress normally for her age. Because she isn't nurtured at home, she also fails to develop socially and her personality is too thin to make her sympathetic to the other students. Predictably, she is treated as poorly at school as she is at home. Welcome to the Dollhouse is full of these devastating scenes in which Dawn get her hopes up only to have them knocked down again. Her parents and classmates are oblivious to her suffering; no matter how bad things are for her nobody ever seems to think about her feelings. Things also tend to go against her as a matter of course. She is frequently unlucky as when she attempts to get revenge on her tormentors and accidentally targets an unsuspecting adult. Welcome to the Dollhouse does a fairly good job of capturing an unfortunate girl at a particularly awkward time of life. It suffers from a lack of realism at times, however, since it's unlikely that every teacher and student would hate a person that is more bland than offensive. Even more detrimental than the film's lack of realism in establishing Dawn's situation is the film's lack of style. The visuals are unremarkable and the only memorable aesthetic choice is the tacky design in Dawn's home. The plot takes a detour into absurdity when Dawn's sister is kidnapped but surprisingly this isn't really played for laughs in spite of some humorous elements. I was surprised to learn that this wasn't director Todd Solondz's first feature as it felt like the work of a film-maker looking to gain enough confidence to do the things he really wanted to. Welcome to the Dollhouse does an adequate job of establishing a single character but it feels like it's missing some crucial elements that could have made it truly memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Todd Solondz initiates a world of downers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never heard of Todd Solondz, then I should explain that "Welcome to the Dollhouse" is probably the most watchable. His movies - at least the few that I've seen - are always complete downers, containing characters who are either sickos, helpless, or something similar. His first notable movie concerns Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo), a New Jersey middle school girl ostracized by everyone around her. The only boy who gives her any good advice is totally pitiful himself. Dawn's entire life is one big FML. I recommend "WTTD", but with the caution that it IS a total downer. Hell, you might not even end up liking it. But it is worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the horrors of middle school
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film well encapsulates the horrors of middle school, perhaps more than was your experience, but the point is well taken. This unfortunately-named girl (Dawn Wiener), whose plight is not helped by her gawky looks, nerdiness, and refusal to take her punishment lying down, brings the pain of middle school into sharp relief. Having read a lot of the comments on IMDb, it's clear that this movie resonates with many. Landmark director Todd Solondz doesn't shrink from depicting the most cringe-inducing, skin-peeling, soul-destroying tortures inflicted by kids on their peers during those difficult tweener/teen years. Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo) lives with a mother who has no idea of the pain in which her daughter is in and with a father with no guts to intervene to his wife on his daughter's behalf. Her older brother is an academic success, although also very nerdy and her younger sister is the belle of the ball who can do no wrong in her mother's eyes. Solondz has constructed a very plausible hell in which his young protagonist suffers. She has no friends save for one boy who is the only other member of her "Special People Club". Her locker is the site of some particularly vitriolic abuse (although, having worked at schools, I found it implausible to believe that no teacher would have intervened to have the abuse removed), she is called "lesbo" and one girl who is particularly nasty will not let her leave the restroom without taking a crap. I liked the fact that this protagonist does not take the abuse lying down. Solondz creates such a good movie that he does not make Wiener into a wallflower. Indeed, she reacts in sometimes callous ways, taking out the anger she feels on someone less powerful than her. It's not necessarily pretty, but it's human nature. She reacts in anger to several things and I found this refreshing. She is not depicted as an ineffectual person. She fights back against her treatment-which people do, in real life-and Solondz deserves credit for this characterization of his protagonist. This really is a tough film to watch but I think this is one many young teens and tweeners would do well to watch and discuss with their parents because it could be a jumping-off point for a discussion about bullying and cruelty at this very difficult age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At three o'clock today, I'm going to rape you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dawn is bullied in her middle school. She is insecure, wears unflattering clothes and doesn't feel attractive. Her inattentive parents care far more about her smart and nerdy older brother and her spoilt, elegant little sister(that she actually has to share a room with, in spite of being 11) than her, leaving her the overlooked middle child. She falls in love with a guy five years her senior. But could that possibly work out? This is one of the most brutally honest(it admits that teenagers actually think about sex), painful(the cake scene is torture), and difficult to watch films I've ever seen. I knew that it would be, because this is not my first exposure to the immensely talented Solondz... I own a copy of the quite good Storytelling, and I had heard that this was much harder on the viewer. This really doesn't let up(there are those that will use the word "nihilistic"), it's pure bared nerve endings, and it shows with no pretense the kind of cruelty some of us experience, and what effect it has on us. Everyone lashes out at someone weaker than them when they're in agony. While some of the actions do encourage headscratching, the characters in this are entirely realistic(I would say almost everything in this is), credible and well-developed. No one is a hero or a villain(don't expect to like everything about any of them). The acting is amazing. Matarazzo(who I can barely believe was willing to play the role) is impossibly perfect. Her body language, voice, eyes, everything is spot-on. Everyone is convincing in this. The tension is present and thick right from the beginning. I suppose one could argue that this doesn't have all that much genuine plot... we get a string of scenes in chronological order, and several things aren't followed up on. A ton does happen; I think this is mainly meant to show a small portion of the girl's life. Don't expect a lot of growth or change, or for this to have a conclusion(it kind of just stops... one can interpret the last image to mean something, though, and it certainly isn't randomly chosen). I'm not sure I understand classifying this as a comedy... if so, definitely note that it's black and sardonic humor. You can really *feel* the setting. The lunch-room, class-room and the suburban home... you're *there*, and you feel as suffocated and trapped as our lead does. This is filmed and edited impeccably well. There is disturbing content and strong language throughout this. The DVD comes with a trailer. I recommend this to anyone who wants an uncompromising look at what for many are the worst years of their life. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On trying to find DVDs, v1.10
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    annevejb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A prime quality that the DVD had for me was a price much higher than I usually can pay. Used to be that when I browsed IMDb details I sometimes looked at the tag at the top that showed availability in the different Amazon countries, availability as disk or tape or whatever. Way back then I purchased from local low cost shops, but it was interesting to browse. Then I progressed to purchases from the local, UK, Amazon but only for what I could pay for by cheque. Then I got to be able to pay electronically and it was suddenly possible to purchase low cost disks from second hand sources in the UK, Germany, USA and Canada, etc, via Amazon UK. The disk availability box at the top of an IMDb page was starting to have potential for real value, though I tended to search just in Amazon UK. Some of the really interesting disks were not available, some needed access to paying to a different country's Amazon, especially for low cost disks, but this was a massive start for being able to search for disks by title rather than from the more restricted range of what was available locally. Locally is still really useful, but it is more a serendipity sort of thing. Then the IMDb system changed. The disk availability button was not there. Then it was there but not showing the range of countries or versions of disks, if UK Amazon had the title in a variety of versions then either only one would be shown or an Amazon USA version would be shown. So, there was a basic indicator of availability, which is useful knowledge, just the way of searching the different stores was gone and at August 2009 this was still gone. So things were okay and unless an Amazon other than UK became the sole outlet for such as The Adventures Of Pete And Pete Season 3, some have a hunger for that Trachtenberg series, then things were tolerable. What happened instead was that Amazon USA became the sole outlet for Unfabulous Seasons 1 and 2. Also Zoey 101 seasons 3 and 4. While the prices are nothing like my ideal it was suddenly essential for me to get a payment method that Amazon USA accepts and in August 2009 I managed. Dollhouse. When I got to make my first order there was a copy of this at USA at a much lower price than I had ever noticed at Amazon UK or any other outlet. Except that order failed, it was not available for a delivery address in the UK. Two other items went through, though. It looks as if some traders are able to export, but not others. Later experiences told me that I still have a problem re availability of difficult to find titles. The outlook can seem bleak. The stuff that I had been noticing will mostly have not been available for export. * Dollhouse is from the year when season 3 of Pete, Pete appears and is a couple of years after Heather Matarazzo appeared in an episode of each of seasons 0 and 1. It is weaker than Pete, but in some ways it is as strong. I find that it echoes My Girl and Tideland, but from a different culture and in a more down to earth way. All have the main actor as of an appropriate age, scary but sense when musing on these sort of aspects. Dollhouse is bound to feel offensive to some who can accept My Girl. To me it has a reality that I can relate to more than with My Girl, though both stories are alien at the same time. Napoleon Dynamite, about a different age range and a different subset of symptoms, I now have to wonder how those characters would appear if that story was set at age eleven. Mysterious Skin and The Quiet expand on the range of faces of this. I found Dollhouse difficult to get into, but I vastly prefer this to Princess Diaries as that falls flat for me as soon as Mia gets the makeover, the point where one is supposed to gain empathy with Mia? Much is said of Dollhouse being a story about the difficulties that an ugly girl can face at age 12, but watch this with any care at all and it is obvious that this is a rather nice looking girl who is badly damaged by the ugly ways of those around her. One needs the right sort of helps to be able to get around that sort of thing and this story makes a loud comment about how real those helps can be. I have to like this feature a lot. The message board hints of some considering the three bad boys to be pure criminal types, but the strongest hint put in a criminal way. For me, Dollhouse gives a context that puts such into perspective. What this shows of their back to front reality, criminal seems an inappropriate label. That is the real strength of this feature. This is not about the apex of the pyramid of society, it shows a dunghill. Dawn comes out with some really putrid behaviour and there are some reviews here that consider that to be a reflection of her personality. To me, she is just showing some effects that can happen when one is blowing in the wind, chaff that does not have enough free will to escape being blown in that way. Rather than Dawn being horror I consider that she is blown into a horrifying and damaging situation, but one has had to have been in that sort of situation oneself to accept that is an aspect of her being a victim of horror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmGuy34567
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse-***1/2 (out of 4): Junior high can be tough and it is especially tough for little Dawn, who suffers from her abusive classmates, less than satisfactory home life, and her own discomfort with the problems of adolescence. Perhaps one of the most raw and unsentimental coming of age pictures ever made, though the tone is purely original. We are in many ways touched and even heartbroken by the central character and her troubles, but often catch ourselves laughing at the sheer misery and misfortune encountered by her. Half black comic and half drama, but completely insightful: this film is definitely one for the books. It also is the first display of the humorous misery of writer-director's Todd Solondz's imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to watch... But brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rich Wright
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'd think, with all the humiliations that pile up on our mousy heroine over the course of this unbearably cruel film, the scene is set for a big revenge moment... A huge climax where she finally sticks it to all her enemies and proves her worth. You would be completely wrong. This is no 'triumph of the underdog' tale, just a survival story about the spirit of a kid who must endure almost consistent harassment everyday, whether she's at school or home... And we wonder, how does she avoid cracking up? Her family don't want anything to do with her, preferring to lavish their affections on her 'perfect' younger sister, while in class she's the target of bullies, and the teachers seem to consist of a bunch of patronising jerks. Even the few chinks of light that occasionally shine through the gloom of her existence are quickly snuffed out, so if you're looking for a movie to put you in a good mood you're better off watching Bambi's mother get shot on an endless loop. BUT... (and this is a massive BUT) it also happens to be one of the finest films I've seen in years. I had it on DVD but guess what... a massive scratch on the disc stopped it after half an hour. Even with that small taste, I knew it was something special. So I waited... And FINALLY the whole thing has been uploaded to Youtube... And may I just say, it fulfilled my initial reaction to it, and then some. A huge part of it's success lies squarely at the feet of Heather Matarazzo, who cuts a sympathetic (or perhaps just pathetic) figure as she shuffles through life, being abused and hated by all. It's a role which could easily have descended into caricature, but her breathtaking performance as a bright girl doomed by circumstance to eke out this rubbish existence makes her plight evermore tragic. The supporting parts hit the bullseye too, as everyone from her nerdy best (and only) friend to her tutu-wearing, sickly-sweet younger sibling infuse proceedings with a quality which is rarely seen. This is a great film... Not a happy one, but I guarantee a far more relatable flick than half the homogenised coming-of-age motion pictures out there. You know, the ones where everyone is beautiful, most of your fellow students are wealthy minorities and you burst into the chorus of a cheesy song every few minutes. Hmm, what could I possibly be talking about... 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennsouthwest
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ha ha ha. Her friends make her poop on the floor of the school bathroom. Her little sister gets kidnapped by a pedophile and is kept prisoner in sub-floor space. Isn't that funny? I didn't think so. I can enjoy very dark humor. I can laugh about things that others find offensive, so it takes something really cruel and raw to turn my stomach. This was not done in a satirical way. It looked dead serious, but they added little tidbits here and there to let you know it was supposed to be a comedy. I wasn't sure in the movie theater whether I was more disturbed by the movie, or by the fact that other viewers were laughing! If you aren't disturbed by pedophilia, excrement-related bullying and other such themes, and in fact, you find all of those topics very funny, this may be just the movie for you. The actors were very talented and certainly convincing in their roles. The director made it all seem very real. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kind of misanthropic but fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Adam Thirwell
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing about watching a film like this at a time when the American high school genre has moved on to the much rosier visions of Napoleon Dynamite and Glee is that it strikes you how almost every character is a flawed, unlikeable person. Sure, you feel sorry and empathise with Dawn, the main character, but she's equally willing to bully, and doesn't have saving graces like the standard US school film geek - she's no brainbox. The guys in the film are portrayed as far less vindictive than the girls - bad boy Brandon has a sort of rogue honour, and the main fault of the other males in Dawn's life is that they are obsessed with doing their own thing or else following expectations laid down for them. It's a very watchable film - more so than Todd Solondz's later works. It looks like the work of an embittered outsider, but at least an outsider who, like the main character, tries to do their own thing against the odds.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbie and the Beast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like Woody Allen, Todd Solondz spends his time poking fun at man's foibles, whilst perhaps simultaneously wishing he weren't part of the very social fabric he condemns. It's your classic ego trap: "I'm better and above you, but worthless and wish I were with you." Solondz made "Fear, Anxiety and Depression" in 1989. He wrote and directed that film and, like Woody Allen, also cast himself as the film's neurotic hero. Like Allen's alter ego in "Annie Hall", the geeky looking Solondz spent the entire film bumbling about, venting his various dissaffections. Solondz was never happy with "Fear", however, and promptly disowned the film when his producers re-edited it behind his back. Burnt by the film industry, Solondz slipped into depression. He withdrew into isolation and became a teacher and writer. During these years his approach to art changed drastically. His screenplays became more formal, more precise, more caustic, and his visual style became cold. Ice cold. Solondz's first film when he emerged from his depression was "Welcome to the Dollhouse". Drawing upon his own unhappy school years, "Dollhouse" is about Dawn Weiner, a girl whom the universe seems to have condemned. More sinister than similar teen movies, "Dollhouse's" Dawn is so insecure she's happy to let a kid at school rape her if it means validating her own self worth. This would be rapist is himself marginalized, insecure and so reliant on sexual threats for self validation. Dawn is so filled with rage she even saws off the heads of her sister's dolls, fantasises about bashing people with a hammer and deliberately causes her sibling to be kidnapped by a local paedophile. Meanwhile, all the abuses people hurl at the geeky Dawn, Dawn hurls down at her little sister, a girl whom she unfairly despises. The result is that Dawn is shown to be capable of the same kind of brutality that she's subjected to. Social bullying is internalised, becomes self-hatred, and is then redirected violently back out at others. "Dollhouse" was a cosy film compared to Solondz's next three flicks. In "Happiness" he portrays a web of characters, all of whom harbour different problems and neuroses, and all of whom are linked by their desire for absolute contentment. And so we have a paedophile who is only happy around kids, a successful writer who is only happy if she writes something of substance, a musician (who ironically writes songs of substance) who can't find success and is so discontent, an elderly couple who no longer have the will to live, a fat man who fantasises about raping women, a fat woman who is disgusted by sex and a dopey housewife who is blissfully unaware of the disturbing truths that exist beneath her sweet suburban facade. Forget "American Beauty" and "Blue Velvet". Solondz ends his film with a Norman Rockwell kid ejaculating on his front balcony. Solondz's point is almost classically psychoanalytic: Lack breeds Desire breeds Suffering. Peel away the emotional baggage and happiness is a stain that oft amounts to nothing more than a fleeting moment of biological bliss. "Happiness" doesn't broadening its horizons to tackle the wider social and structural issues that better directors align to their existential musings, but it does offer more than Sam Mendes' "American Beauty". Indeed, Solondz's next film, "Storytelling", seemed designed to address those critics who pointed out the similarities between "Happiness" and "American Beauty". Mendes has himself slammed Solondz on numerous occasions, and so perhaps "Storytelling" is best viewed as a sort of intellectual assault on Solondz's critics. "Storytelling" is divided into two segments, the first called "fiction" the second called "non-fiction". "Fiction" is about a creative writing student who has "sympathy sex" with a mentally disabled kid and later lets her African American teacher "rape" her. She then turns her experiences into a work of fiction which purports to be "truthfully" based on these factual encounters. "Storytelling's" second segment then focuses on a documentary director who makes a documentary called "American Scooby" (a parody of "American Beauty") in which he follows a high school student around campus. The documentary director hopes to uncover the "truth" of growing up in suburbia, but in reality is merely transposing his own "deep thoughts", self-analysis and existential hang-ups onto a modern teen who is actually a dopey airhead. The end result is that film-maker and child enter a sort of exploitative relationship. The kid gets fame and is portrayed as being "deeper" than he is, while the film-maker gets prestige for nothing. End result: Solondz essentially advocates the sort of "truthful" sensationalism present in the non-fiction segment of the film, whilst aligning human delusions (love, romantic illusions, family etc) with the fictions of the second half. Other themes abound - the power games and domination/exploitatin reversals of "Dollhouse" are reworked here with subplots about a vengeful maid and a black teacher - but it's the "American Beauty" angle that's most interesting. "Palindromes" is thus far the weakest of Solondz's films. The first and last words in the movie are "Mom", a pair of palindromes through which Solondz implies that "nothing ever changes". Indeed, Solondz makes the film a palindrome at every level, his Schopenhaueran point being that we are paradoxically always changing and never changing (hence different actors play the same character), every desire and addiction merely supplanting another. It's an extremely bleak film, depending how much trust the audience puts in its final monologue. This bleakness has led to critics labelling Solondz a misanthrope, but he's no more colder than both Allen and the Coens, two other contemporary critical darlings who've spent their careers reworking similar material. 7.9/10  "Welcome to the Dollhouse", "Palindromes" 8/10  "Storytelling", "Happiness"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sketch of adolescent alienation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse is about a girl named Dawn who fails to find a place anywhere in society. She seems to be the victim of middle child syndrome as her parents are too worried about their other two children to bother much with her. Dawn's brother is already established as the brainy oldest child and her sister is the cute one, leaving her without an easy way to establish her own identity. At school she is is unable to fit in at least partially because her parents don't care enough about her to help her dress normally for her age. Because she isn't nurtured at home, she also fails to develop socially and her personality is too thin to make her sympathetic to the other students. Predictably, she is treated as poorly at school as she is at home. Welcome to the Dollhouse is full of these devastating scenes in which Dawn get her hopes up only to have them knocked down again. Her parents and classmates are oblivious to her suffering; no matter how bad things are for her nobody ever seems to think about her feelings. Things also tend to go against her as a matter of course. She is frequently unlucky as when she attempts to get revenge on her tormentors and accidentally targets an unsuspecting adult. Welcome to the Dollhouse does a fairly good job of capturing an unfortunate girl at a particularly awkward time of life. It suffers from a lack of realism at times, however, since it's unlikely that every teacher and student would hate a person that is more bland than offensive. Even more detrimental than the film's lack of realism in establishing Dawn's situation is the film's lack of style. The visuals are unremarkable and the only memorable aesthetic choice is the tacky design in Dawn's home. The plot takes a detour into absurdity when Dawn's sister is kidnapped but surprisingly this isn't really played for laughs in spite of some humorous elements. I was surprised to learn that this wasn't director Todd Solondz's first feature as it felt like the work of a film-maker looking to gain enough confidence to do the things he really wanted to. Welcome to the Dollhouse does an adequate job of establishing a single character but it feels like it's missing some crucial elements that could have made it truly memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Todd Solondz initiates a world of downers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never heard of Todd Solondz, then I should explain that "Welcome to the Dollhouse" is probably the most watchable. His movies - at least the few that I've seen - are always complete downers, containing characters who are either sickos, helpless, or something similar. His first notable movie concerns Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo), a New Jersey middle school girl ostracized by everyone around her. The only boy who gives her any good advice is totally pitiful himself. Dawn's entire life is one big FML. I recommend "WTTD", but with the caution that it IS a total downer. Hell, you might not even end up liking it. But it is worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the horrors of middle school
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film well encapsulates the horrors of middle school, perhaps more than was your experience, but the point is well taken. This unfortunately-named girl (Dawn Wiener), whose plight is not helped by her gawky looks, nerdiness, and refusal to take her punishment lying down, brings the pain of middle school into sharp relief. Having read a lot of the comments on IMDb, it's clear that this movie resonates with many. Landmark director Todd Solondz doesn't shrink from depicting the most cringe-inducing, skin-peeling, soul-destroying tortures inflicted by kids on their peers during those difficult tweener/teen years. Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo) lives with a mother who has no idea of the pain in which her daughter is in and with a father with no guts to intervene to his wife on his daughter's behalf. Her older brother is an academic success, although also very nerdy and her younger sister is the belle of the ball who can do no wrong in her mother's eyes. Solondz has constructed a very plausible hell in which his young protagonist suffers. She has no friends save for one boy who is the only other member of her "Special People Club". Her locker is the site of some particularly vitriolic abuse (although, having worked at schools, I found it implausible to believe that no teacher would have intervened to have the abuse removed), she is called "lesbo" and one girl who is particularly nasty will not let her leave the restroom without taking a crap. I liked the fact that this protagonist does not take the abuse lying down. Solondz creates such a good movie that he does not make Wiener into a wallflower. Indeed, she reacts in sometimes callous ways, taking out the anger she feels on someone less powerful than her. It's not necessarily pretty, but it's human nature. She reacts in anger to several things and I found this refreshing. She is not depicted as an ineffectual person. She fights back against her treatment-which people do, in real life-and Solondz deserves credit for this characterization of his protagonist. This really is a tough film to watch but I think this is one many young teens and tweeners would do well to watch and discuss with their parents because it could be a jumping-off point for a discussion about bullying and cruelty at this very difficult age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At three o'clock today, I'm going to rape you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dawn is bullied in her middle school. She is insecure, wears unflattering clothes and doesn't feel attractive. Her inattentive parents care far more about her smart and nerdy older brother and her spoilt, elegant little sister(that she actually has to share a room with, in spite of being 11) than her, leaving her the overlooked middle child. She falls in love with a guy five years her senior. But could that possibly work out? This is one of the most brutally honest(it admits that teenagers actually think about sex), painful(the cake scene is torture), and difficult to watch films I've ever seen. I knew that it would be, because this is not my first exposure to the immensely talented Solondz... I own a copy of the quite good Storytelling, and I had heard that this was much harder on the viewer. This really doesn't let up(there are those that will use the word "nihilistic"), it's pure bared nerve endings, and it shows with no pretense the kind of cruelty some of us experience, and what effect it has on us. Everyone lashes out at someone weaker than them when they're in agony. While some of the actions do encourage headscratching, the characters in this are entirely realistic(I would say almost everything in this is), credible and well-developed. No one is a hero or a villain(don't expect to like everything about any of them). The acting is amazing. Matarazzo(who I can barely believe was willing to play the role) is impossibly perfect. Her body language, voice, eyes, everything is spot-on. Everyone is convincing in this. The tension is present and thick right from the beginning. I suppose one could argue that this doesn't have all that much genuine plot... we get a string of scenes in chronological order, and several things aren't followed up on. A ton does happen; I think this is mainly meant to show a small portion of the girl's life. Don't expect a lot of growth or change, or for this to have a conclusion(it kind of just stops... one can interpret the last image to mean something, though, and it certainly isn't randomly chosen). I'm not sure I understand classifying this as a comedy... if so, definitely note that it's black and sardonic humor. You can really *feel* the setting. The lunch-room, class-room and the suburban home... you're *there*, and you feel as suffocated and trapped as our lead does. This is filmed and edited impeccably well. There is disturbing content and strong language throughout this. The DVD comes with a trailer. I recommend this to anyone who wants an uncompromising look at what for many are the worst years of their life. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On trying to find DVDs, v1.10
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    annevejb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A prime quality that the DVD had for me was a price much higher than I usually can pay. Used to be that when I browsed IMDb details I sometimes looked at the tag at the top that showed availability in the different Amazon countries, availability as disk or tape or whatever. Way back then I purchased from local low cost shops, but it was interesting to browse. Then I progressed to purchases from the local, UK, Amazon but only for what I could pay for by cheque. Then I got to be able to pay electronically and it was suddenly possible to purchase low cost disks from second hand sources in the UK, Germany, USA and Canada, etc, via Amazon UK. The disk availability box at the top of an IMDb page was starting to have potential for real value, though I tended to search just in Amazon UK. Some of the really interesting disks were not available, some needed access to paying to a different country's Amazon, especially for low cost disks, but this was a massive start for being able to search for disks by title rather than from the more restricted range of what was available locally. Locally is still really useful, but it is more a serendipity sort of thing. Then the IMDb system changed. The disk availability button was not there. Then it was there but not showing the range of countries or versions of disks, if UK Amazon had the title in a variety of versions then either only one would be shown or an Amazon USA version would be shown. So, there was a basic indicator of availability, which is useful knowledge, just the way of searching the different stores was gone and at August 2009 this was still gone. So things were okay and unless an Amazon other than UK became the sole outlet for such as The Adventures Of Pete And Pete Season 3, some have a hunger for that Trachtenberg series, then things were tolerable. What happened instead was that Amazon USA became the sole outlet for Unfabulous Seasons 1 and 2. Also Zoey 101 seasons 3 and 4. While the prices are nothing like my ideal it was suddenly essential for me to get a payment method that Amazon USA accepts and in August 2009 I managed. Dollhouse. When I got to make my first order there was a copy of this at USA at a much lower price than I had ever noticed at Amazon UK or any other outlet. Except that order failed, it was not available for a delivery address in the UK. Two other items went through, though. It looks as if some traders are able to export, but not others. Later experiences told me that I still have a problem re availability of difficult to find titles. The outlook can seem bleak. The stuff that I had been noticing will mostly have not been available for export. * Dollhouse is from the year when season 3 of Pete, Pete appears and is a couple of years after Heather Matarazzo appeared in an episode of each of seasons 0 and 1. It is weaker than Pete, but in some ways it is as strong. I find that it echoes My Girl and Tideland, but from a different culture and in a more down to earth way. All have the main actor as of an appropriate age, scary but sense when musing on these sort of aspects. Dollhouse is bound to feel offensive to some who can accept My Girl. To me it has a reality that I can relate to more than with My Girl, though both stories are alien at the same time. Napoleon Dynamite, about a different age range and a different subset of symptoms, I now have to wonder how those characters would appear if that story was set at age eleven. Mysterious Skin and The Quiet expand on the range of faces of this. I found Dollhouse difficult to get into, but I vastly prefer this to Princess Diaries as that falls flat for me as soon as Mia gets the makeover, the point where one is supposed to gain empathy with Mia? Much is said of Dollhouse being a story about the difficulties that an ugly girl can face at age 12, but watch this with any care at all and it is obvious that this is a rather nice looking girl who is badly damaged by the ugly ways of those around her. One needs the right sort of helps to be able to get around that sort of thing and this story makes a loud comment about how real those helps can be. I have to like this feature a lot. The message board hints of some considering the three bad boys to be pure criminal types, but the strongest hint put in a criminal way. For me, Dollhouse gives a context that puts such into perspective. What this shows of their back to front reality, criminal seems an inappropriate label. That is the real strength of this feature. This is not about the apex of the pyramid of society, it shows a dunghill. Dawn comes out with some really putrid behaviour and there are some reviews here that consider that to be a reflection of her personality. To me, she is just showing some effects that can happen when one is blowing in the wind, chaff that does not have enough free will to escape being blown in that way. Rather than Dawn being horror I consider that she is blown into a horrifying and damaging situation, but one has had to have been in that sort of situation oneself to accept that is an aspect of her being a victim of horror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmGuy34567
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse-***1/2 (out of 4): Junior high can be tough and it is especially tough for little Dawn, who suffers from her abusive classmates, less than satisfactory home life, and her own discomfort with the problems of adolescence. Perhaps one of the most raw and unsentimental coming of age pictures ever made, though the tone is purely original. We are in many ways touched and even heartbroken by the central character and her troubles, but often catch ourselves laughing at the sheer misery and misfortune encountered by her. Half black comic and half drama, but completely insightful: this film is definitely one for the books. It also is the first display of the humorous misery of writer-director's Todd Solondz's imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to watch... But brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rich Wright
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'd think, with all the humiliations that pile up on our mousy heroine over the course of this unbearably cruel film, the scene is set for a big revenge moment... A huge climax where she finally sticks it to all her enemies and proves her worth. You would be completely wrong. This is no 'triumph of the underdog' tale, just a survival story about the spirit of a kid who must endure almost consistent harassment everyday, whether she's at school or home... And we wonder, how does she avoid cracking up? Her family don't want anything to do with her, preferring to lavish their affections on her 'perfect' younger sister, while in class she's the target of bullies, and the teachers seem to consist of a bunch of patronising jerks. Even the few chinks of light that occasionally shine through the gloom of her existence are quickly snuffed out, so if you're looking for a movie to put you in a good mood you're better off watching Bambi's mother get shot on an endless loop. BUT... (and this is a massive BUT) it also happens to be one of the finest films I've seen in years. I had it on DVD but guess what... a massive scratch on the disc stopped it after half an hour. Even with that small taste, I knew it was something special. So I waited... And FINALLY the whole thing has been uploaded to Youtube... And may I just say, it fulfilled my initial reaction to it, and then some. A huge part of it's success lies squarely at the feet of Heather Matarazzo, who cuts a sympathetic (or perhaps just pathetic) figure as she shuffles through life, being abused and hated by all. It's a role which could easily have descended into caricature, but her breathtaking performance as a bright girl doomed by circumstance to eke out this rubbish existence makes her plight evermore tragic. The supporting parts hit the bullseye too, as everyone from her nerdy best (and only) friend to her tutu-wearing, sickly-sweet younger sibling infuse proceedings with a quality which is rarely seen. This is a great film... Not a happy one, but I guarantee a far more relatable flick than half the homogenised coming-of-age motion pictures out there. You know, the ones where everyone is beautiful, most of your fellow students are wealthy minorities and you burst into the chorus of a cheesy song every few minutes. Hmm, what could I possibly be talking about... 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennsouthwest
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ha ha ha. Her friends make her poop on the floor of the school bathroom. Her little sister gets kidnapped by a pedophile and is kept prisoner in sub-floor space. Isn't that funny? I didn't think so. I can enjoy very dark humor. I can laugh about things that others find offensive, so it takes something really cruel and raw to turn my stomach. This was not done in a satirical way. It looked dead serious, but they added little tidbits here and there to let you know it was supposed to be a comedy. I wasn't sure in the movie theater whether I was more disturbed by the movie, or by the fact that other viewers were laughing! If you aren't disturbed by pedophilia, excrement-related bullying and other such themes, and in fact, you find all of those topics very funny, this may be just the movie for you. The actors were very talented and certainly convincing in their roles. The director made it all seem very real. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kind of misanthropic but fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Adam Thirwell
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing about watching a film like this at a time when the American high school genre has moved on to the much rosier visions of Napoleon Dynamite and Glee is that it strikes you how almost every character is a flawed, unlikeable person. Sure, you feel sorry and empathise with Dawn, the main character, but she's equally willing to bully, and doesn't have saving graces like the standard US school film geek - she's no brainbox. The guys in the film are portrayed as far less vindictive than the girls - bad boy Brandon has a sort of rogue honour, and the main fault of the other males in Dawn's life is that they are obsessed with doing their own thing or else following expectations laid down for them. It's a very watchable film - more so than Todd Solondz's later works. It looks like the work of an embittered outsider, but at least an outsider who, like the main character, tries to do their own thing against the odds.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbie and the Beast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like Woody Allen, Todd Solondz spends his time poking fun at man's foibles, whilst perhaps simultaneously wishing he weren't part of the very social fabric he condemns. It's your classic ego trap: "I'm better and above you, but worthless and wish I were with you." Solondz made "Fear, Anxiety and Depression" in 1989. He wrote and directed that film and, like Woody Allen, also cast himself as the film's neurotic hero. Like Allen's alter ego in "Annie Hall", the geeky looking Solondz spent the entire film bumbling about, venting his various dissaffections. Solondz was never happy with "Fear", however, and promptly disowned the film when his producers re-edited it behind his back. Burnt by the film industry, Solondz slipped into depression. He withdrew into isolation and became a teacher and writer. During these years his approach to art changed drastically. His screenplays became more formal, more precise, more caustic, and his visual style became cold. Ice cold. Solondz's first film when he emerged from his depression was "Welcome to the Dollhouse". Drawing upon his own unhappy school years, "Dollhouse" is about Dawn Weiner, a girl whom the universe seems to have condemned. More sinister than similar teen movies, "Dollhouse's" Dawn is so insecure she's happy to let a kid at school rape her if it means validating her own self worth. This would be rapist is himself marginalized, insecure and so reliant on sexual threats for self validation. Dawn is so filled with rage she even saws off the heads of her sister's dolls, fantasises about bashing people with a hammer and deliberately causes her sibling to be kidnapped by a local paedophile. Meanwhile, all the abuses people hurl at the geeky Dawn, Dawn hurls down at her little sister, a girl whom she unfairly despises. The result is that Dawn is shown to be capable of the same kind of brutality that she's subjected to. Social bullying is internalised, becomes self-hatred, and is then redirected violently back out at others. "Dollhouse" was a cosy film compared to Solondz's next three flicks. In "Happiness" he portrays a web of characters, all of whom harbour different problems and neuroses, and all of whom are linked by their desire for absolute contentment. And so we have a paedophile who is only happy around kids, a successful writer who is only happy if she writes something of substance, a musician (who ironically writes songs of substance) who can't find success and is so discontent, an elderly couple who no longer have the will to live, a fat man who fantasises about raping women, a fat woman who is disgusted by sex and a dopey housewife who is blissfully unaware of the disturbing truths that exist beneath her sweet suburban facade. Forget "American Beauty" and "Blue Velvet". Solondz ends his film with a Norman Rockwell kid ejaculating on his front balcony. Solondz's point is almost classically psychoanalytic: Lack breeds Desire breeds Suffering. Peel away the emotional baggage and happiness is a stain that oft amounts to nothing more than a fleeting moment of biological bliss. "Happiness" doesn't broadening its horizons to tackle the wider social and structural issues that better directors align to their existential musings, but it does offer more than Sam Mendes' "American Beauty". Indeed, Solondz's next film, "Storytelling", seemed designed to address those critics who pointed out the similarities between "Happiness" and "American Beauty". Mendes has himself slammed Solondz on numerous occasions, and so perhaps "Storytelling" is best viewed as a sort of intellectual assault on Solondz's critics. "Storytelling" is divided into two segments, the first called "fiction" the second called "non-fiction". "Fiction" is about a creative writing student who has "sympathy sex" with a mentally disabled kid and later lets her African American teacher "rape" her. She then turns her experiences into a work of fiction which purports to be "truthfully" based on these factual encounters. "Storytelling's" second segment then focuses on a documentary director who makes a documentary called "American Scooby" (a parody of "American Beauty") in which he follows a high school student around campus. The documentary director hopes to uncover the "truth" of growing up in suburbia, but in reality is merely transposing his own "deep thoughts", self-analysis and existential hang-ups onto a modern teen who is actually a dopey airhead. The end result is that film-maker and child enter a sort of exploitative relationship. The kid gets fame and is portrayed as being "deeper" than he is, while the film-maker gets prestige for nothing. End result: Solondz essentially advocates the sort of "truthful" sensationalism present in the non-fiction segment of the film, whilst aligning human delusions (love, romantic illusions, family etc) with the fictions of the second half. Other themes abound - the power games and domination/exploitatin reversals of "Dollhouse" are reworked here with subplots about a vengeful maid and a black teacher - but it's the "American Beauty" angle that's most interesting. "Palindromes" is thus far the weakest of Solondz's films. The first and last words in the movie are "Mom", a pair of palindromes through which Solondz implies that "nothing ever changes". Indeed, Solondz makes the film a palindrome at every level, his Schopenhaueran point being that we are paradoxically always changing and never changing (hence different actors play the same character), every desire and addiction merely supplanting another. It's an extremely bleak film, depending how much trust the audience puts in its final monologue. This bleakness has led to critics labelling Solondz a misanthrope, but he's no more colder than both Allen and the Coens, two other contemporary critical darlings who've spent their careers reworking similar material. 7.9/10  "Welcome to the Dollhouse", "Palindromes" 8/10  "Storytelling", "Happiness"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sketch of adolescent alienation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse is about a girl named Dawn who fails to find a place anywhere in society. She seems to be the victim of middle child syndrome as her parents are too worried about their other two children to bother much with her. Dawn's brother is already established as the brainy oldest child and her sister is the cute one, leaving her without an easy way to establish her own identity. At school she is is unable to fit in at least partially because her parents don't care enough about her to help her dress normally for her age. Because she isn't nurtured at home, she also fails to develop socially and her personality is too thin to make her sympathetic to the other students. Predictably, she is treated as poorly at school as she is at home. Welcome to the Dollhouse is full of these devastating scenes in which Dawn get her hopes up only to have them knocked down again. Her parents and classmates are oblivious to her suffering; no matter how bad things are for her nobody ever seems to think about her feelings. Things also tend to go against her as a matter of course. She is frequently unlucky as when she attempts to get revenge on her tormentors and accidentally targets an unsuspecting adult. Welcome to the Dollhouse does a fairly good job of capturing an unfortunate girl at a particularly awkward time of life. It suffers from a lack of realism at times, however, since it's unlikely that every teacher and student would hate a person that is more bland than offensive. Even more detrimental than the film's lack of realism in establishing Dawn's situation is the film's lack of style. The visuals are unremarkable and the only memorable aesthetic choice is the tacky design in Dawn's home. The plot takes a detour into absurdity when Dawn's sister is kidnapped but surprisingly this isn't really played for laughs in spite of some humorous elements. I was surprised to learn that this wasn't director Todd Solondz's first feature as it felt like the work of a film-maker looking to gain enough confidence to do the things he really wanted to. Welcome to the Dollhouse does an adequate job of establishing a single character but it feels like it's missing some crucial elements that could have made it truly memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Todd Solondz initiates a world of downers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never heard of Todd Solondz, then I should explain that "Welcome to the Dollhouse" is probably the most watchable. His movies - at least the few that I've seen - are always complete downers, containing characters who are either sickos, helpless, or something similar. His first notable movie concerns Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo), a New Jersey middle school girl ostracized by everyone around her. The only boy who gives her any good advice is totally pitiful himself. Dawn's entire life is one big FML. I recommend "WTTD", but with the caution that it IS a total downer. Hell, you might not even end up liking it. But it is worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the horrors of middle school
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film well encapsulates the horrors of middle school, perhaps more than was your experience, but the point is well taken. This unfortunately-named girl (Dawn Wiener), whose plight is not helped by her gawky looks, nerdiness, and refusal to take her punishment lying down, brings the pain of middle school into sharp relief. Having read a lot of the comments on IMDb, it's clear that this movie resonates with many. Landmark director Todd Solondz doesn't shrink from depicting the most cringe-inducing, skin-peeling, soul-destroying tortures inflicted by kids on their peers during those difficult tweener/teen years. Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo) lives with a mother who has no idea of the pain in which her daughter is in and with a father with no guts to intervene to his wife on his daughter's behalf. Her older brother is an academic success, although also very nerdy and her younger sister is the belle of the ball who can do no wrong in her mother's eyes. Solondz has constructed a very plausible hell in which his young protagonist suffers. She has no friends save for one boy who is the only other member of her "Special People Club". Her locker is the site of some particularly vitriolic abuse (although, having worked at schools, I found it implausible to believe that no teacher would have intervened to have the abuse removed), she is called "lesbo" and one girl who is particularly nasty will not let her leave the restroom without taking a crap. I liked the fact that this protagonist does not take the abuse lying down. Solondz creates such a good movie that he does not make Wiener into a wallflower. Indeed, she reacts in sometimes callous ways, taking out the anger she feels on someone less powerful than her. It's not necessarily pretty, but it's human nature. She reacts in anger to several things and I found this refreshing. She is not depicted as an ineffectual person. She fights back against her treatment-which people do, in real life-and Solondz deserves credit for this characterization of his protagonist. This really is a tough film to watch but I think this is one many young teens and tweeners would do well to watch and discuss with their parents because it could be a jumping-off point for a discussion about bullying and cruelty at this very difficult age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At three o'clock today, I'm going to rape you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dawn is bullied in her middle school. She is insecure, wears unflattering clothes and doesn't feel attractive. Her inattentive parents care far more about her smart and nerdy older brother and her spoilt, elegant little sister(that she actually has to share a room with, in spite of being 11) than her, leaving her the overlooked middle child. She falls in love with a guy five years her senior. But could that possibly work out? This is one of the most brutally honest(it admits that teenagers actually think about sex), painful(the cake scene is torture), and difficult to watch films I've ever seen. I knew that it would be, because this is not my first exposure to the immensely talented Solondz... I own a copy of the quite good Storytelling, and I had heard that this was much harder on the viewer. This really doesn't let up(there are those that will use the word "nihilistic"), it's pure bared nerve endings, and it shows with no pretense the kind of cruelty some of us experience, and what effect it has on us. Everyone lashes out at someone weaker than them when they're in agony. While some of the actions do encourage headscratching, the characters in this are entirely realistic(I would say almost everything in this is), credible and well-developed. No one is a hero or a villain(don't expect to like everything about any of them). The acting is amazing. Matarazzo(who I can barely believe was willing to play the role) is impossibly perfect. Her body language, voice, eyes, everything is spot-on. Everyone is convincing in this. The tension is present and thick right from the beginning. I suppose one could argue that this doesn't have all that much genuine plot... we get a string of scenes in chronological order, and several things aren't followed up on. A ton does happen; I think this is mainly meant to show a small portion of the girl's life. Don't expect a lot of growth or change, or for this to have a conclusion(it kind of just stops... one can interpret the last image to mean something, though, and it certainly isn't randomly chosen). I'm not sure I understand classifying this as a comedy... if so, definitely note that it's black and sardonic humor. You can really *feel* the setting. The lunch-room, class-room and the suburban home... you're *there*, and you feel as suffocated and trapped as our lead does. This is filmed and edited impeccably well. There is disturbing content and strong language throughout this. The DVD comes with a trailer. I recommend this to anyone who wants an uncompromising look at what for many are the worst years of their life. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On trying to find DVDs, v1.10
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    annevejb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A prime quality that the DVD had for me was a price much higher than I usually can pay. Used to be that when I browsed IMDb details I sometimes looked at the tag at the top that showed availability in the different Amazon countries, availability as disk or tape or whatever. Way back then I purchased from local low cost shops, but it was interesting to browse. Then I progressed to purchases from the local, UK, Amazon but only for what I could pay for by cheque. Then I got to be able to pay electronically and it was suddenly possible to purchase low cost disks from second hand sources in the UK, Germany, USA and Canada, etc, via Amazon UK. The disk availability box at the top of an IMDb page was starting to have potential for real value, though I tended to search just in Amazon UK. Some of the really interesting disks were not available, some needed access to paying to a different country's Amazon, especially for low cost disks, but this was a massive start for being able to search for disks by title rather than from the more restricted range of what was available locally. Locally is still really useful, but it is more a serendipity sort of thing. Then the IMDb system changed. The disk availability button was not there. Then it was there but not showing the range of countries or versions of disks, if UK Amazon had the title in a variety of versions then either only one would be shown or an Amazon USA version would be shown. So, there was a basic indicator of availability, which is useful knowledge, just the way of searching the different stores was gone and at August 2009 this was still gone. So things were okay and unless an Amazon other than UK became the sole outlet for such as The Adventures Of Pete And Pete Season 3, some have a hunger for that Trachtenberg series, then things were tolerable. What happened instead was that Amazon USA became the sole outlet for Unfabulous Seasons 1 and 2. Also Zoey 101 seasons 3 and 4. While the prices are nothing like my ideal it was suddenly essential for me to get a payment method that Amazon USA accepts and in August 2009 I managed. Dollhouse. When I got to make my first order there was a copy of this at USA at a much lower price than I had ever noticed at Amazon UK or any other outlet. Except that order failed, it was not available for a delivery address in the UK. Two other items went through, though. It looks as if some traders are able to export, but not others. Later experiences told me that I still have a problem re availability of difficult to find titles. The outlook can seem bleak. The stuff that I had been noticing will mostly have not been available for export. * Dollhouse is from the year when season 3 of Pete, Pete appears and is a couple of years after Heather Matarazzo appeared in an episode of each of seasons 0 and 1. It is weaker than Pete, but in some ways it is as strong. I find that it echoes My Girl and Tideland, but from a different culture and in a more down to earth way. All have the main actor as of an appropriate age, scary but sense when musing on these sort of aspects. Dollhouse is bound to feel offensive to some who can accept My Girl. To me it has a reality that I can relate to more than with My Girl, though both stories are alien at the same time. Napoleon Dynamite, about a different age range and a different subset of symptoms, I now have to wonder how those characters would appear if that story was set at age eleven. Mysterious Skin and The Quiet expand on the range of faces of this. I found Dollhouse difficult to get into, but I vastly prefer this to Princess Diaries as that falls flat for me as soon as Mia gets the makeover, the point where one is supposed to gain empathy with Mia? Much is said of Dollhouse being a story about the difficulties that an ugly girl can face at age 12, but watch this with any care at all and it is obvious that this is a rather nice looking girl who is badly damaged by the ugly ways of those around her. One needs the right sort of helps to be able to get around that sort of thing and this story makes a loud comment about how real those helps can be. I have to like this feature a lot. The message board hints of some considering the three bad boys to be pure criminal types, but the strongest hint put in a criminal way. For me, Dollhouse gives a context that puts such into perspective. What this shows of their back to front reality, criminal seems an inappropriate label. That is the real strength of this feature. This is not about the apex of the pyramid of society, it shows a dunghill. Dawn comes out with some really putrid behaviour and there are some reviews here that consider that to be a reflection of her personality. To me, she is just showing some effects that can happen when one is blowing in the wind, chaff that does not have enough free will to escape being blown in that way. Rather than Dawn being horror I consider that she is blown into a horrifying and damaging situation, but one has had to have been in that sort of situation oneself to accept that is an aspect of her being a victim of horror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmGuy34567
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse-***1/2 (out of 4): Junior high can be tough and it is especially tough for little Dawn, who suffers from her abusive classmates, less than satisfactory home life, and her own discomfort with the problems of adolescence. Perhaps one of the most raw and unsentimental coming of age pictures ever made, though the tone is purely original. We are in many ways touched and even heartbroken by the central character and her troubles, but often catch ourselves laughing at the sheer misery and misfortune encountered by her. Half black comic and half drama, but completely insightful: this film is definitely one for the books. It also is the first display of the humorous misery of writer-director's Todd Solondz's imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to watch... But brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rich Wright
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'd think, with all the humiliations that pile up on our mousy heroine over the course of this unbearably cruel film, the scene is set for a big revenge moment... A huge climax where she finally sticks it to all her enemies and proves her worth. You would be completely wrong. This is no 'triumph of the underdog' tale, just a survival story about the spirit of a kid who must endure almost consistent harassment everyday, whether she's at school or home... And we wonder, how does she avoid cracking up? Her family don't want anything to do with her, preferring to lavish their affections on her 'perfect' younger sister, while in class she's the target of bullies, and the teachers seem to consist of a bunch of patronising jerks. Even the few chinks of light that occasionally shine through the gloom of her existence are quickly snuffed out, so if you're looking for a movie to put you in a good mood you're better off watching Bambi's mother get shot on an endless loop. BUT... (and this is a massive BUT) it also happens to be one of the finest films I've seen in years. I had it on DVD but guess what... a massive scratch on the disc stopped it after half an hour. Even with that small taste, I knew it was something special. So I waited... And FINALLY the whole thing has been uploaded to Youtube... And may I just say, it fulfilled my initial reaction to it, and then some. A huge part of it's success lies squarely at the feet of Heather Matarazzo, who cuts a sympathetic (or perhaps just pathetic) figure as she shuffles through life, being abused and hated by all. It's a role which could easily have descended into caricature, but her breathtaking performance as a bright girl doomed by circumstance to eke out this rubbish existence makes her plight evermore tragic. The supporting parts hit the bullseye too, as everyone from her nerdy best (and only) friend to her tutu-wearing, sickly-sweet younger sibling infuse proceedings with a quality which is rarely seen. This is a great film... Not a happy one, but I guarantee a far more relatable flick than half the homogenised coming-of-age motion pictures out there. You know, the ones where everyone is beautiful, most of your fellow students are wealthy minorities and you burst into the chorus of a cheesy song every few minutes. Hmm, what could I possibly be talking about... 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennsouthwest
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ha ha ha. Her friends make her poop on the floor of the school bathroom. Her little sister gets kidnapped by a pedophile and is kept prisoner in sub-floor space. Isn't that funny? I didn't think so. I can enjoy very dark humor. I can laugh about things that others find offensive, so it takes something really cruel and raw to turn my stomach. This was not done in a satirical way. It looked dead serious, but they added little tidbits here and there to let you know it was supposed to be a comedy. I wasn't sure in the movie theater whether I was more disturbed by the movie, or by the fact that other viewers were laughing! If you aren't disturbed by pedophilia, excrement-related bullying and other such themes, and in fact, you find all of those topics very funny, this may be just the movie for you. The actors were very talented and certainly convincing in their roles. The director made it all seem very real. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kind of misanthropic but fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Adam Thirwell
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing about watching a film like this at a time when the American high school genre has moved on to the much rosier visions of Napoleon Dynamite and Glee is that it strikes you how almost every character is a flawed, unlikeable person. Sure, you feel sorry and empathise with Dawn, the main character, but she's equally willing to bully, and doesn't have saving graces like the standard US school film geek - she's no brainbox. The guys in the film are portrayed as far less vindictive than the girls - bad boy Brandon has a sort of rogue honour, and the main fault of the other males in Dawn's life is that they are obsessed with doing their own thing or else following expectations laid down for them. It's a very watchable film - more so than Todd Solondz's later works. It looks like the work of an embittered outsider, but at least an outsider who, like the main character, tries to do their own thing against the odds.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbie and the Beast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like Woody Allen, Todd Solondz spends his time poking fun at man's foibles, whilst perhaps simultaneously wishing he weren't part of the very social fabric he condemns. It's your classic ego trap: "I'm better and above you, but worthless and wish I were with you." Solondz made "Fear, Anxiety and Depression" in 1989. He wrote and directed that film and, like Woody Allen, also cast himself as the film's neurotic hero. Like Allen's alter ego in "Annie Hall", the geeky looking Solondz spent the entire film bumbling about, venting his various dissaffections. Solondz was never happy with "Fear", however, and promptly disowned the film when his producers re-edited it behind his back. Burnt by the film industry, Solondz slipped into depression. He withdrew into isolation and became a teacher and writer. During these years his approach to art changed drastically. His screenplays became more formal, more precise, more caustic, and his visual style became cold. Ice cold. Solondz's first film when he emerged from his depression was "Welcome to the Dollhouse". Drawing upon his own unhappy school years, "Dollhouse" is about Dawn Weiner, a girl whom the universe seems to have condemned. More sinister than similar teen movies, "Dollhouse's" Dawn is so insecure she's happy to let a kid at school rape her if it means validating her own self worth. This would be rapist is himself marginalized, insecure and so reliant on sexual threats for self validation. Dawn is so filled with rage she even saws off the heads of her sister's dolls, fantasises about bashing people with a hammer and deliberately causes her sibling to be kidnapped by a local paedophile. Meanwhile, all the abuses people hurl at the geeky Dawn, Dawn hurls down at her little sister, a girl whom she unfairly despises. The result is that Dawn is shown to be capable of the same kind of brutality that she's subjected to. Social bullying is internalised, becomes self-hatred, and is then redirected violently back out at others. "Dollhouse" was a cosy film compared to Solondz's next three flicks. In "Happiness" he portrays a web of characters, all of whom harbour different problems and neuroses, and all of whom are linked by their desire for absolute contentment. And so we have a paedophile who is only happy around kids, a successful writer who is only happy if she writes something of substance, a musician (who ironically writes songs of substance) who can't find success and is so discontent, an elderly couple who no longer have the will to live, a fat man who fantasises about raping women, a fat woman who is disgusted by sex and a dopey housewife who is blissfully unaware of the disturbing truths that exist beneath her sweet suburban facade. Forget "American Beauty" and "Blue Velvet". Solondz ends his film with a Norman Rockwell kid ejaculating on his front balcony. Solondz's point is almost classically psychoanalytic: Lack breeds Desire breeds Suffering. Peel away the emotional baggage and happiness is a stain that oft amounts to nothing more than a fleeting moment of biological bliss. "Happiness" doesn't broadening its horizons to tackle the wider social and structural issues that better directors align to their existential musings, but it does offer more than Sam Mendes' "American Beauty". Indeed, Solondz's next film, "Storytelling", seemed designed to address those critics who pointed out the similarities between "Happiness" and "American Beauty". Mendes has himself slammed Solondz on numerous occasions, and so perhaps "Storytelling" is best viewed as a sort of intellectual assault on Solondz's critics. "Storytelling" is divided into two segments, the first called "fiction" the second called "non-fiction". "Fiction" is about a creative writing student who has "sympathy sex" with a mentally disabled kid and later lets her African American teacher "rape" her. She then turns her experiences into a work of fiction which purports to be "truthfully" based on these factual encounters. "Storytelling's" second segment then focuses on a documentary director who makes a documentary called "American Scooby" (a parody of "American Beauty") in which he follows a high school student around campus. The documentary director hopes to uncover the "truth" of growing up in suburbia, but in reality is merely transposing his own "deep thoughts", self-analysis and existential hang-ups onto a modern teen who is actually a dopey airhead. The end result is that film-maker and child enter a sort of exploitative relationship. The kid gets fame and is portrayed as being "deeper" than he is, while the film-maker gets prestige for nothing. End result: Solondz essentially advocates the sort of "truthful" sensationalism present in the non-fiction segment of the film, whilst aligning human delusions (love, romantic illusions, family etc) with the fictions of the second half. Other themes abound - the power games and domination/exploitatin reversals of "Dollhouse" are reworked here with subplots about a vengeful maid and a black teacher - but it's the "American Beauty" angle that's most interesting. "Palindromes" is thus far the weakest of Solondz's films. The first and last words in the movie are "Mom", a pair of palindromes through which Solondz implies that "nothing ever changes". Indeed, Solondz makes the film a palindrome at every level, his Schopenhaueran point being that we are paradoxically always changing and never changing (hence different actors play the same character), every desire and addiction merely supplanting another. It's an extremely bleak film, depending how much trust the audience puts in its final monologue. This bleakness has led to critics labelling Solondz a misanthrope, but he's no more colder than both Allen and the Coens, two other contemporary critical darlings who've spent their careers reworking similar material. 7.9/10  "Welcome to the Dollhouse", "Palindromes" 8/10  "Storytelling", "Happiness"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sketch of adolescent alienation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse is about a girl named Dawn who fails to find a place anywhere in society. She seems to be the victim of middle child syndrome as her parents are too worried about their other two children to bother much with her. Dawn's brother is already established as the brainy oldest child and her sister is the cute one, leaving her without an easy way to establish her own identity. At school she is is unable to fit in at least partially because her parents don't care enough about her to help her dress normally for her age. Because she isn't nurtured at home, she also fails to develop socially and her personality is too thin to make her sympathetic to the other students. Predictably, she is treated as poorly at school as she is at home. Welcome to the Dollhouse is full of these devastating scenes in which Dawn get her hopes up only to have them knocked down again. Her parents and classmates are oblivious to her suffering; no matter how bad things are for her nobody ever seems to think about her feelings. Things also tend to go against her as a matter of course. She is frequently unlucky as when she attempts to get revenge on her tormentors and accidentally targets an unsuspecting adult. Welcome to the Dollhouse does a fairly good job of capturing an unfortunate girl at a particularly awkward time of life. It suffers from a lack of realism at times, however, since it's unlikely that every teacher and student would hate a person that is more bland than offensive. Even more detrimental than the film's lack of realism in establishing Dawn's situation is the film's lack of style. The visuals are unremarkable and the only memorable aesthetic choice is the tacky design in Dawn's home. The plot takes a detour into absurdity when Dawn's sister is kidnapped but surprisingly this isn't really played for laughs in spite of some humorous elements. I was surprised to learn that this wasn't director Todd Solondz's first feature as it felt like the work of a film-maker looking to gain enough confidence to do the things he really wanted to. Welcome to the Dollhouse does an adequate job of establishing a single character but it feels like it's missing some crucial elements that could have made it truly memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Todd Solondz initiates a world of downers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never heard of Todd Solondz, then I should explain that "Welcome to the Dollhouse" is probably the most watchable. His movies - at least the few that I've seen - are always complete downers, containing characters who are either sickos, helpless, or something similar. His first notable movie concerns Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo), a New Jersey middle school girl ostracized by everyone around her. The only boy who gives her any good advice is totally pitiful himself. Dawn's entire life is one big FML. I recommend "WTTD", but with the caution that it IS a total downer. Hell, you might not even end up liking it. But it is worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the horrors of middle school
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film well encapsulates the horrors of middle school, perhaps more than was your experience, but the point is well taken. This unfortunately-named girl (Dawn Wiener), whose plight is not helped by her gawky looks, nerdiness, and refusal to take her punishment lying down, brings the pain of middle school into sharp relief. Having read a lot of the comments on IMDb, it's clear that this movie resonates with many. Landmark director Todd Solondz doesn't shrink from depicting the most cringe-inducing, skin-peeling, soul-destroying tortures inflicted by kids on their peers during those difficult tweener/teen years. Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo) lives with a mother who has no idea of the pain in which her daughter is in and with a father with no guts to intervene to his wife on his daughter's behalf. Her older brother is an academic success, although also very nerdy and her younger sister is the belle of the ball who can do no wrong in her mother's eyes. Solondz has constructed a very plausible hell in which his young protagonist suffers. She has no friends save for one boy who is the only other member of her "Special People Club". Her locker is the site of some particularly vitriolic abuse (although, having worked at schools, I found it implausible to believe that no teacher would have intervened to have the abuse removed), she is called "lesbo" and one girl who is particularly nasty will not let her leave the restroom without taking a crap. I liked the fact that this protagonist does not take the abuse lying down. Solondz creates such a good movie that he does not make Wiener into a wallflower. Indeed, she reacts in sometimes callous ways, taking out the anger she feels on someone less powerful than her. It's not necessarily pretty, but it's human nature. She reacts in anger to several things and I found this refreshing. She is not depicted as an ineffectual person. She fights back against her treatment-which people do, in real life-and Solondz deserves credit for this characterization of his protagonist. This really is a tough film to watch but I think this is one many young teens and tweeners would do well to watch and discuss with their parents because it could be a jumping-off point for a discussion about bullying and cruelty at this very difficult age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At three o'clock today, I'm going to rape you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dawn is bullied in her middle school. She is insecure, wears unflattering clothes and doesn't feel attractive. Her inattentive parents care far more about her smart and nerdy older brother and her spoilt, elegant little sister(that she actually has to share a room with, in spite of being 11) than her, leaving her the overlooked middle child. She falls in love with a guy five years her senior. But could that possibly work out? This is one of the most brutally honest(it admits that teenagers actually think about sex), painful(the cake scene is torture), and difficult to watch films I've ever seen. I knew that it would be, because this is not my first exposure to the immensely talented Solondz... I own a copy of the quite good Storytelling, and I had heard that this was much harder on the viewer. This really doesn't let up(there are those that will use the word "nihilistic"), it's pure bared nerve endings, and it shows with no pretense the kind of cruelty some of us experience, and what effect it has on us. Everyone lashes out at someone weaker than them when they're in agony. While some of the actions do encourage headscratching, the characters in this are entirely realistic(I would say almost everything in this is), credible and well-developed. No one is a hero or a villain(don't expect to like everything about any of them). The acting is amazing. Matarazzo(who I can barely believe was willing to play the role) is impossibly perfect. Her body language, voice, eyes, everything is spot-on. Everyone is convincing in this. The tension is present and thick right from the beginning. I suppose one could argue that this doesn't have all that much genuine plot... we get a string of scenes in chronological order, and several things aren't followed up on. A ton does happen; I think this is mainly meant to show a small portion of the girl's life. Don't expect a lot of growth or change, or for this to have a conclusion(it kind of just stops... one can interpret the last image to mean something, though, and it certainly isn't randomly chosen). I'm not sure I understand classifying this as a comedy... if so, definitely note that it's black and sardonic humor. You can really *feel* the setting. The lunch-room, class-room and the suburban home... you're *there*, and you feel as suffocated and trapped as our lead does. This is filmed and edited impeccably well. There is disturbing content and strong language throughout this. The DVD comes with a trailer. I recommend this to anyone who wants an uncompromising look at what for many are the worst years of their life. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On trying to find DVDs, v1.10
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    annevejb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A prime quality that the DVD had for me was a price much higher than I usually can pay. Used to be that when I browsed IMDb details I sometimes looked at the tag at the top that showed availability in the different Amazon countries, availability as disk or tape or whatever. Way back then I purchased from local low cost shops, but it was interesting to browse. Then I progressed to purchases from the local, UK, Amazon but only for what I could pay for by cheque. Then I got to be able to pay electronically and it was suddenly possible to purchase low cost disks from second hand sources in the UK, Germany, USA and Canada, etc, via Amazon UK. The disk availability box at the top of an IMDb page was starting to have potential for real value, though I tended to search just in Amazon UK. Some of the really interesting disks were not available, some needed access to paying to a different country's Amazon, especially for low cost disks, but this was a massive start for being able to search for disks by title rather than from the more restricted range of what was available locally. Locally is still really useful, but it is more a serendipity sort of thing. Then the IMDb system changed. The disk availability button was not there. Then it was there but not showing the range of countries or versions of disks, if UK Amazon had the title in a variety of versions then either only one would be shown or an Amazon USA version would be shown. So, there was a basic indicator of availability, which is useful knowledge, just the way of searching the different stores was gone and at August 2009 this was still gone. So things were okay and unless an Amazon other than UK became the sole outlet for such as The Adventures Of Pete And Pete Season 3, some have a hunger for that Trachtenberg series, then things were tolerable. What happened instead was that Amazon USA became the sole outlet for Unfabulous Seasons 1 and 2. Also Zoey 101 seasons 3 and 4. While the prices are nothing like my ideal it was suddenly essential for me to get a payment method that Amazon USA accepts and in August 2009 I managed. Dollhouse. When I got to make my first order there was a copy of this at USA at a much lower price than I had ever noticed at Amazon UK or any other outlet. Except that order failed, it was not available for a delivery address in the UK. Two other items went through, though. It looks as if some traders are able to export, but not others. Later experiences told me that I still have a problem re availability of difficult to find titles. The outlook can seem bleak. The stuff that I had been noticing will mostly have not been available for export. * Dollhouse is from the year when season 3 of Pete, Pete appears and is a couple of years after Heather Matarazzo appeared in an episode of each of seasons 0 and 1. It is weaker than Pete, but in some ways it is as strong. I find that it echoes My Girl and Tideland, but from a different culture and in a more down to earth way. All have the main actor as of an appropriate age, scary but sense when musing on these sort of aspects. Dollhouse is bound to feel offensive to some who can accept My Girl. To me it has a reality that I can relate to more than with My Girl, though both stories are alien at the same time. Napoleon Dynamite, about a different age range and a different subset of symptoms, I now have to wonder how those characters would appear if that story was set at age eleven. Mysterious Skin and The Quiet expand on the range of faces of this. I found Dollhouse difficult to get into, but I vastly prefer this to Princess Diaries as that falls flat for me as soon as Mia gets the makeover, the point where one is supposed to gain empathy with Mia? Much is said of Dollhouse being a story about the difficulties that an ugly girl can face at age 12, but watch this with any care at all and it is obvious that this is a rather nice looking girl who is badly damaged by the ugly ways of those around her. One needs the right sort of helps to be able to get around that sort of thing and this story makes a loud comment about how real those helps can be. I have to like this feature a lot. The message board hints of some considering the three bad boys to be pure criminal types, but the strongest hint put in a criminal way. For me, Dollhouse gives a context that puts such into perspective. What this shows of their back to front reality, criminal seems an inappropriate label. That is the real strength of this feature. This is not about the apex of the pyramid of society, it shows a dunghill. Dawn comes out with some really putrid behaviour and there are some reviews here that consider that to be a reflection of her personality. To me, she is just showing some effects that can happen when one is blowing in the wind, chaff that does not have enough free will to escape being blown in that way. Rather than Dawn being horror I consider that she is blown into a horrifying and damaging situation, but one has had to have been in that sort of situation oneself to accept that is an aspect of her being a victim of horror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmGuy34567
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse-***1/2 (out of 4): Junior high can be tough and it is especially tough for little Dawn, who suffers from her abusive classmates, less than satisfactory home life, and her own discomfort with the problems of adolescence. Perhaps one of the most raw and unsentimental coming of age pictures ever made, though the tone is purely original. We are in many ways touched and even heartbroken by the central character and her troubles, but often catch ourselves laughing at the sheer misery and misfortune encountered by her. Half black comic and half drama, but completely insightful: this film is definitely one for the books. It also is the first display of the humorous misery of writer-director's Todd Solondz's imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to watch... But brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rich Wright
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'd think, with all the humiliations that pile up on our mousy heroine over the course of this unbearably cruel film, the scene is set for a big revenge moment... A huge climax where she finally sticks it to all her enemies and proves her worth. You would be completely wrong. This is no 'triumph of the underdog' tale, just a survival story about the spirit of a kid who must endure almost consistent harassment everyday, whether she's at school or home... And we wonder, how does she avoid cracking up? Her family don't want anything to do with her, preferring to lavish their affections on her 'perfect' younger sister, while in class she's the target of bullies, and the teachers seem to consist of a bunch of patronising jerks. Even the few chinks of light that occasionally shine through the gloom of her existence are quickly snuffed out, so if you're looking for a movie to put you in a good mood you're better off watching Bambi's mother get shot on an endless loop. BUT... (and this is a massive BUT) it also happens to be one of the finest films I've seen in years. I had it on DVD but guess what... a massive scratch on the disc stopped it after half an hour. Even with that small taste, I knew it was something special. So I waited... And FINALLY the whole thing has been uploaded to Youtube... And may I just say, it fulfilled my initial reaction to it, and then some. A huge part of it's success lies squarely at the feet of Heather Matarazzo, who cuts a sympathetic (or perhaps just pathetic) figure as she shuffles through life, being abused and hated by all. It's a role which could easily have descended into caricature, but her breathtaking performance as a bright girl doomed by circumstance to eke out this rubbish existence makes her plight evermore tragic. The supporting parts hit the bullseye too, as everyone from her nerdy best (and only) friend to her tutu-wearing, sickly-sweet younger sibling infuse proceedings with a quality which is rarely seen. This is a great film... Not a happy one, but I guarantee a far more relatable flick than half the homogenised coming-of-age motion pictures out there. You know, the ones where everyone is beautiful, most of your fellow students are wealthy minorities and you burst into the chorus of a cheesy song every few minutes. Hmm, what could I possibly be talking about... 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennsouthwest
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ha ha ha. Her friends make her poop on the floor of the school bathroom. Her little sister gets kidnapped by a pedophile and is kept prisoner in sub-floor space. Isn't that funny? I didn't think so. I can enjoy very dark humor. I can laugh about things that others find offensive, so it takes something really cruel and raw to turn my stomach. This was not done in a satirical way. It looked dead serious, but they added little tidbits here and there to let you know it was supposed to be a comedy. I wasn't sure in the movie theater whether I was more disturbed by the movie, or by the fact that other viewers were laughing! If you aren't disturbed by pedophilia, excrement-related bullying and other such themes, and in fact, you find all of those topics very funny, this may be just the movie for you. The actors were very talented and certainly convincing in their roles. The director made it all seem very real. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kind of misanthropic but fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Adam Thirwell
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing about watching a film like this at a time when the American high school genre has moved on to the much rosier visions of Napoleon Dynamite and Glee is that it strikes you how almost every character is a flawed, unlikeable person. Sure, you feel sorry and empathise with Dawn, the main character, but she's equally willing to bully, and doesn't have saving graces like the standard US school film geek - she's no brainbox. The guys in the film are portrayed as far less vindictive than the girls - bad boy Brandon has a sort of rogue honour, and the main fault of the other males in Dawn's life is that they are obsessed with doing their own thing or else following expectations laid down for them. It's a very watchable film - more so than Todd Solondz's later works. It looks like the work of an embittered outsider, but at least an outsider who, like the main character, tries to do their own thing against the odds.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbie and the Beast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like Woody Allen, Todd Solondz spends his time poking fun at man's foibles, whilst perhaps simultaneously wishing he weren't part of the very social fabric he condemns. It's your classic ego trap: "I'm better and above you, but worthless and wish I were with you." Solondz made "Fear, Anxiety and Depression" in 1989. He wrote and directed that film and, like Woody Allen, also cast himself as the film's neurotic hero. Like Allen's alter ego in "Annie Hall", the geeky looking Solondz spent the entire film bumbling about, venting his various dissaffections. Solondz was never happy with "Fear", however, and promptly disowned the film when his producers re-edited it behind his back. Burnt by the film industry, Solondz slipped into depression. He withdrew into isolation and became a teacher and writer. During these years his approach to art changed drastically. His screenplays became more formal, more precise, more caustic, and his visual style became cold. Ice cold. Solondz's first film when he emerged from his depression was "Welcome to the Dollhouse". Drawing upon his own unhappy school years, "Dollhouse" is about Dawn Weiner, a girl whom the universe seems to have condemned. More sinister than similar teen movies, "Dollhouse's" Dawn is so insecure she's happy to let a kid at school rape her if it means validating her own self worth. This would be rapist is himself marginalized, insecure and so reliant on sexual threats for self validation. Dawn is so filled with rage she even saws off the heads of her sister's dolls, fantasises about bashing people with a hammer and deliberately causes her sibling to be kidnapped by a local paedophile. Meanwhile, all the abuses people hurl at the geeky Dawn, Dawn hurls down at her little sister, a girl whom she unfairly despises. The result is that Dawn is shown to be capable of the same kind of brutality that she's subjected to. Social bullying is internalised, becomes self-hatred, and is then redirected violently back out at others. "Dollhouse" was a cosy film compared to Solondz's next three flicks. In "Happiness" he portrays a web of characters, all of whom harbour different problems and neuroses, and all of whom are linked by their desire for absolute contentment. And so we have a paedophile who is only happy around kids, a successful writer who is only happy if she writes something of substance, a musician (who ironically writes songs of substance) who can't find success and is so discontent, an elderly couple who no longer have the will to live, a fat man who fantasises about raping women, a fat woman who is disgusted by sex and a dopey housewife who is blissfully unaware of the disturbing truths that exist beneath her sweet suburban facade. Forget "American Beauty" and "Blue Velvet". Solondz ends his film with a Norman Rockwell kid ejaculating on his front balcony. Solondz's point is almost classically psychoanalytic: Lack breeds Desire breeds Suffering. Peel away the emotional baggage and happiness is a stain that oft amounts to nothing more than a fleeting moment of biological bliss. "Happiness" doesn't broadening its horizons to tackle the wider social and structural issues that better directors align to their existential musings, but it does offer more than Sam Mendes' "American Beauty". Indeed, Solondz's next film, "Storytelling", seemed designed to address those critics who pointed out the similarities between "Happiness" and "American Beauty". Mendes has himself slammed Solondz on numerous occasions, and so perhaps "Storytelling" is best viewed as a sort of intellectual assault on Solondz's critics. "Storytelling" is divided into two segments, the first called "fiction" the second called "non-fiction". "Fiction" is about a creative writing student who has "sympathy sex" with a mentally disabled kid and later lets her African American teacher "rape" her. She then turns her experiences into a work of fiction which purports to be "truthfully" based on these factual encounters. "Storytelling's" second segment then focuses on a documentary director who makes a documentary called "American Scooby" (a parody of "American Beauty") in which he follows a high school student around campus. The documentary director hopes to uncover the "truth" of growing up in suburbia, but in reality is merely transposing his own "deep thoughts", self-analysis and existential hang-ups onto a modern teen who is actually a dopey airhead. The end result is that film-maker and child enter a sort of exploitative relationship. The kid gets fame and is portrayed as being "deeper" than he is, while the film-maker gets prestige for nothing. End result: Solondz essentially advocates the sort of "truthful" sensationalism present in the non-fiction segment of the film, whilst aligning human delusions (love, romantic illusions, family etc) with the fictions of the second half. Other themes abound - the power games and domination/exploitatin reversals of "Dollhouse" are reworked here with subplots about a vengeful maid and a black teacher - but it's the "American Beauty" angle that's most interesting. "Palindromes" is thus far the weakest of Solondz's films. The first and last words in the movie are "Mom", a pair of palindromes through which Solondz implies that "nothing ever changes". Indeed, Solondz makes the film a palindrome at every level, his Schopenhaueran point being that we are paradoxically always changing and never changing (hence different actors play the same character), every desire and addiction merely supplanting another. It's an extremely bleak film, depending how much trust the audience puts in its final monologue. This bleakness has led to critics labelling Solondz a misanthrope, but he's no more colder than both Allen and the Coens, two other contemporary critical darlings who've spent their careers reworking similar material. 7.9/10  "Welcome to the Dollhouse", "Palindromes" 8/10  "Storytelling", "Happiness"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sketch of adolescent alienation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse is about a girl named Dawn who fails to find a place anywhere in society. She seems to be the victim of middle child syndrome as her parents are too worried about their other two children to bother much with her. Dawn's brother is already established as the brainy oldest child and her sister is the cute one, leaving her without an easy way to establish her own identity. At school she is is unable to fit in at least partially because her parents don't care enough about her to help her dress normally for her age. Because she isn't nurtured at home, she also fails to develop socially and her personality is too thin to make her sympathetic to the other students. Predictably, she is treated as poorly at school as she is at home. Welcome to the Dollhouse is full of these devastating scenes in which Dawn get her hopes up only to have them knocked down again. Her parents and classmates are oblivious to her suffering; no matter how bad things are for her nobody ever seems to think about her feelings. Things also tend to go against her as a matter of course. She is frequently unlucky as when she attempts to get revenge on her tormentors and accidentally targets an unsuspecting adult. Welcome to the Dollhouse does a fairly good job of capturing an unfortunate girl at a particularly awkward time of life. It suffers from a lack of realism at times, however, since it's unlikely that every teacher and student would hate a person that is more bland than offensive. Even more detrimental than the film's lack of realism in establishing Dawn's situation is the film's lack of style. The visuals are unremarkable and the only memorable aesthetic choice is the tacky design in Dawn's home. The plot takes a detour into absurdity when Dawn's sister is kidnapped but surprisingly this isn't really played for laughs in spite of some humorous elements. I was surprised to learn that this wasn't director Todd Solondz's first feature as it felt like the work of a film-maker looking to gain enough confidence to do the things he really wanted to. Welcome to the Dollhouse does an adequate job of establishing a single character but it feels like it's missing some crucial elements that could have made it truly memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Todd Solondz initiates a world of downers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never heard of Todd Solondz, then I should explain that "Welcome to the Dollhouse" is probably the most watchable. His movies - at least the few that I've seen - are always complete downers, containing characters who are either sickos, helpless, or something similar. His first notable movie concerns Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo), a New Jersey middle school girl ostracized by everyone around her. The only boy who gives her any good advice is totally pitiful himself. Dawn's entire life is one big FML. I recommend "WTTD", but with the caution that it IS a total downer. Hell, you might not even end up liking it. But it is worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the horrors of middle school
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film well encapsulates the horrors of middle school, perhaps more than was your experience, but the point is well taken. This unfortunately-named girl (Dawn Wiener), whose plight is not helped by her gawky looks, nerdiness, and refusal to take her punishment lying down, brings the pain of middle school into sharp relief. Having read a lot of the comments on IMDb, it's clear that this movie resonates with many. Landmark director Todd Solondz doesn't shrink from depicting the most cringe-inducing, skin-peeling, soul-destroying tortures inflicted by kids on their peers during those difficult tweener/teen years. Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo) lives with a mother who has no idea of the pain in which her daughter is in and with a father with no guts to intervene to his wife on his daughter's behalf. Her older brother is an academic success, although also very nerdy and her younger sister is the belle of the ball who can do no wrong in her mother's eyes. Solondz has constructed a very plausible hell in which his young protagonist suffers. She has no friends save for one boy who is the only other member of her "Special People Club". Her locker is the site of some particularly vitriolic abuse (although, having worked at schools, I found it implausible to believe that no teacher would have intervened to have the abuse removed), she is called "lesbo" and one girl who is particularly nasty will not let her leave the restroom without taking a crap. I liked the fact that this protagonist does not take the abuse lying down. Solondz creates such a good movie that he does not make Wiener into a wallflower. Indeed, she reacts in sometimes callous ways, taking out the anger she feels on someone less powerful than her. It's not necessarily pretty, but it's human nature. She reacts in anger to several things and I found this refreshing. She is not depicted as an ineffectual person. She fights back against her treatment-which people do, in real life-and Solondz deserves credit for this characterization of his protagonist. This really is a tough film to watch but I think this is one many young teens and tweeners would do well to watch and discuss with their parents because it could be a jumping-off point for a discussion about bullying and cruelty at this very difficult age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At three o'clock today, I'm going to rape you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dawn is bullied in her middle school. She is insecure, wears unflattering clothes and doesn't feel attractive. Her inattentive parents care far more about her smart and nerdy older brother and her spoilt, elegant little sister(that she actually has to share a room with, in spite of being 11) than her, leaving her the overlooked middle child. She falls in love with a guy five years her senior. But could that possibly work out? This is one of the most brutally honest(it admits that teenagers actually think about sex), painful(the cake scene is torture), and difficult to watch films I've ever seen. I knew that it would be, because this is not my first exposure to the immensely talented Solondz... I own a copy of the quite good Storytelling, and I had heard that this was much harder on the viewer. This really doesn't let up(there are those that will use the word "nihilistic"), it's pure bared nerve endings, and it shows with no pretense the kind of cruelty some of us experience, and what effect it has on us. Everyone lashes out at someone weaker than them when they're in agony. While some of the actions do encourage headscratching, the characters in this are entirely realistic(I would say almost everything in this is), credible and well-developed. No one is a hero or a villain(don't expect to like everything about any of them). The acting is amazing. Matarazzo(who I can barely believe was willing to play the role) is impossibly perfect. Her body language, voice, eyes, everything is spot-on. Everyone is convincing in this. The tension is present and thick right from the beginning. I suppose one could argue that this doesn't have all that much genuine plot... we get a string of scenes in chronological order, and several things aren't followed up on. A ton does happen; I think this is mainly meant to show a small portion of the girl's life. Don't expect a lot of growth or change, or for this to have a conclusion(it kind of just stops... one can interpret the last image to mean something, though, and it certainly isn't randomly chosen). I'm not sure I understand classifying this as a comedy... if so, definitely note that it's black and sardonic humor. You can really *feel* the setting. The lunch-room, class-room and the suburban home... you're *there*, and you feel as suffocated and trapped as our lead does. This is filmed and edited impeccably well. There is disturbing content and strong language throughout this. The DVD comes with a trailer. I recommend this to anyone who wants an uncompromising look at what for many are the worst years of their life. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On trying to find DVDs, v1.10
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    annevejb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A prime quality that the DVD had for me was a price much higher than I usually can pay. Used to be that when I browsed IMDb details I sometimes looked at the tag at the top that showed availability in the different Amazon countries, availability as disk or tape or whatever. Way back then I purchased from local low cost shops, but it was interesting to browse. Then I progressed to purchases from the local, UK, Amazon but only for what I could pay for by cheque. Then I got to be able to pay electronically and it was suddenly possible to purchase low cost disks from second hand sources in the UK, Germany, USA and Canada, etc, via Amazon UK. The disk availability box at the top of an IMDb page was starting to have potential for real value, though I tended to search just in Amazon UK. Some of the really interesting disks were not available, some needed access to paying to a different country's Amazon, especially for low cost disks, but this was a massive start for being able to search for disks by title rather than from the more restricted range of what was available locally. Locally is still really useful, but it is more a serendipity sort of thing. Then the IMDb system changed. The disk availability button was not there. Then it was there but not showing the range of countries or versions of disks, if UK Amazon had the title in a variety of versions then either only one would be shown or an Amazon USA version would be shown. So, there was a basic indicator of availability, which is useful knowledge, just the way of searching the different stores was gone and at August 2009 this was still gone. So things were okay and unless an Amazon other than UK became the sole outlet for such as The Adventures Of Pete And Pete Season 3, some have a hunger for that Trachtenberg series, then things were tolerable. What happened instead was that Amazon USA became the sole outlet for Unfabulous Seasons 1 and 2. Also Zoey 101 seasons 3 and 4. While the prices are nothing like my ideal it was suddenly essential for me to get a payment method that Amazon USA accepts and in August 2009 I managed. Dollhouse. When I got to make my first order there was a copy of this at USA at a much lower price than I had ever noticed at Amazon UK or any other outlet. Except that order failed, it was not available for a delivery address in the UK. Two other items went through, though. It looks as if some traders are able to export, but not others. Later experiences told me that I still have a problem re availability of difficult to find titles. The outlook can seem bleak. The stuff that I had been noticing will mostly have not been available for export. * Dollhouse is from the year when season 3 of Pete, Pete appears and is a couple of years after Heather Matarazzo appeared in an episode of each of seasons 0 and 1. It is weaker than Pete, but in some ways it is as strong. I find that it echoes My Girl and Tideland, but from a different culture and in a more down to earth way. All have the main actor as of an appropriate age, scary but sense when musing on these sort of aspects. Dollhouse is bound to feel offensive to some who can accept My Girl. To me it has a reality that I can relate to more than with My Girl, though both stories are alien at the same time. Napoleon Dynamite, about a different age range and a different subset of symptoms, I now have to wonder how those characters would appear if that story was set at age eleven. Mysterious Skin and The Quiet expand on the range of faces of this. I found Dollhouse difficult to get into, but I vastly prefer this to Princess Diaries as that falls flat for me as soon as Mia gets the makeover, the point where one is supposed to gain empathy with Mia? Much is said of Dollhouse being a story about the difficulties that an ugly girl can face at age 12, but watch this with any care at all and it is obvious that this is a rather nice looking girl who is badly damaged by the ugly ways of those around her. One needs the right sort of helps to be able to get around that sort of thing and this story makes a loud comment about how real those helps can be. I have to like this feature a lot. The message board hints of some considering the three bad boys to be pure criminal types, but the strongest hint put in a criminal way. For me, Dollhouse gives a context that puts such into perspective. What this shows of their back to front reality, criminal seems an inappropriate label. That is the real strength of this feature. This is not about the apex of the pyramid of society, it shows a dunghill. Dawn comes out with some really putrid behaviour and there are some reviews here that consider that to be a reflection of her personality. To me, she is just showing some effects that can happen when one is blowing in the wind, chaff that does not have enough free will to escape being blown in that way. Rather than Dawn being horror I consider that she is blown into a horrifying and damaging situation, but one has had to have been in that sort of situation oneself to accept that is an aspect of her being a victim of horror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmGuy34567
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse-***1/2 (out of 4): Junior high can be tough and it is especially tough for little Dawn, who suffers from her abusive classmates, less than satisfactory home life, and her own discomfort with the problems of adolescence. Perhaps one of the most raw and unsentimental coming of age pictures ever made, though the tone is purely original. We are in many ways touched and even heartbroken by the central character and her troubles, but often catch ourselves laughing at the sheer misery and misfortune encountered by her. Half black comic and half drama, but completely insightful: this film is definitely one for the books. It also is the first display of the humorous misery of writer-director's Todd Solondz's imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to watch... But brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rich Wright
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'd think, with all the humiliations that pile up on our mousy heroine over the course of this unbearably cruel film, the scene is set for a big revenge moment... A huge climax where she finally sticks it to all her enemies and proves her worth. You would be completely wrong. This is no 'triumph of the underdog' tale, just a survival story about the spirit of a kid who must endure almost consistent harassment everyday, whether she's at school or home... And we wonder, how does she avoid cracking up? Her family don't want anything to do with her, preferring to lavish their affections on her 'perfect' younger sister, while in class she's the target of bullies, and the teachers seem to consist of a bunch of patronising jerks. Even the few chinks of light that occasionally shine through the gloom of her existence are quickly snuffed out, so if you're looking for a movie to put you in a good mood you're better off watching Bambi's mother get shot on an endless loop. BUT... (and this is a massive BUT) it also happens to be one of the finest films I've seen in years. I had it on DVD but guess what... a massive scratch on the disc stopped it after half an hour. Even with that small taste, I knew it was something special. So I waited... And FINALLY the whole thing has been uploaded to Youtube... And may I just say, it fulfilled my initial reaction to it, and then some. A huge part of it's success lies squarely at the feet of Heather Matarazzo, who cuts a sympathetic (or perhaps just pathetic) figure as she shuffles through life, being abused and hated by all. It's a role which could easily have descended into caricature, but her breathtaking performance as a bright girl doomed by circumstance to eke out this rubbish existence makes her plight evermore tragic. The supporting parts hit the bullseye too, as everyone from her nerdy best (and only) friend to her tutu-wearing, sickly-sweet younger sibling infuse proceedings with a quality which is rarely seen. This is a great film... Not a happy one, but I guarantee a far more relatable flick than half the homogenised coming-of-age motion pictures out there. You know, the ones where everyone is beautiful, most of your fellow students are wealthy minorities and you burst into the chorus of a cheesy song every few minutes. Hmm, what could I possibly be talking about... 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennsouthwest
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ha ha ha. Her friends make her poop on the floor of the school bathroom. Her little sister gets kidnapped by a pedophile and is kept prisoner in sub-floor space. Isn't that funny? I didn't think so. I can enjoy very dark humor. I can laugh about things that others find offensive, so it takes something really cruel and raw to turn my stomach. This was not done in a satirical way. It looked dead serious, but they added little tidbits here and there to let you know it was supposed to be a comedy. I wasn't sure in the movie theater whether I was more disturbed by the movie, or by the fact that other viewers were laughing! If you aren't disturbed by pedophilia, excrement-related bullying and other such themes, and in fact, you find all of those topics very funny, this may be just the movie for you. The actors were very talented and certainly convincing in their roles. The director made it all seem very real. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kind of misanthropic but fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Adam Thirwell
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing about watching a film like this at a time when the American high school genre has moved on to the much rosier visions of Napoleon Dynamite and Glee is that it strikes you how almost every character is a flawed, unlikeable person. Sure, you feel sorry and empathise with Dawn, the main character, but she's equally willing to bully, and doesn't have saving graces like the standard US school film geek - she's no brainbox. The guys in the film are portrayed as far less vindictive than the girls - bad boy Brandon has a sort of rogue honour, and the main fault of the other males in Dawn's life is that they are obsessed with doing their own thing or else following expectations laid down for them. It's a very watchable film - more so than Todd Solondz's later works. It looks like the work of an embittered outsider, but at least an outsider who, like the main character, tries to do their own thing against the odds.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbie and the Beast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like Woody Allen, Todd Solondz spends his time poking fun at man's foibles, whilst perhaps simultaneously wishing he weren't part of the very social fabric he condemns. It's your classic ego trap: "I'm better and above you, but worthless and wish I were with you." Solondz made "Fear, Anxiety and Depression" in 1989. He wrote and directed that film and, like Woody Allen, also cast himself as the film's neurotic hero. Like Allen's alter ego in "Annie Hall", the geeky looking Solondz spent the entire film bumbling about, venting his various dissaffections. Solondz was never happy with "Fear", however, and promptly disowned the film when his producers re-edited it behind his back. Burnt by the film industry, Solondz slipped into depression. He withdrew into isolation and became a teacher and writer. During these years his approach to art changed drastically. His screenplays became more formal, more precise, more caustic, and his visual style became cold. Ice cold. Solondz's first film when he emerged from his depression was "Welcome to the Dollhouse". Drawing upon his own unhappy school years, "Dollhouse" is about Dawn Weiner, a girl whom the universe seems to have condemned. More sinister than similar teen movies, "Dollhouse's" Dawn is so insecure she's happy to let a kid at school rape her if it means validating her own self worth. This would be rapist is himself marginalized, insecure and so reliant on sexual threats for self validation. Dawn is so filled with rage she even saws off the heads of her sister's dolls, fantasises about bashing people with a hammer and deliberately causes her sibling to be kidnapped by a local paedophile. Meanwhile, all the abuses people hurl at the geeky Dawn, Dawn hurls down at her little sister, a girl whom she unfairly despises. The result is that Dawn is shown to be capable of the same kind of brutality that she's subjected to. Social bullying is internalised, becomes self-hatred, and is then redirected violently back out at others. "Dollhouse" was a cosy film compared to Solondz's next three flicks. In "Happiness" he portrays a web of characters, all of whom harbour different problems and neuroses, and all of whom are linked by their desire for absolute contentment. And so we have a paedophile who is only happy around kids, a successful writer who is only happy if she writes something of substance, a musician (who ironically writes songs of substance) who can't find success and is so discontent, an elderly couple who no longer have the will to live, a fat man who fantasises about raping women, a fat woman who is disgusted by sex and a dopey housewife who is blissfully unaware of the disturbing truths that exist beneath her sweet suburban facade. Forget "American Beauty" and "Blue Velvet". Solondz ends his film with a Norman Rockwell kid ejaculating on his front balcony. Solondz's point is almost classically psychoanalytic: Lack breeds Desire breeds Suffering. Peel away the emotional baggage and happiness is a stain that oft amounts to nothing more than a fleeting moment of biological bliss. "Happiness" doesn't broadening its horizons to tackle the wider social and structural issues that better directors align to their existential musings, but it does offer more than Sam Mendes' "American Beauty". Indeed, Solondz's next film, "Storytelling", seemed designed to address those critics who pointed out the similarities between "Happiness" and "American Beauty". Mendes has himself slammed Solondz on numerous occasions, and so perhaps "Storytelling" is best viewed as a sort of intellectual assault on Solondz's critics. "Storytelling" is divided into two segments, the first called "fiction" the second called "non-fiction". "Fiction" is about a creative writing student who has "sympathy sex" with a mentally disabled kid and later lets her African American teacher "rape" her. She then turns her experiences into a work of fiction which purports to be "truthfully" based on these factual encounters. "Storytelling's" second segment then focuses on a documentary director who makes a documentary called "American Scooby" (a parody of "American Beauty") in which he follows a high school student around campus. The documentary director hopes to uncover the "truth" of growing up in suburbia, but in reality is merely transposing his own "deep thoughts", self-analysis and existential hang-ups onto a modern teen who is actually a dopey airhead. The end result is that film-maker and child enter a sort of exploitative relationship. The kid gets fame and is portrayed as being "deeper" than he is, while the film-maker gets prestige for nothing. End result: Solondz essentially advocates the sort of "truthful" sensationalism present in the non-fiction segment of the film, whilst aligning human delusions (love, romantic illusions, family etc) with the fictions of the second half. Other themes abound - the power games and domination/exploitatin reversals of "Dollhouse" are reworked here with subplots about a vengeful maid and a black teacher - but it's the "American Beauty" angle that's most interesting. "Palindromes" is thus far the weakest of Solondz's films. The first and last words in the movie are "Mom", a pair of palindromes through which Solondz implies that "nothing ever changes". Indeed, Solondz makes the film a palindrome at every level, his Schopenhaueran point being that we are paradoxically always changing and never changing (hence different actors play the same character), every desire and addiction merely supplanting another. It's an extremely bleak film, depending how much trust the audience puts in its final monologue. This bleakness has led to critics labelling Solondz a misanthrope, but he's no more colder than both Allen and the Coens, two other contemporary critical darlings who've spent their careers reworking similar material. 7.9/10  "Welcome to the Dollhouse", "Palindromes" 8/10  "Storytelling", "Happiness"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sketch of adolescent alienation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse is about a girl named Dawn who fails to find a place anywhere in society. She seems to be the victim of middle child syndrome as her parents are too worried about their other two children to bother much with her. Dawn's brother is already established as the brainy oldest child and her sister is the cute one, leaving her without an easy way to establish her own identity. At school she is is unable to fit in at least partially because her parents don't care enough about her to help her dress normally for her age. Because she isn't nurtured at home, she also fails to develop socially and her personality is too thin to make her sympathetic to the other students. Predictably, she is treated as poorly at school as she is at home. Welcome to the Dollhouse is full of these devastating scenes in which Dawn get her hopes up only to have them knocked down again. Her parents and classmates are oblivious to her suffering; no matter how bad things are for her nobody ever seems to think about her feelings. Things also tend to go against her as a matter of course. She is frequently unlucky as when she attempts to get revenge on her tormentors and accidentally targets an unsuspecting adult. Welcome to the Dollhouse does a fairly good job of capturing an unfortunate girl at a particularly awkward time of life. It suffers from a lack of realism at times, however, since it's unlikely that every teacher and student would hate a person that is more bland than offensive. Even more detrimental than the film's lack of realism in establishing Dawn's situation is the film's lack of style. The visuals are unremarkable and the only memorable aesthetic choice is the tacky design in Dawn's home. The plot takes a detour into absurdity when Dawn's sister is kidnapped but surprisingly this isn't really played for laughs in spite of some humorous elements. I was surprised to learn that this wasn't director Todd Solondz's first feature as it felt like the work of a film-maker looking to gain enough confidence to do the things he really wanted to. Welcome to the Dollhouse does an adequate job of establishing a single character but it feels like it's missing some crucial elements that could have made it truly memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Todd Solondz initiates a world of downers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never heard of Todd Solondz, then I should explain that "Welcome to the Dollhouse" is probably the most watchable. His movies - at least the few that I've seen - are always complete downers, containing characters who are either sickos, helpless, or something similar. His first notable movie concerns Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo), a New Jersey middle school girl ostracized by everyone around her. The only boy who gives her any good advice is totally pitiful himself. Dawn's entire life is one big FML. I recommend "WTTD", but with the caution that it IS a total downer. Hell, you might not even end up liking it. But it is worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the horrors of middle school
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film well encapsulates the horrors of middle school, perhaps more than was your experience, but the point is well taken. This unfortunately-named girl (Dawn Wiener), whose plight is not helped by her gawky looks, nerdiness, and refusal to take her punishment lying down, brings the pain of middle school into sharp relief. Having read a lot of the comments on IMDb, it's clear that this movie resonates with many. Landmark director Todd Solondz doesn't shrink from depicting the most cringe-inducing, skin-peeling, soul-destroying tortures inflicted by kids on their peers during those difficult tweener/teen years. Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo) lives with a mother who has no idea of the pain in which her daughter is in and with a father with no guts to intervene to his wife on his daughter's behalf. Her older brother is an academic success, although also very nerdy and her younger sister is the belle of the ball who can do no wrong in her mother's eyes. Solondz has constructed a very plausible hell in which his young protagonist suffers. She has no friends save for one boy who is the only other member of her "Special People Club". Her locker is the site of some particularly vitriolic abuse (although, having worked at schools, I found it implausible to believe that no teacher would have intervened to have the abuse removed), she is called "lesbo" and one girl who is particularly nasty will not let her leave the restroom without taking a crap. I liked the fact that this protagonist does not take the abuse lying down. Solondz creates such a good movie that he does not make Wiener into a wallflower. Indeed, she reacts in sometimes callous ways, taking out the anger she feels on someone less powerful than her. It's not necessarily pretty, but it's human nature. She reacts in anger to several things and I found this refreshing. She is not depicted as an ineffectual person. She fights back against her treatment-which people do, in real life-and Solondz deserves credit for this characterization of his protagonist. This really is a tough film to watch but I think this is one many young teens and tweeners would do well to watch and discuss with their parents because it could be a jumping-off point for a discussion about bullying and cruelty at this very difficult age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At three o'clock today, I'm going to rape you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dawn is bullied in her middle school. She is insecure, wears unflattering clothes and doesn't feel attractive. Her inattentive parents care far more about her smart and nerdy older brother and her spoilt, elegant little sister(that she actually has to share a room with, in spite of being 11) than her, leaving her the overlooked middle child. She falls in love with a guy five years her senior. But could that possibly work out? This is one of the most brutally honest(it admits that teenagers actually think about sex), painful(the cake scene is torture), and difficult to watch films I've ever seen. I knew that it would be, because this is not my first exposure to the immensely talented Solondz... I own a copy of the quite good Storytelling, and I had heard that this was much harder on the viewer. This really doesn't let up(there are those that will use the word "nihilistic"), it's pure bared nerve endings, and it shows with no pretense the kind of cruelty some of us experience, and what effect it has on us. Everyone lashes out at someone weaker than them when they're in agony. While some of the actions do encourage headscratching, the characters in this are entirely realistic(I would say almost everything in this is), credible and well-developed. No one is a hero or a villain(don't expect to like everything about any of them). The acting is amazing. Matarazzo(who I can barely believe was willing to play the role) is impossibly perfect. Her body language, voice, eyes, everything is spot-on. Everyone is convincing in this. The tension is present and thick right from the beginning. I suppose one could argue that this doesn't have all that much genuine plot... we get a string of scenes in chronological order, and several things aren't followed up on. A ton does happen; I think this is mainly meant to show a small portion of the girl's life. Don't expect a lot of growth or change, or for this to have a conclusion(it kind of just stops... one can interpret the last image to mean something, though, and it certainly isn't randomly chosen). I'm not sure I understand classifying this as a comedy... if so, definitely note that it's black and sardonic humor. You can really *feel* the setting. The lunch-room, class-room and the suburban home... you're *there*, and you feel as suffocated and trapped as our lead does. This is filmed and edited impeccably well. There is disturbing content and strong language throughout this. The DVD comes with a trailer. I recommend this to anyone who wants an uncompromising look at what for many are the worst years of their life. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On trying to find DVDs, v1.10
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    annevejb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A prime quality that the DVD had for me was a price much higher than I usually can pay. Used to be that when I browsed IMDb details I sometimes looked at the tag at the top that showed availability in the different Amazon countries, availability as disk or tape or whatever. Way back then I purchased from local low cost shops, but it was interesting to browse. Then I progressed to purchases from the local, UK, Amazon but only for what I could pay for by cheque. Then I got to be able to pay electronically and it was suddenly possible to purchase low cost disks from second hand sources in the UK, Germany, USA and Canada, etc, via Amazon UK. The disk availability box at the top of an IMDb page was starting to have potential for real value, though I tended to search just in Amazon UK. Some of the really interesting disks were not available, some needed access to paying to a different country's Amazon, especially for low cost disks, but this was a massive start for being able to search for disks by title rather than from the more restricted range of what was available locally. Locally is still really useful, but it is more a serendipity sort of thing. Then the IMDb system changed. The disk availability button was not there. Then it was there but not showing the range of countries or versions of disks, if UK Amazon had the title in a variety of versions then either only one would be shown or an Amazon USA version would be shown. So, there was a basic indicator of availability, which is useful knowledge, just the way of searching the different stores was gone and at August 2009 this was still gone. So things were okay and unless an Amazon other than UK became the sole outlet for such as The Adventures Of Pete And Pete Season 3, some have a hunger for that Trachtenberg series, then things were tolerable. What happened instead was that Amazon USA became the sole outlet for Unfabulous Seasons 1 and 2. Also Zoey 101 seasons 3 and 4. While the prices are nothing like my ideal it was suddenly essential for me to get a payment method that Amazon USA accepts and in August 2009 I managed. Dollhouse. When I got to make my first order there was a copy of this at USA at a much lower price than I had ever noticed at Amazon UK or any other outlet. Except that order failed, it was not available for a delivery address in the UK. Two other items went through, though. It looks as if some traders are able to export, but not others. Later experiences told me that I still have a problem re availability of difficult to find titles. The outlook can seem bleak. The stuff that I had been noticing will mostly have not been available for export. * Dollhouse is from the year when season 3 of Pete, Pete appears and is a couple of years after Heather Matarazzo appeared in an episode of each of seasons 0 and 1. It is weaker than Pete, but in some ways it is as strong. I find that it echoes My Girl and Tideland, but from a different culture and in a more down to earth way. All have the main actor as of an appropriate age, scary but sense when musing on these sort of aspects. Dollhouse is bound to feel offensive to some who can accept My Girl. To me it has a reality that I can relate to more than with My Girl, though both stories are alien at the same time. Napoleon Dynamite, about a different age range and a different subset of symptoms, I now have to wonder how those characters would appear if that story was set at age eleven. Mysterious Skin and The Quiet expand on the range of faces of this. I found Dollhouse difficult to get into, but I vastly prefer this to Princess Diaries as that falls flat for me as soon as Mia gets the makeover, the point where one is supposed to gain empathy with Mia? Much is said of Dollhouse being a story about the difficulties that an ugly girl can face at age 12, but watch this with any care at all and it is obvious that this is a rather nice looking girl who is badly damaged by the ugly ways of those around her. One needs the right sort of helps to be able to get around that sort of thing and this story makes a loud comment about how real those helps can be. I have to like this feature a lot. The message board hints of some considering the three bad boys to be pure criminal types, but the strongest hint put in a criminal way. For me, Dollhouse gives a context that puts such into perspective. What this shows of their back to front reality, criminal seems an inappropriate label. That is the real strength of this feature. This is not about the apex of the pyramid of society, it shows a dunghill. Dawn comes out with some really putrid behaviour and there are some reviews here that consider that to be a reflection of her personality. To me, she is just showing some effects that can happen when one is blowing in the wind, chaff that does not have enough free will to escape being blown in that way. Rather than Dawn being horror I consider that she is blown into a horrifying and damaging situation, but one has had to have been in that sort of situation oneself to accept that is an aspect of her being a victim of horror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmGuy34567
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse-***1/2 (out of 4): Junior high can be tough and it is especially tough for little Dawn, who suffers from her abusive classmates, less than satisfactory home life, and her own discomfort with the problems of adolescence. Perhaps one of the most raw and unsentimental coming of age pictures ever made, though the tone is purely original. We are in many ways touched and even heartbroken by the central character and her troubles, but often catch ourselves laughing at the sheer misery and misfortune encountered by her. Half black comic and half drama, but completely insightful: this film is definitely one for the books. It also is the first display of the humorous misery of writer-director's Todd Solondz's imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to watch... But brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rich Wright
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'd think, with all the humiliations that pile up on our mousy heroine over the course of this unbearably cruel film, the scene is set for a big revenge moment... A huge climax where she finally sticks it to all her enemies and proves her worth. You would be completely wrong. This is no 'triumph of the underdog' tale, just a survival story about the spirit of a kid who must endure almost consistent harassment everyday, whether she's at school or home... And we wonder, how does she avoid cracking up? Her family don't want anything to do with her, preferring to lavish their affections on her 'perfect' younger sister, while in class she's the target of bullies, and the teachers seem to consist of a bunch of patronising jerks. Even the few chinks of light that occasionally shine through the gloom of her existence are quickly snuffed out, so if you're looking for a movie to put you in a good mood you're better off watching Bambi's mother get shot on an endless loop. BUT... (and this is a massive BUT) it also happens to be one of the finest films I've seen in years. I had it on DVD but guess what... a massive scratch on the disc stopped it after half an hour. Even with that small taste, I knew it was something special. So I waited... And FINALLY the whole thing has been uploaded to Youtube... And may I just say, it fulfilled my initial reaction to it, and then some. A huge part of it's success lies squarely at the feet of Heather Matarazzo, who cuts a sympathetic (or perhaps just pathetic) figure as she shuffles through life, being abused and hated by all. It's a role which could easily have descended into caricature, but her breathtaking performance as a bright girl doomed by circumstance to eke out this rubbish existence makes her plight evermore tragic. The supporting parts hit the bullseye too, as everyone from her nerdy best (and only) friend to her tutu-wearing, sickly-sweet younger sibling infuse proceedings with a quality which is rarely seen. This is a great film... Not a happy one, but I guarantee a far more relatable flick than half the homogenised coming-of-age motion pictures out there. You know, the ones where everyone is beautiful, most of your fellow students are wealthy minorities and you burst into the chorus of a cheesy song every few minutes. Hmm, what could I possibly be talking about... 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennsouthwest
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ha ha ha. Her friends make her poop on the floor of the school bathroom. Her little sister gets kidnapped by a pedophile and is kept prisoner in sub-floor space. Isn't that funny? I didn't think so. I can enjoy very dark humor. I can laugh about things that others find offensive, so it takes something really cruel and raw to turn my stomach. This was not done in a satirical way. It looked dead serious, but they added little tidbits here and there to let you know it was supposed to be a comedy. I wasn't sure in the movie theater whether I was more disturbed by the movie, or by the fact that other viewers were laughing! If you aren't disturbed by pedophilia, excrement-related bullying and other such themes, and in fact, you find all of those topics very funny, this may be just the movie for you. The actors were very talented and certainly convincing in their roles. The director made it all seem very real. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kind of misanthropic but fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Adam Thirwell
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing about watching a film like this at a time when the American high school genre has moved on to the much rosier visions of Napoleon Dynamite and Glee is that it strikes you how almost every character is a flawed, unlikeable person. Sure, you feel sorry and empathise with Dawn, the main character, but she's equally willing to bully, and doesn't have saving graces like the standard US school film geek - she's no brainbox. The guys in the film are portrayed as far less vindictive than the girls - bad boy Brandon has a sort of rogue honour, and the main fault of the other males in Dawn's life is that they are obsessed with doing their own thing or else following expectations laid down for them. It's a very watchable film - more so than Todd Solondz's later works. It looks like the work of an embittered outsider, but at least an outsider who, like the main character, tries to do their own thing against the odds.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbie and the Beast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like Woody Allen, Todd Solondz spends his time poking fun at man's foibles, whilst perhaps simultaneously wishing he weren't part of the very social fabric he condemns. It's your classic ego trap: "I'm better and above you, but worthless and wish I were with you." Solondz made "Fear, Anxiety and Depression" in 1989. He wrote and directed that film and, like Woody Allen, also cast himself as the film's neurotic hero. Like Allen's alter ego in "Annie Hall", the geeky looking Solondz spent the entire film bumbling about, venting his various dissaffections. Solondz was never happy with "Fear", however, and promptly disowned the film when his producers re-edited it behind his back. Burnt by the film industry, Solondz slipped into depression. He withdrew into isolation and became a teacher and writer. During these years his approach to art changed drastically. His screenplays became more formal, more precise, more caustic, and his visual style became cold. Ice cold. Solondz's first film when he emerged from his depression was "Welcome to the Dollhouse". Drawing upon his own unhappy school years, "Dollhouse" is about Dawn Weiner, a girl whom the universe seems to have condemned. More sinister than similar teen movies, "Dollhouse's" Dawn is so insecure she's happy to let a kid at school rape her if it means validating her own self worth. This would be rapist is himself marginalized, insecure and so reliant on sexual threats for self validation. Dawn is so filled with rage she even saws off the heads of her sister's dolls, fantasises about bashing people with a hammer and deliberately causes her sibling to be kidnapped by a local paedophile. Meanwhile, all the abuses people hurl at the geeky Dawn, Dawn hurls down at her little sister, a girl whom she unfairly despises. The result is that Dawn is shown to be capable of the same kind of brutality that she's subjected to. Social bullying is internalised, becomes self-hatred, and is then redirected violently back out at others. "Dollhouse" was a cosy film compared to Solondz's next three flicks. In "Happiness" he portrays a web of characters, all of whom harbour different problems and neuroses, and all of whom are linked by their desire for absolute contentment. And so we have a paedophile who is only happy around kids, a successful writer who is only happy if she writes something of substance, a musician (who ironically writes songs of substance) who can't find success and is so discontent, an elderly couple who no longer have the will to live, a fat man who fantasises about raping women, a fat woman who is disgusted by sex and a dopey housewife who is blissfully unaware of the disturbing truths that exist beneath her sweet suburban facade. Forget "American Beauty" and "Blue Velvet". Solondz ends his film with a Norman Rockwell kid ejaculating on his front balcony. Solondz's point is almost classically psychoanalytic: Lack breeds Desire breeds Suffering. Peel away the emotional baggage and happiness is a stain that oft amounts to nothing more than a fleeting moment of biological bliss. "Happiness" doesn't broadening its horizons to tackle the wider social and structural issues that better directors align to their existential musings, but it does offer more than Sam Mendes' "American Beauty". Indeed, Solondz's next film, "Storytelling", seemed designed to address those critics who pointed out the similarities between "Happiness" and "American Beauty". Mendes has himself slammed Solondz on numerous occasions, and so perhaps "Storytelling" is best viewed as a sort of intellectual assault on Solondz's critics. "Storytelling" is divided into two segments, the first called "fiction" the second called "non-fiction". "Fiction" is about a creative writing student who has "sympathy sex" with a mentally disabled kid and later lets her African American teacher "rape" her. She then turns her experiences into a work of fiction which purports to be "truthfully" based on these factual encounters. "Storytelling's" second segment then focuses on a documentary director who makes a documentary called "American Scooby" (a parody of "American Beauty") in which he follows a high school student around campus. The documentary director hopes to uncover the "truth" of growing up in suburbia, but in reality is merely transposing his own "deep thoughts", self-analysis and existential hang-ups onto a modern teen who is actually a dopey airhead. The end result is that film-maker and child enter a sort of exploitative relationship. The kid gets fame and is portrayed as being "deeper" than he is, while the film-maker gets prestige for nothing. End result: Solondz essentially advocates the sort of "truthful" sensationalism present in the non-fiction segment of the film, whilst aligning human delusions (love, romantic illusions, family etc) with the fictions of the second half. Other themes abound - the power games and domination/exploitatin reversals of "Dollhouse" are reworked here with subplots about a vengeful maid and a black teacher - but it's the "American Beauty" angle that's most interesting. "Palindromes" is thus far the weakest of Solondz's films. The first and last words in the movie are "Mom", a pair of palindromes through which Solondz implies that "nothing ever changes". Indeed, Solondz makes the film a palindrome at every level, his Schopenhaueran point being that we are paradoxically always changing and never changing (hence different actors play the same character), every desire and addiction merely supplanting another. It's an extremely bleak film, depending how much trust the audience puts in its final monologue. This bleakness has led to critics labelling Solondz a misanthrope, but he's no more colder than both Allen and the Coens, two other contemporary critical darlings who've spent their careers reworking similar material. 7.9/10  "Welcome to the Dollhouse", "Palindromes" 8/10  "Storytelling", "Happiness"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sketch of adolescent alienation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse is about a girl named Dawn who fails to find a place anywhere in society. She seems to be the victim of middle child syndrome as her parents are too worried about their other two children to bother much with her. Dawn's brother is already established as the brainy oldest child and her sister is the cute one, leaving her without an easy way to establish her own identity. At school she is is unable to fit in at least partially because her parents don't care enough about her to help her dress normally for her age. Because she isn't nurtured at home, she also fails to develop socially and her personality is too thin to make her sympathetic to the other students. Predictably, she is treated as poorly at school as she is at home. Welcome to the Dollhouse is full of these devastating scenes in which Dawn get her hopes up only to have them knocked down again. Her parents and classmates are oblivious to her suffering; no matter how bad things are for her nobody ever seems to think about her feelings. Things also tend to go against her as a matter of course. She is frequently unlucky as when she attempts to get revenge on her tormentors and accidentally targets an unsuspecting adult. Welcome to the Dollhouse does a fairly good job of capturing an unfortunate girl at a particularly awkward time of life. It suffers from a lack of realism at times, however, since it's unlikely that every teacher and student would hate a person that is more bland than offensive. Even more detrimental than the film's lack of realism in establishing Dawn's situation is the film's lack of style. The visuals are unremarkable and the only memorable aesthetic choice is the tacky design in Dawn's home. The plot takes a detour into absurdity when Dawn's sister is kidnapped but surprisingly this isn't really played for laughs in spite of some humorous elements. I was surprised to learn that this wasn't director Todd Solondz's first feature as it felt like the work of a film-maker looking to gain enough confidence to do the things he really wanted to. Welcome to the Dollhouse does an adequate job of establishing a single character but it feels like it's missing some crucial elements that could have made it truly memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Todd Solondz initiates a world of downers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never heard of Todd Solondz, then I should explain that "Welcome to the Dollhouse" is probably the most watchable. His movies - at least the few that I've seen - are always complete downers, containing characters who are either sickos, helpless, or something similar. His first notable movie concerns Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo), a New Jersey middle school girl ostracized by everyone around her. The only boy who gives her any good advice is totally pitiful himself. Dawn's entire life is one big FML. I recommend "WTTD", but with the caution that it IS a total downer. Hell, you might not even end up liking it. But it is worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the horrors of middle school
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film well encapsulates the horrors of middle school, perhaps more than was your experience, but the point is well taken. This unfortunately-named girl (Dawn Wiener), whose plight is not helped by her gawky looks, nerdiness, and refusal to take her punishment lying down, brings the pain of middle school into sharp relief. Having read a lot of the comments on IMDb, it's clear that this movie resonates with many. Landmark director Todd Solondz doesn't shrink from depicting the most cringe-inducing, skin-peeling, soul-destroying tortures inflicted by kids on their peers during those difficult tweener/teen years. Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo) lives with a mother who has no idea of the pain in which her daughter is in and with a father with no guts to intervene to his wife on his daughter's behalf. Her older brother is an academic success, although also very nerdy and her younger sister is the belle of the ball who can do no wrong in her mother's eyes. Solondz has constructed a very plausible hell in which his young protagonist suffers. She has no friends save for one boy who is the only other member of her "Special People Club". Her locker is the site of some particularly vitriolic abuse (although, having worked at schools, I found it implausible to believe that no teacher would have intervened to have the abuse removed), she is called "lesbo" and one girl who is particularly nasty will not let her leave the restroom without taking a crap. I liked the fact that this protagonist does not take the abuse lying down. Solondz creates such a good movie that he does not make Wiener into a wallflower. Indeed, she reacts in sometimes callous ways, taking out the anger she feels on someone less powerful than her. It's not necessarily pretty, but it's human nature. She reacts in anger to several things and I found this refreshing. She is not depicted as an ineffectual person. She fights back against her treatment-which people do, in real life-and Solondz deserves credit for this characterization of his protagonist. This really is a tough film to watch but I think this is one many young teens and tweeners would do well to watch and discuss with their parents because it could be a jumping-off point for a discussion about bullying and cruelty at this very difficult age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At three o'clock today, I'm going to rape you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dawn is bullied in her middle school. She is insecure, wears unflattering clothes and doesn't feel attractive. Her inattentive parents care far more about her smart and nerdy older brother and her spoilt, elegant little sister(that she actually has to share a room with, in spite of being 11) than her, leaving her the overlooked middle child. She falls in love with a guy five years her senior. But could that possibly work out? This is one of the most brutally honest(it admits that teenagers actually think about sex), painful(the cake scene is torture), and difficult to watch films I've ever seen. I knew that it would be, because this is not my first exposure to the immensely talented Solondz... I own a copy of the quite good Storytelling, and I had heard that this was much harder on the viewer. This really doesn't let up(there are those that will use the word "nihilistic"), it's pure bared nerve endings, and it shows with no pretense the kind of cruelty some of us experience, and what effect it has on us. Everyone lashes out at someone weaker than them when they're in agony. While some of the actions do encourage headscratching, the characters in this are entirely realistic(I would say almost everything in this is), credible and well-developed. No one is a hero or a villain(don't expect to like everything about any of them). The acting is amazing. Matarazzo(who I can barely believe was willing to play the role) is impossibly perfect. Her body language, voice, eyes, everything is spot-on. Everyone is convincing in this. The tension is present and thick right from the beginning. I suppose one could argue that this doesn't have all that much genuine plot... we get a string of scenes in chronological order, and several things aren't followed up on. A ton does happen; I think this is mainly meant to show a small portion of the girl's life. Don't expect a lot of growth or change, or for this to have a conclusion(it kind of just stops... one can interpret the last image to mean something, though, and it certainly isn't randomly chosen). I'm not sure I understand classifying this as a comedy... if so, definitely note that it's black and sardonic humor. You can really *feel* the setting. The lunch-room, class-room and the suburban home... you're *there*, and you feel as suffocated and trapped as our lead does. This is filmed and edited impeccably well. There is disturbing content and strong language throughout this. The DVD comes with a trailer. I recommend this to anyone who wants an uncompromising look at what for many are the worst years of their life. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On trying to find DVDs, v1.10
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    annevejb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A prime quality that the DVD had for me was a price much higher than I usually can pay. Used to be that when I browsed IMDb details I sometimes looked at the tag at the top that showed availability in the different Amazon countries, availability as disk or tape or whatever. Way back then I purchased from local low cost shops, but it was interesting to browse. Then I progressed to purchases from the local, UK, Amazon but only for what I could pay for by cheque. Then I got to be able to pay electronically and it was suddenly possible to purchase low cost disks from second hand sources in the UK, Germany, USA and Canada, etc, via Amazon UK. The disk availability box at the top of an IMDb page was starting to have potential for real value, though I tended to search just in Amazon UK. Some of the really interesting disks were not available, some needed access to paying to a different country's Amazon, especially for low cost disks, but this was a massive start for being able to search for disks by title rather than from the more restricted range of what was available locally. Locally is still really useful, but it is more a serendipity sort of thing. Then the IMDb system changed. The disk availability button was not there. Then it was there but not showing the range of countries or versions of disks, if UK Amazon had the title in a variety of versions then either only one would be shown or an Amazon USA version would be shown. So, there was a basic indicator of availability, which is useful knowledge, just the way of searching the different stores was gone and at August 2009 this was still gone. So things were okay and unless an Amazon other than UK became the sole outlet for such as The Adventures Of Pete And Pete Season 3, some have a hunger for that Trachtenberg series, then things were tolerable. What happened instead was that Amazon USA became the sole outlet for Unfabulous Seasons 1 and 2. Also Zoey 101 seasons 3 and 4. While the prices are nothing like my ideal it was suddenly essential for me to get a payment method that Amazon USA accepts and in August 2009 I managed. Dollhouse. When I got to make my first order there was a copy of this at USA at a much lower price than I had ever noticed at Amazon UK or any other outlet. Except that order failed, it was not available for a delivery address in the UK. Two other items went through, though. It looks as if some traders are able to export, but not others. Later experiences told me that I still have a problem re availability of difficult to find titles. The outlook can seem bleak. The stuff that I had been noticing will mostly have not been available for export. * Dollhouse is from the year when season 3 of Pete, Pete appears and is a couple of years after Heather Matarazzo appeared in an episode of each of seasons 0 and 1. It is weaker than Pete, but in some ways it is as strong. I find that it echoes My Girl and Tideland, but from a different culture and in a more down to earth way. All have the main actor as of an appropriate age, scary but sense when musing on these sort of aspects. Dollhouse is bound to feel offensive to some who can accept My Girl. To me it has a reality that I can relate to more than with My Girl, though both stories are alien at the same time. Napoleon Dynamite, about a different age range and a different subset of symptoms, I now have to wonder how those characters would appear if that story was set at age eleven. Mysterious Skin and The Quiet expand on the range of faces of this. I found Dollhouse difficult to get into, but I vastly prefer this to Princess Diaries as that falls flat for me as soon as Mia gets the makeover, the point where one is supposed to gain empathy with Mia? Much is said of Dollhouse being a story about the difficulties that an ugly girl can face at age 12, but watch this with any care at all and it is obvious that this is a rather nice looking girl who is badly damaged by the ugly ways of those around her. One needs the right sort of helps to be able to get around that sort of thing and this story makes a loud comment about how real those helps can be. I have to like this feature a lot. The message board hints of some considering the three bad boys to be pure criminal types, but the strongest hint put in a criminal way. For me, Dollhouse gives a context that puts such into perspective. What this shows of their back to front reality, criminal seems an inappropriate label. That is the real strength of this feature. This is not about the apex of the pyramid of society, it shows a dunghill. Dawn comes out with some really putrid behaviour and there are some reviews here that consider that to be a reflection of her personality. To me, she is just showing some effects that can happen when one is blowing in the wind, chaff that does not have enough free will to escape being blown in that way. Rather than Dawn being horror I consider that she is blown into a horrifying and damaging situation, but one has had to have been in that sort of situation oneself to accept that is an aspect of her being a victim of horror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmGuy34567
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse-***1/2 (out of 4): Junior high can be tough and it is especially tough for little Dawn, who suffers from her abusive classmates, less than satisfactory home life, and her own discomfort with the problems of adolescence. Perhaps one of the most raw and unsentimental coming of age pictures ever made, though the tone is purely original. We are in many ways touched and even heartbroken by the central character and her troubles, but often catch ourselves laughing at the sheer misery and misfortune encountered by her. Half black comic and half drama, but completely insightful: this film is definitely one for the books. It also is the first display of the humorous misery of writer-director's Todd Solondz's imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to watch... But brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rich Wright
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'd think, with all the humiliations that pile up on our mousy heroine over the course of this unbearably cruel film, the scene is set for a big revenge moment... A huge climax where she finally sticks it to all her enemies and proves her worth. You would be completely wrong. This is no 'triumph of the underdog' tale, just a survival story about the spirit of a kid who must endure almost consistent harassment everyday, whether she's at school or home... And we wonder, how does she avoid cracking up? Her family don't want anything to do with her, preferring to lavish their affections on her 'perfect' younger sister, while in class she's the target of bullies, and the teachers seem to consist of a bunch of patronising jerks. Even the few chinks of light that occasionally shine through the gloom of her existence are quickly snuffed out, so if you're looking for a movie to put you in a good mood you're better off watching Bambi's mother get shot on an endless loop. BUT... (and this is a massive BUT) it also happens to be one of the finest films I've seen in years. I had it on DVD but guess what... a massive scratch on the disc stopped it after half an hour. Even with that small taste, I knew it was something special. So I waited... And FINALLY the whole thing has been uploaded to Youtube... And may I just say, it fulfilled my initial reaction to it, and then some. A huge part of it's success lies squarely at the feet of Heather Matarazzo, who cuts a sympathetic (or perhaps just pathetic) figure as she shuffles through life, being abused and hated by all. It's a role which could easily have descended into caricature, but her breathtaking performance as a bright girl doomed by circumstance to eke out this rubbish existence makes her plight evermore tragic. The supporting parts hit the bullseye too, as everyone from her nerdy best (and only) friend to her tutu-wearing, sickly-sweet younger sibling infuse proceedings with a quality which is rarely seen. This is a great film... Not a happy one, but I guarantee a far more relatable flick than half the homogenised coming-of-age motion pictures out there. You know, the ones where everyone is beautiful, most of your fellow students are wealthy minorities and you burst into the chorus of a cheesy song every few minutes. Hmm, what could I possibly be talking about... 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennsouthwest
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ha ha ha. Her friends make her poop on the floor of the school bathroom. Her little sister gets kidnapped by a pedophile and is kept prisoner in sub-floor space. Isn't that funny? I didn't think so. I can enjoy very dark humor. I can laugh about things that others find offensive, so it takes something really cruel and raw to turn my stomach. This was not done in a satirical way. It looked dead serious, but they added little tidbits here and there to let you know it was supposed to be a comedy. I wasn't sure in the movie theater whether I was more disturbed by the movie, or by the fact that other viewers were laughing! If you aren't disturbed by pedophilia, excrement-related bullying and other such themes, and in fact, you find all of those topics very funny, this may be just the movie for you. The actors were very talented and certainly convincing in their roles. The director made it all seem very real. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kind of misanthropic but fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Adam Thirwell
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing about watching a film like this at a time when the American high school genre has moved on to the much rosier visions of Napoleon Dynamite and Glee is that it strikes you how almost every character is a flawed, unlikeable person. Sure, you feel sorry and empathise with Dawn, the main character, but she's equally willing to bully, and doesn't have saving graces like the standard US school film geek - she's no brainbox. The guys in the film are portrayed as far less vindictive than the girls - bad boy Brandon has a sort of rogue honour, and the main fault of the other males in Dawn's life is that they are obsessed with doing their own thing or else following expectations laid down for them. It's a very watchable film - more so than Todd Solondz's later works. It looks like the work of an embittered outsider, but at least an outsider who, like the main character, tries to do their own thing against the odds.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbie and the Beast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like Woody Allen, Todd Solondz spends his time poking fun at man's foibles, whilst perhaps simultaneously wishing he weren't part of the very social fabric he condemns. It's your classic ego trap: "I'm better and above you, but worthless and wish I were with you." Solondz made "Fear, Anxiety and Depression" in 1989. He wrote and directed that film and, like Woody Allen, also cast himself as the film's neurotic hero. Like Allen's alter ego in "Annie Hall", the geeky looking Solondz spent the entire film bumbling about, venting his various dissaffections. Solondz was never happy with "Fear", however, and promptly disowned the film when his producers re-edited it behind his back. Burnt by the film industry, Solondz slipped into depression. He withdrew into isolation and became a teacher and writer. During these years his approach to art changed drastically. His screenplays became more formal, more precise, more caustic, and his visual style became cold. Ice cold. Solondz's first film when he emerged from his depression was "Welcome to the Dollhouse". Drawing upon his own unhappy school years, "Dollhouse" is about Dawn Weiner, a girl whom the universe seems to have condemned. More sinister than similar teen movies, "Dollhouse's" Dawn is so insecure she's happy to let a kid at school rape her if it means validating her own self worth. This would be rapist is himself marginalized, insecure and so reliant on sexual threats for self validation. Dawn is so filled with rage she even saws off the heads of her sister's dolls, fantasises about bashing people with a hammer and deliberately causes her sibling to be kidnapped by a local paedophile. Meanwhile, all the abuses people hurl at the geeky Dawn, Dawn hurls down at her little sister, a girl whom she unfairly despises. The result is that Dawn is shown to be capable of the same kind of brutality that she's subjected to. Social bullying is internalised, becomes self-hatred, and is then redirected violently back out at others. "Dollhouse" was a cosy film compared to Solondz's next three flicks. In "Happiness" he portrays a web of characters, all of whom harbour different problems and neuroses, and all of whom are linked by their desire for absolute contentment. And so we have a paedophile who is only happy around kids, a successful writer who is only happy if she writes something of substance, a musician (who ironically writes songs of substance) who can't find success and is so discontent, an elderly couple who no longer have the will to live, a fat man who fantasises about raping women, a fat woman who is disgusted by sex and a dopey housewife who is blissfully unaware of the disturbing truths that exist beneath her sweet suburban facade. Forget "American Beauty" and "Blue Velvet". Solondz ends his film with a Norman Rockwell kid ejaculating on his front balcony. Solondz's point is almost classically psychoanalytic: Lack breeds Desire breeds Suffering. Peel away the emotional baggage and happiness is a stain that oft amounts to nothing more than a fleeting moment of biological bliss. "Happiness" doesn't broadening its horizons to tackle the wider social and structural issues that better directors align to their existential musings, but it does offer more than Sam Mendes' "American Beauty". Indeed, Solondz's next film, "Storytelling", seemed designed to address those critics who pointed out the similarities between "Happiness" and "American Beauty". Mendes has himself slammed Solondz on numerous occasions, and so perhaps "Storytelling" is best viewed as a sort of intellectual assault on Solondz's critics. "Storytelling" is divided into two segments, the first called "fiction" the second called "non-fiction". "Fiction" is about a creative writing student who has "sympathy sex" with a mentally disabled kid and later lets her African American teacher "rape" her. She then turns her experiences into a work of fiction which purports to be "truthfully" based on these factual encounters. "Storytelling's" second segment then focuses on a documentary director who makes a documentary called "American Scooby" (a parody of "American Beauty") in which he follows a high school student around campus. The documentary director hopes to uncover the "truth" of growing up in suburbia, but in reality is merely transposing his own "deep thoughts", self-analysis and existential hang-ups onto a modern teen who is actually a dopey airhead. The end result is that film-maker and child enter a sort of exploitative relationship. The kid gets fame and is portrayed as being "deeper" than he is, while the film-maker gets prestige for nothing. End result: Solondz essentially advocates the sort of "truthful" sensationalism present in the non-fiction segment of the film, whilst aligning human delusions (love, romantic illusions, family etc) with the fictions of the second half. Other themes abound - the power games and domination/exploitatin reversals of "Dollhouse" are reworked here with subplots about a vengeful maid and a black teacher - but it's the "American Beauty" angle that's most interesting. "Palindromes" is thus far the weakest of Solondz's films. The first and last words in the movie are "Mom", a pair of palindromes through which Solondz implies that "nothing ever changes". Indeed, Solondz makes the film a palindrome at every level, his Schopenhaueran point being that we are paradoxically always changing and never changing (hence different actors play the same character), every desire and addiction merely supplanting another. It's an extremely bleak film, depending how much trust the audience puts in its final monologue. This bleakness has led to critics labelling Solondz a misanthrope, but he's no more colder than both Allen and the Coens, two other contemporary critical darlings who've spent their careers reworking similar material. 7.9/10  "Welcome to the Dollhouse", "Palindromes" 8/10  "Storytelling", "Happiness"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sketch of adolescent alienation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse is about a girl named Dawn who fails to find a place anywhere in society. She seems to be the victim of middle child syndrome as her parents are too worried about their other two children to bother much with her. Dawn's brother is already established as the brainy oldest child and her sister is the cute one, leaving her without an easy way to establish her own identity. At school she is is unable to fit in at least partially because her parents don't care enough about her to help her dress normally for her age. Because she isn't nurtured at home, she also fails to develop socially and her personality is too thin to make her sympathetic to the other students. Predictably, she is treated as poorly at school as she is at home. Welcome to the Dollhouse is full of these devastating scenes in which Dawn get her hopes up only to have them knocked down again. Her parents and classmates are oblivious to her suffering; no matter how bad things are for her nobody ever seems to think about her feelings. Things also tend to go against her as a matter of course. She is frequently unlucky as when she attempts to get revenge on her tormentors and accidentally targets an unsuspecting adult. Welcome to the Dollhouse does a fairly good job of capturing an unfortunate girl at a particularly awkward time of life. It suffers from a lack of realism at times, however, since it's unlikely that every teacher and student would hate a person that is more bland than offensive. Even more detrimental than the film's lack of realism in establishing Dawn's situation is the film's lack of style. The visuals are unremarkable and the only memorable aesthetic choice is the tacky design in Dawn's home. The plot takes a detour into absurdity when Dawn's sister is kidnapped but surprisingly this isn't really played for laughs in spite of some humorous elements. I was surprised to learn that this wasn't director Todd Solondz's first feature as it felt like the work of a film-maker looking to gain enough confidence to do the things he really wanted to. Welcome to the Dollhouse does an adequate job of establishing a single character but it feels like it's missing some crucial elements that could have made it truly memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Todd Solondz initiates a world of downers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never heard of Todd Solondz, then I should explain that "Welcome to the Dollhouse" is probably the most watchable. His movies - at least the few that I've seen - are always complete downers, containing characters who are either sickos, helpless, or something similar. His first notable movie concerns Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo), a New Jersey middle school girl ostracized by everyone around her. The only boy who gives her any good advice is totally pitiful himself. Dawn's entire life is one big FML. I recommend "WTTD", but with the caution that it IS a total downer. Hell, you might not even end up liking it. But it is worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the horrors of middle school
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film well encapsulates the horrors of middle school, perhaps more than was your experience, but the point is well taken. This unfortunately-named girl (Dawn Wiener), whose plight is not helped by her gawky looks, nerdiness, and refusal to take her punishment lying down, brings the pain of middle school into sharp relief. Having read a lot of the comments on IMDb, it's clear that this movie resonates with many. Landmark director Todd Solondz doesn't shrink from depicting the most cringe-inducing, skin-peeling, soul-destroying tortures inflicted by kids on their peers during those difficult tweener/teen years. Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo) lives with a mother who has no idea of the pain in which her daughter is in and with a father with no guts to intervene to his wife on his daughter's behalf. Her older brother is an academic success, although also very nerdy and her younger sister is the belle of the ball who can do no wrong in her mother's eyes. Solondz has constructed a very plausible hell in which his young protagonist suffers. She has no friends save for one boy who is the only other member of her "Special People Club". Her locker is the site of some particularly vitriolic abuse (although, having worked at schools, I found it implausible to believe that no teacher would have intervened to have the abuse removed), she is called "lesbo" and one girl who is particularly nasty will not let her leave the restroom without taking a crap. I liked the fact that this protagonist does not take the abuse lying down. Solondz creates such a good movie that he does not make Wiener into a wallflower. Indeed, she reacts in sometimes callous ways, taking out the anger she feels on someone less powerful than her. It's not necessarily pretty, but it's human nature. She reacts in anger to several things and I found this refreshing. She is not depicted as an ineffectual person. She fights back against her treatment-which people do, in real life-and Solondz deserves credit for this characterization of his protagonist. This really is a tough film to watch but I think this is one many young teens and tweeners would do well to watch and discuss with their parents because it could be a jumping-off point for a discussion about bullying and cruelty at this very difficult age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At three o'clock today, I'm going to rape you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dawn is bullied in her middle school. She is insecure, wears unflattering clothes and doesn't feel attractive. Her inattentive parents care far more about her smart and nerdy older brother and her spoilt, elegant little sister(that she actually has to share a room with, in spite of being 11) than her, leaving her the overlooked middle child. She falls in love with a guy five years her senior. But could that possibly work out? This is one of the most brutally honest(it admits that teenagers actually think about sex), painful(the cake scene is torture), and difficult to watch films I've ever seen. I knew that it would be, because this is not my first exposure to the immensely talented Solondz... I own a copy of the quite good Storytelling, and I had heard that this was much harder on the viewer. This really doesn't let up(there are those that will use the word "nihilistic"), it's pure bared nerve endings, and it shows with no pretense the kind of cruelty some of us experience, and what effect it has on us. Everyone lashes out at someone weaker than them when they're in agony. While some of the actions do encourage headscratching, the characters in this are entirely realistic(I would say almost everything in this is), credible and well-developed. No one is a hero or a villain(don't expect to like everything about any of them). The acting is amazing. Matarazzo(who I can barely believe was willing to play the role) is impossibly perfect. Her body language, voice, eyes, everything is spot-on. Everyone is convincing in this. The tension is present and thick right from the beginning. I suppose one could argue that this doesn't have all that much genuine plot... we get a string of scenes in chronological order, and several things aren't followed up on. A ton does happen; I think this is mainly meant to show a small portion of the girl's life. Don't expect a lot of growth or change, or for this to have a conclusion(it kind of just stops... one can interpret the last image to mean something, though, and it certainly isn't randomly chosen). I'm not sure I understand classifying this as a comedy... if so, definitely note that it's black and sardonic humor. You can really *feel* the setting. The lunch-room, class-room and the suburban home... you're *there*, and you feel as suffocated and trapped as our lead does. This is filmed and edited impeccably well. There is disturbing content and strong language throughout this. The DVD comes with a trailer. I recommend this to anyone who wants an uncompromising look at what for many are the worst years of their life. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On trying to find DVDs, v1.10
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    annevejb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A prime quality that the DVD had for me was a price much higher than I usually can pay. Used to be that when I browsed IMDb details I sometimes looked at the tag at the top that showed availability in the different Amazon countries, availability as disk or tape or whatever. Way back then I purchased from local low cost shops, but it was interesting to browse. Then I progressed to purchases from the local, UK, Amazon but only for what I could pay for by cheque. Then I got to be able to pay electronically and it was suddenly possible to purchase low cost disks from second hand sources in the UK, Germany, USA and Canada, etc, via Amazon UK. The disk availability box at the top of an IMDb page was starting to have potential for real value, though I tended to search just in Amazon UK. Some of the really interesting disks were not available, some needed access to paying to a different country's Amazon, especially for low cost disks, but this was a massive start for being able to search for disks by title rather than from the more restricted range of what was available locally. Locally is still really useful, but it is more a serendipity sort of thing. Then the IMDb system changed. The disk availability button was not there. Then it was there but not showing the range of countries or versions of disks, if UK Amazon had the title in a variety of versions then either only one would be shown or an Amazon USA version would be shown. So, there was a basic indicator of availability, which is useful knowledge, just the way of searching the different stores was gone and at August 2009 this was still gone. So things were okay and unless an Amazon other than UK became the sole outlet for such as The Adventures Of Pete And Pete Season 3, some have a hunger for that Trachtenberg series, then things were tolerable. What happened instead was that Amazon USA became the sole outlet for Unfabulous Seasons 1 and 2. Also Zoey 101 seasons 3 and 4. While the prices are nothing like my ideal it was suddenly essential for me to get a payment method that Amazon USA accepts and in August 2009 I managed. Dollhouse. When I got to make my first order there was a copy of this at USA at a much lower price than I had ever noticed at Amazon UK or any other outlet. Except that order failed, it was not available for a delivery address in the UK. Two other items went through, though. It looks as if some traders are able to export, but not others. Later experiences told me that I still have a problem re availability of difficult to find titles. The outlook can seem bleak. The stuff that I had been noticing will mostly have not been available for export. * Dollhouse is from the year when season 3 of Pete, Pete appears and is a couple of years after Heather Matarazzo appeared in an episode of each of seasons 0 and 1. It is weaker than Pete, but in some ways it is as strong. I find that it echoes My Girl and Tideland, but from a different culture and in a more down to earth way. All have the main actor as of an appropriate age, scary but sense when musing on these sort of aspects. Dollhouse is bound to feel offensive to some who can accept My Girl. To me it has a reality that I can relate to more than with My Girl, though both stories are alien at the same time. Napoleon Dynamite, about a different age range and a different subset of symptoms, I now have to wonder how those characters would appear if that story was set at age eleven. Mysterious Skin and The Quiet expand on the range of faces of this. I found Dollhouse difficult to get into, but I vastly prefer this to Princess Diaries as that falls flat for me as soon as Mia gets the makeover, the point where one is supposed to gain empathy with Mia? Much is said of Dollhouse being a story about the difficulties that an ugly girl can face at age 12, but watch this with any care at all and it is obvious that this is a rather nice looking girl who is badly damaged by the ugly ways of those around her. One needs the right sort of helps to be able to get around that sort of thing and this story makes a loud comment about how real those helps can be. I have to like this feature a lot. The message board hints of some considering the three bad boys to be pure criminal types, but the strongest hint put in a criminal way. For me, Dollhouse gives a context that puts such into perspective. What this shows of their back to front reality, criminal seems an inappropriate label. That is the real strength of this feature. This is not about the apex of the pyramid of society, it shows a dunghill. Dawn comes out with some really putrid behaviour and there are some reviews here that consider that to be a reflection of her personality. To me, she is just showing some effects that can happen when one is blowing in the wind, chaff that does not have enough free will to escape being blown in that way. Rather than Dawn being horror I consider that she is blown into a horrifying and damaging situation, but one has had to have been in that sort of situation oneself to accept that is an aspect of her being a victim of horror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse Review
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmGuy34567
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse-***1/2 (out of 4): Junior high can be tough and it is especially tough for little Dawn, who suffers from her abusive classmates, less than satisfactory home life, and her own discomfort with the problems of adolescence. Perhaps one of the most raw and unsentimental coming of age pictures ever made, though the tone is purely original. We are in many ways touched and even heartbroken by the central character and her troubles, but often catch ourselves laughing at the sheer misery and misfortune encountered by her. Half black comic and half drama, but completely insightful: this film is definitely one for the books. It also is the first display of the humorous misery of writer-director's Todd Solondz's imagination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hard to watch... But brilliant.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rich Wright
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You'd think, with all the humiliations that pile up on our mousy heroine over the course of this unbearably cruel film, the scene is set for a big revenge moment... A huge climax where she finally sticks it to all her enemies and proves her worth. You would be completely wrong. This is no 'triumph of the underdog' tale, just a survival story about the spirit of a kid who must endure almost consistent harassment everyday, whether she's at school or home... And we wonder, how does she avoid cracking up? Her family don't want anything to do with her, preferring to lavish their affections on her 'perfect' younger sister, while in class she's the target of bullies, and the teachers seem to consist of a bunch of patronising jerks. Even the few chinks of light that occasionally shine through the gloom of her existence are quickly snuffed out, so if you're looking for a movie to put you in a good mood you're better off watching Bambi's mother get shot on an endless loop. BUT... (and this is a massive BUT) it also happens to be one of the finest films I've seen in years. I had it on DVD but guess what... a massive scratch on the disc stopped it after half an hour. Even with that small taste, I knew it was something special. So I waited... And FINALLY the whole thing has been uploaded to Youtube... And may I just say, it fulfilled my initial reaction to it, and then some. A huge part of it's success lies squarely at the feet of Heather Matarazzo, who cuts a sympathetic (or perhaps just pathetic) figure as she shuffles through life, being abused and hated by all. It's a role which could easily have descended into caricature, but her breathtaking performance as a bright girl doomed by circumstance to eke out this rubbish existence makes her plight evermore tragic. The supporting parts hit the bullseye too, as everyone from her nerdy best (and only) friend to her tutu-wearing, sickly-sweet younger sibling infuse proceedings with a quality which is rarely seen. This is a great film... Not a happy one, but I guarantee a far more relatable flick than half the homogenised coming-of-age motion pictures out there. You know, the ones where everyone is beautiful, most of your fellow students are wealthy minorities and you burst into the chorus of a cheesy song every few minutes. Hmm, what could I possibly be talking about... 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Profoundly Disturbing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jennsouthwest
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ha ha ha. Her friends make her poop on the floor of the school bathroom. Her little sister gets kidnapped by a pedophile and is kept prisoner in sub-floor space. Isn't that funny? I didn't think so. I can enjoy very dark humor. I can laugh about things that others find offensive, so it takes something really cruel and raw to turn my stomach. This was not done in a satirical way. It looked dead serious, but they added little tidbits here and there to let you know it was supposed to be a comedy. I wasn't sure in the movie theater whether I was more disturbed by the movie, or by the fact that other viewers were laughing! If you aren't disturbed by pedophilia, excrement-related bullying and other such themes, and in fact, you find all of those topics very funny, this may be just the movie for you. The actors were very talented and certainly convincing in their roles. The director made it all seem very real. Enjoy!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kind of misanthropic but fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Adam Thirwell
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing about watching a film like this at a time when the American high school genre has moved on to the much rosier visions of Napoleon Dynamite and Glee is that it strikes you how almost every character is a flawed, unlikeable person. Sure, you feel sorry and empathise with Dawn, the main character, but she's equally willing to bully, and doesn't have saving graces like the standard US school film geek - she's no brainbox. The guys in the film are portrayed as far less vindictive than the girls - bad boy Brandon has a sort of rogue honour, and the main fault of the other males in Dawn's life is that they are obsessed with doing their own thing or else following expectations laid down for them. It's a very watchable film - more so than Todd Solondz's later works. It looks like the work of an embittered outsider, but at least an outsider who, like the main character, tries to do their own thing against the odds.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barbie and the Beast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like Woody Allen, Todd Solondz spends his time poking fun at man's foibles, whilst perhaps simultaneously wishing he weren't part of the very social fabric he condemns. It's your classic ego trap: "I'm better and above you, but worthless and wish I were with you." Solondz made "Fear, Anxiety and Depression" in 1989. He wrote and directed that film and, like Woody Allen, also cast himself as the film's neurotic hero. Like Allen's alter ego in "Annie Hall", the geeky looking Solondz spent the entire film bumbling about, venting his various dissaffections. Solondz was never happy with "Fear", however, and promptly disowned the film when his producers re-edited it behind his back. Burnt by the film industry, Solondz slipped into depression. He withdrew into isolation and became a teacher and writer. During these years his approach to art changed drastically. His screenplays became more formal, more precise, more caustic, and his visual style became cold. Ice cold. Solondz's first film when he emerged from his depression was "Welcome to the Dollhouse". Drawing upon his own unhappy school years, "Dollhouse" is about Dawn Weiner, a girl whom the universe seems to have condemned. More sinister than similar teen movies, "Dollhouse's" Dawn is so insecure she's happy to let a kid at school rape her if it means validating her own self worth. This would be rapist is himself marginalized, insecure and so reliant on sexual threats for self validation. Dawn is so filled with rage she even saws off the heads of her sister's dolls, fantasises about bashing people with a hammer and deliberately causes her sibling to be kidnapped by a local paedophile. Meanwhile, all the abuses people hurl at the geeky Dawn, Dawn hurls down at her little sister, a girl whom she unfairly despises. The result is that Dawn is shown to be capable of the same kind of brutality that she's subjected to. Social bullying is internalised, becomes self-hatred, and is then redirected violently back out at others. "Dollhouse" was a cosy film compared to Solondz's next three flicks. In "Happiness" he portrays a web of characters, all of whom harbour different problems and neuroses, and all of whom are linked by their desire for absolute contentment. And so we have a paedophile who is only happy around kids, a successful writer who is only happy if she writes something of substance, a musician (who ironically writes songs of substance) who can't find success and is so discontent, an elderly couple who no longer have the will to live, a fat man who fantasises about raping women, a fat woman who is disgusted by sex and a dopey housewife who is blissfully unaware of the disturbing truths that exist beneath her sweet suburban facade. Forget "American Beauty" and "Blue Velvet". Solondz ends his film with a Norman Rockwell kid ejaculating on his front balcony. Solondz's point is almost classically psychoanalytic: Lack breeds Desire breeds Suffering. Peel away the emotional baggage and happiness is a stain that oft amounts to nothing more than a fleeting moment of biological bliss. "Happiness" doesn't broadening its horizons to tackle the wider social and structural issues that better directors align to their existential musings, but it does offer more than Sam Mendes' "American Beauty". Indeed, Solondz's next film, "Storytelling", seemed designed to address those critics who pointed out the similarities between "Happiness" and "American Beauty". Mendes has himself slammed Solondz on numerous occasions, and so perhaps "Storytelling" is best viewed as a sort of intellectual assault on Solondz's critics. "Storytelling" is divided into two segments, the first called "fiction" the second called "non-fiction". "Fiction" is about a creative writing student who has "sympathy sex" with a mentally disabled kid and later lets her African American teacher "rape" her. She then turns her experiences into a work of fiction which purports to be "truthfully" based on these factual encounters. "Storytelling's" second segment then focuses on a documentary director who makes a documentary called "American Scooby" (a parody of "American Beauty") in which he follows a high school student around campus. The documentary director hopes to uncover the "truth" of growing up in suburbia, but in reality is merely transposing his own "deep thoughts", self-analysis and existential hang-ups onto a modern teen who is actually a dopey airhead. The end result is that film-maker and child enter a sort of exploitative relationship. The kid gets fame and is portrayed as being "deeper" than he is, while the film-maker gets prestige for nothing. End result: Solondz essentially advocates the sort of "truthful" sensationalism present in the non-fiction segment of the film, whilst aligning human delusions (love, romantic illusions, family etc) with the fictions of the second half. Other themes abound - the power games and domination/exploitatin reversals of "Dollhouse" are reworked here with subplots about a vengeful maid and a black teacher - but it's the "American Beauty" angle that's most interesting. "Palindromes" is thus far the weakest of Solondz's films. The first and last words in the movie are "Mom", a pair of palindromes through which Solondz implies that "nothing ever changes". Indeed, Solondz makes the film a palindrome at every level, his Schopenhaueran point being that we are paradoxically always changing and never changing (hence different actors play the same character), every desire and addiction merely supplanting another. It's an extremely bleak film, depending how much trust the audience puts in its final monologue. This bleakness has led to critics labelling Solondz a misanthrope, but he's no more colder than both Allen and the Coens, two other contemporary critical darlings who've spent their careers reworking similar material. 7.9/10  "Welcome to the Dollhouse", "Palindromes" 8/10  "Storytelling", "Happiness"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sketch of adolescent alienation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    timmy_501
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Welcome to the Dollhouse is about a girl named Dawn who fails to find a place anywhere in society. She seems to be the victim of middle child syndrome as her parents are too worried about their other two children to bother much with her. Dawn's brother is already established as the brainy oldest child and her sister is the cute one, leaving her without an easy way to establish her own identity. At school she is is unable to fit in at least partially because her parents don't care enough about her to help her dress normally for her age. Because she isn't nurtured at home, she also fails to develop socially and her personality is too thin to make her sympathetic to the other students. Predictably, she is treated as poorly at school as she is at home. Welcome to the Dollhouse is full of these devastating scenes in which Dawn get her hopes up only to have them knocked down again. Her parents and classmates are oblivious to her suffering; no matter how bad things are for her nobody ever seems to think about her feelings. Things also tend to go against her as a matter of course. She is frequently unlucky as when she attempts to get revenge on her tormentors and accidentally targets an unsuspecting adult. Welcome to the Dollhouse does a fairly good job of capturing an unfortunate girl at a particularly awkward time of life. It suffers from a lack of realism at times, however, since it's unlikely that every teacher and student would hate a person that is more bland than offensive. Even more detrimental than the film's lack of realism in establishing Dawn's situation is the film's lack of style. The visuals are unremarkable and the only memorable aesthetic choice is the tacky design in Dawn's home. The plot takes a detour into absurdity when Dawn's sister is kidnapped but surprisingly this isn't really played for laughs in spite of some humorous elements. I was surprised to learn that this wasn't director Todd Solondz's first feature as it felt like the work of a film-maker looking to gain enough confidence to do the things he really wanted to. Welcome to the Dollhouse does an adequate job of establishing a single character but it feels like it's missing some crucial elements that could have made it truly memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Todd Solondz initiates a world of downers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've never heard of Todd Solondz, then I should explain that "Welcome to the Dollhouse" is probably the most watchable. His movies - at least the few that I've seen - are always complete downers, containing characters who are either sickos, helpless, or something similar. His first notable movie concerns Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo), a New Jersey middle school girl ostracized by everyone around her. The only boy who gives her any good advice is totally pitiful himself. Dawn's entire life is one big FML. I recommend "WTTD", but with the caution that it IS a total downer. Hell, you might not even end up liking it. But it is worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the horrors of middle school
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tnrcooper
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film well encapsulates the horrors of middle school, perhaps more than was your experience, but the point is well taken. This unfortunately-named girl (Dawn Wiener), whose plight is not helped by her gawky looks, nerdiness, and refusal to take her punishment lying down, brings the pain of middle school into sharp relief. Having read a lot of the comments on IMDb, it's clear that this movie resonates with many. Landmark director Todd Solondz doesn't shrink from depicting the most cringe-inducing, skin-peeling, soul-destroying tortures inflicted by kids on their peers during those difficult tweener/teen years. Dawn Wiener (Heather Matarazzo) lives with a mother who has no idea of the pain in which her daughter is in and with a father with no guts to intervene to his wife on his daughter's behalf. Her older brother is an academic success, although also very nerdy and her younger sister is the belle of the ball who can do no wrong in her mother's eyes. Solondz has constructed a very plausible hell in which his young protagonist suffers. She has no friends save for one boy who is the only other member of her "Special People Club". Her locker is the site of some particularly vitriolic abuse (although, having worked at schools, I found it implausible to believe that no teacher would have intervened to have the abuse removed), she is called "lesbo" and one girl who is particularly nasty will not let her leave the restroom without taking a crap. I liked the fact that this protagonist does not take the abuse lying down. Solondz creates such a good movie that he does not make Wiener into a wallflower. Indeed, she reacts in sometimes callous ways, taking out the anger she feels on someone less powerful than her. It's not necessarily pretty, but it's human nature. She reacts in anger to several things and I found this refreshing. She is not depicted as an ineffectual person. She fights back against her treatment-which people do, in real life-and Solondz deserves credit for this characterization of his protagonist. This really is a tough film to watch but I think this is one many young teens and tweeners would do well to watch and discuss with their parents because it could be a jumping-off point for a discussion about bullying and cruelty at this very difficult age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At three o'clock today, I'm going to rape you
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Grann-Bach (Grann-Bach@jubii.dk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dawn is bullied in her middle school. She is insecure, wears unflattering clothes and doesn't feel attractive. Her inattentive parents care far more about her smart and nerdy older brother and her spoilt, elegant little sister(that she actually has to share a room with, in spite of being 11) than her, leaving her the overlooked middle child. She falls in love with a guy five years her senior. But could that possibly work out? This is one of the most brutally honest(it admits that teenagers actually think about sex), painful(the cake scene is torture), and difficult to watch films I've ever seen. I knew that it would be, because this is not my first exposure to the immensely talented Solondz... I own a copy of the quite good Storytelling, and I had heard that this was much harder on the viewer. This really doesn't let up(there are those that will use the word "nihilistic"), it's pure bared nerve endings, and it shows with no pretense the kind of cruelty some of us experience, and what effect it has on us. Everyone lashes out at someone weaker than them when they're in agony. While some of the actions do encourage headscratching, the characters in this are entirely realistic(I would say almost everything in this is), credible and well-developed. No one is a hero or a villain(don't expect to like everything about any of them). The acting is amazing. Matarazzo(who I can barely believe was willing to play the role) is impossibly perfect. Her body language, voice, eyes, everything is spot-on. Everyone is convincing in this. The tension is present and thick right from the beginning. I suppose one could argue that this doesn't have all that much genuine plot... we get a string of scenes in chronological order, and several things aren't followed up on. A ton does happen; I think this is mainly meant to show a small portion of the girl's life. Don't expect a lot of growth or change, or for this to have a conclusion(it kind of just stops... one can interpret the last image to mean something, though, and it certainly isn't randomly chosen). I'm not sure I understand classifying this as a comedy... if so, definitely note that it's black and sardonic humor. You can really *feel* the setting. The lunch-room, class-room and the suburban home... you're *there*, and you feel as suffocated and trapped as our lead does. This is filmed and edited impeccably well. There is disturbing content and strong language throughout this. The DVD comes with a trailer. I recommend this to anyone who wants an uncompromising look at what for many are the worst years of their life. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On trying to find DVDs, v1.10
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    annevejb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A prime quality that the DVD had for me was a price much higher than I usually can pay. Used to be that when I browsed IMDb details I sometimes looked at the tag at the top that showed availability in the different Amazon countries, availability as disk or tape or whatever. Way back then I purchased from local low cost shops, but it was interesting to browse. Then I progressed to purchases from the local, UK, Amazon but only for what I could pay for by cheque. Then I got to be able to pay electronically and it was suddenly possible to purchase low cost disks from second hand sources in the UK, Germany, USA and Canada, etc, via Amazon UK. The disk availability box at the top of an IMDb page was starting to have potential for real value, though I tended to search just in Amazon UK. Some of the really interesting disks were not available, some needed access to paying to a different country's Amazon, especially for low cost disks, but this was a massive start for being able to search for disks by title rather than from the more restricted range of what was available locally. Locally is still really useful, but it is more a serendipity sort of thing. Then the IMDb system changed. The disk availability button was not there. Then it was there but not showing the range of countries or versions of disks, if UK Amazon had the title in a variety of versions then either only one would be shown or an Amazon USA version would be shown. So, there was a basic indicator of availability, which is useful knowledge, just the way of searching the different stores was gone and at August 2009 this was still gone. So things were okay and unless an Amazon other than UK became the sole outlet for such as The Adventures Of Pete And Pete Season 3, some have a hunger for that Trachtenberg series, then things were tolerable. What happened instead was that Amazon USA became the sole outlet for Unfabulous Seasons 1 and 2. Also Zoey 101 seasons 3 and 4. While the prices are nothing like my ideal it was suddenly essential for me to get a payment method that Amazon USA accepts and in August 2009 I managed. Dollhouse. When I got to make my first order there was a copy of this at USA at a much lower price than I had ever noticed at Amazon UK or any other outlet. Except that order failed, it was not available for a delivery address in the UK. Two other items went through, though. It looks as if some traders are able to export, but not others. Later experiences told me that I still have a problem re availability of difficult to find titles. The outlook can seem bleak. The stuff that I had been noticing will mostly have not been available for export. * Dollhouse is from the year when season 3 of Pete, Pete appears and is a couple of years after Heather Matarazzo appeared in an episode of each of seasons 0 and 1. It is weaker than Pete, but in some ways it is as strong. I find that it echoes My Girl and Tideland, but from a different culture and in a more down to earth way. All have the main actor as of an appropriate age, scary but sense when musing on these sort of aspects. Dollhouse is bound to feel offensive to some who can accept My Girl. To me it has a reality that I can relate to more than with My Girl, though both stories are alien at the same time. Napoleon Dynamite, about a different age range and a different subset of symptoms, I now have to wonder how those characters would appear if that story was set at age eleven. Mysterious Skin and The Quiet expand on the range of faces of this. I found Dollhouse difficult to get into, but I vastly prefer this to Princess Diaries as that falls flat for me as soon as Mia gets the makeover, the point where one is supposed to gain empathy with Mia? Much is said of Dollhouse being a story about the difficulties that an ugly girl can face at age 12, but watch this with any care at all and it is obvious that this is a rather nice looking girl who is badly damaged by the ugly ways of those around her. One needs the right sort of helps to be able to get around that sort of thing and this story makes a loud comment about how real those helps can be. I have to like this feature a lot. The message board hints of some considering the three bad boys to be pure criminal types, but the strongest hint put in a criminal way. For me, Dollhouse gives a context that puts such into perspective. What this shows of their back to front reality, criminal seems an inappropriate label. That is the real strength of this feature. This is not about the apex of the pyramid of society, it shows a dunghill. Dawn comes out with some really putrid behaviour and there are some reviews here that consider that to be a reflection of her personality. To me, she is just showing some effects that can happen when one is blowing in the wind, chaff that does not have enough free will to escape being blown in that way. Rather than Dawn being horror I consider that she is blown into a horrifying and damaging situation, but one has had to have been in that sort of situation oneself to accept that is an aspect of her being a victim of horror.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
