<filme>
 <id>
  934
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117372
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Um Anjo em Minha Vida
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Good natured Reverend Henry Biggs finds that his marriage to choir mistress Julia is flagging, due to his constant absence caring for the deprived neighborhood they live in. On top of all ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Good natured Reverend Henry Biggs finds that his marriage to choir mistress Julia is flagging, due to his constant absence caring for the deprived neighborhood they live in. On top of all this, his church is coming under threat from property developer Joe Hamilton. In desperation, Rev. Biggs prays to God for help - and help arrives in the form of an angel named Dudley. However, Dudley's arrival seems to cause even more trouble...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   angel
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   church
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   marriage
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   reverend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gospel
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Penny Marshall
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Robert Nathan
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Robert E. Sherwood
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Denzel Washington
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Whitney Houston
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Courtney B. Vance
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what a positive movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    erykah8402
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    how can anyone say this movie is boring?? I recently saw this on a few reviews... what a shame because this is a positive movie an only a silly person who is extremely negative may think its boring. maybe because I'm a softie for positive movies.... Mr. Washington what a pretty fine job on his role in this film, the whole cast was pretty neat,especially the mother in law an little Jeremiah... (love his name, BTW) Overall great film, very positive an enlightening... there was several funny lines an jokes. I was laughing quite a bit throughout this movie. great family movie. thumbs up Whitney Houston, Courtney Vince an the fab Mr. Washington!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That man is so oily, you could fry chicken on his smile.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Taking nothing away from Cary Grant and David Niven, as The Bishop's Wife is one of my favorite films - a film that I can watch over and over - this film is a worthy successor. The music is incomparable, of course. Nothing matches Whitney Houston. That alone makes the film a must see. And, Denzel Washington. What can I say, He is fantastic in everything he does, and the chance to see him play an angel is a real treat. It reminds me of Devil in the Blue Dress or The Mighty Quinn . Those two films showed a different side to Denzel and this film is in that vein. With Courtney B. Vance, Gregory Hines, Loretta Devine, Lionel Richie,and Whitney's mother Cissy Houston, this was an enjoyable film about faith and hope and love, with magnificent singing by Whitney.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a Wonderful Bishop's Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zunitrail-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this when it was in the theaters. I basically loved it mainly for its music and Jennifer Lewis' (Julia's mother) performance, but also I loved the opening and closing (climax) scenes. I'm basically a sucker for that kind of thing, and I understand how other people wouldn't find it interesting. I just saw the movie (The Bishop's Wife) which it was based on and finally feel qualified to comment. TPW was not just a remake of TBW, but more of a combination of TBW and "It's a Wonderful Life." Henry in TPW was the character of Jimmy Stewart in IWL, always caring for the underdog (altho very cynical to the angel's angelhood); Joe Hamilton in TPW was "Mr Potter" of the same, with his schemes to redevelop and control the town. I actually found it charming the way elements of TBW found themselves woven into TPW: the ice skating scene, the typewriter-turned-PC, the final sermon, to name a few. But I did realize that the message had been diluted into a feel-good comedy. There are no moments where one feels deeply moved merely by dialogue, such as TBW's Dudley's story of David and the Lion, which captivates the Bishop's entire household, down to the all-business secretary (not to mention the audience!). In TPW, we are made to be moved by the beautiful music; and as such, I guess we might as well just buy the soundtrack. TBW reminded me that special effects are only as good as the movie itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I loved it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carolynspringmorrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very long time ago I happened on "The Bishop's Wife" and really liked it, but it wasn't a Christmas classic and I never saw it again. So when I realized there was a "re-make" I was excited. I liked this story even better! I thought Whitney Houston was terrific and the rest of the characters (especially her mother) were also very enjoyable. Sometimes I just need a break from the mayhem and violence and this is a sweet, uplifting, old-fashioned Christmas pleasure I try to watch every year. If you like Denzel, if you like Lionel Ritchie, if you like Gregory Hines, and especially if you like gospel music, please give this movie a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful Romantic Entertaining Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a rule I don't tend to warm to remakes of classic films however the Penny Marshall directed Christmas story "The Preacher's Wife", is a definite exception and has become one of my favourite festive season viewing experiences. Based on the classic Samuel Goldwyn film "The Bishop's Wife", which starred legends Cary Grant, Loretta Young and David Niven, this 1996 effort has a charm and slant on the essentially same story all its own. Denzel Washington in the role of an angel sent down to earth to sort out the life of a preacher who has lost sight of what really is important, is a most worthy successor to Cary Grant in the original film and Whitney Houston in the female lead displays a warm screen presence and great musical talent that couldn't be bettered in this type of story. Amazingly I only saw this film for the first time 3 years ago but it has become a firm favourite of mine ever since. Combining a traditional and much loved Christmas tale with some truly wonderful gospel singing gives this effort a really upbeat feel which however never sacrifices for one minute the more touching aspects of the story. A truly inspirational and touching story filled with some beautiful music and comic pieces is the best way to describe this beautiful little movie. I love all three lead performances here and it's a joy to see Denzel Washington, normally the star of some intensely dramatic films, in such a charming and light hearted role as Dudley. He displays a fine comic talent and teams especially well with the other two leads. If ever there was a proper successor to Cary Grant in this role then Denzel Washington is it. Whitney Houston does very well in the role of Julia and she displays a nicely touching persona especially in her scenes with her screen son. She of course comes alive in the musical numbers many of which she produced herself. I've become a big fan of gospel music after her terrific rendition of such numbers as,"Step by Step", and especially the show stopping "I believe in you and me". Courtney Vance playing the earlier David Niven role of Henry is also excellent and his performance contains a lot of the dramatic meat of the story as the essentially kind hearted preacher who is torn too many ways and sees himself loosing his family. His work with Denzel Washington in particular is note worthy especially in the scenes when he can't seem to understand just "where", this mysterious helper has suddenly come from. Other standouts in the cast are Loretta Devine as Julia's mother in a very funny performance full of great lines and wry observations about what is happening in the Biggs household, and Gregory Hines as sharp business man Joe Hamilton who in turn is also affected by Dudley's presence in his previously rather shallow life. The look and feel of "The Preacher's Wife", makes it a wonderful newer Christmas viewing experience and much of the credit goes to the church scenes with the St. Matthew's choir taking centre stage. Their singing and expert handling of all the gospel music is perfect and really gets you into the feel of the season. As a "modern", Christmas story I personally feel "The Preacher's Wife", is a most worthy successor to the well known and greatly loved earlier classics like "White Christmas", and "Miracle on 34th Street". Taking a very different slant on the story than the earlier 'The Bishop's Wife", it manages to be wholly original in its own way and makes delightful seasonal viewing. Try and see this touching film next Christmas and I'm sure it will become a treasured part of your holiday viewing like it is in my home. danceability-1, Amsterdam Holland
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good, enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is no reason to be hard on this film. An overall rating of 5.2 is very low, in my opinion, and there is little to dislike about "The Preacher's Wife." It's a fairly simple story involving Dudley (Denzel Washington), an angel sent to earth to assist a pastor's marriage during Christmas time. One reason I liked this film is because few romantic comedies in recent years have been clean enough to watch with the entire family. There is almost nothing objectionable here, just a few brief, very mild swear words that have no bearing on the film. It's a decently funny film as well. I had to laugh at Dudley finding an image of a Windows computer screen in his angel handbook. The wisecracking grandmother was also a beneficial addition to the movie. Take her comment "We're gonna play Monopoly, with real money." There are still a few things that could have been improved on. The plot twist involving Dudley falling in love with Whitney Houston could have been played up more and was not nearly as funny as it had the potential to be. Also, the chemistry between the main couple is not super good, and the film lacks the romance necessary to make this a great rom-com. Nevertheless, it's enjoyable and doesn't deserve any harsh comments. Note: Because of the abundance of Christmas-related content, it's best to watch this around Christmas time, or you may feel slightly embarrassed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Liked It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olivia porazzi
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I am one of the few people on this message board that actually liked this movie. I thought it was great. It was a charming story about the power of miracles and the fact that angels do really exist. (Of course, we wish they all looked like Denzel Washington, but they do exist!) This is my favorite type of a story because so many people these days forget about the miracles every day. I mean, here comes Dudley, an angel, from heaven sent to help out a family that was about to come apart. Maybe some people don't believe that is possible, but I certainly do. The performances were amazing and we get to hear Whitney Houston's beautiful voice. Give this movie a shot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cg-cgeorge
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a wonderful piece of work that should not be compared with any other in the genre of the Christmas/angel type or the so often mentioned Bishop's Wife. Its not the first film to use an old story and alter it and should be looked at as an original piece of work which is what it is. It simply works well mainly because it is perfectly cast, any romantic will be drawn in, willing the beautiful people in this case Whitney Houston and Dezel Washington together. Washington is pure magic on the screen, playing the inoffensive angel who ignores the ignorance and rudeness thrown at him by thoughtless people who should know better, he pulls off some great moments in the story. Unusually too the children are well cast, not too sugary or given scene stealing lines, they complement the adults rather than displace or ridicule them. This is a specialist type of film, a romantic, unrealistic dreamy story, and must be judged in that light.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Angel's don't have sex on their mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    emdragon
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a weak remake of the Bishop's Wife, a wonderful film from the 40s with Cary Grant, Loretta Young, and David Niven creating the characters as they were really meant to be from the novel by Robert Nathan. There were some aspects of this movie that I liked. The children were uniformly good. The camera work and street scenes were well orchestrated. The singing was a joy. But the script has Denzel Washington basically lusting after Whitney Houston, which is not supposed to be what the movie is about. In one scene Dudley (Denzel) and Julia (Whitney Houston) are gazing into a store shop window. He is telling her in a tone that is obviously sexually oriented. . . that if she wears a certain negligee her husband would'nt want more of a present than that. But it is he that is practically drooling. C'mon, he is supposed to be an angel!? Everything that was sweet and wonderful about the original film is missing from this one. I have usually liked Penny Marshall movies in the past, but this one misses the boat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davegering
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me state up front that I am a fan of both Denzel Washington and Whitney Houston. I am not, however, a fan of this movie. The script is a complete mess; this movie doesn't know what it wants to be or wants to do. None of the leads is particularly credible in his or her roles. The story is not funny enough to be a comedy, nor compelling enough to be a drama. Another problem, and a big one, is the constant lead-ins to Whitney Houston musical numbers that don't really fit the story. I didn't find this movie very entertaining, and frankly, there were a couple of times I surfed away looking for something better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what a positive movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    erykah8402
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    how can anyone say this movie is boring?? I recently saw this on a few reviews... what a shame because this is a positive movie an only a silly person who is extremely negative may think its boring. maybe because I'm a softie for positive movies.... Mr. Washington what a pretty fine job on his role in this film, the whole cast was pretty neat,especially the mother in law an little Jeremiah... (love his name, BTW) Overall great film, very positive an enlightening... there was several funny lines an jokes. I was laughing quite a bit throughout this movie. great family movie. thumbs up Whitney Houston, Courtney Vince an the fab Mr. Washington!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That man is so oily, you could fry chicken on his smile.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Taking nothing away from Cary Grant and David Niven, as The Bishop's Wife is one of my favorite films - a film that I can watch over and over - this film is a worthy successor. The music is incomparable, of course. Nothing matches Whitney Houston. That alone makes the film a must see. And, Denzel Washington. What can I say, He is fantastic in everything he does, and the chance to see him play an angel is a real treat. It reminds me of Devil in the Blue Dress or The Mighty Quinn . Those two films showed a different side to Denzel and this film is in that vein. With Courtney B. Vance, Gregory Hines, Loretta Devine, Lionel Richie,and Whitney's mother Cissy Houston, this was an enjoyable film about faith and hope and love, with magnificent singing by Whitney.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a Wonderful Bishop's Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zunitrail-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this when it was in the theaters. I basically loved it mainly for its music and Jennifer Lewis' (Julia's mother) performance, but also I loved the opening and closing (climax) scenes. I'm basically a sucker for that kind of thing, and I understand how other people wouldn't find it interesting. I just saw the movie (The Bishop's Wife) which it was based on and finally feel qualified to comment. TPW was not just a remake of TBW, but more of a combination of TBW and "It's a Wonderful Life." Henry in TPW was the character of Jimmy Stewart in IWL, always caring for the underdog (altho very cynical to the angel's angelhood); Joe Hamilton in TPW was "Mr Potter" of the same, with his schemes to redevelop and control the town. I actually found it charming the way elements of TBW found themselves woven into TPW: the ice skating scene, the typewriter-turned-PC, the final sermon, to name a few. But I did realize that the message had been diluted into a feel-good comedy. There are no moments where one feels deeply moved merely by dialogue, such as TBW's Dudley's story of David and the Lion, which captivates the Bishop's entire household, down to the all-business secretary (not to mention the audience!). In TPW, we are made to be moved by the beautiful music; and as such, I guess we might as well just buy the soundtrack. TBW reminded me that special effects are only as good as the movie itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I loved it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carolynspringmorrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very long time ago I happened on "The Bishop's Wife" and really liked it, but it wasn't a Christmas classic and I never saw it again. So when I realized there was a "re-make" I was excited. I liked this story even better! I thought Whitney Houston was terrific and the rest of the characters (especially her mother) were also very enjoyable. Sometimes I just need a break from the mayhem and violence and this is a sweet, uplifting, old-fashioned Christmas pleasure I try to watch every year. If you like Denzel, if you like Lionel Ritchie, if you like Gregory Hines, and especially if you like gospel music, please give this movie a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful Romantic Entertaining Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a rule I don't tend to warm to remakes of classic films however the Penny Marshall directed Christmas story "The Preacher's Wife", is a definite exception and has become one of my favourite festive season viewing experiences. Based on the classic Samuel Goldwyn film "The Bishop's Wife", which starred legends Cary Grant, Loretta Young and David Niven, this 1996 effort has a charm and slant on the essentially same story all its own. Denzel Washington in the role of an angel sent down to earth to sort out the life of a preacher who has lost sight of what really is important, is a most worthy successor to Cary Grant in the original film and Whitney Houston in the female lead displays a warm screen presence and great musical talent that couldn't be bettered in this type of story. Amazingly I only saw this film for the first time 3 years ago but it has become a firm favourite of mine ever since. Combining a traditional and much loved Christmas tale with some truly wonderful gospel singing gives this effort a really upbeat feel which however never sacrifices for one minute the more touching aspects of the story. A truly inspirational and touching story filled with some beautiful music and comic pieces is the best way to describe this beautiful little movie. I love all three lead performances here and it's a joy to see Denzel Washington, normally the star of some intensely dramatic films, in such a charming and light hearted role as Dudley. He displays a fine comic talent and teams especially well with the other two leads. If ever there was a proper successor to Cary Grant in this role then Denzel Washington is it. Whitney Houston does very well in the role of Julia and she displays a nicely touching persona especially in her scenes with her screen son. She of course comes alive in the musical numbers many of which she produced herself. I've become a big fan of gospel music after her terrific rendition of such numbers as,"Step by Step", and especially the show stopping "I believe in you and me". Courtney Vance playing the earlier David Niven role of Henry is also excellent and his performance contains a lot of the dramatic meat of the story as the essentially kind hearted preacher who is torn too many ways and sees himself loosing his family. His work with Denzel Washington in particular is note worthy especially in the scenes when he can't seem to understand just "where", this mysterious helper has suddenly come from. Other standouts in the cast are Loretta Devine as Julia's mother in a very funny performance full of great lines and wry observations about what is happening in the Biggs household, and Gregory Hines as sharp business man Joe Hamilton who in turn is also affected by Dudley's presence in his previously rather shallow life. The look and feel of "The Preacher's Wife", makes it a wonderful newer Christmas viewing experience and much of the credit goes to the church scenes with the St. Matthew's choir taking centre stage. Their singing and expert handling of all the gospel music is perfect and really gets you into the feel of the season. As a "modern", Christmas story I personally feel "The Preacher's Wife", is a most worthy successor to the well known and greatly loved earlier classics like "White Christmas", and "Miracle on 34th Street". Taking a very different slant on the story than the earlier 'The Bishop's Wife", it manages to be wholly original in its own way and makes delightful seasonal viewing. Try and see this touching film next Christmas and I'm sure it will become a treasured part of your holiday viewing like it is in my home. danceability-1, Amsterdam Holland
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good, enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is no reason to be hard on this film. An overall rating of 5.2 is very low, in my opinion, and there is little to dislike about "The Preacher's Wife." It's a fairly simple story involving Dudley (Denzel Washington), an angel sent to earth to assist a pastor's marriage during Christmas time. One reason I liked this film is because few romantic comedies in recent years have been clean enough to watch with the entire family. There is almost nothing objectionable here, just a few brief, very mild swear words that have no bearing on the film. It's a decently funny film as well. I had to laugh at Dudley finding an image of a Windows computer screen in his angel handbook. The wisecracking grandmother was also a beneficial addition to the movie. Take her comment "We're gonna play Monopoly, with real money." There are still a few things that could have been improved on. The plot twist involving Dudley falling in love with Whitney Houston could have been played up more and was not nearly as funny as it had the potential to be. Also, the chemistry between the main couple is not super good, and the film lacks the romance necessary to make this a great rom-com. Nevertheless, it's enjoyable and doesn't deserve any harsh comments. Note: Because of the abundance of Christmas-related content, it's best to watch this around Christmas time, or you may feel slightly embarrassed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Liked It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olivia porazzi
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I am one of the few people on this message board that actually liked this movie. I thought it was great. It was a charming story about the power of miracles and the fact that angels do really exist. (Of course, we wish they all looked like Denzel Washington, but they do exist!) This is my favorite type of a story because so many people these days forget about the miracles every day. I mean, here comes Dudley, an angel, from heaven sent to help out a family that was about to come apart. Maybe some people don't believe that is possible, but I certainly do. The performances were amazing and we get to hear Whitney Houston's beautiful voice. Give this movie a shot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cg-cgeorge
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a wonderful piece of work that should not be compared with any other in the genre of the Christmas/angel type or the so often mentioned Bishop's Wife. Its not the first film to use an old story and alter it and should be looked at as an original piece of work which is what it is. It simply works well mainly because it is perfectly cast, any romantic will be drawn in, willing the beautiful people in this case Whitney Houston and Dezel Washington together. Washington is pure magic on the screen, playing the inoffensive angel who ignores the ignorance and rudeness thrown at him by thoughtless people who should know better, he pulls off some great moments in the story. Unusually too the children are well cast, not too sugary or given scene stealing lines, they complement the adults rather than displace or ridicule them. This is a specialist type of film, a romantic, unrealistic dreamy story, and must be judged in that light.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Angel's don't have sex on their mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    emdragon
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a weak remake of the Bishop's Wife, a wonderful film from the 40s with Cary Grant, Loretta Young, and David Niven creating the characters as they were really meant to be from the novel by Robert Nathan. There were some aspects of this movie that I liked. The children were uniformly good. The camera work and street scenes were well orchestrated. The singing was a joy. But the script has Denzel Washington basically lusting after Whitney Houston, which is not supposed to be what the movie is about. In one scene Dudley (Denzel) and Julia (Whitney Houston) are gazing into a store shop window. He is telling her in a tone that is obviously sexually oriented. . . that if she wears a certain negligee her husband would'nt want more of a present than that. But it is he that is practically drooling. C'mon, he is supposed to be an angel!? Everything that was sweet and wonderful about the original film is missing from this one. I have usually liked Penny Marshall movies in the past, but this one misses the boat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davegering
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me state up front that I am a fan of both Denzel Washington and Whitney Houston. I am not, however, a fan of this movie. The script is a complete mess; this movie doesn't know what it wants to be or wants to do. None of the leads is particularly credible in his or her roles. The story is not funny enough to be a comedy, nor compelling enough to be a drama. Another problem, and a big one, is the constant lead-ins to Whitney Houston musical numbers that don't really fit the story. I didn't find this movie very entertaining, and frankly, there were a couple of times I surfed away looking for something better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what a positive movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    erykah8402
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    how can anyone say this movie is boring?? I recently saw this on a few reviews... what a shame because this is a positive movie an only a silly person who is extremely negative may think its boring. maybe because I'm a softie for positive movies.... Mr. Washington what a pretty fine job on his role in this film, the whole cast was pretty neat,especially the mother in law an little Jeremiah... (love his name, BTW) Overall great film, very positive an enlightening... there was several funny lines an jokes. I was laughing quite a bit throughout this movie. great family movie. thumbs up Whitney Houston, Courtney Vince an the fab Mr. Washington!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That man is so oily, you could fry chicken on his smile.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Taking nothing away from Cary Grant and David Niven, as The Bishop's Wife is one of my favorite films - a film that I can watch over and over - this film is a worthy successor. The music is incomparable, of course. Nothing matches Whitney Houston. That alone makes the film a must see. And, Denzel Washington. What can I say, He is fantastic in everything he does, and the chance to see him play an angel is a real treat. It reminds me of Devil in the Blue Dress or The Mighty Quinn . Those two films showed a different side to Denzel and this film is in that vein. With Courtney B. Vance, Gregory Hines, Loretta Devine, Lionel Richie,and Whitney's mother Cissy Houston, this was an enjoyable film about faith and hope and love, with magnificent singing by Whitney.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a Wonderful Bishop's Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zunitrail-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this when it was in the theaters. I basically loved it mainly for its music and Jennifer Lewis' (Julia's mother) performance, but also I loved the opening and closing (climax) scenes. I'm basically a sucker for that kind of thing, and I understand how other people wouldn't find it interesting. I just saw the movie (The Bishop's Wife) which it was based on and finally feel qualified to comment. TPW was not just a remake of TBW, but more of a combination of TBW and "It's a Wonderful Life." Henry in TPW was the character of Jimmy Stewart in IWL, always caring for the underdog (altho very cynical to the angel's angelhood); Joe Hamilton in TPW was "Mr Potter" of the same, with his schemes to redevelop and control the town. I actually found it charming the way elements of TBW found themselves woven into TPW: the ice skating scene, the typewriter-turned-PC, the final sermon, to name a few. But I did realize that the message had been diluted into a feel-good comedy. There are no moments where one feels deeply moved merely by dialogue, such as TBW's Dudley's story of David and the Lion, which captivates the Bishop's entire household, down to the all-business secretary (not to mention the audience!). In TPW, we are made to be moved by the beautiful music; and as such, I guess we might as well just buy the soundtrack. TBW reminded me that special effects are only as good as the movie itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I loved it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carolynspringmorrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very long time ago I happened on "The Bishop's Wife" and really liked it, but it wasn't a Christmas classic and I never saw it again. So when I realized there was a "re-make" I was excited. I liked this story even better! I thought Whitney Houston was terrific and the rest of the characters (especially her mother) were also very enjoyable. Sometimes I just need a break from the mayhem and violence and this is a sweet, uplifting, old-fashioned Christmas pleasure I try to watch every year. If you like Denzel, if you like Lionel Ritchie, if you like Gregory Hines, and especially if you like gospel music, please give this movie a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful Romantic Entertaining Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a rule I don't tend to warm to remakes of classic films however the Penny Marshall directed Christmas story "The Preacher's Wife", is a definite exception and has become one of my favourite festive season viewing experiences. Based on the classic Samuel Goldwyn film "The Bishop's Wife", which starred legends Cary Grant, Loretta Young and David Niven, this 1996 effort has a charm and slant on the essentially same story all its own. Denzel Washington in the role of an angel sent down to earth to sort out the life of a preacher who has lost sight of what really is important, is a most worthy successor to Cary Grant in the original film and Whitney Houston in the female lead displays a warm screen presence and great musical talent that couldn't be bettered in this type of story. Amazingly I only saw this film for the first time 3 years ago but it has become a firm favourite of mine ever since. Combining a traditional and much loved Christmas tale with some truly wonderful gospel singing gives this effort a really upbeat feel which however never sacrifices for one minute the more touching aspects of the story. A truly inspirational and touching story filled with some beautiful music and comic pieces is the best way to describe this beautiful little movie. I love all three lead performances here and it's a joy to see Denzel Washington, normally the star of some intensely dramatic films, in such a charming and light hearted role as Dudley. He displays a fine comic talent and teams especially well with the other two leads. If ever there was a proper successor to Cary Grant in this role then Denzel Washington is it. Whitney Houston does very well in the role of Julia and she displays a nicely touching persona especially in her scenes with her screen son. She of course comes alive in the musical numbers many of which she produced herself. I've become a big fan of gospel music after her terrific rendition of such numbers as,"Step by Step", and especially the show stopping "I believe in you and me". Courtney Vance playing the earlier David Niven role of Henry is also excellent and his performance contains a lot of the dramatic meat of the story as the essentially kind hearted preacher who is torn too many ways and sees himself loosing his family. His work with Denzel Washington in particular is note worthy especially in the scenes when he can't seem to understand just "where", this mysterious helper has suddenly come from. Other standouts in the cast are Loretta Devine as Julia's mother in a very funny performance full of great lines and wry observations about what is happening in the Biggs household, and Gregory Hines as sharp business man Joe Hamilton who in turn is also affected by Dudley's presence in his previously rather shallow life. The look and feel of "The Preacher's Wife", makes it a wonderful newer Christmas viewing experience and much of the credit goes to the church scenes with the St. Matthew's choir taking centre stage. Their singing and expert handling of all the gospel music is perfect and really gets you into the feel of the season. As a "modern", Christmas story I personally feel "The Preacher's Wife", is a most worthy successor to the well known and greatly loved earlier classics like "White Christmas", and "Miracle on 34th Street". Taking a very different slant on the story than the earlier 'The Bishop's Wife", it manages to be wholly original in its own way and makes delightful seasonal viewing. Try and see this touching film next Christmas and I'm sure it will become a treasured part of your holiday viewing like it is in my home. danceability-1, Amsterdam Holland
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good, enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is no reason to be hard on this film. An overall rating of 5.2 is very low, in my opinion, and there is little to dislike about "The Preacher's Wife." It's a fairly simple story involving Dudley (Denzel Washington), an angel sent to earth to assist a pastor's marriage during Christmas time. One reason I liked this film is because few romantic comedies in recent years have been clean enough to watch with the entire family. There is almost nothing objectionable here, just a few brief, very mild swear words that have no bearing on the film. It's a decently funny film as well. I had to laugh at Dudley finding an image of a Windows computer screen in his angel handbook. The wisecracking grandmother was also a beneficial addition to the movie. Take her comment "We're gonna play Monopoly, with real money." There are still a few things that could have been improved on. The plot twist involving Dudley falling in love with Whitney Houston could have been played up more and was not nearly as funny as it had the potential to be. Also, the chemistry between the main couple is not super good, and the film lacks the romance necessary to make this a great rom-com. Nevertheless, it's enjoyable and doesn't deserve any harsh comments. Note: Because of the abundance of Christmas-related content, it's best to watch this around Christmas time, or you may feel slightly embarrassed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Liked It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olivia porazzi
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I am one of the few people on this message board that actually liked this movie. I thought it was great. It was a charming story about the power of miracles and the fact that angels do really exist. (Of course, we wish they all looked like Denzel Washington, but they do exist!) This is my favorite type of a story because so many people these days forget about the miracles every day. I mean, here comes Dudley, an angel, from heaven sent to help out a family that was about to come apart. Maybe some people don't believe that is possible, but I certainly do. The performances were amazing and we get to hear Whitney Houston's beautiful voice. Give this movie a shot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cg-cgeorge
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a wonderful piece of work that should not be compared with any other in the genre of the Christmas/angel type or the so often mentioned Bishop's Wife. Its not the first film to use an old story and alter it and should be looked at as an original piece of work which is what it is. It simply works well mainly because it is perfectly cast, any romantic will be drawn in, willing the beautiful people in this case Whitney Houston and Dezel Washington together. Washington is pure magic on the screen, playing the inoffensive angel who ignores the ignorance and rudeness thrown at him by thoughtless people who should know better, he pulls off some great moments in the story. Unusually too the children are well cast, not too sugary or given scene stealing lines, they complement the adults rather than displace or ridicule them. This is a specialist type of film, a romantic, unrealistic dreamy story, and must be judged in that light.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Angel's don't have sex on their mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    emdragon
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a weak remake of the Bishop's Wife, a wonderful film from the 40s with Cary Grant, Loretta Young, and David Niven creating the characters as they were really meant to be from the novel by Robert Nathan. There were some aspects of this movie that I liked. The children were uniformly good. The camera work and street scenes were well orchestrated. The singing was a joy. But the script has Denzel Washington basically lusting after Whitney Houston, which is not supposed to be what the movie is about. In one scene Dudley (Denzel) and Julia (Whitney Houston) are gazing into a store shop window. He is telling her in a tone that is obviously sexually oriented. . . that if she wears a certain negligee her husband would'nt want more of a present than that. But it is he that is practically drooling. C'mon, he is supposed to be an angel!? Everything that was sweet and wonderful about the original film is missing from this one. I have usually liked Penny Marshall movies in the past, but this one misses the boat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davegering
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me state up front that I am a fan of both Denzel Washington and Whitney Houston. I am not, however, a fan of this movie. The script is a complete mess; this movie doesn't know what it wants to be or wants to do. None of the leads is particularly credible in his or her roles. The story is not funny enough to be a comedy, nor compelling enough to be a drama. Another problem, and a big one, is the constant lead-ins to Whitney Houston musical numbers that don't really fit the story. I didn't find this movie very entertaining, and frankly, there were a couple of times I surfed away looking for something better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what a positive movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    erykah8402
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    how can anyone say this movie is boring?? I recently saw this on a few reviews... what a shame because this is a positive movie an only a silly person who is extremely negative may think its boring. maybe because I'm a softie for positive movies.... Mr. Washington what a pretty fine job on his role in this film, the whole cast was pretty neat,especially the mother in law an little Jeremiah... (love his name, BTW) Overall great film, very positive an enlightening... there was several funny lines an jokes. I was laughing quite a bit throughout this movie. great family movie. thumbs up Whitney Houston, Courtney Vince an the fab Mr. Washington!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That man is so oily, you could fry chicken on his smile.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Taking nothing away from Cary Grant and David Niven, as The Bishop's Wife is one of my favorite films - a film that I can watch over and over - this film is a worthy successor. The music is incomparable, of course. Nothing matches Whitney Houston. That alone makes the film a must see. And, Denzel Washington. What can I say, He is fantastic in everything he does, and the chance to see him play an angel is a real treat. It reminds me of Devil in the Blue Dress or The Mighty Quinn . Those two films showed a different side to Denzel and this film is in that vein. With Courtney B. Vance, Gregory Hines, Loretta Devine, Lionel Richie,and Whitney's mother Cissy Houston, this was an enjoyable film about faith and hope and love, with magnificent singing by Whitney.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a Wonderful Bishop's Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zunitrail-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this when it was in the theaters. I basically loved it mainly for its music and Jennifer Lewis' (Julia's mother) performance, but also I loved the opening and closing (climax) scenes. I'm basically a sucker for that kind of thing, and I understand how other people wouldn't find it interesting. I just saw the movie (The Bishop's Wife) which it was based on and finally feel qualified to comment. TPW was not just a remake of TBW, but more of a combination of TBW and "It's a Wonderful Life." Henry in TPW was the character of Jimmy Stewart in IWL, always caring for the underdog (altho very cynical to the angel's angelhood); Joe Hamilton in TPW was "Mr Potter" of the same, with his schemes to redevelop and control the town. I actually found it charming the way elements of TBW found themselves woven into TPW: the ice skating scene, the typewriter-turned-PC, the final sermon, to name a few. But I did realize that the message had been diluted into a feel-good comedy. There are no moments where one feels deeply moved merely by dialogue, such as TBW's Dudley's story of David and the Lion, which captivates the Bishop's entire household, down to the all-business secretary (not to mention the audience!). In TPW, we are made to be moved by the beautiful music; and as such, I guess we might as well just buy the soundtrack. TBW reminded me that special effects are only as good as the movie itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I loved it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carolynspringmorrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very long time ago I happened on "The Bishop's Wife" and really liked it, but it wasn't a Christmas classic and I never saw it again. So when I realized there was a "re-make" I was excited. I liked this story even better! I thought Whitney Houston was terrific and the rest of the characters (especially her mother) were also very enjoyable. Sometimes I just need a break from the mayhem and violence and this is a sweet, uplifting, old-fashioned Christmas pleasure I try to watch every year. If you like Denzel, if you like Lionel Ritchie, if you like Gregory Hines, and especially if you like gospel music, please give this movie a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful Romantic Entertaining Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a rule I don't tend to warm to remakes of classic films however the Penny Marshall directed Christmas story "The Preacher's Wife", is a definite exception and has become one of my favourite festive season viewing experiences. Based on the classic Samuel Goldwyn film "The Bishop's Wife", which starred legends Cary Grant, Loretta Young and David Niven, this 1996 effort has a charm and slant on the essentially same story all its own. Denzel Washington in the role of an angel sent down to earth to sort out the life of a preacher who has lost sight of what really is important, is a most worthy successor to Cary Grant in the original film and Whitney Houston in the female lead displays a warm screen presence and great musical talent that couldn't be bettered in this type of story. Amazingly I only saw this film for the first time 3 years ago but it has become a firm favourite of mine ever since. Combining a traditional and much loved Christmas tale with some truly wonderful gospel singing gives this effort a really upbeat feel which however never sacrifices for one minute the more touching aspects of the story. A truly inspirational and touching story filled with some beautiful music and comic pieces is the best way to describe this beautiful little movie. I love all three lead performances here and it's a joy to see Denzel Washington, normally the star of some intensely dramatic films, in such a charming and light hearted role as Dudley. He displays a fine comic talent and teams especially well with the other two leads. If ever there was a proper successor to Cary Grant in this role then Denzel Washington is it. Whitney Houston does very well in the role of Julia and she displays a nicely touching persona especially in her scenes with her screen son. She of course comes alive in the musical numbers many of which she produced herself. I've become a big fan of gospel music after her terrific rendition of such numbers as,"Step by Step", and especially the show stopping "I believe in you and me". Courtney Vance playing the earlier David Niven role of Henry is also excellent and his performance contains a lot of the dramatic meat of the story as the essentially kind hearted preacher who is torn too many ways and sees himself loosing his family. His work with Denzel Washington in particular is note worthy especially in the scenes when he can't seem to understand just "where", this mysterious helper has suddenly come from. Other standouts in the cast are Loretta Devine as Julia's mother in a very funny performance full of great lines and wry observations about what is happening in the Biggs household, and Gregory Hines as sharp business man Joe Hamilton who in turn is also affected by Dudley's presence in his previously rather shallow life. The look and feel of "The Preacher's Wife", makes it a wonderful newer Christmas viewing experience and much of the credit goes to the church scenes with the St. Matthew's choir taking centre stage. Their singing and expert handling of all the gospel music is perfect and really gets you into the feel of the season. As a "modern", Christmas story I personally feel "The Preacher's Wife", is a most worthy successor to the well known and greatly loved earlier classics like "White Christmas", and "Miracle on 34th Street". Taking a very different slant on the story than the earlier 'The Bishop's Wife", it manages to be wholly original in its own way and makes delightful seasonal viewing. Try and see this touching film next Christmas and I'm sure it will become a treasured part of your holiday viewing like it is in my home. danceability-1, Amsterdam Holland
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good, enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is no reason to be hard on this film. An overall rating of 5.2 is very low, in my opinion, and there is little to dislike about "The Preacher's Wife." It's a fairly simple story involving Dudley (Denzel Washington), an angel sent to earth to assist a pastor's marriage during Christmas time. One reason I liked this film is because few romantic comedies in recent years have been clean enough to watch with the entire family. There is almost nothing objectionable here, just a few brief, very mild swear words that have no bearing on the film. It's a decently funny film as well. I had to laugh at Dudley finding an image of a Windows computer screen in his angel handbook. The wisecracking grandmother was also a beneficial addition to the movie. Take her comment "We're gonna play Monopoly, with real money." There are still a few things that could have been improved on. The plot twist involving Dudley falling in love with Whitney Houston could have been played up more and was not nearly as funny as it had the potential to be. Also, the chemistry between the main couple is not super good, and the film lacks the romance necessary to make this a great rom-com. Nevertheless, it's enjoyable and doesn't deserve any harsh comments. Note: Because of the abundance of Christmas-related content, it's best to watch this around Christmas time, or you may feel slightly embarrassed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Liked It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olivia porazzi
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I am one of the few people on this message board that actually liked this movie. I thought it was great. It was a charming story about the power of miracles and the fact that angels do really exist. (Of course, we wish they all looked like Denzel Washington, but they do exist!) This is my favorite type of a story because so many people these days forget about the miracles every day. I mean, here comes Dudley, an angel, from heaven sent to help out a family that was about to come apart. Maybe some people don't believe that is possible, but I certainly do. The performances were amazing and we get to hear Whitney Houston's beautiful voice. Give this movie a shot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cg-cgeorge
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a wonderful piece of work that should not be compared with any other in the genre of the Christmas/angel type or the so often mentioned Bishop's Wife. Its not the first film to use an old story and alter it and should be looked at as an original piece of work which is what it is. It simply works well mainly because it is perfectly cast, any romantic will be drawn in, willing the beautiful people in this case Whitney Houston and Dezel Washington together. Washington is pure magic on the screen, playing the inoffensive angel who ignores the ignorance and rudeness thrown at him by thoughtless people who should know better, he pulls off some great moments in the story. Unusually too the children are well cast, not too sugary or given scene stealing lines, they complement the adults rather than displace or ridicule them. This is a specialist type of film, a romantic, unrealistic dreamy story, and must be judged in that light.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Angel's don't have sex on their mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    emdragon
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a weak remake of the Bishop's Wife, a wonderful film from the 40s with Cary Grant, Loretta Young, and David Niven creating the characters as they were really meant to be from the novel by Robert Nathan. There were some aspects of this movie that I liked. The children were uniformly good. The camera work and street scenes were well orchestrated. The singing was a joy. But the script has Denzel Washington basically lusting after Whitney Houston, which is not supposed to be what the movie is about. In one scene Dudley (Denzel) and Julia (Whitney Houston) are gazing into a store shop window. He is telling her in a tone that is obviously sexually oriented. . . that if she wears a certain negligee her husband would'nt want more of a present than that. But it is he that is practically drooling. C'mon, he is supposed to be an angel!? Everything that was sweet and wonderful about the original film is missing from this one. I have usually liked Penny Marshall movies in the past, but this one misses the boat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davegering
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me state up front that I am a fan of both Denzel Washington and Whitney Houston. I am not, however, a fan of this movie. The script is a complete mess; this movie doesn't know what it wants to be or wants to do. None of the leads is particularly credible in his or her roles. The story is not funny enough to be a comedy, nor compelling enough to be a drama. Another problem, and a big one, is the constant lead-ins to Whitney Houston musical numbers that don't really fit the story. I didn't find this movie very entertaining, and frankly, there were a couple of times I surfed away looking for something better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    what a positive movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    erykah8402
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    how can anyone say this movie is boring?? I recently saw this on a few reviews... what a shame because this is a positive movie an only a silly person who is extremely negative may think its boring. maybe because I'm a softie for positive movies.... Mr. Washington what a pretty fine job on his role in this film, the whole cast was pretty neat,especially the mother in law an little Jeremiah... (love his name, BTW) Overall great film, very positive an enlightening... there was several funny lines an jokes. I was laughing quite a bit throughout this movie. great family movie. thumbs up Whitney Houston, Courtney Vince an the fab Mr. Washington!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That man is so oily, you could fry chicken on his smile.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Taking nothing away from Cary Grant and David Niven, as The Bishop's Wife is one of my favorite films - a film that I can watch over and over - this film is a worthy successor. The music is incomparable, of course. Nothing matches Whitney Houston. That alone makes the film a must see. And, Denzel Washington. What can I say, He is fantastic in everything he does, and the chance to see him play an angel is a real treat. It reminds me of Devil in the Blue Dress or The Mighty Quinn . Those two films showed a different side to Denzel and this film is in that vein. With Courtney B. Vance, Gregory Hines, Loretta Devine, Lionel Richie,and Whitney's mother Cissy Houston, this was an enjoyable film about faith and hope and love, with magnificent singing by Whitney.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a Wonderful Bishop's Life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zunitrail-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this when it was in the theaters. I basically loved it mainly for its music and Jennifer Lewis' (Julia's mother) performance, but also I loved the opening and closing (climax) scenes. I'm basically a sucker for that kind of thing, and I understand how other people wouldn't find it interesting. I just saw the movie (The Bishop's Wife) which it was based on and finally feel qualified to comment. TPW was not just a remake of TBW, but more of a combination of TBW and "It's a Wonderful Life." Henry in TPW was the character of Jimmy Stewart in IWL, always caring for the underdog (altho very cynical to the angel's angelhood); Joe Hamilton in TPW was "Mr Potter" of the same, with his schemes to redevelop and control the town. I actually found it charming the way elements of TBW found themselves woven into TPW: the ice skating scene, the typewriter-turned-PC, the final sermon, to name a few. But I did realize that the message had been diluted into a feel-good comedy. There are no moments where one feels deeply moved merely by dialogue, such as TBW's Dudley's story of David and the Lion, which captivates the Bishop's entire household, down to the all-business secretary (not to mention the audience!). In TPW, we are made to be moved by the beautiful music; and as such, I guess we might as well just buy the soundtrack. TBW reminded me that special effects are only as good as the movie itself.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I loved it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carolynspringmorrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A very long time ago I happened on "The Bishop's Wife" and really liked it, but it wasn't a Christmas classic and I never saw it again. So when I realized there was a "re-make" I was excited. I liked this story even better! I thought Whitney Houston was terrific and the rest of the characters (especially her mother) were also very enjoyable. Sometimes I just need a break from the mayhem and violence and this is a sweet, uplifting, old-fashioned Christmas pleasure I try to watch every year. If you like Denzel, if you like Lionel Ritchie, if you like Gregory Hines, and especially if you like gospel music, please give this movie a try.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful Romantic Entertaining Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    danceability-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a rule I don't tend to warm to remakes of classic films however the Penny Marshall directed Christmas story "The Preacher's Wife", is a definite exception and has become one of my favourite festive season viewing experiences. Based on the classic Samuel Goldwyn film "The Bishop's Wife", which starred legends Cary Grant, Loretta Young and David Niven, this 1996 effort has a charm and slant on the essentially same story all its own. Denzel Washington in the role of an angel sent down to earth to sort out the life of a preacher who has lost sight of what really is important, is a most worthy successor to Cary Grant in the original film and Whitney Houston in the female lead displays a warm screen presence and great musical talent that couldn't be bettered in this type of story. Amazingly I only saw this film for the first time 3 years ago but it has become a firm favourite of mine ever since. Combining a traditional and much loved Christmas tale with some truly wonderful gospel singing gives this effort a really upbeat feel which however never sacrifices for one minute the more touching aspects of the story. A truly inspirational and touching story filled with some beautiful music and comic pieces is the best way to describe this beautiful little movie. I love all three lead performances here and it's a joy to see Denzel Washington, normally the star of some intensely dramatic films, in such a charming and light hearted role as Dudley. He displays a fine comic talent and teams especially well with the other two leads. If ever there was a proper successor to Cary Grant in this role then Denzel Washington is it. Whitney Houston does very well in the role of Julia and she displays a nicely touching persona especially in her scenes with her screen son. She of course comes alive in the musical numbers many of which she produced herself. I've become a big fan of gospel music after her terrific rendition of such numbers as,"Step by Step", and especially the show stopping "I believe in you and me". Courtney Vance playing the earlier David Niven role of Henry is also excellent and his performance contains a lot of the dramatic meat of the story as the essentially kind hearted preacher who is torn too many ways and sees himself loosing his family. His work with Denzel Washington in particular is note worthy especially in the scenes when he can't seem to understand just "where", this mysterious helper has suddenly come from. Other standouts in the cast are Loretta Devine as Julia's mother in a very funny performance full of great lines and wry observations about what is happening in the Biggs household, and Gregory Hines as sharp business man Joe Hamilton who in turn is also affected by Dudley's presence in his previously rather shallow life. The look and feel of "The Preacher's Wife", makes it a wonderful newer Christmas viewing experience and much of the credit goes to the church scenes with the St. Matthew's choir taking centre stage. Their singing and expert handling of all the gospel music is perfect and really gets you into the feel of the season. As a "modern", Christmas story I personally feel "The Preacher's Wife", is a most worthy successor to the well known and greatly loved earlier classics like "White Christmas", and "Miracle on 34th Street". Taking a very different slant on the story than the earlier 'The Bishop's Wife", it manages to be wholly original in its own way and makes delightful seasonal viewing. Try and see this touching film next Christmas and I'm sure it will become a treasured part of your holiday viewing like it is in my home. danceability-1, Amsterdam Holland
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty good, enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyle-cruse
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is no reason to be hard on this film. An overall rating of 5.2 is very low, in my opinion, and there is little to dislike about "The Preacher's Wife." It's a fairly simple story involving Dudley (Denzel Washington), an angel sent to earth to assist a pastor's marriage during Christmas time. One reason I liked this film is because few romantic comedies in recent years have been clean enough to watch with the entire family. There is almost nothing objectionable here, just a few brief, very mild swear words that have no bearing on the film. It's a decently funny film as well. I had to laugh at Dudley finding an image of a Windows computer screen in his angel handbook. The wisecracking grandmother was also a beneficial addition to the movie. Take her comment "We're gonna play Monopoly, with real money." There are still a few things that could have been improved on. The plot twist involving Dudley falling in love with Whitney Houston could have been played up more and was not nearly as funny as it had the potential to be. Also, the chemistry between the main couple is not super good, and the film lacks the romance necessary to make this a great rom-com. Nevertheless, it's enjoyable and doesn't deserve any harsh comments. Note: Because of the abundance of Christmas-related content, it's best to watch this around Christmas time, or you may feel slightly embarrassed. *** out of ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Liked It
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    olivia porazzi
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maybe I am one of the few people on this message board that actually liked this movie. I thought it was great. It was a charming story about the power of miracles and the fact that angels do really exist. (Of course, we wish they all looked like Denzel Washington, but they do exist!) This is my favorite type of a story because so many people these days forget about the miracles every day. I mean, here comes Dudley, an angel, from heaven sent to help out a family that was about to come apart. Maybe some people don't believe that is possible, but I certainly do. The performances were amazing and we get to hear Whitney Houston's beautiful voice. Give this movie a shot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic winner
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cg-cgeorge
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a wonderful piece of work that should not be compared with any other in the genre of the Christmas/angel type or the so often mentioned Bishop's Wife. Its not the first film to use an old story and alter it and should be looked at as an original piece of work which is what it is. It simply works well mainly because it is perfectly cast, any romantic will be drawn in, willing the beautiful people in this case Whitney Houston and Dezel Washington together. Washington is pure magic on the screen, playing the inoffensive angel who ignores the ignorance and rudeness thrown at him by thoughtless people who should know better, he pulls off some great moments in the story. Unusually too the children are well cast, not too sugary or given scene stealing lines, they complement the adults rather than displace or ridicule them. This is a specialist type of film, a romantic, unrealistic dreamy story, and must be judged in that light.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Angel's don't have sex on their mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    emdragon
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a weak remake of the Bishop's Wife, a wonderful film from the 40s with Cary Grant, Loretta Young, and David Niven creating the characters as they were really meant to be from the novel by Robert Nathan. There were some aspects of this movie that I liked. The children were uniformly good. The camera work and street scenes were well orchestrated. The singing was a joy. But the script has Denzel Washington basically lusting after Whitney Houston, which is not supposed to be what the movie is about. In one scene Dudley (Denzel) and Julia (Whitney Houston) are gazing into a store shop window. He is telling her in a tone that is obviously sexually oriented. . . that if she wears a certain negligee her husband would'nt want more of a present than that. But it is he that is practically drooling. C'mon, he is supposed to be an angel!? Everything that was sweet and wonderful about the original film is missing from this one. I have usually liked Penny Marshall movies in the past, but this one misses the boat.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Barely Watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davegering
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me state up front that I am a fan of both Denzel Washington and Whitney Houston. I am not, however, a fan of this movie. The script is a complete mess; this movie doesn't know what it wants to be or wants to do. None of the leads is particularly credible in his or her roles. The story is not funny enough to be a comedy, nor compelling enough to be a drama. Another problem, and a big one, is the constant lead-ins to Whitney Houston musical numbers that don't really fit the story. I didn't find this movie very entertaining, and frankly, there were a couple of times I surfed away looking for something better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
