<filme>
 <id>
  943
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110265
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Parceiros do Crime
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Zed has only just arrived in the beautiful Paris and already he's up to no good. Having just slept with a call girl, he spends a night on the town with his dangerous friends. They all ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Zed has only just arrived in the beautiful Paris and already he's up to no good. Having just slept with a call girl, he spends a night on the town with his dangerous friends. They all decide to rob a bank the following day. There's only one problem: Zed's call-girl, Zoe, just happens to work at the bank which is to be robbed!
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   call girl
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bank
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bastille day
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   heroin
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   shootout
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Roger Avary
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Roger Avary
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Eric Stoltz
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Julie Delpy
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Martin Raymond
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to make a Parisian Film in Los Angeles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a lot of Tarintino influence in it, especially as he helped director Roger Avary make it. Like From Dusk Til Dawn, Killing Zoe spends the first half of the movie setting the scene and the rest of the movie with the action. Killing Zoe is a low budget film made in Los Angeles with a few Parisian shots. This is also Avary's first movie and I think he has some talent. Zed (Eric Stolz) has been invited to Paris by an old friend, Eric (Jean-Hughes Anglade) to crack a safe in a bank. Zed is a professional, and we see this as he sets to work opening a safe, yet he is a quiet humble man who prefers to make love than to kill. He is also a man who is easily manipulated and Eric does this quite regularly in the movie. We see Zed being forced into taking drugs and having women dragged away from him because Eric doesn't particularly like them. He is also taken of a tour through a very dark side of Paris where we see drugs, sleazy women, and men screwing like animal (I use such terminology because it is only for the selfish desire of pleasure). The next day, Bastille Day, he then must participate in a daring bank robbery. Daring because everybody is hung over, or still on drugs; it is a high security bank; and it seems very little planning has gone into it. Eric is not the typical Hollywood robber. He kills at a whim and has no preferences to who he will kill. He murders a woman and a man and lets another man go free. In fact Eric seems to have a thing against women as he brutally throws Zoe (Julie Delpy) out of the room when he first meets Zed and throws another whore across the room when she tries to seduce Zed (even though he cannot understand her). He kills people on a whim and represents the worst that humanity can offer. Zoe is another character who begins as a prostitute yet does not want to think of herself as one. She needs to money to get through school and just considers the job as a little thing on the side. Yet she knows what she is, and even though she considers herself beautiful and refined, everybody else treats her as a whore. The reality of what she does hits home when she listens to three men tell a joke about a whore. Killing Zoe is a reasonable movie and good for a low budget production. Much of the movie was spoken in French which is supposed to reflect the fact that it was in France, but this didn't irritate me as it did in Stargate when everybody spoke ancient Egyptian. Still it is a good movie and worth a watch if you can handle drugs and brutal violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad kill from Quentin's mate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On my view, I do admit I was a bit disappointed. Give it a few views, I was entertained intensely. First we have Paris, one of the most beautiful cities of the world, though we don't get to see much of it in this. Granted, this is no Pulp Fiction, some of it's dialogue with it's intellectual humor, leads us to question Quentin might of got his pen a little wet here. Like Reservoir Dogs, we have a heist gone wrong, amidst a little frank and shocking violence. (Eric) Jean Hughes Anglande has invited a childhood friend over, safe cracker Zed (Stoltz) he hasn't seen in some time. They're to do over a big bank on Bastille day, where the night before they get on the p**s and H, so obviously we're in the hand of some real experts. This too becomes a shock to Zed, who's only given a day's notice, not even having time to checked the bank out. In part, as seen to the amateur display of activities by our thieves, in these ugly masks, you could silently label this as an anti drug movie. Now here's the fun angle to the title. On the day of Zed's arrival, he's sent an escort, Zoe, (Julie Delpy) who just happens to work at the same bank, they do over, where Zed caught at a pivotal moment, towards it's end, is forced to make a choice, and I did too like the way it ended. Too, Eric's drunken admittance of aids, to Zed, made sense in the way he literally shoved Zoe out of his room, after the two's little interlude. Loved the cool opening plus it's title song, where were shown numerous streets of Paris, as if from a driver's POV. I loved the end song too, with Delpy saying "Let me show you the real Paris". Also Stoltz's whacked out POV, of visible music tunes, drifting out of friend, Anglande's trumpet. Not for all Tarantino fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of 2 haves.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KILLING ZOE I liked it... but it was a film of 2 halves. The first half of the movie was just average at best. A group of people that get together to arrange a bank robbery, but most of the first 45 minutes was just them getting wasted on drugs and messing about around Paris. This part of the movie dragged on a bit. It was OK, but more could have happened. But the second half was awesome. The bank robbery. When the entered the bank, the movie really picked up the pace. Zoe is the receptionist in the bank that the group hold up...the problem is, Zoe is also a hooker that one of the robbers has fallen in love with. He didn't know she worked there. The cast was good though. Eric Stoltz, Jean-Hughes Anglade & Julie Delpy really do well. I connected with the characters these guys played. There were even some good supporting roles too. Especially Gary Kemp. Who would have known that the guy from Spandau Ballet could be a good actor. He was really good in the Krays too. There was one scene in the movie though that made me laugh. Someone gets shot and has about 200 bullets shot at him from a few guns all at the same time... yet he did not go down! He still stood there for about 30 seconds after. I am pretty sure he would have gone down a long time after that. Also, there is a brilliant comical scene with a cat. :) There was a really good raw feel to this movie that I loved... Tarantino usually has that feel with his films. I suppose this has it because he was Executive Producer. All in all this film was good. I will give it 7 out of 10. A slow first half, but a great second half and ending. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of best ways to kill 90 minutes of your life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    K V
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is exceptional. In same way Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction are. Story is well thought out, down to the point, not all characters are fleshed out (Reservoir Dogs does fleshing out much better), but they are not meant to be for reasons that become obvious once you watch the movie. Acting is superb. Casting is great. Story is believable. Ending is perhaps predictable (or I saw too many movies, perhaps both), but it is fitting. There should be lot more movies like this one. A rare gem! This movie had rating of 6.4, I gave it a 10. I don't really understand why would anybody give it less than 8. If you are not into genre, don't watch the movie, or at least don't rate it down for all the wrong reasons. I rate movies either 1 or 10 for very simple reason. All the other numbers are meaningless. I either recommend you see a movie, or advise you to stay away as when compared to other movies of its type falls too short to bother with. I neither rate, not review average movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe Since banks aren't open past 5 p.m., if you're a moonlighting bank robber, you're going to have to take time off work. Fortunately, the bandits in this bank heist were born into a life of crime. In Paris to assist his old friend Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) with a job, American safecracker Zed (Eric Stoltz) kills time with a prostitute, Zoe (Julie Delpy), whom he shares an instant rapport with. The two lovers are later reunited when a masked Zed holds up the bank where Zoe works. Compelled to protect her from the erratic Eric, who has instigated a gunfight with Paris' finest, Zed puts his lifelong friendship with Eric as well as his own life on the line. Truly a hidden heist gem, Killing Zoe is an innovative and intriguing investment that gains greater interest with each viewing. However, robbing banks is now futile since no one has any money. (Green Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i was expecting so much more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    i_love_chaos
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    with this film being directed by Roger Avery and Quentin Tarantino doing the screenplay i was sure this was going to be a gem. i was wrong. i don't hate this film but in no ways do i like it. i love Roger Avery because of his amazing direction in rules of attraction and his screenplays to pulp fiction and silent hill but he made a mistake making this. do i really need to comment on Tarantino, we all know hes a genius. this movie is just set around a gang robbing a bank but fails due to silly people participating in the robbery i'm disappointed in Tarantino and Avery for doing this film but doesn't change my mind on how amazing they both are. everyone makes mistakes......... 3/10...........j.d Seaton
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drugs & bullets....that's all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kshitij (axile007)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe revolves around Zed who was invited to Paris to contribute in a bank robbery.Unfortunately that's all the story plot contains. Rest is all about unnecessary violence which really don't make any sense. There's been also some scenes of drugs depiction and consumption.Also there is no twist in storyline,weak plot and very predictable. The only strong link of the movie is the presence of Julie Delphy who looked extremely charming. Its obvious to expect more from this movie but it do not stands anywhere around its expectations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid exploitation art-house thriller, though not without flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonymurphylee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eric Stoltz plays a man named Zed who travels to Paris in order to catch up with a childhood friend named Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) and help him rob a Federal Reserve bank. Upon his arrival, he sleeps with a call girl named Zoe (Julie Delpy) who he ends up falling in love with. When Zed goes to meet Eric, he ends up spending the night with him and all of his junkie friends who hide out in a run down apartment building with a dead feline near the entrance to their room. They plan to rob the bank the next morning, and Zed is going to be the safe cracker. After much passing out, puking, hallucinating, and a male rape, Zed and the rest of the gang awaken in a drunken daze, already late for their robbery, and then they foolishly attempt to rob the bank while still moderately trashed, hungover, and restless. Naturally things go very wrong very fast, and it becomes no longer about getting the money, but more about trying to survive. If Roger Avary's intention was to make a truly memorable art house exploitation film, he succeeded with flying colors. I'm pretty sure that this was intention and there's no denying that this is a good film. I have some serious problems with Killing Zoe, however, and those problems have much to do with the first two thirds of the picture. Avary spends a very large portion of the film in this junkie world with these truly atrocious and ugly characters doing ugly things. I felt that too much time was spent in this world. The only likable character is Julie Delpy's character, and she doesn't get nearly enough screen time as she should. As for Eric Stoltz, he pretty much plays the same character as he played in Pulp Fiction, though not anywhere near as much as a prick. His character, Zed, for the most part is a fairly goofy, eccentric, and slight perverted guy. I liked how he wasn't an entirely sympathetic protagonist. His character, for the most part, works. Likewise for his friend Eric, who is a completely horrific villain. He's disgusting, sleazy, skeletal-looking, and a sweaty mess of a man who has little conscience and no morals, and I applaud Jean-Hugues Anglade for playing a role that few actors would have the balls to play. This brings me to my biggest gripe with the film, however. These are the three main characters, but they are also the three most interesting characters as well. Every other character is completely disposable they take up far too much screen time that should have been devoted to the three main characters. To make matters worse, in the third act of the film when the characters actually try to rob the bank, a good portion of all of these characters are killed off almost immediately. While I applaud Roger Avary for crafting such a strong vision of graphic carnage in the third act, I felt that he was betraying the trash quality that took place in the first two acts with these junkie characters getting slaughtered so damn quickly. As the last act of the film stands, most of the characters end up getting killed off almost constantly and with little to no emotion. When it is not a member of the gang getting killed it is either a security guard or an innocent civilian. Somebody is almost always getting killed, often in over-the-top fashion. What I did love about Killing Zoe was the look of the film. The bank that the film takes place in during the final act is just gorgeous in how claustrophobic it is. The walls of the bank are red, and it only adds to the psychotic nature of the Eric character. The character really is quite terrifying, and the bank that Avary shot in has a perfect interior for these sort of characters. The middle section mostly takes place in real grimy, dirty, dark areas that look completely hellish. Somehow the bank looks like a scarier location than the junkie hideouts, and I liked that. The opening and closing scenes show some beautiful shots of Paris as well, which definitely helped elevate the film even more. I also felt that the final act of the film, despite the gratuitous bloodshed and carnage, really was quite suspenseful and intense. The film is so furious in it's tone and the final act really pulls it all together. At times it is difficult to watch because the audience knows right away that the situation is going to go wrong and the characters are doomed. When the bank robbery actually starts, it is so disorganized and so uncoordinated that a feeling of unhinged maniacal danger sets in immediately. It makes the film a little bit different from other heist films. The characters are all young, hapless, and careless people who have abandoned reality. Killing Zoe lacks a sense of control, which both helps and hurts the film. On one hand, it certainly helps make the final act of the film that much more shocking and realistic. On the other hand, it is difficult to look part the first two thirds of the film. I do think that this film has an audience, but I also think that it's difficult to call it a good film. It works in a lot of ways. Visually, it's better than it needs to be. The performances are all very strong, not to mention ballsy, and the vision of hell this film paints is pretty tough to shake. It's a rough film, but it manages to have a lot of energy. It is a very flawed film. However, if you're a fan of trash cinema and exploitation, you may want to give this a try. It's a messy film, but it's effective and definitely memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloody and entertaining, sometimes both but never uninteresting or un-engaging.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is an energy behind Killing Zoe, there is a passion and a commitment from its director behind Killing Zoe and that is to make a fast, furious and bloody film that entertains as well as shocks in equal measure. Given the situation regarding this film's production, the film comes across upon reading the pre-production stage as a bit of an accident. Whilst scouting for locations for Reservoir Dogs, director Roger Avary would discover a place where a 'perfect' heist film could take place. Since the whole gimmick (in the nicest possible way) for Reservoir Dogs is that it's a heist film without the heist, the bank couldn't really be used but it suited Avary's other script he had going and that was Killing Zoe. An interesting back-story to a film that is never anything but interesting, apart from perhaps being entertaining at certain points. For Reservoir Dogs to take a mere two years before it itself would become a victim of a pastiche is testament to Reservoir Dog's influential power as well as Avary's own passion and drive behind this production. Notice how the script supposedly took a week to write, also. The film revolves predominantly around a heist going on in a French bank in which master safecracker Zed (Stoltz) is working with an old French buddy who also just happens to be a heroin addict and a psychopathic criminal, amongst other things. He is Eric (Anglade) and is played with ruthless efficiency by the respective French actor. But Killing Zoe is not another routine heist film. Killing Zoe spells out all the tiny, painstaking details that go with robbing a bank and it utilises the conventional 'race against time' drive. Amongst other things, the guys will have to go through each hostage one by one in order to get codes, they will have to pass the time in the main office while other robbers work downstairs on the vault and they will have to deal with any security guards they might miss once entering new bank owned territory. But that's the joy of Killing Zoe. Once it all gets up and running, there is no going back. It is a roller-coaster of violence, disturbance and dark, dark humour that isn't over until it's over. The film is all about stealing and mugging. Zed is the perfect 'fish out of water': an American in Paris; an American in France; an American in Europe. One of the first scenes of the film has a porter stand there and accept a tip that is probably too much; Zed is being 'robbed'. Then there is Zoe (Delpy) herself who charges a thousand Francs for sex but maintains she is no prostitute. "In that case, can I have my money back?" wise-cracks Zed but if you go by her convincing analysis of what she is, she is right and thus has got herself some money not through stealing but in a slimy working way. Similar to the porter who gets extra cash bringing up bags and Zoe acting as a prostitute for money, Zed and his group of cronies are breaking into banks; breaking into vaults and trying to steal the cash that they probably all think they earn by doing this. With this reading, the film is about greed. Then there are the influences of other work made by Tarantino and Avary round about the time. The sex scene between Zed and Zoe is inter-cut with images from the Nosferatu film echoing the technique used in Natural Born Killers; a film Tarantino wrote but disowned. There is also the establishment of a genuine love affair between a male lead and a prostitute echoing True Romance of the previous year, another Tarantino penned film. So if Zed is established as this lost soul as an American in France, it is because he is mugged out of a thousand Francs from a girl who isn't selling herself; he is never given the time in plain English and is informed by Eric about how wrong foreign people are when it comes to French iconography and tourism. But when push comes to shove and he is placed in his 'zone', Zed performs. This is first followed through when he looks at a map of the bank and comes up with an alternate plan that will save them time as well as possible trouble  he has solved the robbers a problem. Killing Zoe is a film that although is American, does not conform to European stereotypes just archetypes the genre demands. The French are not buffoons, the Englishman played by Gary Kemp is not a total idiot and if anything they are all a match for one another with the Zed, the American, himself sticking out for ridicule thanks to the evidence mentioned in the previous paragraph. Eric is a psychotic criminal into hard drugs and homicide, he would also rather blow someone up than shoot them in the vault. The film is one that does not start off with typical French iconography of whatever you like but stays a ground level, literally. The fast moving cars and sense of travelling kicks the film off perfectly and with a good guy to root for, a love story cleverly thrown in and an awesome bad guy, it is no surprise the film maintains that air of near perfection throughout.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From badly executed drama to funny gangster comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryu_Darkwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can completely skip the boring and utterly annoying first hour to go to the second half. The drama in it is really lame. They try to spice it up with controversial topics ( AIDS, hookers ) but in the end that is just to cover up the lack of good ideas to make an innovative action movie. From a bad executed drama it suddenly turns into a nice gangster comedy like Reservoir Dogs. Everything just leads up to the robbing of the bank and the dark humor that goes along with it. Okay, so it's all a bit clich&eacute;d, but who cares...? This is not world class cinema, but it is good enough for a boring Saturday eve. Just don't watch it with too many expectations. And don't think that something produced by Tarantino makes it into a new Pulp Fiction, it just doesn't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to make a Parisian Film in Los Angeles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a lot of Tarintino influence in it, especially as he helped director Roger Avary make it. Like From Dusk Til Dawn, Killing Zoe spends the first half of the movie setting the scene and the rest of the movie with the action. Killing Zoe is a low budget film made in Los Angeles with a few Parisian shots. This is also Avary's first movie and I think he has some talent. Zed (Eric Stolz) has been invited to Paris by an old friend, Eric (Jean-Hughes Anglade) to crack a safe in a bank. Zed is a professional, and we see this as he sets to work opening a safe, yet he is a quiet humble man who prefers to make love than to kill. He is also a man who is easily manipulated and Eric does this quite regularly in the movie. We see Zed being forced into taking drugs and having women dragged away from him because Eric doesn't particularly like them. He is also taken of a tour through a very dark side of Paris where we see drugs, sleazy women, and men screwing like animal (I use such terminology because it is only for the selfish desire of pleasure). The next day, Bastille Day, he then must participate in a daring bank robbery. Daring because everybody is hung over, or still on drugs; it is a high security bank; and it seems very little planning has gone into it. Eric is not the typical Hollywood robber. He kills at a whim and has no preferences to who he will kill. He murders a woman and a man and lets another man go free. In fact Eric seems to have a thing against women as he brutally throws Zoe (Julie Delpy) out of the room when he first meets Zed and throws another whore across the room when she tries to seduce Zed (even though he cannot understand her). He kills people on a whim and represents the worst that humanity can offer. Zoe is another character who begins as a prostitute yet does not want to think of herself as one. She needs to money to get through school and just considers the job as a little thing on the side. Yet she knows what she is, and even though she considers herself beautiful and refined, everybody else treats her as a whore. The reality of what she does hits home when she listens to three men tell a joke about a whore. Killing Zoe is a reasonable movie and good for a low budget production. Much of the movie was spoken in French which is supposed to reflect the fact that it was in France, but this didn't irritate me as it did in Stargate when everybody spoke ancient Egyptian. Still it is a good movie and worth a watch if you can handle drugs and brutal violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad kill from Quentin's mate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On my view, I do admit I was a bit disappointed. Give it a few views, I was entertained intensely. First we have Paris, one of the most beautiful cities of the world, though we don't get to see much of it in this. Granted, this is no Pulp Fiction, some of it's dialogue with it's intellectual humor, leads us to question Quentin might of got his pen a little wet here. Like Reservoir Dogs, we have a heist gone wrong, amidst a little frank and shocking violence. (Eric) Jean Hughes Anglande has invited a childhood friend over, safe cracker Zed (Stoltz) he hasn't seen in some time. They're to do over a big bank on Bastille day, where the night before they get on the p**s and H, so obviously we're in the hand of some real experts. This too becomes a shock to Zed, who's only given a day's notice, not even having time to checked the bank out. In part, as seen to the amateur display of activities by our thieves, in these ugly masks, you could silently label this as an anti drug movie. Now here's the fun angle to the title. On the day of Zed's arrival, he's sent an escort, Zoe, (Julie Delpy) who just happens to work at the same bank, they do over, where Zed caught at a pivotal moment, towards it's end, is forced to make a choice, and I did too like the way it ended. Too, Eric's drunken admittance of aids, to Zed, made sense in the way he literally shoved Zoe out of his room, after the two's little interlude. Loved the cool opening plus it's title song, where were shown numerous streets of Paris, as if from a driver's POV. I loved the end song too, with Delpy saying "Let me show you the real Paris". Also Stoltz's whacked out POV, of visible music tunes, drifting out of friend, Anglande's trumpet. Not for all Tarantino fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of 2 haves.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KILLING ZOE I liked it... but it was a film of 2 halves. The first half of the movie was just average at best. A group of people that get together to arrange a bank robbery, but most of the first 45 minutes was just them getting wasted on drugs and messing about around Paris. This part of the movie dragged on a bit. It was OK, but more could have happened. But the second half was awesome. The bank robbery. When the entered the bank, the movie really picked up the pace. Zoe is the receptionist in the bank that the group hold up...the problem is, Zoe is also a hooker that one of the robbers has fallen in love with. He didn't know she worked there. The cast was good though. Eric Stoltz, Jean-Hughes Anglade & Julie Delpy really do well. I connected with the characters these guys played. There were even some good supporting roles too. Especially Gary Kemp. Who would have known that the guy from Spandau Ballet could be a good actor. He was really good in the Krays too. There was one scene in the movie though that made me laugh. Someone gets shot and has about 200 bullets shot at him from a few guns all at the same time... yet he did not go down! He still stood there for about 30 seconds after. I am pretty sure he would have gone down a long time after that. Also, there is a brilliant comical scene with a cat. :) There was a really good raw feel to this movie that I loved... Tarantino usually has that feel with his films. I suppose this has it because he was Executive Producer. All in all this film was good. I will give it 7 out of 10. A slow first half, but a great second half and ending. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of best ways to kill 90 minutes of your life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    K V
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is exceptional. In same way Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction are. Story is well thought out, down to the point, not all characters are fleshed out (Reservoir Dogs does fleshing out much better), but they are not meant to be for reasons that become obvious once you watch the movie. Acting is superb. Casting is great. Story is believable. Ending is perhaps predictable (or I saw too many movies, perhaps both), but it is fitting. There should be lot more movies like this one. A rare gem! This movie had rating of 6.4, I gave it a 10. I don't really understand why would anybody give it less than 8. If you are not into genre, don't watch the movie, or at least don't rate it down for all the wrong reasons. I rate movies either 1 or 10 for very simple reason. All the other numbers are meaningless. I either recommend you see a movie, or advise you to stay away as when compared to other movies of its type falls too short to bother with. I neither rate, not review average movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe Since banks aren't open past 5 p.m., if you're a moonlighting bank robber, you're going to have to take time off work. Fortunately, the bandits in this bank heist were born into a life of crime. In Paris to assist his old friend Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) with a job, American safecracker Zed (Eric Stoltz) kills time with a prostitute, Zoe (Julie Delpy), whom he shares an instant rapport with. The two lovers are later reunited when a masked Zed holds up the bank where Zoe works. Compelled to protect her from the erratic Eric, who has instigated a gunfight with Paris' finest, Zed puts his lifelong friendship with Eric as well as his own life on the line. Truly a hidden heist gem, Killing Zoe is an innovative and intriguing investment that gains greater interest with each viewing. However, robbing banks is now futile since no one has any money. (Green Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i was expecting so much more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    i_love_chaos
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    with this film being directed by Roger Avery and Quentin Tarantino doing the screenplay i was sure this was going to be a gem. i was wrong. i don't hate this film but in no ways do i like it. i love Roger Avery because of his amazing direction in rules of attraction and his screenplays to pulp fiction and silent hill but he made a mistake making this. do i really need to comment on Tarantino, we all know hes a genius. this movie is just set around a gang robbing a bank but fails due to silly people participating in the robbery i'm disappointed in Tarantino and Avery for doing this film but doesn't change my mind on how amazing they both are. everyone makes mistakes......... 3/10...........j.d Seaton
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drugs & bullets....that's all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kshitij (axile007)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe revolves around Zed who was invited to Paris to contribute in a bank robbery.Unfortunately that's all the story plot contains. Rest is all about unnecessary violence which really don't make any sense. There's been also some scenes of drugs depiction and consumption.Also there is no twist in storyline,weak plot and very predictable. The only strong link of the movie is the presence of Julie Delphy who looked extremely charming. Its obvious to expect more from this movie but it do not stands anywhere around its expectations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid exploitation art-house thriller, though not without flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonymurphylee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eric Stoltz plays a man named Zed who travels to Paris in order to catch up with a childhood friend named Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) and help him rob a Federal Reserve bank. Upon his arrival, he sleeps with a call girl named Zoe (Julie Delpy) who he ends up falling in love with. When Zed goes to meet Eric, he ends up spending the night with him and all of his junkie friends who hide out in a run down apartment building with a dead feline near the entrance to their room. They plan to rob the bank the next morning, and Zed is going to be the safe cracker. After much passing out, puking, hallucinating, and a male rape, Zed and the rest of the gang awaken in a drunken daze, already late for their robbery, and then they foolishly attempt to rob the bank while still moderately trashed, hungover, and restless. Naturally things go very wrong very fast, and it becomes no longer about getting the money, but more about trying to survive. If Roger Avary's intention was to make a truly memorable art house exploitation film, he succeeded with flying colors. I'm pretty sure that this was intention and there's no denying that this is a good film. I have some serious problems with Killing Zoe, however, and those problems have much to do with the first two thirds of the picture. Avary spends a very large portion of the film in this junkie world with these truly atrocious and ugly characters doing ugly things. I felt that too much time was spent in this world. The only likable character is Julie Delpy's character, and she doesn't get nearly enough screen time as she should. As for Eric Stoltz, he pretty much plays the same character as he played in Pulp Fiction, though not anywhere near as much as a prick. His character, Zed, for the most part is a fairly goofy, eccentric, and slight perverted guy. I liked how he wasn't an entirely sympathetic protagonist. His character, for the most part, works. Likewise for his friend Eric, who is a completely horrific villain. He's disgusting, sleazy, skeletal-looking, and a sweaty mess of a man who has little conscience and no morals, and I applaud Jean-Hugues Anglade for playing a role that few actors would have the balls to play. This brings me to my biggest gripe with the film, however. These are the three main characters, but they are also the three most interesting characters as well. Every other character is completely disposable they take up far too much screen time that should have been devoted to the three main characters. To make matters worse, in the third act of the film when the characters actually try to rob the bank, a good portion of all of these characters are killed off almost immediately. While I applaud Roger Avary for crafting such a strong vision of graphic carnage in the third act, I felt that he was betraying the trash quality that took place in the first two acts with these junkie characters getting slaughtered so damn quickly. As the last act of the film stands, most of the characters end up getting killed off almost constantly and with little to no emotion. When it is not a member of the gang getting killed it is either a security guard or an innocent civilian. Somebody is almost always getting killed, often in over-the-top fashion. What I did love about Killing Zoe was the look of the film. The bank that the film takes place in during the final act is just gorgeous in how claustrophobic it is. The walls of the bank are red, and it only adds to the psychotic nature of the Eric character. The character really is quite terrifying, and the bank that Avary shot in has a perfect interior for these sort of characters. The middle section mostly takes place in real grimy, dirty, dark areas that look completely hellish. Somehow the bank looks like a scarier location than the junkie hideouts, and I liked that. The opening and closing scenes show some beautiful shots of Paris as well, which definitely helped elevate the film even more. I also felt that the final act of the film, despite the gratuitous bloodshed and carnage, really was quite suspenseful and intense. The film is so furious in it's tone and the final act really pulls it all together. At times it is difficult to watch because the audience knows right away that the situation is going to go wrong and the characters are doomed. When the bank robbery actually starts, it is so disorganized and so uncoordinated that a feeling of unhinged maniacal danger sets in immediately. It makes the film a little bit different from other heist films. The characters are all young, hapless, and careless people who have abandoned reality. Killing Zoe lacks a sense of control, which both helps and hurts the film. On one hand, it certainly helps make the final act of the film that much more shocking and realistic. On the other hand, it is difficult to look part the first two thirds of the film. I do think that this film has an audience, but I also think that it's difficult to call it a good film. It works in a lot of ways. Visually, it's better than it needs to be. The performances are all very strong, not to mention ballsy, and the vision of hell this film paints is pretty tough to shake. It's a rough film, but it manages to have a lot of energy. It is a very flawed film. However, if you're a fan of trash cinema and exploitation, you may want to give this a try. It's a messy film, but it's effective and definitely memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloody and entertaining, sometimes both but never uninteresting or un-engaging.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is an energy behind Killing Zoe, there is a passion and a commitment from its director behind Killing Zoe and that is to make a fast, furious and bloody film that entertains as well as shocks in equal measure. Given the situation regarding this film's production, the film comes across upon reading the pre-production stage as a bit of an accident. Whilst scouting for locations for Reservoir Dogs, director Roger Avary would discover a place where a 'perfect' heist film could take place. Since the whole gimmick (in the nicest possible way) for Reservoir Dogs is that it's a heist film without the heist, the bank couldn't really be used but it suited Avary's other script he had going and that was Killing Zoe. An interesting back-story to a film that is never anything but interesting, apart from perhaps being entertaining at certain points. For Reservoir Dogs to take a mere two years before it itself would become a victim of a pastiche is testament to Reservoir Dog's influential power as well as Avary's own passion and drive behind this production. Notice how the script supposedly took a week to write, also. The film revolves predominantly around a heist going on in a French bank in which master safecracker Zed (Stoltz) is working with an old French buddy who also just happens to be a heroin addict and a psychopathic criminal, amongst other things. He is Eric (Anglade) and is played with ruthless efficiency by the respective French actor. But Killing Zoe is not another routine heist film. Killing Zoe spells out all the tiny, painstaking details that go with robbing a bank and it utilises the conventional 'race against time' drive. Amongst other things, the guys will have to go through each hostage one by one in order to get codes, they will have to pass the time in the main office while other robbers work downstairs on the vault and they will have to deal with any security guards they might miss once entering new bank owned territory. But that's the joy of Killing Zoe. Once it all gets up and running, there is no going back. It is a roller-coaster of violence, disturbance and dark, dark humour that isn't over until it's over. The film is all about stealing and mugging. Zed is the perfect 'fish out of water': an American in Paris; an American in France; an American in Europe. One of the first scenes of the film has a porter stand there and accept a tip that is probably too much; Zed is being 'robbed'. Then there is Zoe (Delpy) herself who charges a thousand Francs for sex but maintains she is no prostitute. "In that case, can I have my money back?" wise-cracks Zed but if you go by her convincing analysis of what she is, she is right and thus has got herself some money not through stealing but in a slimy working way. Similar to the porter who gets extra cash bringing up bags and Zoe acting as a prostitute for money, Zed and his group of cronies are breaking into banks; breaking into vaults and trying to steal the cash that they probably all think they earn by doing this. With this reading, the film is about greed. Then there are the influences of other work made by Tarantino and Avary round about the time. The sex scene between Zed and Zoe is inter-cut with images from the Nosferatu film echoing the technique used in Natural Born Killers; a film Tarantino wrote but disowned. There is also the establishment of a genuine love affair between a male lead and a prostitute echoing True Romance of the previous year, another Tarantino penned film. So if Zed is established as this lost soul as an American in France, it is because he is mugged out of a thousand Francs from a girl who isn't selling herself; he is never given the time in plain English and is informed by Eric about how wrong foreign people are when it comes to French iconography and tourism. But when push comes to shove and he is placed in his 'zone', Zed performs. This is first followed through when he looks at a map of the bank and comes up with an alternate plan that will save them time as well as possible trouble  he has solved the robbers a problem. Killing Zoe is a film that although is American, does not conform to European stereotypes just archetypes the genre demands. The French are not buffoons, the Englishman played by Gary Kemp is not a total idiot and if anything they are all a match for one another with the Zed, the American, himself sticking out for ridicule thanks to the evidence mentioned in the previous paragraph. Eric is a psychotic criminal into hard drugs and homicide, he would also rather blow someone up than shoot them in the vault. The film is one that does not start off with typical French iconography of whatever you like but stays a ground level, literally. The fast moving cars and sense of travelling kicks the film off perfectly and with a good guy to root for, a love story cleverly thrown in and an awesome bad guy, it is no surprise the film maintains that air of near perfection throughout.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From badly executed drama to funny gangster comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryu_Darkwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can completely skip the boring and utterly annoying first hour to go to the second half. The drama in it is really lame. They try to spice it up with controversial topics ( AIDS, hookers ) but in the end that is just to cover up the lack of good ideas to make an innovative action movie. From a bad executed drama it suddenly turns into a nice gangster comedy like Reservoir Dogs. Everything just leads up to the robbing of the bank and the dark humor that goes along with it. Okay, so it's all a bit clich&eacute;d, but who cares...? This is not world class cinema, but it is good enough for a boring Saturday eve. Just don't watch it with too many expectations. And don't think that something produced by Tarantino makes it into a new Pulp Fiction, it just doesn't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to make a Parisian Film in Los Angeles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a lot of Tarintino influence in it, especially as he helped director Roger Avary make it. Like From Dusk Til Dawn, Killing Zoe spends the first half of the movie setting the scene and the rest of the movie with the action. Killing Zoe is a low budget film made in Los Angeles with a few Parisian shots. This is also Avary's first movie and I think he has some talent. Zed (Eric Stolz) has been invited to Paris by an old friend, Eric (Jean-Hughes Anglade) to crack a safe in a bank. Zed is a professional, and we see this as he sets to work opening a safe, yet he is a quiet humble man who prefers to make love than to kill. He is also a man who is easily manipulated and Eric does this quite regularly in the movie. We see Zed being forced into taking drugs and having women dragged away from him because Eric doesn't particularly like them. He is also taken of a tour through a very dark side of Paris where we see drugs, sleazy women, and men screwing like animal (I use such terminology because it is only for the selfish desire of pleasure). The next day, Bastille Day, he then must participate in a daring bank robbery. Daring because everybody is hung over, or still on drugs; it is a high security bank; and it seems very little planning has gone into it. Eric is not the typical Hollywood robber. He kills at a whim and has no preferences to who he will kill. He murders a woman and a man and lets another man go free. In fact Eric seems to have a thing against women as he brutally throws Zoe (Julie Delpy) out of the room when he first meets Zed and throws another whore across the room when she tries to seduce Zed (even though he cannot understand her). He kills people on a whim and represents the worst that humanity can offer. Zoe is another character who begins as a prostitute yet does not want to think of herself as one. She needs to money to get through school and just considers the job as a little thing on the side. Yet she knows what she is, and even though she considers herself beautiful and refined, everybody else treats her as a whore. The reality of what she does hits home when she listens to three men tell a joke about a whore. Killing Zoe is a reasonable movie and good for a low budget production. Much of the movie was spoken in French which is supposed to reflect the fact that it was in France, but this didn't irritate me as it did in Stargate when everybody spoke ancient Egyptian. Still it is a good movie and worth a watch if you can handle drugs and brutal violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad kill from Quentin's mate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On my view, I do admit I was a bit disappointed. Give it a few views, I was entertained intensely. First we have Paris, one of the most beautiful cities of the world, though we don't get to see much of it in this. Granted, this is no Pulp Fiction, some of it's dialogue with it's intellectual humor, leads us to question Quentin might of got his pen a little wet here. Like Reservoir Dogs, we have a heist gone wrong, amidst a little frank and shocking violence. (Eric) Jean Hughes Anglande has invited a childhood friend over, safe cracker Zed (Stoltz) he hasn't seen in some time. They're to do over a big bank on Bastille day, where the night before they get on the p**s and H, so obviously we're in the hand of some real experts. This too becomes a shock to Zed, who's only given a day's notice, not even having time to checked the bank out. In part, as seen to the amateur display of activities by our thieves, in these ugly masks, you could silently label this as an anti drug movie. Now here's the fun angle to the title. On the day of Zed's arrival, he's sent an escort, Zoe, (Julie Delpy) who just happens to work at the same bank, they do over, where Zed caught at a pivotal moment, towards it's end, is forced to make a choice, and I did too like the way it ended. Too, Eric's drunken admittance of aids, to Zed, made sense in the way he literally shoved Zoe out of his room, after the two's little interlude. Loved the cool opening plus it's title song, where were shown numerous streets of Paris, as if from a driver's POV. I loved the end song too, with Delpy saying "Let me show you the real Paris". Also Stoltz's whacked out POV, of visible music tunes, drifting out of friend, Anglande's trumpet. Not for all Tarantino fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of 2 haves.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KILLING ZOE I liked it... but it was a film of 2 halves. The first half of the movie was just average at best. A group of people that get together to arrange a bank robbery, but most of the first 45 minutes was just them getting wasted on drugs and messing about around Paris. This part of the movie dragged on a bit. It was OK, but more could have happened. But the second half was awesome. The bank robbery. When the entered the bank, the movie really picked up the pace. Zoe is the receptionist in the bank that the group hold up...the problem is, Zoe is also a hooker that one of the robbers has fallen in love with. He didn't know she worked there. The cast was good though. Eric Stoltz, Jean-Hughes Anglade & Julie Delpy really do well. I connected with the characters these guys played. There were even some good supporting roles too. Especially Gary Kemp. Who would have known that the guy from Spandau Ballet could be a good actor. He was really good in the Krays too. There was one scene in the movie though that made me laugh. Someone gets shot and has about 200 bullets shot at him from a few guns all at the same time... yet he did not go down! He still stood there for about 30 seconds after. I am pretty sure he would have gone down a long time after that. Also, there is a brilliant comical scene with a cat. :) There was a really good raw feel to this movie that I loved... Tarantino usually has that feel with his films. I suppose this has it because he was Executive Producer. All in all this film was good. I will give it 7 out of 10. A slow first half, but a great second half and ending. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of best ways to kill 90 minutes of your life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    K V
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is exceptional. In same way Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction are. Story is well thought out, down to the point, not all characters are fleshed out (Reservoir Dogs does fleshing out much better), but they are not meant to be for reasons that become obvious once you watch the movie. Acting is superb. Casting is great. Story is believable. Ending is perhaps predictable (or I saw too many movies, perhaps both), but it is fitting. There should be lot more movies like this one. A rare gem! This movie had rating of 6.4, I gave it a 10. I don't really understand why would anybody give it less than 8. If you are not into genre, don't watch the movie, or at least don't rate it down for all the wrong reasons. I rate movies either 1 or 10 for very simple reason. All the other numbers are meaningless. I either recommend you see a movie, or advise you to stay away as when compared to other movies of its type falls too short to bother with. I neither rate, not review average movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe Since banks aren't open past 5 p.m., if you're a moonlighting bank robber, you're going to have to take time off work. Fortunately, the bandits in this bank heist were born into a life of crime. In Paris to assist his old friend Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) with a job, American safecracker Zed (Eric Stoltz) kills time with a prostitute, Zoe (Julie Delpy), whom he shares an instant rapport with. The two lovers are later reunited when a masked Zed holds up the bank where Zoe works. Compelled to protect her from the erratic Eric, who has instigated a gunfight with Paris' finest, Zed puts his lifelong friendship with Eric as well as his own life on the line. Truly a hidden heist gem, Killing Zoe is an innovative and intriguing investment that gains greater interest with each viewing. However, robbing banks is now futile since no one has any money. (Green Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i was expecting so much more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    i_love_chaos
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    with this film being directed by Roger Avery and Quentin Tarantino doing the screenplay i was sure this was going to be a gem. i was wrong. i don't hate this film but in no ways do i like it. i love Roger Avery because of his amazing direction in rules of attraction and his screenplays to pulp fiction and silent hill but he made a mistake making this. do i really need to comment on Tarantino, we all know hes a genius. this movie is just set around a gang robbing a bank but fails due to silly people participating in the robbery i'm disappointed in Tarantino and Avery for doing this film but doesn't change my mind on how amazing they both are. everyone makes mistakes......... 3/10...........j.d Seaton
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drugs & bullets....that's all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kshitij (axile007)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe revolves around Zed who was invited to Paris to contribute in a bank robbery.Unfortunately that's all the story plot contains. Rest is all about unnecessary violence which really don't make any sense. There's been also some scenes of drugs depiction and consumption.Also there is no twist in storyline,weak plot and very predictable. The only strong link of the movie is the presence of Julie Delphy who looked extremely charming. Its obvious to expect more from this movie but it do not stands anywhere around its expectations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid exploitation art-house thriller, though not without flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonymurphylee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eric Stoltz plays a man named Zed who travels to Paris in order to catch up with a childhood friend named Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) and help him rob a Federal Reserve bank. Upon his arrival, he sleeps with a call girl named Zoe (Julie Delpy) who he ends up falling in love with. When Zed goes to meet Eric, he ends up spending the night with him and all of his junkie friends who hide out in a run down apartment building with a dead feline near the entrance to their room. They plan to rob the bank the next morning, and Zed is going to be the safe cracker. After much passing out, puking, hallucinating, and a male rape, Zed and the rest of the gang awaken in a drunken daze, already late for their robbery, and then they foolishly attempt to rob the bank while still moderately trashed, hungover, and restless. Naturally things go very wrong very fast, and it becomes no longer about getting the money, but more about trying to survive. If Roger Avary's intention was to make a truly memorable art house exploitation film, he succeeded with flying colors. I'm pretty sure that this was intention and there's no denying that this is a good film. I have some serious problems with Killing Zoe, however, and those problems have much to do with the first two thirds of the picture. Avary spends a very large portion of the film in this junkie world with these truly atrocious and ugly characters doing ugly things. I felt that too much time was spent in this world. The only likable character is Julie Delpy's character, and she doesn't get nearly enough screen time as she should. As for Eric Stoltz, he pretty much plays the same character as he played in Pulp Fiction, though not anywhere near as much as a prick. His character, Zed, for the most part is a fairly goofy, eccentric, and slight perverted guy. I liked how he wasn't an entirely sympathetic protagonist. His character, for the most part, works. Likewise for his friend Eric, who is a completely horrific villain. He's disgusting, sleazy, skeletal-looking, and a sweaty mess of a man who has little conscience and no morals, and I applaud Jean-Hugues Anglade for playing a role that few actors would have the balls to play. This brings me to my biggest gripe with the film, however. These are the three main characters, but they are also the three most interesting characters as well. Every other character is completely disposable they take up far too much screen time that should have been devoted to the three main characters. To make matters worse, in the third act of the film when the characters actually try to rob the bank, a good portion of all of these characters are killed off almost immediately. While I applaud Roger Avary for crafting such a strong vision of graphic carnage in the third act, I felt that he was betraying the trash quality that took place in the first two acts with these junkie characters getting slaughtered so damn quickly. As the last act of the film stands, most of the characters end up getting killed off almost constantly and with little to no emotion. When it is not a member of the gang getting killed it is either a security guard or an innocent civilian. Somebody is almost always getting killed, often in over-the-top fashion. What I did love about Killing Zoe was the look of the film. The bank that the film takes place in during the final act is just gorgeous in how claustrophobic it is. The walls of the bank are red, and it only adds to the psychotic nature of the Eric character. The character really is quite terrifying, and the bank that Avary shot in has a perfect interior for these sort of characters. The middle section mostly takes place in real grimy, dirty, dark areas that look completely hellish. Somehow the bank looks like a scarier location than the junkie hideouts, and I liked that. The opening and closing scenes show some beautiful shots of Paris as well, which definitely helped elevate the film even more. I also felt that the final act of the film, despite the gratuitous bloodshed and carnage, really was quite suspenseful and intense. The film is so furious in it's tone and the final act really pulls it all together. At times it is difficult to watch because the audience knows right away that the situation is going to go wrong and the characters are doomed. When the bank robbery actually starts, it is so disorganized and so uncoordinated that a feeling of unhinged maniacal danger sets in immediately. It makes the film a little bit different from other heist films. The characters are all young, hapless, and careless people who have abandoned reality. Killing Zoe lacks a sense of control, which both helps and hurts the film. On one hand, it certainly helps make the final act of the film that much more shocking and realistic. On the other hand, it is difficult to look part the first two thirds of the film. I do think that this film has an audience, but I also think that it's difficult to call it a good film. It works in a lot of ways. Visually, it's better than it needs to be. The performances are all very strong, not to mention ballsy, and the vision of hell this film paints is pretty tough to shake. It's a rough film, but it manages to have a lot of energy. It is a very flawed film. However, if you're a fan of trash cinema and exploitation, you may want to give this a try. It's a messy film, but it's effective and definitely memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloody and entertaining, sometimes both but never uninteresting or un-engaging.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is an energy behind Killing Zoe, there is a passion and a commitment from its director behind Killing Zoe and that is to make a fast, furious and bloody film that entertains as well as shocks in equal measure. Given the situation regarding this film's production, the film comes across upon reading the pre-production stage as a bit of an accident. Whilst scouting for locations for Reservoir Dogs, director Roger Avary would discover a place where a 'perfect' heist film could take place. Since the whole gimmick (in the nicest possible way) for Reservoir Dogs is that it's a heist film without the heist, the bank couldn't really be used but it suited Avary's other script he had going and that was Killing Zoe. An interesting back-story to a film that is never anything but interesting, apart from perhaps being entertaining at certain points. For Reservoir Dogs to take a mere two years before it itself would become a victim of a pastiche is testament to Reservoir Dog's influential power as well as Avary's own passion and drive behind this production. Notice how the script supposedly took a week to write, also. The film revolves predominantly around a heist going on in a French bank in which master safecracker Zed (Stoltz) is working with an old French buddy who also just happens to be a heroin addict and a psychopathic criminal, amongst other things. He is Eric (Anglade) and is played with ruthless efficiency by the respective French actor. But Killing Zoe is not another routine heist film. Killing Zoe spells out all the tiny, painstaking details that go with robbing a bank and it utilises the conventional 'race against time' drive. Amongst other things, the guys will have to go through each hostage one by one in order to get codes, they will have to pass the time in the main office while other robbers work downstairs on the vault and they will have to deal with any security guards they might miss once entering new bank owned territory. But that's the joy of Killing Zoe. Once it all gets up and running, there is no going back. It is a roller-coaster of violence, disturbance and dark, dark humour that isn't over until it's over. The film is all about stealing and mugging. Zed is the perfect 'fish out of water': an American in Paris; an American in France; an American in Europe. One of the first scenes of the film has a porter stand there and accept a tip that is probably too much; Zed is being 'robbed'. Then there is Zoe (Delpy) herself who charges a thousand Francs for sex but maintains she is no prostitute. "In that case, can I have my money back?" wise-cracks Zed but if you go by her convincing analysis of what she is, she is right and thus has got herself some money not through stealing but in a slimy working way. Similar to the porter who gets extra cash bringing up bags and Zoe acting as a prostitute for money, Zed and his group of cronies are breaking into banks; breaking into vaults and trying to steal the cash that they probably all think they earn by doing this. With this reading, the film is about greed. Then there are the influences of other work made by Tarantino and Avary round about the time. The sex scene between Zed and Zoe is inter-cut with images from the Nosferatu film echoing the technique used in Natural Born Killers; a film Tarantino wrote but disowned. There is also the establishment of a genuine love affair between a male lead and a prostitute echoing True Romance of the previous year, another Tarantino penned film. So if Zed is established as this lost soul as an American in France, it is because he is mugged out of a thousand Francs from a girl who isn't selling herself; he is never given the time in plain English and is informed by Eric about how wrong foreign people are when it comes to French iconography and tourism. But when push comes to shove and he is placed in his 'zone', Zed performs. This is first followed through when he looks at a map of the bank and comes up with an alternate plan that will save them time as well as possible trouble  he has solved the robbers a problem. Killing Zoe is a film that although is American, does not conform to European stereotypes just archetypes the genre demands. The French are not buffoons, the Englishman played by Gary Kemp is not a total idiot and if anything they are all a match for one another with the Zed, the American, himself sticking out for ridicule thanks to the evidence mentioned in the previous paragraph. Eric is a psychotic criminal into hard drugs and homicide, he would also rather blow someone up than shoot them in the vault. The film is one that does not start off with typical French iconography of whatever you like but stays a ground level, literally. The fast moving cars and sense of travelling kicks the film off perfectly and with a good guy to root for, a love story cleverly thrown in and an awesome bad guy, it is no surprise the film maintains that air of near perfection throughout.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From badly executed drama to funny gangster comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryu_Darkwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can completely skip the boring and utterly annoying first hour to go to the second half. The drama in it is really lame. They try to spice it up with controversial topics ( AIDS, hookers ) but in the end that is just to cover up the lack of good ideas to make an innovative action movie. From a bad executed drama it suddenly turns into a nice gangster comedy like Reservoir Dogs. Everything just leads up to the robbing of the bank and the dark humor that goes along with it. Okay, so it's all a bit clich&eacute;d, but who cares...? This is not world class cinema, but it is good enough for a boring Saturday eve. Just don't watch it with too many expectations. And don't think that something produced by Tarantino makes it into a new Pulp Fiction, it just doesn't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to make a Parisian Film in Los Angeles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a lot of Tarintino influence in it, especially as he helped director Roger Avary make it. Like From Dusk Til Dawn, Killing Zoe spends the first half of the movie setting the scene and the rest of the movie with the action. Killing Zoe is a low budget film made in Los Angeles with a few Parisian shots. This is also Avary's first movie and I think he has some talent. Zed (Eric Stolz) has been invited to Paris by an old friend, Eric (Jean-Hughes Anglade) to crack a safe in a bank. Zed is a professional, and we see this as he sets to work opening a safe, yet he is a quiet humble man who prefers to make love than to kill. He is also a man who is easily manipulated and Eric does this quite regularly in the movie. We see Zed being forced into taking drugs and having women dragged away from him because Eric doesn't particularly like them. He is also taken of a tour through a very dark side of Paris where we see drugs, sleazy women, and men screwing like animal (I use such terminology because it is only for the selfish desire of pleasure). The next day, Bastille Day, he then must participate in a daring bank robbery. Daring because everybody is hung over, or still on drugs; it is a high security bank; and it seems very little planning has gone into it. Eric is not the typical Hollywood robber. He kills at a whim and has no preferences to who he will kill. He murders a woman and a man and lets another man go free. In fact Eric seems to have a thing against women as he brutally throws Zoe (Julie Delpy) out of the room when he first meets Zed and throws another whore across the room when she tries to seduce Zed (even though he cannot understand her). He kills people on a whim and represents the worst that humanity can offer. Zoe is another character who begins as a prostitute yet does not want to think of herself as one. She needs to money to get through school and just considers the job as a little thing on the side. Yet she knows what she is, and even though she considers herself beautiful and refined, everybody else treats her as a whore. The reality of what she does hits home when she listens to three men tell a joke about a whore. Killing Zoe is a reasonable movie and good for a low budget production. Much of the movie was spoken in French which is supposed to reflect the fact that it was in France, but this didn't irritate me as it did in Stargate when everybody spoke ancient Egyptian. Still it is a good movie and worth a watch if you can handle drugs and brutal violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad kill from Quentin's mate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On my view, I do admit I was a bit disappointed. Give it a few views, I was entertained intensely. First we have Paris, one of the most beautiful cities of the world, though we don't get to see much of it in this. Granted, this is no Pulp Fiction, some of it's dialogue with it's intellectual humor, leads us to question Quentin might of got his pen a little wet here. Like Reservoir Dogs, we have a heist gone wrong, amidst a little frank and shocking violence. (Eric) Jean Hughes Anglande has invited a childhood friend over, safe cracker Zed (Stoltz) he hasn't seen in some time. They're to do over a big bank on Bastille day, where the night before they get on the p**s and H, so obviously we're in the hand of some real experts. This too becomes a shock to Zed, who's only given a day's notice, not even having time to checked the bank out. In part, as seen to the amateur display of activities by our thieves, in these ugly masks, you could silently label this as an anti drug movie. Now here's the fun angle to the title. On the day of Zed's arrival, he's sent an escort, Zoe, (Julie Delpy) who just happens to work at the same bank, they do over, where Zed caught at a pivotal moment, towards it's end, is forced to make a choice, and I did too like the way it ended. Too, Eric's drunken admittance of aids, to Zed, made sense in the way he literally shoved Zoe out of his room, after the two's little interlude. Loved the cool opening plus it's title song, where were shown numerous streets of Paris, as if from a driver's POV. I loved the end song too, with Delpy saying "Let me show you the real Paris". Also Stoltz's whacked out POV, of visible music tunes, drifting out of friend, Anglande's trumpet. Not for all Tarantino fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of 2 haves.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KILLING ZOE I liked it... but it was a film of 2 halves. The first half of the movie was just average at best. A group of people that get together to arrange a bank robbery, but most of the first 45 minutes was just them getting wasted on drugs and messing about around Paris. This part of the movie dragged on a bit. It was OK, but more could have happened. But the second half was awesome. The bank robbery. When the entered the bank, the movie really picked up the pace. Zoe is the receptionist in the bank that the group hold up...the problem is, Zoe is also a hooker that one of the robbers has fallen in love with. He didn't know she worked there. The cast was good though. Eric Stoltz, Jean-Hughes Anglade & Julie Delpy really do well. I connected with the characters these guys played. There were even some good supporting roles too. Especially Gary Kemp. Who would have known that the guy from Spandau Ballet could be a good actor. He was really good in the Krays too. There was one scene in the movie though that made me laugh. Someone gets shot and has about 200 bullets shot at him from a few guns all at the same time... yet he did not go down! He still stood there for about 30 seconds after. I am pretty sure he would have gone down a long time after that. Also, there is a brilliant comical scene with a cat. :) There was a really good raw feel to this movie that I loved... Tarantino usually has that feel with his films. I suppose this has it because he was Executive Producer. All in all this film was good. I will give it 7 out of 10. A slow first half, but a great second half and ending. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of best ways to kill 90 minutes of your life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    K V
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is exceptional. In same way Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction are. Story is well thought out, down to the point, not all characters are fleshed out (Reservoir Dogs does fleshing out much better), but they are not meant to be for reasons that become obvious once you watch the movie. Acting is superb. Casting is great. Story is believable. Ending is perhaps predictable (or I saw too many movies, perhaps both), but it is fitting. There should be lot more movies like this one. A rare gem! This movie had rating of 6.4, I gave it a 10. I don't really understand why would anybody give it less than 8. If you are not into genre, don't watch the movie, or at least don't rate it down for all the wrong reasons. I rate movies either 1 or 10 for very simple reason. All the other numbers are meaningless. I either recommend you see a movie, or advise you to stay away as when compared to other movies of its type falls too short to bother with. I neither rate, not review average movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe Since banks aren't open past 5 p.m., if you're a moonlighting bank robber, you're going to have to take time off work. Fortunately, the bandits in this bank heist were born into a life of crime. In Paris to assist his old friend Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) with a job, American safecracker Zed (Eric Stoltz) kills time with a prostitute, Zoe (Julie Delpy), whom he shares an instant rapport with. The two lovers are later reunited when a masked Zed holds up the bank where Zoe works. Compelled to protect her from the erratic Eric, who has instigated a gunfight with Paris' finest, Zed puts his lifelong friendship with Eric as well as his own life on the line. Truly a hidden heist gem, Killing Zoe is an innovative and intriguing investment that gains greater interest with each viewing. However, robbing banks is now futile since no one has any money. (Green Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i was expecting so much more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    i_love_chaos
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    with this film being directed by Roger Avery and Quentin Tarantino doing the screenplay i was sure this was going to be a gem. i was wrong. i don't hate this film but in no ways do i like it. i love Roger Avery because of his amazing direction in rules of attraction and his screenplays to pulp fiction and silent hill but he made a mistake making this. do i really need to comment on Tarantino, we all know hes a genius. this movie is just set around a gang robbing a bank but fails due to silly people participating in the robbery i'm disappointed in Tarantino and Avery for doing this film but doesn't change my mind on how amazing they both are. everyone makes mistakes......... 3/10...........j.d Seaton
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drugs & bullets....that's all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kshitij (axile007)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe revolves around Zed who was invited to Paris to contribute in a bank robbery.Unfortunately that's all the story plot contains. Rest is all about unnecessary violence which really don't make any sense. There's been also some scenes of drugs depiction and consumption.Also there is no twist in storyline,weak plot and very predictable. The only strong link of the movie is the presence of Julie Delphy who looked extremely charming. Its obvious to expect more from this movie but it do not stands anywhere around its expectations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid exploitation art-house thriller, though not without flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonymurphylee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eric Stoltz plays a man named Zed who travels to Paris in order to catch up with a childhood friend named Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) and help him rob a Federal Reserve bank. Upon his arrival, he sleeps with a call girl named Zoe (Julie Delpy) who he ends up falling in love with. When Zed goes to meet Eric, he ends up spending the night with him and all of his junkie friends who hide out in a run down apartment building with a dead feline near the entrance to their room. They plan to rob the bank the next morning, and Zed is going to be the safe cracker. After much passing out, puking, hallucinating, and a male rape, Zed and the rest of the gang awaken in a drunken daze, already late for their robbery, and then they foolishly attempt to rob the bank while still moderately trashed, hungover, and restless. Naturally things go very wrong very fast, and it becomes no longer about getting the money, but more about trying to survive. If Roger Avary's intention was to make a truly memorable art house exploitation film, he succeeded with flying colors. I'm pretty sure that this was intention and there's no denying that this is a good film. I have some serious problems with Killing Zoe, however, and those problems have much to do with the first two thirds of the picture. Avary spends a very large portion of the film in this junkie world with these truly atrocious and ugly characters doing ugly things. I felt that too much time was spent in this world. The only likable character is Julie Delpy's character, and she doesn't get nearly enough screen time as she should. As for Eric Stoltz, he pretty much plays the same character as he played in Pulp Fiction, though not anywhere near as much as a prick. His character, Zed, for the most part is a fairly goofy, eccentric, and slight perverted guy. I liked how he wasn't an entirely sympathetic protagonist. His character, for the most part, works. Likewise for his friend Eric, who is a completely horrific villain. He's disgusting, sleazy, skeletal-looking, and a sweaty mess of a man who has little conscience and no morals, and I applaud Jean-Hugues Anglade for playing a role that few actors would have the balls to play. This brings me to my biggest gripe with the film, however. These are the three main characters, but they are also the three most interesting characters as well. Every other character is completely disposable they take up far too much screen time that should have been devoted to the three main characters. To make matters worse, in the third act of the film when the characters actually try to rob the bank, a good portion of all of these characters are killed off almost immediately. While I applaud Roger Avary for crafting such a strong vision of graphic carnage in the third act, I felt that he was betraying the trash quality that took place in the first two acts with these junkie characters getting slaughtered so damn quickly. As the last act of the film stands, most of the characters end up getting killed off almost constantly and with little to no emotion. When it is not a member of the gang getting killed it is either a security guard or an innocent civilian. Somebody is almost always getting killed, often in over-the-top fashion. What I did love about Killing Zoe was the look of the film. The bank that the film takes place in during the final act is just gorgeous in how claustrophobic it is. The walls of the bank are red, and it only adds to the psychotic nature of the Eric character. The character really is quite terrifying, and the bank that Avary shot in has a perfect interior for these sort of characters. The middle section mostly takes place in real grimy, dirty, dark areas that look completely hellish. Somehow the bank looks like a scarier location than the junkie hideouts, and I liked that. The opening and closing scenes show some beautiful shots of Paris as well, which definitely helped elevate the film even more. I also felt that the final act of the film, despite the gratuitous bloodshed and carnage, really was quite suspenseful and intense. The film is so furious in it's tone and the final act really pulls it all together. At times it is difficult to watch because the audience knows right away that the situation is going to go wrong and the characters are doomed. When the bank robbery actually starts, it is so disorganized and so uncoordinated that a feeling of unhinged maniacal danger sets in immediately. It makes the film a little bit different from other heist films. The characters are all young, hapless, and careless people who have abandoned reality. Killing Zoe lacks a sense of control, which both helps and hurts the film. On one hand, it certainly helps make the final act of the film that much more shocking and realistic. On the other hand, it is difficult to look part the first two thirds of the film. I do think that this film has an audience, but I also think that it's difficult to call it a good film. It works in a lot of ways. Visually, it's better than it needs to be. The performances are all very strong, not to mention ballsy, and the vision of hell this film paints is pretty tough to shake. It's a rough film, but it manages to have a lot of energy. It is a very flawed film. However, if you're a fan of trash cinema and exploitation, you may want to give this a try. It's a messy film, but it's effective and definitely memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloody and entertaining, sometimes both but never uninteresting or un-engaging.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is an energy behind Killing Zoe, there is a passion and a commitment from its director behind Killing Zoe and that is to make a fast, furious and bloody film that entertains as well as shocks in equal measure. Given the situation regarding this film's production, the film comes across upon reading the pre-production stage as a bit of an accident. Whilst scouting for locations for Reservoir Dogs, director Roger Avary would discover a place where a 'perfect' heist film could take place. Since the whole gimmick (in the nicest possible way) for Reservoir Dogs is that it's a heist film without the heist, the bank couldn't really be used but it suited Avary's other script he had going and that was Killing Zoe. An interesting back-story to a film that is never anything but interesting, apart from perhaps being entertaining at certain points. For Reservoir Dogs to take a mere two years before it itself would become a victim of a pastiche is testament to Reservoir Dog's influential power as well as Avary's own passion and drive behind this production. Notice how the script supposedly took a week to write, also. The film revolves predominantly around a heist going on in a French bank in which master safecracker Zed (Stoltz) is working with an old French buddy who also just happens to be a heroin addict and a psychopathic criminal, amongst other things. He is Eric (Anglade) and is played with ruthless efficiency by the respective French actor. But Killing Zoe is not another routine heist film. Killing Zoe spells out all the tiny, painstaking details that go with robbing a bank and it utilises the conventional 'race against time' drive. Amongst other things, the guys will have to go through each hostage one by one in order to get codes, they will have to pass the time in the main office while other robbers work downstairs on the vault and they will have to deal with any security guards they might miss once entering new bank owned territory. But that's the joy of Killing Zoe. Once it all gets up and running, there is no going back. It is a roller-coaster of violence, disturbance and dark, dark humour that isn't over until it's over. The film is all about stealing and mugging. Zed is the perfect 'fish out of water': an American in Paris; an American in France; an American in Europe. One of the first scenes of the film has a porter stand there and accept a tip that is probably too much; Zed is being 'robbed'. Then there is Zoe (Delpy) herself who charges a thousand Francs for sex but maintains she is no prostitute. "In that case, can I have my money back?" wise-cracks Zed but if you go by her convincing analysis of what she is, she is right and thus has got herself some money not through stealing but in a slimy working way. Similar to the porter who gets extra cash bringing up bags and Zoe acting as a prostitute for money, Zed and his group of cronies are breaking into banks; breaking into vaults and trying to steal the cash that they probably all think they earn by doing this. With this reading, the film is about greed. Then there are the influences of other work made by Tarantino and Avary round about the time. The sex scene between Zed and Zoe is inter-cut with images from the Nosferatu film echoing the technique used in Natural Born Killers; a film Tarantino wrote but disowned. There is also the establishment of a genuine love affair between a male lead and a prostitute echoing True Romance of the previous year, another Tarantino penned film. So if Zed is established as this lost soul as an American in France, it is because he is mugged out of a thousand Francs from a girl who isn't selling herself; he is never given the time in plain English and is informed by Eric about how wrong foreign people are when it comes to French iconography and tourism. But when push comes to shove and he is placed in his 'zone', Zed performs. This is first followed through when he looks at a map of the bank and comes up with an alternate plan that will save them time as well as possible trouble  he has solved the robbers a problem. Killing Zoe is a film that although is American, does not conform to European stereotypes just archetypes the genre demands. The French are not buffoons, the Englishman played by Gary Kemp is not a total idiot and if anything they are all a match for one another with the Zed, the American, himself sticking out for ridicule thanks to the evidence mentioned in the previous paragraph. Eric is a psychotic criminal into hard drugs and homicide, he would also rather blow someone up than shoot them in the vault. The film is one that does not start off with typical French iconography of whatever you like but stays a ground level, literally. The fast moving cars and sense of travelling kicks the film off perfectly and with a good guy to root for, a love story cleverly thrown in and an awesome bad guy, it is no surprise the film maintains that air of near perfection throughout.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From badly executed drama to funny gangster comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryu_Darkwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can completely skip the boring and utterly annoying first hour to go to the second half. The drama in it is really lame. They try to spice it up with controversial topics ( AIDS, hookers ) but in the end that is just to cover up the lack of good ideas to make an innovative action movie. From a bad executed drama it suddenly turns into a nice gangster comedy like Reservoir Dogs. Everything just leads up to the robbing of the bank and the dark humor that goes along with it. Okay, so it's all a bit clich&eacute;d, but who cares...? This is not world class cinema, but it is good enough for a boring Saturday eve. Just don't watch it with too many expectations. And don't think that something produced by Tarantino makes it into a new Pulp Fiction, it just doesn't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to make a Parisian Film in Los Angeles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a lot of Tarintino influence in it, especially as he helped director Roger Avary make it. Like From Dusk Til Dawn, Killing Zoe spends the first half of the movie setting the scene and the rest of the movie with the action. Killing Zoe is a low budget film made in Los Angeles with a few Parisian shots. This is also Avary's first movie and I think he has some talent. Zed (Eric Stolz) has been invited to Paris by an old friend, Eric (Jean-Hughes Anglade) to crack a safe in a bank. Zed is a professional, and we see this as he sets to work opening a safe, yet he is a quiet humble man who prefers to make love than to kill. He is also a man who is easily manipulated and Eric does this quite regularly in the movie. We see Zed being forced into taking drugs and having women dragged away from him because Eric doesn't particularly like them. He is also taken of a tour through a very dark side of Paris where we see drugs, sleazy women, and men screwing like animal (I use such terminology because it is only for the selfish desire of pleasure). The next day, Bastille Day, he then must participate in a daring bank robbery. Daring because everybody is hung over, or still on drugs; it is a high security bank; and it seems very little planning has gone into it. Eric is not the typical Hollywood robber. He kills at a whim and has no preferences to who he will kill. He murders a woman and a man and lets another man go free. In fact Eric seems to have a thing against women as he brutally throws Zoe (Julie Delpy) out of the room when he first meets Zed and throws another whore across the room when she tries to seduce Zed (even though he cannot understand her). He kills people on a whim and represents the worst that humanity can offer. Zoe is another character who begins as a prostitute yet does not want to think of herself as one. She needs to money to get through school and just considers the job as a little thing on the side. Yet she knows what she is, and even though she considers herself beautiful and refined, everybody else treats her as a whore. The reality of what she does hits home when she listens to three men tell a joke about a whore. Killing Zoe is a reasonable movie and good for a low budget production. Much of the movie was spoken in French which is supposed to reflect the fact that it was in France, but this didn't irritate me as it did in Stargate when everybody spoke ancient Egyptian. Still it is a good movie and worth a watch if you can handle drugs and brutal violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad kill from Quentin's mate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On my view, I do admit I was a bit disappointed. Give it a few views, I was entertained intensely. First we have Paris, one of the most beautiful cities of the world, though we don't get to see much of it in this. Granted, this is no Pulp Fiction, some of it's dialogue with it's intellectual humor, leads us to question Quentin might of got his pen a little wet here. Like Reservoir Dogs, we have a heist gone wrong, amidst a little frank and shocking violence. (Eric) Jean Hughes Anglande has invited a childhood friend over, safe cracker Zed (Stoltz) he hasn't seen in some time. They're to do over a big bank on Bastille day, where the night before they get on the p**s and H, so obviously we're in the hand of some real experts. This too becomes a shock to Zed, who's only given a day's notice, not even having time to checked the bank out. In part, as seen to the amateur display of activities by our thieves, in these ugly masks, you could silently label this as an anti drug movie. Now here's the fun angle to the title. On the day of Zed's arrival, he's sent an escort, Zoe, (Julie Delpy) who just happens to work at the same bank, they do over, where Zed caught at a pivotal moment, towards it's end, is forced to make a choice, and I did too like the way it ended. Too, Eric's drunken admittance of aids, to Zed, made sense in the way he literally shoved Zoe out of his room, after the two's little interlude. Loved the cool opening plus it's title song, where were shown numerous streets of Paris, as if from a driver's POV. I loved the end song too, with Delpy saying "Let me show you the real Paris". Also Stoltz's whacked out POV, of visible music tunes, drifting out of friend, Anglande's trumpet. Not for all Tarantino fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of 2 haves.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KILLING ZOE I liked it... but it was a film of 2 halves. The first half of the movie was just average at best. A group of people that get together to arrange a bank robbery, but most of the first 45 minutes was just them getting wasted on drugs and messing about around Paris. This part of the movie dragged on a bit. It was OK, but more could have happened. But the second half was awesome. The bank robbery. When the entered the bank, the movie really picked up the pace. Zoe is the receptionist in the bank that the group hold up...the problem is, Zoe is also a hooker that one of the robbers has fallen in love with. He didn't know she worked there. The cast was good though. Eric Stoltz, Jean-Hughes Anglade & Julie Delpy really do well. I connected with the characters these guys played. There were even some good supporting roles too. Especially Gary Kemp. Who would have known that the guy from Spandau Ballet could be a good actor. He was really good in the Krays too. There was one scene in the movie though that made me laugh. Someone gets shot and has about 200 bullets shot at him from a few guns all at the same time... yet he did not go down! He still stood there for about 30 seconds after. I am pretty sure he would have gone down a long time after that. Also, there is a brilliant comical scene with a cat. :) There was a really good raw feel to this movie that I loved... Tarantino usually has that feel with his films. I suppose this has it because he was Executive Producer. All in all this film was good. I will give it 7 out of 10. A slow first half, but a great second half and ending. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of best ways to kill 90 minutes of your life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    K V
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is exceptional. In same way Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction are. Story is well thought out, down to the point, not all characters are fleshed out (Reservoir Dogs does fleshing out much better), but they are not meant to be for reasons that become obvious once you watch the movie. Acting is superb. Casting is great. Story is believable. Ending is perhaps predictable (or I saw too many movies, perhaps both), but it is fitting. There should be lot more movies like this one. A rare gem! This movie had rating of 6.4, I gave it a 10. I don't really understand why would anybody give it less than 8. If you are not into genre, don't watch the movie, or at least don't rate it down for all the wrong reasons. I rate movies either 1 or 10 for very simple reason. All the other numbers are meaningless. I either recommend you see a movie, or advise you to stay away as when compared to other movies of its type falls too short to bother with. I neither rate, not review average movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe Since banks aren't open past 5 p.m., if you're a moonlighting bank robber, you're going to have to take time off work. Fortunately, the bandits in this bank heist were born into a life of crime. In Paris to assist his old friend Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) with a job, American safecracker Zed (Eric Stoltz) kills time with a prostitute, Zoe (Julie Delpy), whom he shares an instant rapport with. The two lovers are later reunited when a masked Zed holds up the bank where Zoe works. Compelled to protect her from the erratic Eric, who has instigated a gunfight with Paris' finest, Zed puts his lifelong friendship with Eric as well as his own life on the line. Truly a hidden heist gem, Killing Zoe is an innovative and intriguing investment that gains greater interest with each viewing. However, robbing banks is now futile since no one has any money. (Green Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i was expecting so much more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    i_love_chaos
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    with this film being directed by Roger Avery and Quentin Tarantino doing the screenplay i was sure this was going to be a gem. i was wrong. i don't hate this film but in no ways do i like it. i love Roger Avery because of his amazing direction in rules of attraction and his screenplays to pulp fiction and silent hill but he made a mistake making this. do i really need to comment on Tarantino, we all know hes a genius. this movie is just set around a gang robbing a bank but fails due to silly people participating in the robbery i'm disappointed in Tarantino and Avery for doing this film but doesn't change my mind on how amazing they both are. everyone makes mistakes......... 3/10...........j.d Seaton
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drugs & bullets....that's all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kshitij (axile007)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe revolves around Zed who was invited to Paris to contribute in a bank robbery.Unfortunately that's all the story plot contains. Rest is all about unnecessary violence which really don't make any sense. There's been also some scenes of drugs depiction and consumption.Also there is no twist in storyline,weak plot and very predictable. The only strong link of the movie is the presence of Julie Delphy who looked extremely charming. Its obvious to expect more from this movie but it do not stands anywhere around its expectations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid exploitation art-house thriller, though not without flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonymurphylee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eric Stoltz plays a man named Zed who travels to Paris in order to catch up with a childhood friend named Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) and help him rob a Federal Reserve bank. Upon his arrival, he sleeps with a call girl named Zoe (Julie Delpy) who he ends up falling in love with. When Zed goes to meet Eric, he ends up spending the night with him and all of his junkie friends who hide out in a run down apartment building with a dead feline near the entrance to their room. They plan to rob the bank the next morning, and Zed is going to be the safe cracker. After much passing out, puking, hallucinating, and a male rape, Zed and the rest of the gang awaken in a drunken daze, already late for their robbery, and then they foolishly attempt to rob the bank while still moderately trashed, hungover, and restless. Naturally things go very wrong very fast, and it becomes no longer about getting the money, but more about trying to survive. If Roger Avary's intention was to make a truly memorable art house exploitation film, he succeeded with flying colors. I'm pretty sure that this was intention and there's no denying that this is a good film. I have some serious problems with Killing Zoe, however, and those problems have much to do with the first two thirds of the picture. Avary spends a very large portion of the film in this junkie world with these truly atrocious and ugly characters doing ugly things. I felt that too much time was spent in this world. The only likable character is Julie Delpy's character, and she doesn't get nearly enough screen time as she should. As for Eric Stoltz, he pretty much plays the same character as he played in Pulp Fiction, though not anywhere near as much as a prick. His character, Zed, for the most part is a fairly goofy, eccentric, and slight perverted guy. I liked how he wasn't an entirely sympathetic protagonist. His character, for the most part, works. Likewise for his friend Eric, who is a completely horrific villain. He's disgusting, sleazy, skeletal-looking, and a sweaty mess of a man who has little conscience and no morals, and I applaud Jean-Hugues Anglade for playing a role that few actors would have the balls to play. This brings me to my biggest gripe with the film, however. These are the three main characters, but they are also the three most interesting characters as well. Every other character is completely disposable they take up far too much screen time that should have been devoted to the three main characters. To make matters worse, in the third act of the film when the characters actually try to rob the bank, a good portion of all of these characters are killed off almost immediately. While I applaud Roger Avary for crafting such a strong vision of graphic carnage in the third act, I felt that he was betraying the trash quality that took place in the first two acts with these junkie characters getting slaughtered so damn quickly. As the last act of the film stands, most of the characters end up getting killed off almost constantly and with little to no emotion. When it is not a member of the gang getting killed it is either a security guard or an innocent civilian. Somebody is almost always getting killed, often in over-the-top fashion. What I did love about Killing Zoe was the look of the film. The bank that the film takes place in during the final act is just gorgeous in how claustrophobic it is. The walls of the bank are red, and it only adds to the psychotic nature of the Eric character. The character really is quite terrifying, and the bank that Avary shot in has a perfect interior for these sort of characters. The middle section mostly takes place in real grimy, dirty, dark areas that look completely hellish. Somehow the bank looks like a scarier location than the junkie hideouts, and I liked that. The opening and closing scenes show some beautiful shots of Paris as well, which definitely helped elevate the film even more. I also felt that the final act of the film, despite the gratuitous bloodshed and carnage, really was quite suspenseful and intense. The film is so furious in it's tone and the final act really pulls it all together. At times it is difficult to watch because the audience knows right away that the situation is going to go wrong and the characters are doomed. When the bank robbery actually starts, it is so disorganized and so uncoordinated that a feeling of unhinged maniacal danger sets in immediately. It makes the film a little bit different from other heist films. The characters are all young, hapless, and careless people who have abandoned reality. Killing Zoe lacks a sense of control, which both helps and hurts the film. On one hand, it certainly helps make the final act of the film that much more shocking and realistic. On the other hand, it is difficult to look part the first two thirds of the film. I do think that this film has an audience, but I also think that it's difficult to call it a good film. It works in a lot of ways. Visually, it's better than it needs to be. The performances are all very strong, not to mention ballsy, and the vision of hell this film paints is pretty tough to shake. It's a rough film, but it manages to have a lot of energy. It is a very flawed film. However, if you're a fan of trash cinema and exploitation, you may want to give this a try. It's a messy film, but it's effective and definitely memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloody and entertaining, sometimes both but never uninteresting or un-engaging.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is an energy behind Killing Zoe, there is a passion and a commitment from its director behind Killing Zoe and that is to make a fast, furious and bloody film that entertains as well as shocks in equal measure. Given the situation regarding this film's production, the film comes across upon reading the pre-production stage as a bit of an accident. Whilst scouting for locations for Reservoir Dogs, director Roger Avary would discover a place where a 'perfect' heist film could take place. Since the whole gimmick (in the nicest possible way) for Reservoir Dogs is that it's a heist film without the heist, the bank couldn't really be used but it suited Avary's other script he had going and that was Killing Zoe. An interesting back-story to a film that is never anything but interesting, apart from perhaps being entertaining at certain points. For Reservoir Dogs to take a mere two years before it itself would become a victim of a pastiche is testament to Reservoir Dog's influential power as well as Avary's own passion and drive behind this production. Notice how the script supposedly took a week to write, also. The film revolves predominantly around a heist going on in a French bank in which master safecracker Zed (Stoltz) is working with an old French buddy who also just happens to be a heroin addict and a psychopathic criminal, amongst other things. He is Eric (Anglade) and is played with ruthless efficiency by the respective French actor. But Killing Zoe is not another routine heist film. Killing Zoe spells out all the tiny, painstaking details that go with robbing a bank and it utilises the conventional 'race against time' drive. Amongst other things, the guys will have to go through each hostage one by one in order to get codes, they will have to pass the time in the main office while other robbers work downstairs on the vault and they will have to deal with any security guards they might miss once entering new bank owned territory. But that's the joy of Killing Zoe. Once it all gets up and running, there is no going back. It is a roller-coaster of violence, disturbance and dark, dark humour that isn't over until it's over. The film is all about stealing and mugging. Zed is the perfect 'fish out of water': an American in Paris; an American in France; an American in Europe. One of the first scenes of the film has a porter stand there and accept a tip that is probably too much; Zed is being 'robbed'. Then there is Zoe (Delpy) herself who charges a thousand Francs for sex but maintains she is no prostitute. "In that case, can I have my money back?" wise-cracks Zed but if you go by her convincing analysis of what she is, she is right and thus has got herself some money not through stealing but in a slimy working way. Similar to the porter who gets extra cash bringing up bags and Zoe acting as a prostitute for money, Zed and his group of cronies are breaking into banks; breaking into vaults and trying to steal the cash that they probably all think they earn by doing this. With this reading, the film is about greed. Then there are the influences of other work made by Tarantino and Avary round about the time. The sex scene between Zed and Zoe is inter-cut with images from the Nosferatu film echoing the technique used in Natural Born Killers; a film Tarantino wrote but disowned. There is also the establishment of a genuine love affair between a male lead and a prostitute echoing True Romance of the previous year, another Tarantino penned film. So if Zed is established as this lost soul as an American in France, it is because he is mugged out of a thousand Francs from a girl who isn't selling herself; he is never given the time in plain English and is informed by Eric about how wrong foreign people are when it comes to French iconography and tourism. But when push comes to shove and he is placed in his 'zone', Zed performs. This is first followed through when he looks at a map of the bank and comes up with an alternate plan that will save them time as well as possible trouble  he has solved the robbers a problem. Killing Zoe is a film that although is American, does not conform to European stereotypes just archetypes the genre demands. The French are not buffoons, the Englishman played by Gary Kemp is not a total idiot and if anything they are all a match for one another with the Zed, the American, himself sticking out for ridicule thanks to the evidence mentioned in the previous paragraph. Eric is a psychotic criminal into hard drugs and homicide, he would also rather blow someone up than shoot them in the vault. The film is one that does not start off with typical French iconography of whatever you like but stays a ground level, literally. The fast moving cars and sense of travelling kicks the film off perfectly and with a good guy to root for, a love story cleverly thrown in and an awesome bad guy, it is no surprise the film maintains that air of near perfection throughout.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From badly executed drama to funny gangster comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryu_Darkwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can completely skip the boring and utterly annoying first hour to go to the second half. The drama in it is really lame. They try to spice it up with controversial topics ( AIDS, hookers ) but in the end that is just to cover up the lack of good ideas to make an innovative action movie. From a bad executed drama it suddenly turns into a nice gangster comedy like Reservoir Dogs. Everything just leads up to the robbing of the bank and the dark humor that goes along with it. Okay, so it's all a bit clich&eacute;d, but who cares...? This is not world class cinema, but it is good enough for a boring Saturday eve. Just don't watch it with too many expectations. And don't think that something produced by Tarantino makes it into a new Pulp Fiction, it just doesn't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to make a Parisian Film in Los Angeles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a lot of Tarintino influence in it, especially as he helped director Roger Avary make it. Like From Dusk Til Dawn, Killing Zoe spends the first half of the movie setting the scene and the rest of the movie with the action. Killing Zoe is a low budget film made in Los Angeles with a few Parisian shots. This is also Avary's first movie and I think he has some talent. Zed (Eric Stolz) has been invited to Paris by an old friend, Eric (Jean-Hughes Anglade) to crack a safe in a bank. Zed is a professional, and we see this as he sets to work opening a safe, yet he is a quiet humble man who prefers to make love than to kill. He is also a man who is easily manipulated and Eric does this quite regularly in the movie. We see Zed being forced into taking drugs and having women dragged away from him because Eric doesn't particularly like them. He is also taken of a tour through a very dark side of Paris where we see drugs, sleazy women, and men screwing like animal (I use such terminology because it is only for the selfish desire of pleasure). The next day, Bastille Day, he then must participate in a daring bank robbery. Daring because everybody is hung over, or still on drugs; it is a high security bank; and it seems very little planning has gone into it. Eric is not the typical Hollywood robber. He kills at a whim and has no preferences to who he will kill. He murders a woman and a man and lets another man go free. In fact Eric seems to have a thing against women as he brutally throws Zoe (Julie Delpy) out of the room when he first meets Zed and throws another whore across the room when she tries to seduce Zed (even though he cannot understand her). He kills people on a whim and represents the worst that humanity can offer. Zoe is another character who begins as a prostitute yet does not want to think of herself as one. She needs to money to get through school and just considers the job as a little thing on the side. Yet she knows what she is, and even though she considers herself beautiful and refined, everybody else treats her as a whore. The reality of what she does hits home when she listens to three men tell a joke about a whore. Killing Zoe is a reasonable movie and good for a low budget production. Much of the movie was spoken in French which is supposed to reflect the fact that it was in France, but this didn't irritate me as it did in Stargate when everybody spoke ancient Egyptian. Still it is a good movie and worth a watch if you can handle drugs and brutal violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad kill from Quentin's mate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On my view, I do admit I was a bit disappointed. Give it a few views, I was entertained intensely. First we have Paris, one of the most beautiful cities of the world, though we don't get to see much of it in this. Granted, this is no Pulp Fiction, some of it's dialogue with it's intellectual humor, leads us to question Quentin might of got his pen a little wet here. Like Reservoir Dogs, we have a heist gone wrong, amidst a little frank and shocking violence. (Eric) Jean Hughes Anglande has invited a childhood friend over, safe cracker Zed (Stoltz) he hasn't seen in some time. They're to do over a big bank on Bastille day, where the night before they get on the p**s and H, so obviously we're in the hand of some real experts. This too becomes a shock to Zed, who's only given a day's notice, not even having time to checked the bank out. In part, as seen to the amateur display of activities by our thieves, in these ugly masks, you could silently label this as an anti drug movie. Now here's the fun angle to the title. On the day of Zed's arrival, he's sent an escort, Zoe, (Julie Delpy) who just happens to work at the same bank, they do over, where Zed caught at a pivotal moment, towards it's end, is forced to make a choice, and I did too like the way it ended. Too, Eric's drunken admittance of aids, to Zed, made sense in the way he literally shoved Zoe out of his room, after the two's little interlude. Loved the cool opening plus it's title song, where were shown numerous streets of Paris, as if from a driver's POV. I loved the end song too, with Delpy saying "Let me show you the real Paris". Also Stoltz's whacked out POV, of visible music tunes, drifting out of friend, Anglande's trumpet. Not for all Tarantino fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of 2 haves.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KILLING ZOE I liked it... but it was a film of 2 halves. The first half of the movie was just average at best. A group of people that get together to arrange a bank robbery, but most of the first 45 minutes was just them getting wasted on drugs and messing about around Paris. This part of the movie dragged on a bit. It was OK, but more could have happened. But the second half was awesome. The bank robbery. When the entered the bank, the movie really picked up the pace. Zoe is the receptionist in the bank that the group hold up...the problem is, Zoe is also a hooker that one of the robbers has fallen in love with. He didn't know she worked there. The cast was good though. Eric Stoltz, Jean-Hughes Anglade & Julie Delpy really do well. I connected with the characters these guys played. There were even some good supporting roles too. Especially Gary Kemp. Who would have known that the guy from Spandau Ballet could be a good actor. He was really good in the Krays too. There was one scene in the movie though that made me laugh. Someone gets shot and has about 200 bullets shot at him from a few guns all at the same time... yet he did not go down! He still stood there for about 30 seconds after. I am pretty sure he would have gone down a long time after that. Also, there is a brilliant comical scene with a cat. :) There was a really good raw feel to this movie that I loved... Tarantino usually has that feel with his films. I suppose this has it because he was Executive Producer. All in all this film was good. I will give it 7 out of 10. A slow first half, but a great second half and ending. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of best ways to kill 90 minutes of your life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    K V
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is exceptional. In same way Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction are. Story is well thought out, down to the point, not all characters are fleshed out (Reservoir Dogs does fleshing out much better), but they are not meant to be for reasons that become obvious once you watch the movie. Acting is superb. Casting is great. Story is believable. Ending is perhaps predictable (or I saw too many movies, perhaps both), but it is fitting. There should be lot more movies like this one. A rare gem! This movie had rating of 6.4, I gave it a 10. I don't really understand why would anybody give it less than 8. If you are not into genre, don't watch the movie, or at least don't rate it down for all the wrong reasons. I rate movies either 1 or 10 for very simple reason. All the other numbers are meaningless. I either recommend you see a movie, or advise you to stay away as when compared to other movies of its type falls too short to bother with. I neither rate, not review average movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe Since banks aren't open past 5 p.m., if you're a moonlighting bank robber, you're going to have to take time off work. Fortunately, the bandits in this bank heist were born into a life of crime. In Paris to assist his old friend Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) with a job, American safecracker Zed (Eric Stoltz) kills time with a prostitute, Zoe (Julie Delpy), whom he shares an instant rapport with. The two lovers are later reunited when a masked Zed holds up the bank where Zoe works. Compelled to protect her from the erratic Eric, who has instigated a gunfight with Paris' finest, Zed puts his lifelong friendship with Eric as well as his own life on the line. Truly a hidden heist gem, Killing Zoe is an innovative and intriguing investment that gains greater interest with each viewing. However, robbing banks is now futile since no one has any money. (Green Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i was expecting so much more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    i_love_chaos
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    with this film being directed by Roger Avery and Quentin Tarantino doing the screenplay i was sure this was going to be a gem. i was wrong. i don't hate this film but in no ways do i like it. i love Roger Avery because of his amazing direction in rules of attraction and his screenplays to pulp fiction and silent hill but he made a mistake making this. do i really need to comment on Tarantino, we all know hes a genius. this movie is just set around a gang robbing a bank but fails due to silly people participating in the robbery i'm disappointed in Tarantino and Avery for doing this film but doesn't change my mind on how amazing they both are. everyone makes mistakes......... 3/10...........j.d Seaton
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drugs & bullets....that's all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kshitij (axile007)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe revolves around Zed who was invited to Paris to contribute in a bank robbery.Unfortunately that's all the story plot contains. Rest is all about unnecessary violence which really don't make any sense. There's been also some scenes of drugs depiction and consumption.Also there is no twist in storyline,weak plot and very predictable. The only strong link of the movie is the presence of Julie Delphy who looked extremely charming. Its obvious to expect more from this movie but it do not stands anywhere around its expectations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid exploitation art-house thriller, though not without flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonymurphylee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eric Stoltz plays a man named Zed who travels to Paris in order to catch up with a childhood friend named Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) and help him rob a Federal Reserve bank. Upon his arrival, he sleeps with a call girl named Zoe (Julie Delpy) who he ends up falling in love with. When Zed goes to meet Eric, he ends up spending the night with him and all of his junkie friends who hide out in a run down apartment building with a dead feline near the entrance to their room. They plan to rob the bank the next morning, and Zed is going to be the safe cracker. After much passing out, puking, hallucinating, and a male rape, Zed and the rest of the gang awaken in a drunken daze, already late for their robbery, and then they foolishly attempt to rob the bank while still moderately trashed, hungover, and restless. Naturally things go very wrong very fast, and it becomes no longer about getting the money, but more about trying to survive. If Roger Avary's intention was to make a truly memorable art house exploitation film, he succeeded with flying colors. I'm pretty sure that this was intention and there's no denying that this is a good film. I have some serious problems with Killing Zoe, however, and those problems have much to do with the first two thirds of the picture. Avary spends a very large portion of the film in this junkie world with these truly atrocious and ugly characters doing ugly things. I felt that too much time was spent in this world. The only likable character is Julie Delpy's character, and she doesn't get nearly enough screen time as she should. As for Eric Stoltz, he pretty much plays the same character as he played in Pulp Fiction, though not anywhere near as much as a prick. His character, Zed, for the most part is a fairly goofy, eccentric, and slight perverted guy. I liked how he wasn't an entirely sympathetic protagonist. His character, for the most part, works. Likewise for his friend Eric, who is a completely horrific villain. He's disgusting, sleazy, skeletal-looking, and a sweaty mess of a man who has little conscience and no morals, and I applaud Jean-Hugues Anglade for playing a role that few actors would have the balls to play. This brings me to my biggest gripe with the film, however. These are the three main characters, but they are also the three most interesting characters as well. Every other character is completely disposable they take up far too much screen time that should have been devoted to the three main characters. To make matters worse, in the third act of the film when the characters actually try to rob the bank, a good portion of all of these characters are killed off almost immediately. While I applaud Roger Avary for crafting such a strong vision of graphic carnage in the third act, I felt that he was betraying the trash quality that took place in the first two acts with these junkie characters getting slaughtered so damn quickly. As the last act of the film stands, most of the characters end up getting killed off almost constantly and with little to no emotion. When it is not a member of the gang getting killed it is either a security guard or an innocent civilian. Somebody is almost always getting killed, often in over-the-top fashion. What I did love about Killing Zoe was the look of the film. The bank that the film takes place in during the final act is just gorgeous in how claustrophobic it is. The walls of the bank are red, and it only adds to the psychotic nature of the Eric character. The character really is quite terrifying, and the bank that Avary shot in has a perfect interior for these sort of characters. The middle section mostly takes place in real grimy, dirty, dark areas that look completely hellish. Somehow the bank looks like a scarier location than the junkie hideouts, and I liked that. The opening and closing scenes show some beautiful shots of Paris as well, which definitely helped elevate the film even more. I also felt that the final act of the film, despite the gratuitous bloodshed and carnage, really was quite suspenseful and intense. The film is so furious in it's tone and the final act really pulls it all together. At times it is difficult to watch because the audience knows right away that the situation is going to go wrong and the characters are doomed. When the bank robbery actually starts, it is so disorganized and so uncoordinated that a feeling of unhinged maniacal danger sets in immediately. It makes the film a little bit different from other heist films. The characters are all young, hapless, and careless people who have abandoned reality. Killing Zoe lacks a sense of control, which both helps and hurts the film. On one hand, it certainly helps make the final act of the film that much more shocking and realistic. On the other hand, it is difficult to look part the first two thirds of the film. I do think that this film has an audience, but I also think that it's difficult to call it a good film. It works in a lot of ways. Visually, it's better than it needs to be. The performances are all very strong, not to mention ballsy, and the vision of hell this film paints is pretty tough to shake. It's a rough film, but it manages to have a lot of energy. It is a very flawed film. However, if you're a fan of trash cinema and exploitation, you may want to give this a try. It's a messy film, but it's effective and definitely memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloody and entertaining, sometimes both but never uninteresting or un-engaging.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is an energy behind Killing Zoe, there is a passion and a commitment from its director behind Killing Zoe and that is to make a fast, furious and bloody film that entertains as well as shocks in equal measure. Given the situation regarding this film's production, the film comes across upon reading the pre-production stage as a bit of an accident. Whilst scouting for locations for Reservoir Dogs, director Roger Avary would discover a place where a 'perfect' heist film could take place. Since the whole gimmick (in the nicest possible way) for Reservoir Dogs is that it's a heist film without the heist, the bank couldn't really be used but it suited Avary's other script he had going and that was Killing Zoe. An interesting back-story to a film that is never anything but interesting, apart from perhaps being entertaining at certain points. For Reservoir Dogs to take a mere two years before it itself would become a victim of a pastiche is testament to Reservoir Dog's influential power as well as Avary's own passion and drive behind this production. Notice how the script supposedly took a week to write, also. The film revolves predominantly around a heist going on in a French bank in which master safecracker Zed (Stoltz) is working with an old French buddy who also just happens to be a heroin addict and a psychopathic criminal, amongst other things. He is Eric (Anglade) and is played with ruthless efficiency by the respective French actor. But Killing Zoe is not another routine heist film. Killing Zoe spells out all the tiny, painstaking details that go with robbing a bank and it utilises the conventional 'race against time' drive. Amongst other things, the guys will have to go through each hostage one by one in order to get codes, they will have to pass the time in the main office while other robbers work downstairs on the vault and they will have to deal with any security guards they might miss once entering new bank owned territory. But that's the joy of Killing Zoe. Once it all gets up and running, there is no going back. It is a roller-coaster of violence, disturbance and dark, dark humour that isn't over until it's over. The film is all about stealing and mugging. Zed is the perfect 'fish out of water': an American in Paris; an American in France; an American in Europe. One of the first scenes of the film has a porter stand there and accept a tip that is probably too much; Zed is being 'robbed'. Then there is Zoe (Delpy) herself who charges a thousand Francs for sex but maintains she is no prostitute. "In that case, can I have my money back?" wise-cracks Zed but if you go by her convincing analysis of what she is, she is right and thus has got herself some money not through stealing but in a slimy working way. Similar to the porter who gets extra cash bringing up bags and Zoe acting as a prostitute for money, Zed and his group of cronies are breaking into banks; breaking into vaults and trying to steal the cash that they probably all think they earn by doing this. With this reading, the film is about greed. Then there are the influences of other work made by Tarantino and Avary round about the time. The sex scene between Zed and Zoe is inter-cut with images from the Nosferatu film echoing the technique used in Natural Born Killers; a film Tarantino wrote but disowned. There is also the establishment of a genuine love affair between a male lead and a prostitute echoing True Romance of the previous year, another Tarantino penned film. So if Zed is established as this lost soul as an American in France, it is because he is mugged out of a thousand Francs from a girl who isn't selling herself; he is never given the time in plain English and is informed by Eric about how wrong foreign people are when it comes to French iconography and tourism. But when push comes to shove and he is placed in his 'zone', Zed performs. This is first followed through when he looks at a map of the bank and comes up with an alternate plan that will save them time as well as possible trouble  he has solved the robbers a problem. Killing Zoe is a film that although is American, does not conform to European stereotypes just archetypes the genre demands. The French are not buffoons, the Englishman played by Gary Kemp is not a total idiot and if anything they are all a match for one another with the Zed, the American, himself sticking out for ridicule thanks to the evidence mentioned in the previous paragraph. Eric is a psychotic criminal into hard drugs and homicide, he would also rather blow someone up than shoot them in the vault. The film is one that does not start off with typical French iconography of whatever you like but stays a ground level, literally. The fast moving cars and sense of travelling kicks the film off perfectly and with a good guy to root for, a love story cleverly thrown in and an awesome bad guy, it is no surprise the film maintains that air of near perfection throughout.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From badly executed drama to funny gangster comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryu_Darkwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can completely skip the boring and utterly annoying first hour to go to the second half. The drama in it is really lame. They try to spice it up with controversial topics ( AIDS, hookers ) but in the end that is just to cover up the lack of good ideas to make an innovative action movie. From a bad executed drama it suddenly turns into a nice gangster comedy like Reservoir Dogs. Everything just leads up to the robbing of the bank and the dark humor that goes along with it. Okay, so it's all a bit clich&eacute;d, but who cares...? This is not world class cinema, but it is good enough for a boring Saturday eve. Just don't watch it with too many expectations. And don't think that something produced by Tarantino makes it into a new Pulp Fiction, it just doesn't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to make a Parisian Film in Los Angeles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a lot of Tarintino influence in it, especially as he helped director Roger Avary make it. Like From Dusk Til Dawn, Killing Zoe spends the first half of the movie setting the scene and the rest of the movie with the action. Killing Zoe is a low budget film made in Los Angeles with a few Parisian shots. This is also Avary's first movie and I think he has some talent. Zed (Eric Stolz) has been invited to Paris by an old friend, Eric (Jean-Hughes Anglade) to crack a safe in a bank. Zed is a professional, and we see this as he sets to work opening a safe, yet he is a quiet humble man who prefers to make love than to kill. He is also a man who is easily manipulated and Eric does this quite regularly in the movie. We see Zed being forced into taking drugs and having women dragged away from him because Eric doesn't particularly like them. He is also taken of a tour through a very dark side of Paris where we see drugs, sleazy women, and men screwing like animal (I use such terminology because it is only for the selfish desire of pleasure). The next day, Bastille Day, he then must participate in a daring bank robbery. Daring because everybody is hung over, or still on drugs; it is a high security bank; and it seems very little planning has gone into it. Eric is not the typical Hollywood robber. He kills at a whim and has no preferences to who he will kill. He murders a woman and a man and lets another man go free. In fact Eric seems to have a thing against women as he brutally throws Zoe (Julie Delpy) out of the room when he first meets Zed and throws another whore across the room when she tries to seduce Zed (even though he cannot understand her). He kills people on a whim and represents the worst that humanity can offer. Zoe is another character who begins as a prostitute yet does not want to think of herself as one. She needs to money to get through school and just considers the job as a little thing on the side. Yet she knows what she is, and even though she considers herself beautiful and refined, everybody else treats her as a whore. The reality of what she does hits home when she listens to three men tell a joke about a whore. Killing Zoe is a reasonable movie and good for a low budget production. Much of the movie was spoken in French which is supposed to reflect the fact that it was in France, but this didn't irritate me as it did in Stargate when everybody spoke ancient Egyptian. Still it is a good movie and worth a watch if you can handle drugs and brutal violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad kill from Quentin's mate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On my view, I do admit I was a bit disappointed. Give it a few views, I was entertained intensely. First we have Paris, one of the most beautiful cities of the world, though we don't get to see much of it in this. Granted, this is no Pulp Fiction, some of it's dialogue with it's intellectual humor, leads us to question Quentin might of got his pen a little wet here. Like Reservoir Dogs, we have a heist gone wrong, amidst a little frank and shocking violence. (Eric) Jean Hughes Anglande has invited a childhood friend over, safe cracker Zed (Stoltz) he hasn't seen in some time. They're to do over a big bank on Bastille day, where the night before they get on the p**s and H, so obviously we're in the hand of some real experts. This too becomes a shock to Zed, who's only given a day's notice, not even having time to checked the bank out. In part, as seen to the amateur display of activities by our thieves, in these ugly masks, you could silently label this as an anti drug movie. Now here's the fun angle to the title. On the day of Zed's arrival, he's sent an escort, Zoe, (Julie Delpy) who just happens to work at the same bank, they do over, where Zed caught at a pivotal moment, towards it's end, is forced to make a choice, and I did too like the way it ended. Too, Eric's drunken admittance of aids, to Zed, made sense in the way he literally shoved Zoe out of his room, after the two's little interlude. Loved the cool opening plus it's title song, where were shown numerous streets of Paris, as if from a driver's POV. I loved the end song too, with Delpy saying "Let me show you the real Paris". Also Stoltz's whacked out POV, of visible music tunes, drifting out of friend, Anglande's trumpet. Not for all Tarantino fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of 2 haves.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KILLING ZOE I liked it... but it was a film of 2 halves. The first half of the movie was just average at best. A group of people that get together to arrange a bank robbery, but most of the first 45 minutes was just them getting wasted on drugs and messing about around Paris. This part of the movie dragged on a bit. It was OK, but more could have happened. But the second half was awesome. The bank robbery. When the entered the bank, the movie really picked up the pace. Zoe is the receptionist in the bank that the group hold up...the problem is, Zoe is also a hooker that one of the robbers has fallen in love with. He didn't know she worked there. The cast was good though. Eric Stoltz, Jean-Hughes Anglade & Julie Delpy really do well. I connected with the characters these guys played. There were even some good supporting roles too. Especially Gary Kemp. Who would have known that the guy from Spandau Ballet could be a good actor. He was really good in the Krays too. There was one scene in the movie though that made me laugh. Someone gets shot and has about 200 bullets shot at him from a few guns all at the same time... yet he did not go down! He still stood there for about 30 seconds after. I am pretty sure he would have gone down a long time after that. Also, there is a brilliant comical scene with a cat. :) There was a really good raw feel to this movie that I loved... Tarantino usually has that feel with his films. I suppose this has it because he was Executive Producer. All in all this film was good. I will give it 7 out of 10. A slow first half, but a great second half and ending. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of best ways to kill 90 minutes of your life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    K V
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is exceptional. In same way Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction are. Story is well thought out, down to the point, not all characters are fleshed out (Reservoir Dogs does fleshing out much better), but they are not meant to be for reasons that become obvious once you watch the movie. Acting is superb. Casting is great. Story is believable. Ending is perhaps predictable (or I saw too many movies, perhaps both), but it is fitting. There should be lot more movies like this one. A rare gem! This movie had rating of 6.4, I gave it a 10. I don't really understand why would anybody give it less than 8. If you are not into genre, don't watch the movie, or at least don't rate it down for all the wrong reasons. I rate movies either 1 or 10 for very simple reason. All the other numbers are meaningless. I either recommend you see a movie, or advise you to stay away as when compared to other movies of its type falls too short to bother with. I neither rate, not review average movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe Since banks aren't open past 5 p.m., if you're a moonlighting bank robber, you're going to have to take time off work. Fortunately, the bandits in this bank heist were born into a life of crime. In Paris to assist his old friend Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) with a job, American safecracker Zed (Eric Stoltz) kills time with a prostitute, Zoe (Julie Delpy), whom he shares an instant rapport with. The two lovers are later reunited when a masked Zed holds up the bank where Zoe works. Compelled to protect her from the erratic Eric, who has instigated a gunfight with Paris' finest, Zed puts his lifelong friendship with Eric as well as his own life on the line. Truly a hidden heist gem, Killing Zoe is an innovative and intriguing investment that gains greater interest with each viewing. However, robbing banks is now futile since no one has any money. (Green Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i was expecting so much more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    i_love_chaos
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    with this film being directed by Roger Avery and Quentin Tarantino doing the screenplay i was sure this was going to be a gem. i was wrong. i don't hate this film but in no ways do i like it. i love Roger Avery because of his amazing direction in rules of attraction and his screenplays to pulp fiction and silent hill but he made a mistake making this. do i really need to comment on Tarantino, we all know hes a genius. this movie is just set around a gang robbing a bank but fails due to silly people participating in the robbery i'm disappointed in Tarantino and Avery for doing this film but doesn't change my mind on how amazing they both are. everyone makes mistakes......... 3/10...........j.d Seaton
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drugs & bullets....that's all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kshitij (axile007)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe revolves around Zed who was invited to Paris to contribute in a bank robbery.Unfortunately that's all the story plot contains. Rest is all about unnecessary violence which really don't make any sense. There's been also some scenes of drugs depiction and consumption.Also there is no twist in storyline,weak plot and very predictable. The only strong link of the movie is the presence of Julie Delphy who looked extremely charming. Its obvious to expect more from this movie but it do not stands anywhere around its expectations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid exploitation art-house thriller, though not without flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonymurphylee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eric Stoltz plays a man named Zed who travels to Paris in order to catch up with a childhood friend named Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) and help him rob a Federal Reserve bank. Upon his arrival, he sleeps with a call girl named Zoe (Julie Delpy) who he ends up falling in love with. When Zed goes to meet Eric, he ends up spending the night with him and all of his junkie friends who hide out in a run down apartment building with a dead feline near the entrance to their room. They plan to rob the bank the next morning, and Zed is going to be the safe cracker. After much passing out, puking, hallucinating, and a male rape, Zed and the rest of the gang awaken in a drunken daze, already late for their robbery, and then they foolishly attempt to rob the bank while still moderately trashed, hungover, and restless. Naturally things go very wrong very fast, and it becomes no longer about getting the money, but more about trying to survive. If Roger Avary's intention was to make a truly memorable art house exploitation film, he succeeded with flying colors. I'm pretty sure that this was intention and there's no denying that this is a good film. I have some serious problems with Killing Zoe, however, and those problems have much to do with the first two thirds of the picture. Avary spends a very large portion of the film in this junkie world with these truly atrocious and ugly characters doing ugly things. I felt that too much time was spent in this world. The only likable character is Julie Delpy's character, and she doesn't get nearly enough screen time as she should. As for Eric Stoltz, he pretty much plays the same character as he played in Pulp Fiction, though not anywhere near as much as a prick. His character, Zed, for the most part is a fairly goofy, eccentric, and slight perverted guy. I liked how he wasn't an entirely sympathetic protagonist. His character, for the most part, works. Likewise for his friend Eric, who is a completely horrific villain. He's disgusting, sleazy, skeletal-looking, and a sweaty mess of a man who has little conscience and no morals, and I applaud Jean-Hugues Anglade for playing a role that few actors would have the balls to play. This brings me to my biggest gripe with the film, however. These are the three main characters, but they are also the three most interesting characters as well. Every other character is completely disposable they take up far too much screen time that should have been devoted to the three main characters. To make matters worse, in the third act of the film when the characters actually try to rob the bank, a good portion of all of these characters are killed off almost immediately. While I applaud Roger Avary for crafting such a strong vision of graphic carnage in the third act, I felt that he was betraying the trash quality that took place in the first two acts with these junkie characters getting slaughtered so damn quickly. As the last act of the film stands, most of the characters end up getting killed off almost constantly and with little to no emotion. When it is not a member of the gang getting killed it is either a security guard or an innocent civilian. Somebody is almost always getting killed, often in over-the-top fashion. What I did love about Killing Zoe was the look of the film. The bank that the film takes place in during the final act is just gorgeous in how claustrophobic it is. The walls of the bank are red, and it only adds to the psychotic nature of the Eric character. The character really is quite terrifying, and the bank that Avary shot in has a perfect interior for these sort of characters. The middle section mostly takes place in real grimy, dirty, dark areas that look completely hellish. Somehow the bank looks like a scarier location than the junkie hideouts, and I liked that. The opening and closing scenes show some beautiful shots of Paris as well, which definitely helped elevate the film even more. I also felt that the final act of the film, despite the gratuitous bloodshed and carnage, really was quite suspenseful and intense. The film is so furious in it's tone and the final act really pulls it all together. At times it is difficult to watch because the audience knows right away that the situation is going to go wrong and the characters are doomed. When the bank robbery actually starts, it is so disorganized and so uncoordinated that a feeling of unhinged maniacal danger sets in immediately. It makes the film a little bit different from other heist films. The characters are all young, hapless, and careless people who have abandoned reality. Killing Zoe lacks a sense of control, which both helps and hurts the film. On one hand, it certainly helps make the final act of the film that much more shocking and realistic. On the other hand, it is difficult to look part the first two thirds of the film. I do think that this film has an audience, but I also think that it's difficult to call it a good film. It works in a lot of ways. Visually, it's better than it needs to be. The performances are all very strong, not to mention ballsy, and the vision of hell this film paints is pretty tough to shake. It's a rough film, but it manages to have a lot of energy. It is a very flawed film. However, if you're a fan of trash cinema and exploitation, you may want to give this a try. It's a messy film, but it's effective and definitely memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloody and entertaining, sometimes both but never uninteresting or un-engaging.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is an energy behind Killing Zoe, there is a passion and a commitment from its director behind Killing Zoe and that is to make a fast, furious and bloody film that entertains as well as shocks in equal measure. Given the situation regarding this film's production, the film comes across upon reading the pre-production stage as a bit of an accident. Whilst scouting for locations for Reservoir Dogs, director Roger Avary would discover a place where a 'perfect' heist film could take place. Since the whole gimmick (in the nicest possible way) for Reservoir Dogs is that it's a heist film without the heist, the bank couldn't really be used but it suited Avary's other script he had going and that was Killing Zoe. An interesting back-story to a film that is never anything but interesting, apart from perhaps being entertaining at certain points. For Reservoir Dogs to take a mere two years before it itself would become a victim of a pastiche is testament to Reservoir Dog's influential power as well as Avary's own passion and drive behind this production. Notice how the script supposedly took a week to write, also. The film revolves predominantly around a heist going on in a French bank in which master safecracker Zed (Stoltz) is working with an old French buddy who also just happens to be a heroin addict and a psychopathic criminal, amongst other things. He is Eric (Anglade) and is played with ruthless efficiency by the respective French actor. But Killing Zoe is not another routine heist film. Killing Zoe spells out all the tiny, painstaking details that go with robbing a bank and it utilises the conventional 'race against time' drive. Amongst other things, the guys will have to go through each hostage one by one in order to get codes, they will have to pass the time in the main office while other robbers work downstairs on the vault and they will have to deal with any security guards they might miss once entering new bank owned territory. But that's the joy of Killing Zoe. Once it all gets up and running, there is no going back. It is a roller-coaster of violence, disturbance and dark, dark humour that isn't over until it's over. The film is all about stealing and mugging. Zed is the perfect 'fish out of water': an American in Paris; an American in France; an American in Europe. One of the first scenes of the film has a porter stand there and accept a tip that is probably too much; Zed is being 'robbed'. Then there is Zoe (Delpy) herself who charges a thousand Francs for sex but maintains she is no prostitute. "In that case, can I have my money back?" wise-cracks Zed but if you go by her convincing analysis of what she is, she is right and thus has got herself some money not through stealing but in a slimy working way. Similar to the porter who gets extra cash bringing up bags and Zoe acting as a prostitute for money, Zed and his group of cronies are breaking into banks; breaking into vaults and trying to steal the cash that they probably all think they earn by doing this. With this reading, the film is about greed. Then there are the influences of other work made by Tarantino and Avary round about the time. The sex scene between Zed and Zoe is inter-cut with images from the Nosferatu film echoing the technique used in Natural Born Killers; a film Tarantino wrote but disowned. There is also the establishment of a genuine love affair between a male lead and a prostitute echoing True Romance of the previous year, another Tarantino penned film. So if Zed is established as this lost soul as an American in France, it is because he is mugged out of a thousand Francs from a girl who isn't selling herself; he is never given the time in plain English and is informed by Eric about how wrong foreign people are when it comes to French iconography and tourism. But when push comes to shove and he is placed in his 'zone', Zed performs. This is first followed through when he looks at a map of the bank and comes up with an alternate plan that will save them time as well as possible trouble  he has solved the robbers a problem. Killing Zoe is a film that although is American, does not conform to European stereotypes just archetypes the genre demands. The French are not buffoons, the Englishman played by Gary Kemp is not a total idiot and if anything they are all a match for one another with the Zed, the American, himself sticking out for ridicule thanks to the evidence mentioned in the previous paragraph. Eric is a psychotic criminal into hard drugs and homicide, he would also rather blow someone up than shoot them in the vault. The film is one that does not start off with typical French iconography of whatever you like but stays a ground level, literally. The fast moving cars and sense of travelling kicks the film off perfectly and with a good guy to root for, a love story cleverly thrown in and an awesome bad guy, it is no surprise the film maintains that air of near perfection throughout.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From badly executed drama to funny gangster comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryu_Darkwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can completely skip the boring and utterly annoying first hour to go to the second half. The drama in it is really lame. They try to spice it up with controversial topics ( AIDS, hookers ) but in the end that is just to cover up the lack of good ideas to make an innovative action movie. From a bad executed drama it suddenly turns into a nice gangster comedy like Reservoir Dogs. Everything just leads up to the robbing of the bank and the dark humor that goes along with it. Okay, so it's all a bit clich&eacute;d, but who cares...? This is not world class cinema, but it is good enough for a boring Saturday eve. Just don't watch it with too many expectations. And don't think that something produced by Tarantino makes it into a new Pulp Fiction, it just doesn't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to make a Parisian Film in Los Angeles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a lot of Tarintino influence in it, especially as he helped director Roger Avary make it. Like From Dusk Til Dawn, Killing Zoe spends the first half of the movie setting the scene and the rest of the movie with the action. Killing Zoe is a low budget film made in Los Angeles with a few Parisian shots. This is also Avary's first movie and I think he has some talent. Zed (Eric Stolz) has been invited to Paris by an old friend, Eric (Jean-Hughes Anglade) to crack a safe in a bank. Zed is a professional, and we see this as he sets to work opening a safe, yet he is a quiet humble man who prefers to make love than to kill. He is also a man who is easily manipulated and Eric does this quite regularly in the movie. We see Zed being forced into taking drugs and having women dragged away from him because Eric doesn't particularly like them. He is also taken of a tour through a very dark side of Paris where we see drugs, sleazy women, and men screwing like animal (I use such terminology because it is only for the selfish desire of pleasure). The next day, Bastille Day, he then must participate in a daring bank robbery. Daring because everybody is hung over, or still on drugs; it is a high security bank; and it seems very little planning has gone into it. Eric is not the typical Hollywood robber. He kills at a whim and has no preferences to who he will kill. He murders a woman and a man and lets another man go free. In fact Eric seems to have a thing against women as he brutally throws Zoe (Julie Delpy) out of the room when he first meets Zed and throws another whore across the room when she tries to seduce Zed (even though he cannot understand her). He kills people on a whim and represents the worst that humanity can offer. Zoe is another character who begins as a prostitute yet does not want to think of herself as one. She needs to money to get through school and just considers the job as a little thing on the side. Yet she knows what she is, and even though she considers herself beautiful and refined, everybody else treats her as a whore. The reality of what she does hits home when she listens to three men tell a joke about a whore. Killing Zoe is a reasonable movie and good for a low budget production. Much of the movie was spoken in French which is supposed to reflect the fact that it was in France, but this didn't irritate me as it did in Stargate when everybody spoke ancient Egyptian. Still it is a good movie and worth a watch if you can handle drugs and brutal violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad kill from Quentin's mate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On my view, I do admit I was a bit disappointed. Give it a few views, I was entertained intensely. First we have Paris, one of the most beautiful cities of the world, though we don't get to see much of it in this. Granted, this is no Pulp Fiction, some of it's dialogue with it's intellectual humor, leads us to question Quentin might of got his pen a little wet here. Like Reservoir Dogs, we have a heist gone wrong, amidst a little frank and shocking violence. (Eric) Jean Hughes Anglande has invited a childhood friend over, safe cracker Zed (Stoltz) he hasn't seen in some time. They're to do over a big bank on Bastille day, where the night before they get on the p**s and H, so obviously we're in the hand of some real experts. This too becomes a shock to Zed, who's only given a day's notice, not even having time to checked the bank out. In part, as seen to the amateur display of activities by our thieves, in these ugly masks, you could silently label this as an anti drug movie. Now here's the fun angle to the title. On the day of Zed's arrival, he's sent an escort, Zoe, (Julie Delpy) who just happens to work at the same bank, they do over, where Zed caught at a pivotal moment, towards it's end, is forced to make a choice, and I did too like the way it ended. Too, Eric's drunken admittance of aids, to Zed, made sense in the way he literally shoved Zoe out of his room, after the two's little interlude. Loved the cool opening plus it's title song, where were shown numerous streets of Paris, as if from a driver's POV. I loved the end song too, with Delpy saying "Let me show you the real Paris". Also Stoltz's whacked out POV, of visible music tunes, drifting out of friend, Anglande's trumpet. Not for all Tarantino fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of 2 haves.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KILLING ZOE I liked it... but it was a film of 2 halves. The first half of the movie was just average at best. A group of people that get together to arrange a bank robbery, but most of the first 45 minutes was just them getting wasted on drugs and messing about around Paris. This part of the movie dragged on a bit. It was OK, but more could have happened. But the second half was awesome. The bank robbery. When the entered the bank, the movie really picked up the pace. Zoe is the receptionist in the bank that the group hold up...the problem is, Zoe is also a hooker that one of the robbers has fallen in love with. He didn't know she worked there. The cast was good though. Eric Stoltz, Jean-Hughes Anglade & Julie Delpy really do well. I connected with the characters these guys played. There were even some good supporting roles too. Especially Gary Kemp. Who would have known that the guy from Spandau Ballet could be a good actor. He was really good in the Krays too. There was one scene in the movie though that made me laugh. Someone gets shot and has about 200 bullets shot at him from a few guns all at the same time... yet he did not go down! He still stood there for about 30 seconds after. I am pretty sure he would have gone down a long time after that. Also, there is a brilliant comical scene with a cat. :) There was a really good raw feel to this movie that I loved... Tarantino usually has that feel with his films. I suppose this has it because he was Executive Producer. All in all this film was good. I will give it 7 out of 10. A slow first half, but a great second half and ending. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of best ways to kill 90 minutes of your life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    K V
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is exceptional. In same way Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction are. Story is well thought out, down to the point, not all characters are fleshed out (Reservoir Dogs does fleshing out much better), but they are not meant to be for reasons that become obvious once you watch the movie. Acting is superb. Casting is great. Story is believable. Ending is perhaps predictable (or I saw too many movies, perhaps both), but it is fitting. There should be lot more movies like this one. A rare gem! This movie had rating of 6.4, I gave it a 10. I don't really understand why would anybody give it less than 8. If you are not into genre, don't watch the movie, or at least don't rate it down for all the wrong reasons. I rate movies either 1 or 10 for very simple reason. All the other numbers are meaningless. I either recommend you see a movie, or advise you to stay away as when compared to other movies of its type falls too short to bother with. I neither rate, not review average movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe Since banks aren't open past 5 p.m., if you're a moonlighting bank robber, you're going to have to take time off work. Fortunately, the bandits in this bank heist were born into a life of crime. In Paris to assist his old friend Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) with a job, American safecracker Zed (Eric Stoltz) kills time with a prostitute, Zoe (Julie Delpy), whom he shares an instant rapport with. The two lovers are later reunited when a masked Zed holds up the bank where Zoe works. Compelled to protect her from the erratic Eric, who has instigated a gunfight with Paris' finest, Zed puts his lifelong friendship with Eric as well as his own life on the line. Truly a hidden heist gem, Killing Zoe is an innovative and intriguing investment that gains greater interest with each viewing. However, robbing banks is now futile since no one has any money. (Green Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i was expecting so much more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    i_love_chaos
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    with this film being directed by Roger Avery and Quentin Tarantino doing the screenplay i was sure this was going to be a gem. i was wrong. i don't hate this film but in no ways do i like it. i love Roger Avery because of his amazing direction in rules of attraction and his screenplays to pulp fiction and silent hill but he made a mistake making this. do i really need to comment on Tarantino, we all know hes a genius. this movie is just set around a gang robbing a bank but fails due to silly people participating in the robbery i'm disappointed in Tarantino and Avery for doing this film but doesn't change my mind on how amazing they both are. everyone makes mistakes......... 3/10...........j.d Seaton
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drugs & bullets....that's all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kshitij (axile007)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe revolves around Zed who was invited to Paris to contribute in a bank robbery.Unfortunately that's all the story plot contains. Rest is all about unnecessary violence which really don't make any sense. There's been also some scenes of drugs depiction and consumption.Also there is no twist in storyline,weak plot and very predictable. The only strong link of the movie is the presence of Julie Delphy who looked extremely charming. Its obvious to expect more from this movie but it do not stands anywhere around its expectations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid exploitation art-house thriller, though not without flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonymurphylee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eric Stoltz plays a man named Zed who travels to Paris in order to catch up with a childhood friend named Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) and help him rob a Federal Reserve bank. Upon his arrival, he sleeps with a call girl named Zoe (Julie Delpy) who he ends up falling in love with. When Zed goes to meet Eric, he ends up spending the night with him and all of his junkie friends who hide out in a run down apartment building with a dead feline near the entrance to their room. They plan to rob the bank the next morning, and Zed is going to be the safe cracker. After much passing out, puking, hallucinating, and a male rape, Zed and the rest of the gang awaken in a drunken daze, already late for their robbery, and then they foolishly attempt to rob the bank while still moderately trashed, hungover, and restless. Naturally things go very wrong very fast, and it becomes no longer about getting the money, but more about trying to survive. If Roger Avary's intention was to make a truly memorable art house exploitation film, he succeeded with flying colors. I'm pretty sure that this was intention and there's no denying that this is a good film. I have some serious problems with Killing Zoe, however, and those problems have much to do with the first two thirds of the picture. Avary spends a very large portion of the film in this junkie world with these truly atrocious and ugly characters doing ugly things. I felt that too much time was spent in this world. The only likable character is Julie Delpy's character, and she doesn't get nearly enough screen time as she should. As for Eric Stoltz, he pretty much plays the same character as he played in Pulp Fiction, though not anywhere near as much as a prick. His character, Zed, for the most part is a fairly goofy, eccentric, and slight perverted guy. I liked how he wasn't an entirely sympathetic protagonist. His character, for the most part, works. Likewise for his friend Eric, who is a completely horrific villain. He's disgusting, sleazy, skeletal-looking, and a sweaty mess of a man who has little conscience and no morals, and I applaud Jean-Hugues Anglade for playing a role that few actors would have the balls to play. This brings me to my biggest gripe with the film, however. These are the three main characters, but they are also the three most interesting characters as well. Every other character is completely disposable they take up far too much screen time that should have been devoted to the three main characters. To make matters worse, in the third act of the film when the characters actually try to rob the bank, a good portion of all of these characters are killed off almost immediately. While I applaud Roger Avary for crafting such a strong vision of graphic carnage in the third act, I felt that he was betraying the trash quality that took place in the first two acts with these junkie characters getting slaughtered so damn quickly. As the last act of the film stands, most of the characters end up getting killed off almost constantly and with little to no emotion. When it is not a member of the gang getting killed it is either a security guard or an innocent civilian. Somebody is almost always getting killed, often in over-the-top fashion. What I did love about Killing Zoe was the look of the film. The bank that the film takes place in during the final act is just gorgeous in how claustrophobic it is. The walls of the bank are red, and it only adds to the psychotic nature of the Eric character. The character really is quite terrifying, and the bank that Avary shot in has a perfect interior for these sort of characters. The middle section mostly takes place in real grimy, dirty, dark areas that look completely hellish. Somehow the bank looks like a scarier location than the junkie hideouts, and I liked that. The opening and closing scenes show some beautiful shots of Paris as well, which definitely helped elevate the film even more. I also felt that the final act of the film, despite the gratuitous bloodshed and carnage, really was quite suspenseful and intense. The film is so furious in it's tone and the final act really pulls it all together. At times it is difficult to watch because the audience knows right away that the situation is going to go wrong and the characters are doomed. When the bank robbery actually starts, it is so disorganized and so uncoordinated that a feeling of unhinged maniacal danger sets in immediately. It makes the film a little bit different from other heist films. The characters are all young, hapless, and careless people who have abandoned reality. Killing Zoe lacks a sense of control, which both helps and hurts the film. On one hand, it certainly helps make the final act of the film that much more shocking and realistic. On the other hand, it is difficult to look part the first two thirds of the film. I do think that this film has an audience, but I also think that it's difficult to call it a good film. It works in a lot of ways. Visually, it's better than it needs to be. The performances are all very strong, not to mention ballsy, and the vision of hell this film paints is pretty tough to shake. It's a rough film, but it manages to have a lot of energy. It is a very flawed film. However, if you're a fan of trash cinema and exploitation, you may want to give this a try. It's a messy film, but it's effective and definitely memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloody and entertaining, sometimes both but never uninteresting or un-engaging.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is an energy behind Killing Zoe, there is a passion and a commitment from its director behind Killing Zoe and that is to make a fast, furious and bloody film that entertains as well as shocks in equal measure. Given the situation regarding this film's production, the film comes across upon reading the pre-production stage as a bit of an accident. Whilst scouting for locations for Reservoir Dogs, director Roger Avary would discover a place where a 'perfect' heist film could take place. Since the whole gimmick (in the nicest possible way) for Reservoir Dogs is that it's a heist film without the heist, the bank couldn't really be used but it suited Avary's other script he had going and that was Killing Zoe. An interesting back-story to a film that is never anything but interesting, apart from perhaps being entertaining at certain points. For Reservoir Dogs to take a mere two years before it itself would become a victim of a pastiche is testament to Reservoir Dog's influential power as well as Avary's own passion and drive behind this production. Notice how the script supposedly took a week to write, also. The film revolves predominantly around a heist going on in a French bank in which master safecracker Zed (Stoltz) is working with an old French buddy who also just happens to be a heroin addict and a psychopathic criminal, amongst other things. He is Eric (Anglade) and is played with ruthless efficiency by the respective French actor. But Killing Zoe is not another routine heist film. Killing Zoe spells out all the tiny, painstaking details that go with robbing a bank and it utilises the conventional 'race against time' drive. Amongst other things, the guys will have to go through each hostage one by one in order to get codes, they will have to pass the time in the main office while other robbers work downstairs on the vault and they will have to deal with any security guards they might miss once entering new bank owned territory. But that's the joy of Killing Zoe. Once it all gets up and running, there is no going back. It is a roller-coaster of violence, disturbance and dark, dark humour that isn't over until it's over. The film is all about stealing and mugging. Zed is the perfect 'fish out of water': an American in Paris; an American in France; an American in Europe. One of the first scenes of the film has a porter stand there and accept a tip that is probably too much; Zed is being 'robbed'. Then there is Zoe (Delpy) herself who charges a thousand Francs for sex but maintains she is no prostitute. "In that case, can I have my money back?" wise-cracks Zed but if you go by her convincing analysis of what she is, she is right and thus has got herself some money not through stealing but in a slimy working way. Similar to the porter who gets extra cash bringing up bags and Zoe acting as a prostitute for money, Zed and his group of cronies are breaking into banks; breaking into vaults and trying to steal the cash that they probably all think they earn by doing this. With this reading, the film is about greed. Then there are the influences of other work made by Tarantino and Avary round about the time. The sex scene between Zed and Zoe is inter-cut with images from the Nosferatu film echoing the technique used in Natural Born Killers; a film Tarantino wrote but disowned. There is also the establishment of a genuine love affair between a male lead and a prostitute echoing True Romance of the previous year, another Tarantino penned film. So if Zed is established as this lost soul as an American in France, it is because he is mugged out of a thousand Francs from a girl who isn't selling herself; he is never given the time in plain English and is informed by Eric about how wrong foreign people are when it comes to French iconography and tourism. But when push comes to shove and he is placed in his 'zone', Zed performs. This is first followed through when he looks at a map of the bank and comes up with an alternate plan that will save them time as well as possible trouble  he has solved the robbers a problem. Killing Zoe is a film that although is American, does not conform to European stereotypes just archetypes the genre demands. The French are not buffoons, the Englishman played by Gary Kemp is not a total idiot and if anything they are all a match for one another with the Zed, the American, himself sticking out for ridicule thanks to the evidence mentioned in the previous paragraph. Eric is a psychotic criminal into hard drugs and homicide, he would also rather blow someone up than shoot them in the vault. The film is one that does not start off with typical French iconography of whatever you like but stays a ground level, literally. The fast moving cars and sense of travelling kicks the film off perfectly and with a good guy to root for, a love story cleverly thrown in and an awesome bad guy, it is no surprise the film maintains that air of near perfection throughout.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From badly executed drama to funny gangster comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryu_Darkwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can completely skip the boring and utterly annoying first hour to go to the second half. The drama in it is really lame. They try to spice it up with controversial topics ( AIDS, hookers ) but in the end that is just to cover up the lack of good ideas to make an innovative action movie. From a bad executed drama it suddenly turns into a nice gangster comedy like Reservoir Dogs. Everything just leads up to the robbing of the bank and the dark humor that goes along with it. Okay, so it's all a bit clich&eacute;d, but who cares...? This is not world class cinema, but it is good enough for a boring Saturday eve. Just don't watch it with too many expectations. And don't think that something produced by Tarantino makes it into a new Pulp Fiction, it just doesn't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How to make a Parisian Film in Los Angeles
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film has a lot of Tarintino influence in it, especially as he helped director Roger Avary make it. Like From Dusk Til Dawn, Killing Zoe spends the first half of the movie setting the scene and the rest of the movie with the action. Killing Zoe is a low budget film made in Los Angeles with a few Parisian shots. This is also Avary's first movie and I think he has some talent. Zed (Eric Stolz) has been invited to Paris by an old friend, Eric (Jean-Hughes Anglade) to crack a safe in a bank. Zed is a professional, and we see this as he sets to work opening a safe, yet he is a quiet humble man who prefers to make love than to kill. He is also a man who is easily manipulated and Eric does this quite regularly in the movie. We see Zed being forced into taking drugs and having women dragged away from him because Eric doesn't particularly like them. He is also taken of a tour through a very dark side of Paris where we see drugs, sleazy women, and men screwing like animal (I use such terminology because it is only for the selfish desire of pleasure). The next day, Bastille Day, he then must participate in a daring bank robbery. Daring because everybody is hung over, or still on drugs; it is a high security bank; and it seems very little planning has gone into it. Eric is not the typical Hollywood robber. He kills at a whim and has no preferences to who he will kill. He murders a woman and a man and lets another man go free. In fact Eric seems to have a thing against women as he brutally throws Zoe (Julie Delpy) out of the room when he first meets Zed and throws another whore across the room when she tries to seduce Zed (even though he cannot understand her). He kills people on a whim and represents the worst that humanity can offer. Zoe is another character who begins as a prostitute yet does not want to think of herself as one. She needs to money to get through school and just considers the job as a little thing on the side. Yet she knows what she is, and even though she considers herself beautiful and refined, everybody else treats her as a whore. The reality of what she does hits home when she listens to three men tell a joke about a whore. Killing Zoe is a reasonable movie and good for a low budget production. Much of the movie was spoken in French which is supposed to reflect the fact that it was in France, but this didn't irritate me as it did in Stargate when everybody spoke ancient Egyptian. Still it is a good movie and worth a watch if you can handle drugs and brutal violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad kill from Quentin's mate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PeterMitchell-506-564364
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On my view, I do admit I was a bit disappointed. Give it a few views, I was entertained intensely. First we have Paris, one of the most beautiful cities of the world, though we don't get to see much of it in this. Granted, this is no Pulp Fiction, some of it's dialogue with it's intellectual humor, leads us to question Quentin might of got his pen a little wet here. Like Reservoir Dogs, we have a heist gone wrong, amidst a little frank and shocking violence. (Eric) Jean Hughes Anglande has invited a childhood friend over, safe cracker Zed (Stoltz) he hasn't seen in some time. They're to do over a big bank on Bastille day, where the night before they get on the p**s and H, so obviously we're in the hand of some real experts. This too becomes a shock to Zed, who's only given a day's notice, not even having time to checked the bank out. In part, as seen to the amateur display of activities by our thieves, in these ugly masks, you could silently label this as an anti drug movie. Now here's the fun angle to the title. On the day of Zed's arrival, he's sent an escort, Zoe, (Julie Delpy) who just happens to work at the same bank, they do over, where Zed caught at a pivotal moment, towards it's end, is forced to make a choice, and I did too like the way it ended. Too, Eric's drunken admittance of aids, to Zed, made sense in the way he literally shoved Zoe out of his room, after the two's little interlude. Loved the cool opening plus it's title song, where were shown numerous streets of Paris, as if from a driver's POV. I loved the end song too, with Delpy saying "Let me show you the real Paris". Also Stoltz's whacked out POV, of visible music tunes, drifting out of friend, Anglande's trumpet. Not for all Tarantino fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A film of 2 haves.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KILLING ZOE I liked it... but it was a film of 2 halves. The first half of the movie was just average at best. A group of people that get together to arrange a bank robbery, but most of the first 45 minutes was just them getting wasted on drugs and messing about around Paris. This part of the movie dragged on a bit. It was OK, but more could have happened. But the second half was awesome. The bank robbery. When the entered the bank, the movie really picked up the pace. Zoe is the receptionist in the bank that the group hold up...the problem is, Zoe is also a hooker that one of the robbers has fallen in love with. He didn't know she worked there. The cast was good though. Eric Stoltz, Jean-Hughes Anglade & Julie Delpy really do well. I connected with the characters these guys played. There were even some good supporting roles too. Especially Gary Kemp. Who would have known that the guy from Spandau Ballet could be a good actor. He was really good in the Krays too. There was one scene in the movie though that made me laugh. Someone gets shot and has about 200 bullets shot at him from a few guns all at the same time... yet he did not go down! He still stood there for about 30 seconds after. I am pretty sure he would have gone down a long time after that. Also, there is a brilliant comical scene with a cat. :) There was a really good raw feel to this movie that I loved... Tarantino usually has that feel with his films. I suppose this has it because he was Executive Producer. All in all this film was good. I will give it 7 out of 10. A slow first half, but a great second half and ending. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of best ways to kill 90 minutes of your life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    K V
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is exceptional. In same way Reservoir Dogs and Pulp Fiction are. Story is well thought out, down to the point, not all characters are fleshed out (Reservoir Dogs does fleshing out much better), but they are not meant to be for reasons that become obvious once you watch the movie. Acting is superb. Casting is great. Story is believable. Ending is perhaps predictable (or I saw too many movies, perhaps both), but it is fitting. There should be lot more movies like this one. A rare gem! This movie had rating of 6.4, I gave it a 10. I don't really understand why would anybody give it less than 8. If you are not into genre, don't watch the movie, or at least don't rate it down for all the wrong reasons. I rate movies either 1 or 10 for very simple reason. All the other numbers are meaningless. I either recommend you see a movie, or advise you to stay away as when compared to other movies of its type falls too short to bother with. I neither rate, not review average movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Vidiot Reviews...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe Since banks aren't open past 5 p.m., if you're a moonlighting bank robber, you're going to have to take time off work. Fortunately, the bandits in this bank heist were born into a life of crime. In Paris to assist his old friend Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) with a job, American safecracker Zed (Eric Stoltz) kills time with a prostitute, Zoe (Julie Delpy), whom he shares an instant rapport with. The two lovers are later reunited when a masked Zed holds up the bank where Zoe works. Compelled to protect her from the erratic Eric, who has instigated a gunfight with Paris' finest, Zed puts his lifelong friendship with Eric as well as his own life on the line. Truly a hidden heist gem, Killing Zoe is an innovative and intriguing investment that gains greater interest with each viewing. However, robbing banks is now futile since no one has any money. (Green Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    i was expecting so much more
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    i_love_chaos
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    with this film being directed by Roger Avery and Quentin Tarantino doing the screenplay i was sure this was going to be a gem. i was wrong. i don't hate this film but in no ways do i like it. i love Roger Avery because of his amazing direction in rules of attraction and his screenplays to pulp fiction and silent hill but he made a mistake making this. do i really need to comment on Tarantino, we all know hes a genius. this movie is just set around a gang robbing a bank but fails due to silly people participating in the robbery i'm disappointed in Tarantino and Avery for doing this film but doesn't change my mind on how amazing they both are. everyone makes mistakes......... 3/10...........j.d Seaton
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    drugs & bullets....that's all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kshitij (axile007)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Killing Zoe revolves around Zed who was invited to Paris to contribute in a bank robbery.Unfortunately that's all the story plot contains. Rest is all about unnecessary violence which really don't make any sense. There's been also some scenes of drugs depiction and consumption.Also there is no twist in storyline,weak plot and very predictable. The only strong link of the movie is the presence of Julie Delphy who looked extremely charming. Its obvious to expect more from this movie but it do not stands anywhere around its expectations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A solid exploitation art-house thriller, though not without flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonymurphylee
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Eric Stoltz plays a man named Zed who travels to Paris in order to catch up with a childhood friend named Eric (Jean-Hugues Anglade) and help him rob a Federal Reserve bank. Upon his arrival, he sleeps with a call girl named Zoe (Julie Delpy) who he ends up falling in love with. When Zed goes to meet Eric, he ends up spending the night with him and all of his junkie friends who hide out in a run down apartment building with a dead feline near the entrance to their room. They plan to rob the bank the next morning, and Zed is going to be the safe cracker. After much passing out, puking, hallucinating, and a male rape, Zed and the rest of the gang awaken in a drunken daze, already late for their robbery, and then they foolishly attempt to rob the bank while still moderately trashed, hungover, and restless. Naturally things go very wrong very fast, and it becomes no longer about getting the money, but more about trying to survive. If Roger Avary's intention was to make a truly memorable art house exploitation film, he succeeded with flying colors. I'm pretty sure that this was intention and there's no denying that this is a good film. I have some serious problems with Killing Zoe, however, and those problems have much to do with the first two thirds of the picture. Avary spends a very large portion of the film in this junkie world with these truly atrocious and ugly characters doing ugly things. I felt that too much time was spent in this world. The only likable character is Julie Delpy's character, and she doesn't get nearly enough screen time as she should. As for Eric Stoltz, he pretty much plays the same character as he played in Pulp Fiction, though not anywhere near as much as a prick. His character, Zed, for the most part is a fairly goofy, eccentric, and slight perverted guy. I liked how he wasn't an entirely sympathetic protagonist. His character, for the most part, works. Likewise for his friend Eric, who is a completely horrific villain. He's disgusting, sleazy, skeletal-looking, and a sweaty mess of a man who has little conscience and no morals, and I applaud Jean-Hugues Anglade for playing a role that few actors would have the balls to play. This brings me to my biggest gripe with the film, however. These are the three main characters, but they are also the three most interesting characters as well. Every other character is completely disposable they take up far too much screen time that should have been devoted to the three main characters. To make matters worse, in the third act of the film when the characters actually try to rob the bank, a good portion of all of these characters are killed off almost immediately. While I applaud Roger Avary for crafting such a strong vision of graphic carnage in the third act, I felt that he was betraying the trash quality that took place in the first two acts with these junkie characters getting slaughtered so damn quickly. As the last act of the film stands, most of the characters end up getting killed off almost constantly and with little to no emotion. When it is not a member of the gang getting killed it is either a security guard or an innocent civilian. Somebody is almost always getting killed, often in over-the-top fashion. What I did love about Killing Zoe was the look of the film. The bank that the film takes place in during the final act is just gorgeous in how claustrophobic it is. The walls of the bank are red, and it only adds to the psychotic nature of the Eric character. The character really is quite terrifying, and the bank that Avary shot in has a perfect interior for these sort of characters. The middle section mostly takes place in real grimy, dirty, dark areas that look completely hellish. Somehow the bank looks like a scarier location than the junkie hideouts, and I liked that. The opening and closing scenes show some beautiful shots of Paris as well, which definitely helped elevate the film even more. I also felt that the final act of the film, despite the gratuitous bloodshed and carnage, really was quite suspenseful and intense. The film is so furious in it's tone and the final act really pulls it all together. At times it is difficult to watch because the audience knows right away that the situation is going to go wrong and the characters are doomed. When the bank robbery actually starts, it is so disorganized and so uncoordinated that a feeling of unhinged maniacal danger sets in immediately. It makes the film a little bit different from other heist films. The characters are all young, hapless, and careless people who have abandoned reality. Killing Zoe lacks a sense of control, which both helps and hurts the film. On one hand, it certainly helps make the final act of the film that much more shocking and realistic. On the other hand, it is difficult to look part the first two thirds of the film. I do think that this film has an audience, but I also think that it's difficult to call it a good film. It works in a lot of ways. Visually, it's better than it needs to be. The performances are all very strong, not to mention ballsy, and the vision of hell this film paints is pretty tough to shake. It's a rough film, but it manages to have a lot of energy. It is a very flawed film. However, if you're a fan of trash cinema and exploitation, you may want to give this a try. It's a messy film, but it's effective and definitely memorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloody and entertaining, sometimes both but never uninteresting or un-engaging.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is an energy behind Killing Zoe, there is a passion and a commitment from its director behind Killing Zoe and that is to make a fast, furious and bloody film that entertains as well as shocks in equal measure. Given the situation regarding this film's production, the film comes across upon reading the pre-production stage as a bit of an accident. Whilst scouting for locations for Reservoir Dogs, director Roger Avary would discover a place where a 'perfect' heist film could take place. Since the whole gimmick (in the nicest possible way) for Reservoir Dogs is that it's a heist film without the heist, the bank couldn't really be used but it suited Avary's other script he had going and that was Killing Zoe. An interesting back-story to a film that is never anything but interesting, apart from perhaps being entertaining at certain points. For Reservoir Dogs to take a mere two years before it itself would become a victim of a pastiche is testament to Reservoir Dog's influential power as well as Avary's own passion and drive behind this production. Notice how the script supposedly took a week to write, also. The film revolves predominantly around a heist going on in a French bank in which master safecracker Zed (Stoltz) is working with an old French buddy who also just happens to be a heroin addict and a psychopathic criminal, amongst other things. He is Eric (Anglade) and is played with ruthless efficiency by the respective French actor. But Killing Zoe is not another routine heist film. Killing Zoe spells out all the tiny, painstaking details that go with robbing a bank and it utilises the conventional 'race against time' drive. Amongst other things, the guys will have to go through each hostage one by one in order to get codes, they will have to pass the time in the main office while other robbers work downstairs on the vault and they will have to deal with any security guards they might miss once entering new bank owned territory. But that's the joy of Killing Zoe. Once it all gets up and running, there is no going back. It is a roller-coaster of violence, disturbance and dark, dark humour that isn't over until it's over. The film is all about stealing and mugging. Zed is the perfect 'fish out of water': an American in Paris; an American in France; an American in Europe. One of the first scenes of the film has a porter stand there and accept a tip that is probably too much; Zed is being 'robbed'. Then there is Zoe (Delpy) herself who charges a thousand Francs for sex but maintains she is no prostitute. "In that case, can I have my money back?" wise-cracks Zed but if you go by her convincing analysis of what she is, she is right and thus has got herself some money not through stealing but in a slimy working way. Similar to the porter who gets extra cash bringing up bags and Zoe acting as a prostitute for money, Zed and his group of cronies are breaking into banks; breaking into vaults and trying to steal the cash that they probably all think they earn by doing this. With this reading, the film is about greed. Then there are the influences of other work made by Tarantino and Avary round about the time. The sex scene between Zed and Zoe is inter-cut with images from the Nosferatu film echoing the technique used in Natural Born Killers; a film Tarantino wrote but disowned. There is also the establishment of a genuine love affair between a male lead and a prostitute echoing True Romance of the previous year, another Tarantino penned film. So if Zed is established as this lost soul as an American in France, it is because he is mugged out of a thousand Francs from a girl who isn't selling herself; he is never given the time in plain English and is informed by Eric about how wrong foreign people are when it comes to French iconography and tourism. But when push comes to shove and he is placed in his 'zone', Zed performs. This is first followed through when he looks at a map of the bank and comes up with an alternate plan that will save them time as well as possible trouble  he has solved the robbers a problem. Killing Zoe is a film that although is American, does not conform to European stereotypes just archetypes the genre demands. The French are not buffoons, the Englishman played by Gary Kemp is not a total idiot and if anything they are all a match for one another with the Zed, the American, himself sticking out for ridicule thanks to the evidence mentioned in the previous paragraph. Eric is a psychotic criminal into hard drugs and homicide, he would also rather blow someone up than shoot them in the vault. The film is one that does not start off with typical French iconography of whatever you like but stays a ground level, literally. The fast moving cars and sense of travelling kicks the film off perfectly and with a good guy to root for, a love story cleverly thrown in and an awesome bad guy, it is no surprise the film maintains that air of near perfection throughout.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    From badly executed drama to funny gangster comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ryu_Darkwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can completely skip the boring and utterly annoying first hour to go to the second half. The drama in it is really lame. They try to spice it up with controversial topics ( AIDS, hookers ) but in the end that is just to cover up the lack of good ideas to make an innovative action movie. From a bad executed drama it suddenly turns into a nice gangster comedy like Reservoir Dogs. Everything just leads up to the robbing of the bank and the dark humor that goes along with it. Okay, so it's all a bit clich&eacute;d, but who cares...? This is not world class cinema, but it is good enough for a boring Saturday eve. Just don't watch it with too many expectations. And don't think that something produced by Tarantino makes it into a new Pulp Fiction, it just doesn't.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
