<filme>
 <id>
  95
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0103639
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1992
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Aladdin
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Aladdin, a street urchin, accidentally meets Princess Jasmine, who is in the city undercover. They love each other, but she can only marry a prince.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Aladdin is a street-urchin who lives in a large and busy town long ago with his faithful monkey friend Abu. When Princess Jasmine gets tired of being forced to remain in the palace that overlooks the city, she sneaks out to the marketplace, where she accidentally meets Aladdin. Under the orders of the evil Jafar (the sultan's advisor), Aladdin is thrown in jail and becomes caught up in Jafar's plot to rule the land with the aid of a mysterious lamp. Legend has it that only a person who is a "diamond in the rough" can retrieve the lamp from the Cave of Wonders. Aladdin might fit that description, but that's not enough to marry the princess, who must (by law) marry a prince.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Animation
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   princess
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cave
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   palace
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sultan
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   monkey
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Ron Clements
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   John Musker
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ron Clements
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   John Musker
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Scott Weinger
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robin Williams
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Linda Larkin
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion this film and The Lion King are the best animated films Disney has ever produced. And they're surprisingly similar, yet different enough for us to not get bored even if we watched them back to back. They both deal with the realities of power and the responsibility that comes along with it. In The Lion King, Simba doesn't want the power, he feels like he isn't worthy enough to wield it. Whereas in this film, Aladdin isn't the heir to the power (prophecy notwithstanding), but receives it anyway and is willing to use it, but only to a certain point. And in both films that power falls into the hands of someone who least deserves it, which builds up the main conflict in both films. This is pretty heavy stuff for a film that's aimed primarily for kids, but I absolutely love it because of it. Kids need to learn this stuff sooner or later and I'd personally much rather learn it from a film like this than from bitter experience. And it's not like the whole film is one big gloomfest, designed to depress our kids or to show them material way beyond their years. No, it's bright and festive, pretty to look at with great characters and even greater musical numbers. And the story, based on the old Middle-East tale, is a great one. It has underdogs, it has fight scenes, it has love, betrayal, friendship, magic, wonder, ancient entities, treasure hunts, miracles  it has it all. I fell in love with this film when I first saw it as a kid, and I still love it. It has withstood the test of time and it still remains as one of the best films ever made, animated or live-action. If you haven't seen it already Well, it must have been a nice rock to live under.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End of Disney's Golden Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin, a street urchin, accidentally meets Princess Jasmine, who is in the city undercover. They quickly grow to love each other, but she can only marry a prince. Disney's golden years were 1989-1992, which were unfortunately quite brief. Of course they had hits before that and after that, but for these few years every film was an instant classic. "Aladdin", with its excellent music and the inclusion of Robin Williams, just hit home so hard (and spawned multiple sequels and a television show). How do you critique a film that everyone loves? You simply do not. I guess if I was forced to say anything negative, it would be that Aladdin and Jasmine look a tad too similar and some think they are siblings separated at birth -- and that would not be right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great sense of educational!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film fulling of educational information. Brave, it should be the first, without brave Aladdin cannot play the guardians as fools, he would not bring the lamp out of the hole. Of course, the prince saving the kingdom would not exist. Honest, which is also very indispensable, the second main point in this animation. Abu didn't obey the word and touch a diamond, then they almost died in the hole. Forgetting the promise, Aladdin went to doom and nearly lost everything. Being honest, as the return, it is the forgiveness we see at the end of the story. Contentment, also can be seen from the movie. The fool Jafar failed to learn this, waiting for him is the depriving of freedom the most precious thing to a life. Kindness, which I thought is the first main point showing here makes this film a awesome one. Aladdin is the one who possesses this kind of quality, feeding the street children, making justice for them, saving the princess from blade, and did not be beaten by desire. That is what I thought the most significant quality individual should have. Finally, I want to say, although it is a little bit old animation, please let your children watch it, learn from it, that's the worth of a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Aladdin" is a worthy follow-up to the Disney Studios' previous feature "Beauty and the Beast"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After their previous feature Beauty and the Beast (1991) was the first animated feature in Oscar history to be nominated for Best Picture, the Disney Studios would have a tough act to follow with their next animated picture. In able for this next film to at least be in the same league as Beauty and the Beast, it would have to contain characters, songs, music and a story that are just as memorable as what the prior film offered. As it turns out, the result was the Disney Studio's 31st full-length animated feature, Aladdin (1992). This is another highly entertaining Disney animated feature from the Disney Renaissance which contains pretty much everything you could wish for from a Disney flick whether it would be good laughs, thrilling action, cool animation or awesome songs. We follow a young man named Aladdin and his pet monkey Abu who are sick of being poor and always having to dodge the guards all for the sake of stolen food. They dream that one day they'll be rich enough to put an end to all their troubles. But when they meet a princess named Jasmine who doesn't care for life in the palace because she never goes anywhere and is being forced to marry another prince, things change. After a series of events occur, Aladdin is thrown in the dungeon and a fellow prisoner offers him a way to escape in exchange for doing a task for him. Now, Aladdin has to go to a secret place outside the city of Agrabah called the Cave of Wonders where he must retrieve a magic lamp. This magic lamp contains a highly energetic and fully animated genie (Robin Williams) who can grant Aladdin almost any three wishes he would like. So Aladdin wishes that he was a prince, that way he can try and marry Jasmine. But an evil sorcerer named Jafar and his parrot Iago want Aladdin's lamp and will do anything to get it. Will Aladdin be able to outsmart Jafar and win the princess or not? Want me to summarize why to see Aladdin, if you still haven't, in two words? Well, than those two words would be Robin Williams. Robin Williams was naturally born to voice the genie in this film and I'd guarantee that no matter how hard you tried, you couldn't find another actor that could compete with the high energy and witty comedic style that Williams incorporates into the Genie character. It's been said that much of the dialogue by Robin Williams was improvised or added in even though it wasn't in the original script. To be honest, I couldn't tell the difference between what was and what wasn't in the script since Williams does such a great job at making all of it sound natural. That is precisely how inspired the casting of Robin Williams in this role is. It's not just Williams that makes Aladdin such an entertaining Disney flick, but I also thought that Aladdin and Jasmine had good chemistry between each other. I like the conversations they share with one another regarding how frustrated they are with the lives they're currently living. I don't know about you guys, but when Jasmine basically states that her life of luxury is similar to prison since she can't go outside the palace walls, that's when I thought "maybe being a prince or princess isn't such a good idea". The reason being that in some areas of the world, there's a good possibility that some prince or princess may have no choice but to live that lifestyle. If that somehow wasn't enough to steer you guys away from living a royal life like Jasmine, she's also being forced to get married against her will. Suddenly, a normal lifestyle is sounding excellent to most of us, isn't it? Jafar is another worthy addition to a list of the best Disney villains out there. I admire how he basically enjoys being the most diabolical douchebag to everyone he is around. If there is one thing about some of the greatest Disney villains out there that makes them great including Jafar, it's that they enjoy whatever evil things they're doing. Because they're able to get so much thrill and enjoyment out of what they're doing, that makes us all the more entertained by them in the process. You'll practically love to hate this guy. If there's one thing about this picture that I didn't care for story wise, it would be in regards to Aladdin lying to Jasmine about him being a prince in general. I didn't really care for this part of the story much since most of the dialogue that results from it can be a little too cringe worthy and painfully obvious for my taste. Also, the clich&eacute;d conflict between Aladdin and the genie that results from this part of the story feels forced and unnecessary. I simply felt that it was one routine plot device that didn't need to be in this part of the story at all. Given that it's one of the highest grossing animated features of all time, I think it's safe to say that there's little more to explain about why Aladdin is such a great Disney animated feature. We all know how great the songs by Alan Menken, the late Howard Ashman, and Tim Rice are especially "Friend Like Me", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World". The fast paced, highly energetic, and colorful animation is perfectly suited for a film of this style. I've already gone into detail about Robin Williams' performance, the character of Jafar, and the relationship between Aladdin and Jasmine. You guys have probably seen it many times before, and as far as I'm concerned, you guys deserve to continue seeing it a few times more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watched this Disney's optimal animation in its BluRay form, a stock-in-trade family crowd- pleaser which has been engineered with an impeccable technique and what's more impressive, it oozes an unceasing force of genuineness to edify both children and adults, no condescending doctrine nor feckless naivety, and Robin Williams' voice-performance as the Genie is a great bonus and plays a big part in the film's classic status among its genre. To enumerate Genie's potpourri of imitations alone could be cogent enough to showcase the finesse both for the animators and the voice cast, Robin Williams is deadly hilarious, the motormouthed omnipotent servant, massively steals the thunder from everyone else. But it is not a pejorative remark to other players, on the contrary, it has the most effervescent ensemble including a usually trite class-defying mutual attraction between a princess with a lower-status prince charming. Jafar and Iago pair is another hoot apart from Genie, laughters galore! The plot line entwines pretty much in Disney's safe pattern, a romantic encounter, an abrupt departure, a reunion under the pretense as a legitimate suitor, fighting the evil enemy and happy forever ending, while it really pushes Aladdin to the edge of the cliff since Jafar's invincibility seems to be unbreakable, and the eleventh hour turnover is nothing less than a satisfactory one. 2D animation surely has been largely outcast from the lucrative market, but one can never ascertain there will be a wave of coming back in some years ahead, like Black and White films, their unique aestheticism is the wellspring of their vitality, after watching ALADDIN, it perfectly suffices to originate great mojo of satisfaction for an adult first-time viewer, so the last rites seem to be unnecessary, but a niche market-planning should be conducted for the sake of the laborious craftsmanship. The film currently sits at No.2 at my top 10 film of 1992, and Williams earns him a fifth slot in the supporting actor race, the one and only voice-performance on my own Oscar list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid Gold Disney Classic!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is Disney's 31st full-length animated feature film released in 1992. Based on the popular Arab folktale, the film follows a young peasant boy named Aladdin (voice by Scott Weinger) and his sidekick Abu (voiced by Frank Welker) who are in search of a life outside of the streets from stealing food and dodging guards every day. Then one day, they meet the beautiful Princess Jasmine (voiced by Linda Larkin) in the marketplace and after they save her life, they take her to their place and realize that she wants the exact opposite of what they want; a normal life outside of the palace walls. Then, after Aladdin is thrown into prison by the evil Sorcerer Jafar (voiced by Jonathan Freeman), he is unknowingly taken to the Cave of Wonders by Jafar (disguised as an old beggar man) and his wisecracking sidekick Iago to find an ancient magic lamp that unleashes a genie that grants three wishes. After Aladdin and Abu find the lamp and narrowly escape the Cave on the Magic Carpet, they are thrown back into the cave as it crumbles in the ground. In the process however, Abu grabs the magic lamp, gives it to Aladdin and he accidentally rubs the lamp and unleashes the energetic, hilariously funny Genie (voiced by Robin Williams from "Good Morning, Vietnam", "Mrs. Doubtfire") and chaos ensues!!! This was Disney's fourth film of the Renaissance Era and it's has every element of a classic Disney movie present: great story, unforgettable characters (including one of the best Disney villains of all-time, Jafar), great animation, suspense, great climax, and an awesome score/songs composed by famed Disney composers Alan Menken and Tim Rice (stepping in place of Howard Ashman). The best songs in the movie are "One Jump Ahead", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World", played during the magic carpet ride scene. This is yet another one of my favorite Disney movies and my favorite character is the Genie! If you by any chance haven't seen this classic American animated film in the last 20+ years it's been out, all I have to say is: WATCH IT!!! If you need a good Disney film to watch with the family, then I highly recommend this one! Rating: 10/10!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin belongs to a clan of Disney's magical movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know what Disney is capable of. Disney has produced some of the greatest films of all time like the Lion King but 2 years prior to that, Disney released Aladdin which is also widely regarded as one of Disney's best. Aladdin follows the story of a young streeboy named Aladdin who falls in love with Princess Jasmine and attempts to win her heart by using a genie to make him a prince. However, an evil sorcerer named Jafar is after Aladdin in order to gain his hands on the lamp in order to rule the world and marry Jasmine. Okay, we all know what the story is about and we all know the characters in the film. The story of Aladdin is extremely rich and unforgettable filled with magical characters that just warm our heart. The voice acting is brilliant and it makes for an extremely enjoyable film. The songs in the film aren't as good as, say Beauty and the Beast but they are still pretty remarkable. The script is good and gives us plenty of great laughs. The pacing of the film is brilliant and it never really slows down. In fact, the last twenty minutes is filled with excitement and tension over what will happen. This is definitely a MUST SEE Disney classic for all :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Disney's best post-modern era films of the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I have to admit that I was only born in 1994 when The Lion King was released, but my older sister was born before me in 1992 before Disney released this. Sadly, though, we never saw it in the theaters and waited to watch it on video. Our dreams had finally come true and we loved it as much as anyone else who had seen it and grew up with it. Now, I never read the story "One Thousand Arabian Nights", but I think that this classic did some extreme justice to it. Sure, it does start off a bit slow, but as the film progresses, it has it's heart just in the right place thanks to it's being well thought out. The characters, much like the story, are engaging and likable with the likes of Aladdin, the beautiful Princess Jasmine, Abu, the monkey, Iago, the parrot, the Sultan, Jafar (who is by far one of Disney's best villains in history) and Genie, who, thanks to Robin Williams' solid voice-work, steals every scene with his hilarious moments and the comedy is both timeless and unforgettable. In fact, the voice acting isn't that bad at all especially Scott Weinger, Linda Larkin, Jonathan Freeman, and let's not forget Jim Cummings as the leader of the palace guards. I was like, "Winnie The Pooh/Tigger as a palace guard? Top-notch!" The music from Alan Menken is the epitome of brilliance and the songs were timeless and were not to be long forgotten including one of my favorites "A Whole New World". The script is excellent and flawless with witty and hilarious dialog and the pacing is brisk and moves along very nicely. The strongest aspect, however, goes to the animation due to it's beautiful visual look of Agrabah and solid character designs. Overall, this is one of the few movies that I grew up with as a kid back at the 90s and this will not be forgotten by not only families and their children, but long-time Disney fans as well. Totally recommended and uh... Happy 20th Anniversary, Aladdin!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you never had a friend like me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is a Disney cartoon with a character that we all wish we had as friend, the genie. Aladdin is filled with endless thrills, table turning plans and music that you can't help to like and sing along to. The movie's intro is in form of a narrative, where a merchant tells us the tale of Aladdin and his magic lamp. This 1992 Disney classic is based on an Arab folktale of Aladdin and the magic lamp from One Thousand and One Nights. The idea to make the movie was pitched in by the Late Howard Ashman (who died before the film's release) Ashman has been behind a lot of Disney classics from Oliver & Company, Little Mermaid and Beauty and the Beast. He was a writer, lyricist and producer and he was the lyricist for "Arabian Nights", "Friend Like Me", and "Prince Ali" used in this movie. Aladdin's story is about a street boy, who runs into a princess named Jasmine who escaped the palace to see what life was outside the palace walls where you are not told what to do. While they were together Aladdin gets captured by soldiers under the orders of Jafar, the Grand Vizier to the Sultan of Agrabah (Jasmine's father). Jafar needs Aladdin to retrieve a magical oil lamp containing a genie from the Cave of Wonders. The movie's story now grows on what happened when Jafar didn't get the lamp but Aladdin did in an attempt to read the inscriptions on the lamp, released the genie and he is given 3 wishes. As the song goes, you never had a friend like me So it has been, because all through Disney toon history we never found anyone more appealing to have around, Genie is just the best person to have in at corner. The movie's screenplay explores fantasy, world travel, fireworks and action scenes. Aladdin was a box office hit, making over $ 500 million dollars in its theatrical run and also gave birth to two direct to DVD sequels and a TV series. Aladdin won numerous awards, especially for its music, it won only two Academy Awards, Best Original Score and Best Original Song for "A Whole New World" and it also won four Grammy Awards, Best Soundtrack Album, Song of the Year for "A Whole New World", Best Pop Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal for "A Whole New World" and Best Song Written for a Motion Picture, Television or Other Visual Media for "A Whole New World". Like it or not, Aladdin boast of the best of the best music, and it was also funny and fun to watch, so if you don't own this DVD you Disney collection is not complete yet. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Disney at their finest.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Starr
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like most kids, I also grew up with Disney films, and Aladdin came out the year I was born. However, that did not stop me from watching this film many times during my life. Ever since I was little, this was my favorite Disney movie. This is an excellent film. It teaches great morals, and executes them very well. The story is about Aladdin falling in love with Princess Jasmine, but finds out she can only marry a prince, due to the law. He acquires a lamp with the Genie inside, and he wishes to become a prince, or should I say, look like one. This is my only problem with the film, but this can be overlooked. Why can't he wish he WAS a prince instead of looking like one? But it moves very well into the moral, so I can excuse this. After finding out he would become Sultan after marrying Jasmine, he decides to try and tell her the truth that he's not actually a prince. It's actually before the villain fight and not at the exact end where we have a moral. I like that. He learns that he needs to be truthful, and was trying to tell Jasmine before Jafar exposes him for who he really is. He also learns to keep promises. Before his first wish with the Genie, he promises him he would use his 3rd wish to free him, and even at the end, the Genie tries to talk him into wishing into a prince again, but Aladdin still frees him, despite unlikely being able to marry Jasmine. Nice guy. That is a fantastic way of telling your morals. Not only are the morals amazing, but so are the characters, especially Aladdin himself. He starts off as a homeless person on the streets of Agrabah, but he has very impressive smarts. Not only for thievery, but anything in general. I mainly say this because when he defeats Jafar, he says that the Genie has more power than he does, and he can take away his powers. This convinces Jafar to use his third wish to become a genie himself, but gets stuck in his own lamp. I love this guy. He is the textbook definition of genius. Speaking of smart characters, we also have Jasmine. Her father, the sultan of Agrabah, is trying to rush her into getting married, and tries to bring in many princes to marry her. She hates every single one of them. She doesn't care about the law. If she is to marry, she wants it to be for love. She won't marry anyone. She has to actually care for them. I wouldn't marry someone who attempts to whip little kids either. She also nearly figures out Aladdin not being a prince after the Whole New World song, and Aladdin figures out a good excuse. She's another smart and enjoyable character. I also think she's very hot, but I digress. The most important part of this love story is that the two have great chemistry. They have things in common, and want to help each other out. Not only that, but when Aladdin is Prince Ali, Jasmine actually hates him at first. However, Aladdin builds up the relationship again, and gets Jasmine to fall in love with him again. This may not be on quite the level Beauty and the Beast was with building up a relationship, but it works fine here. Jasmine does suspect that it's actually Aladdin and not a prince before the carpet ride, and she already cared for him, so this is not rushed. It does well for its own love story, but the film is not just that. It's also an adventure, especially since Jafar tries to kill Aladdin a lot. He tries to in the Cave of Wonders when Aladdin is hanging off a cliff and he gets the lamp, he tries to when Aladdin is with Jasmine, and he does after he becomes a sorcerer, along with after Aladdin returns to the palace. In conclusion, the film has many things to like about it. It has many great elements in it, and focuses on them in a very coherent manner. It has a great love story, great adventure, great characters, amazing comic relief, and wonderful animation and colors. This is something you can truly call a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion this film and The Lion King are the best animated films Disney has ever produced. And they're surprisingly similar, yet different enough for us to not get bored even if we watched them back to back. They both deal with the realities of power and the responsibility that comes along with it. In The Lion King, Simba doesn't want the power, he feels like he isn't worthy enough to wield it. Whereas in this film, Aladdin isn't the heir to the power (prophecy notwithstanding), but receives it anyway and is willing to use it, but only to a certain point. And in both films that power falls into the hands of someone who least deserves it, which builds up the main conflict in both films. This is pretty heavy stuff for a film that's aimed primarily for kids, but I absolutely love it because of it. Kids need to learn this stuff sooner or later and I'd personally much rather learn it from a film like this than from bitter experience. And it's not like the whole film is one big gloomfest, designed to depress our kids or to show them material way beyond their years. No, it's bright and festive, pretty to look at with great characters and even greater musical numbers. And the story, based on the old Middle-East tale, is a great one. It has underdogs, it has fight scenes, it has love, betrayal, friendship, magic, wonder, ancient entities, treasure hunts, miracles  it has it all. I fell in love with this film when I first saw it as a kid, and I still love it. It has withstood the test of time and it still remains as one of the best films ever made, animated or live-action. If you haven't seen it already Well, it must have been a nice rock to live under.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End of Disney's Golden Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin, a street urchin, accidentally meets Princess Jasmine, who is in the city undercover. They quickly grow to love each other, but she can only marry a prince. Disney's golden years were 1989-1992, which were unfortunately quite brief. Of course they had hits before that and after that, but for these few years every film was an instant classic. "Aladdin", with its excellent music and the inclusion of Robin Williams, just hit home so hard (and spawned multiple sequels and a television show). How do you critique a film that everyone loves? You simply do not. I guess if I was forced to say anything negative, it would be that Aladdin and Jasmine look a tad too similar and some think they are siblings separated at birth -- and that would not be right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great sense of educational!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film fulling of educational information. Brave, it should be the first, without brave Aladdin cannot play the guardians as fools, he would not bring the lamp out of the hole. Of course, the prince saving the kingdom would not exist. Honest, which is also very indispensable, the second main point in this animation. Abu didn't obey the word and touch a diamond, then they almost died in the hole. Forgetting the promise, Aladdin went to doom and nearly lost everything. Being honest, as the return, it is the forgiveness we see at the end of the story. Contentment, also can be seen from the movie. The fool Jafar failed to learn this, waiting for him is the depriving of freedom the most precious thing to a life. Kindness, which I thought is the first main point showing here makes this film a awesome one. Aladdin is the one who possesses this kind of quality, feeding the street children, making justice for them, saving the princess from blade, and did not be beaten by desire. That is what I thought the most significant quality individual should have. Finally, I want to say, although it is a little bit old animation, please let your children watch it, learn from it, that's the worth of a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Aladdin" is a worthy follow-up to the Disney Studios' previous feature "Beauty and the Beast"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After their previous feature Beauty and the Beast (1991) was the first animated feature in Oscar history to be nominated for Best Picture, the Disney Studios would have a tough act to follow with their next animated picture. In able for this next film to at least be in the same league as Beauty and the Beast, it would have to contain characters, songs, music and a story that are just as memorable as what the prior film offered. As it turns out, the result was the Disney Studio's 31st full-length animated feature, Aladdin (1992). This is another highly entertaining Disney animated feature from the Disney Renaissance which contains pretty much everything you could wish for from a Disney flick whether it would be good laughs, thrilling action, cool animation or awesome songs. We follow a young man named Aladdin and his pet monkey Abu who are sick of being poor and always having to dodge the guards all for the sake of stolen food. They dream that one day they'll be rich enough to put an end to all their troubles. But when they meet a princess named Jasmine who doesn't care for life in the palace because she never goes anywhere and is being forced to marry another prince, things change. After a series of events occur, Aladdin is thrown in the dungeon and a fellow prisoner offers him a way to escape in exchange for doing a task for him. Now, Aladdin has to go to a secret place outside the city of Agrabah called the Cave of Wonders where he must retrieve a magic lamp. This magic lamp contains a highly energetic and fully animated genie (Robin Williams) who can grant Aladdin almost any three wishes he would like. So Aladdin wishes that he was a prince, that way he can try and marry Jasmine. But an evil sorcerer named Jafar and his parrot Iago want Aladdin's lamp and will do anything to get it. Will Aladdin be able to outsmart Jafar and win the princess or not? Want me to summarize why to see Aladdin, if you still haven't, in two words? Well, than those two words would be Robin Williams. Robin Williams was naturally born to voice the genie in this film and I'd guarantee that no matter how hard you tried, you couldn't find another actor that could compete with the high energy and witty comedic style that Williams incorporates into the Genie character. It's been said that much of the dialogue by Robin Williams was improvised or added in even though it wasn't in the original script. To be honest, I couldn't tell the difference between what was and what wasn't in the script since Williams does such a great job at making all of it sound natural. That is precisely how inspired the casting of Robin Williams in this role is. It's not just Williams that makes Aladdin such an entertaining Disney flick, but I also thought that Aladdin and Jasmine had good chemistry between each other. I like the conversations they share with one another regarding how frustrated they are with the lives they're currently living. I don't know about you guys, but when Jasmine basically states that her life of luxury is similar to prison since she can't go outside the palace walls, that's when I thought "maybe being a prince or princess isn't such a good idea". The reason being that in some areas of the world, there's a good possibility that some prince or princess may have no choice but to live that lifestyle. If that somehow wasn't enough to steer you guys away from living a royal life like Jasmine, she's also being forced to get married against her will. Suddenly, a normal lifestyle is sounding excellent to most of us, isn't it? Jafar is another worthy addition to a list of the best Disney villains out there. I admire how he basically enjoys being the most diabolical douchebag to everyone he is around. If there is one thing about some of the greatest Disney villains out there that makes them great including Jafar, it's that they enjoy whatever evil things they're doing. Because they're able to get so much thrill and enjoyment out of what they're doing, that makes us all the more entertained by them in the process. You'll practically love to hate this guy. If there's one thing about this picture that I didn't care for story wise, it would be in regards to Aladdin lying to Jasmine about him being a prince in general. I didn't really care for this part of the story much since most of the dialogue that results from it can be a little too cringe worthy and painfully obvious for my taste. Also, the clich&eacute;d conflict between Aladdin and the genie that results from this part of the story feels forced and unnecessary. I simply felt that it was one routine plot device that didn't need to be in this part of the story at all. Given that it's one of the highest grossing animated features of all time, I think it's safe to say that there's little more to explain about why Aladdin is such a great Disney animated feature. We all know how great the songs by Alan Menken, the late Howard Ashman, and Tim Rice are especially "Friend Like Me", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World". The fast paced, highly energetic, and colorful animation is perfectly suited for a film of this style. I've already gone into detail about Robin Williams' performance, the character of Jafar, and the relationship between Aladdin and Jasmine. You guys have probably seen it many times before, and as far as I'm concerned, you guys deserve to continue seeing it a few times more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watched this Disney's optimal animation in its BluRay form, a stock-in-trade family crowd- pleaser which has been engineered with an impeccable technique and what's more impressive, it oozes an unceasing force of genuineness to edify both children and adults, no condescending doctrine nor feckless naivety, and Robin Williams' voice-performance as the Genie is a great bonus and plays a big part in the film's classic status among its genre. To enumerate Genie's potpourri of imitations alone could be cogent enough to showcase the finesse both for the animators and the voice cast, Robin Williams is deadly hilarious, the motormouthed omnipotent servant, massively steals the thunder from everyone else. But it is not a pejorative remark to other players, on the contrary, it has the most effervescent ensemble including a usually trite class-defying mutual attraction between a princess with a lower-status prince charming. Jafar and Iago pair is another hoot apart from Genie, laughters galore! The plot line entwines pretty much in Disney's safe pattern, a romantic encounter, an abrupt departure, a reunion under the pretense as a legitimate suitor, fighting the evil enemy and happy forever ending, while it really pushes Aladdin to the edge of the cliff since Jafar's invincibility seems to be unbreakable, and the eleventh hour turnover is nothing less than a satisfactory one. 2D animation surely has been largely outcast from the lucrative market, but one can never ascertain there will be a wave of coming back in some years ahead, like Black and White films, their unique aestheticism is the wellspring of their vitality, after watching ALADDIN, it perfectly suffices to originate great mojo of satisfaction for an adult first-time viewer, so the last rites seem to be unnecessary, but a niche market-planning should be conducted for the sake of the laborious craftsmanship. The film currently sits at No.2 at my top 10 film of 1992, and Williams earns him a fifth slot in the supporting actor race, the one and only voice-performance on my own Oscar list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid Gold Disney Classic!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is Disney's 31st full-length animated feature film released in 1992. Based on the popular Arab folktale, the film follows a young peasant boy named Aladdin (voice by Scott Weinger) and his sidekick Abu (voiced by Frank Welker) who are in search of a life outside of the streets from stealing food and dodging guards every day. Then one day, they meet the beautiful Princess Jasmine (voiced by Linda Larkin) in the marketplace and after they save her life, they take her to their place and realize that she wants the exact opposite of what they want; a normal life outside of the palace walls. Then, after Aladdin is thrown into prison by the evil Sorcerer Jafar (voiced by Jonathan Freeman), he is unknowingly taken to the Cave of Wonders by Jafar (disguised as an old beggar man) and his wisecracking sidekick Iago to find an ancient magic lamp that unleashes a genie that grants three wishes. After Aladdin and Abu find the lamp and narrowly escape the Cave on the Magic Carpet, they are thrown back into the cave as it crumbles in the ground. In the process however, Abu grabs the magic lamp, gives it to Aladdin and he accidentally rubs the lamp and unleashes the energetic, hilariously funny Genie (voiced by Robin Williams from "Good Morning, Vietnam", "Mrs. Doubtfire") and chaos ensues!!! This was Disney's fourth film of the Renaissance Era and it's has every element of a classic Disney movie present: great story, unforgettable characters (including one of the best Disney villains of all-time, Jafar), great animation, suspense, great climax, and an awesome score/songs composed by famed Disney composers Alan Menken and Tim Rice (stepping in place of Howard Ashman). The best songs in the movie are "One Jump Ahead", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World", played during the magic carpet ride scene. This is yet another one of my favorite Disney movies and my favorite character is the Genie! If you by any chance haven't seen this classic American animated film in the last 20+ years it's been out, all I have to say is: WATCH IT!!! If you need a good Disney film to watch with the family, then I highly recommend this one! Rating: 10/10!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin belongs to a clan of Disney's magical movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know what Disney is capable of. Disney has produced some of the greatest films of all time like the Lion King but 2 years prior to that, Disney released Aladdin which is also widely regarded as one of Disney's best. Aladdin follows the story of a young streeboy named Aladdin who falls in love with Princess Jasmine and attempts to win her heart by using a genie to make him a prince. However, an evil sorcerer named Jafar is after Aladdin in order to gain his hands on the lamp in order to rule the world and marry Jasmine. Okay, we all know what the story is about and we all know the characters in the film. The story of Aladdin is extremely rich and unforgettable filled with magical characters that just warm our heart. The voice acting is brilliant and it makes for an extremely enjoyable film. The songs in the film aren't as good as, say Beauty and the Beast but they are still pretty remarkable. The script is good and gives us plenty of great laughs. The pacing of the film is brilliant and it never really slows down. In fact, the last twenty minutes is filled with excitement and tension over what will happen. This is definitely a MUST SEE Disney classic for all :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Disney's best post-modern era films of the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I have to admit that I was only born in 1994 when The Lion King was released, but my older sister was born before me in 1992 before Disney released this. Sadly, though, we never saw it in the theaters and waited to watch it on video. Our dreams had finally come true and we loved it as much as anyone else who had seen it and grew up with it. Now, I never read the story "One Thousand Arabian Nights", but I think that this classic did some extreme justice to it. Sure, it does start off a bit slow, but as the film progresses, it has it's heart just in the right place thanks to it's being well thought out. The characters, much like the story, are engaging and likable with the likes of Aladdin, the beautiful Princess Jasmine, Abu, the monkey, Iago, the parrot, the Sultan, Jafar (who is by far one of Disney's best villains in history) and Genie, who, thanks to Robin Williams' solid voice-work, steals every scene with his hilarious moments and the comedy is both timeless and unforgettable. In fact, the voice acting isn't that bad at all especially Scott Weinger, Linda Larkin, Jonathan Freeman, and let's not forget Jim Cummings as the leader of the palace guards. I was like, "Winnie The Pooh/Tigger as a palace guard? Top-notch!" The music from Alan Menken is the epitome of brilliance and the songs were timeless and were not to be long forgotten including one of my favorites "A Whole New World". The script is excellent and flawless with witty and hilarious dialog and the pacing is brisk and moves along very nicely. The strongest aspect, however, goes to the animation due to it's beautiful visual look of Agrabah and solid character designs. Overall, this is one of the few movies that I grew up with as a kid back at the 90s and this will not be forgotten by not only families and their children, but long-time Disney fans as well. Totally recommended and uh... Happy 20th Anniversary, Aladdin!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you never had a friend like me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is a Disney cartoon with a character that we all wish we had as friend, the genie. Aladdin is filled with endless thrills, table turning plans and music that you can't help to like and sing along to. The movie's intro is in form of a narrative, where a merchant tells us the tale of Aladdin and his magic lamp. This 1992 Disney classic is based on an Arab folktale of Aladdin and the magic lamp from One Thousand and One Nights. The idea to make the movie was pitched in by the Late Howard Ashman (who died before the film's release) Ashman has been behind a lot of Disney classics from Oliver & Company, Little Mermaid and Beauty and the Beast. He was a writer, lyricist and producer and he was the lyricist for "Arabian Nights", "Friend Like Me", and "Prince Ali" used in this movie. Aladdin's story is about a street boy, who runs into a princess named Jasmine who escaped the palace to see what life was outside the palace walls where you are not told what to do. While they were together Aladdin gets captured by soldiers under the orders of Jafar, the Grand Vizier to the Sultan of Agrabah (Jasmine's father). Jafar needs Aladdin to retrieve a magical oil lamp containing a genie from the Cave of Wonders. The movie's story now grows on what happened when Jafar didn't get the lamp but Aladdin did in an attempt to read the inscriptions on the lamp, released the genie and he is given 3 wishes. As the song goes, you never had a friend like me So it has been, because all through Disney toon history we never found anyone more appealing to have around, Genie is just the best person to have in at corner. The movie's screenplay explores fantasy, world travel, fireworks and action scenes. Aladdin was a box office hit, making over $ 500 million dollars in its theatrical run and also gave birth to two direct to DVD sequels and a TV series. Aladdin won numerous awards, especially for its music, it won only two Academy Awards, Best Original Score and Best Original Song for "A Whole New World" and it also won four Grammy Awards, Best Soundtrack Album, Song of the Year for "A Whole New World", Best Pop Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal for "A Whole New World" and Best Song Written for a Motion Picture, Television or Other Visual Media for "A Whole New World". Like it or not, Aladdin boast of the best of the best music, and it was also funny and fun to watch, so if you don't own this DVD you Disney collection is not complete yet. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Disney at their finest.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Starr
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like most kids, I also grew up with Disney films, and Aladdin came out the year I was born. However, that did not stop me from watching this film many times during my life. Ever since I was little, this was my favorite Disney movie. This is an excellent film. It teaches great morals, and executes them very well. The story is about Aladdin falling in love with Princess Jasmine, but finds out she can only marry a prince, due to the law. He acquires a lamp with the Genie inside, and he wishes to become a prince, or should I say, look like one. This is my only problem with the film, but this can be overlooked. Why can't he wish he WAS a prince instead of looking like one? But it moves very well into the moral, so I can excuse this. After finding out he would become Sultan after marrying Jasmine, he decides to try and tell her the truth that he's not actually a prince. It's actually before the villain fight and not at the exact end where we have a moral. I like that. He learns that he needs to be truthful, and was trying to tell Jasmine before Jafar exposes him for who he really is. He also learns to keep promises. Before his first wish with the Genie, he promises him he would use his 3rd wish to free him, and even at the end, the Genie tries to talk him into wishing into a prince again, but Aladdin still frees him, despite unlikely being able to marry Jasmine. Nice guy. That is a fantastic way of telling your morals. Not only are the morals amazing, but so are the characters, especially Aladdin himself. He starts off as a homeless person on the streets of Agrabah, but he has very impressive smarts. Not only for thievery, but anything in general. I mainly say this because when he defeats Jafar, he says that the Genie has more power than he does, and he can take away his powers. This convinces Jafar to use his third wish to become a genie himself, but gets stuck in his own lamp. I love this guy. He is the textbook definition of genius. Speaking of smart characters, we also have Jasmine. Her father, the sultan of Agrabah, is trying to rush her into getting married, and tries to bring in many princes to marry her. She hates every single one of them. She doesn't care about the law. If she is to marry, she wants it to be for love. She won't marry anyone. She has to actually care for them. I wouldn't marry someone who attempts to whip little kids either. She also nearly figures out Aladdin not being a prince after the Whole New World song, and Aladdin figures out a good excuse. She's another smart and enjoyable character. I also think she's very hot, but I digress. The most important part of this love story is that the two have great chemistry. They have things in common, and want to help each other out. Not only that, but when Aladdin is Prince Ali, Jasmine actually hates him at first. However, Aladdin builds up the relationship again, and gets Jasmine to fall in love with him again. This may not be on quite the level Beauty and the Beast was with building up a relationship, but it works fine here. Jasmine does suspect that it's actually Aladdin and not a prince before the carpet ride, and she already cared for him, so this is not rushed. It does well for its own love story, but the film is not just that. It's also an adventure, especially since Jafar tries to kill Aladdin a lot. He tries to in the Cave of Wonders when Aladdin is hanging off a cliff and he gets the lamp, he tries to when Aladdin is with Jasmine, and he does after he becomes a sorcerer, along with after Aladdin returns to the palace. In conclusion, the film has many things to like about it. It has many great elements in it, and focuses on them in a very coherent manner. It has a great love story, great adventure, great characters, amazing comic relief, and wonderful animation and colors. This is something you can truly call a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion this film and The Lion King are the best animated films Disney has ever produced. And they're surprisingly similar, yet different enough for us to not get bored even if we watched them back to back. They both deal with the realities of power and the responsibility that comes along with it. In The Lion King, Simba doesn't want the power, he feels like he isn't worthy enough to wield it. Whereas in this film, Aladdin isn't the heir to the power (prophecy notwithstanding), but receives it anyway and is willing to use it, but only to a certain point. And in both films that power falls into the hands of someone who least deserves it, which builds up the main conflict in both films. This is pretty heavy stuff for a film that's aimed primarily for kids, but I absolutely love it because of it. Kids need to learn this stuff sooner or later and I'd personally much rather learn it from a film like this than from bitter experience. And it's not like the whole film is one big gloomfest, designed to depress our kids or to show them material way beyond their years. No, it's bright and festive, pretty to look at with great characters and even greater musical numbers. And the story, based on the old Middle-East tale, is a great one. It has underdogs, it has fight scenes, it has love, betrayal, friendship, magic, wonder, ancient entities, treasure hunts, miracles  it has it all. I fell in love with this film when I first saw it as a kid, and I still love it. It has withstood the test of time and it still remains as one of the best films ever made, animated or live-action. If you haven't seen it already Well, it must have been a nice rock to live under.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End of Disney's Golden Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin, a street urchin, accidentally meets Princess Jasmine, who is in the city undercover. They quickly grow to love each other, but she can only marry a prince. Disney's golden years were 1989-1992, which were unfortunately quite brief. Of course they had hits before that and after that, but for these few years every film was an instant classic. "Aladdin", with its excellent music and the inclusion of Robin Williams, just hit home so hard (and spawned multiple sequels and a television show). How do you critique a film that everyone loves? You simply do not. I guess if I was forced to say anything negative, it would be that Aladdin and Jasmine look a tad too similar and some think they are siblings separated at birth -- and that would not be right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great sense of educational!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film fulling of educational information. Brave, it should be the first, without brave Aladdin cannot play the guardians as fools, he would not bring the lamp out of the hole. Of course, the prince saving the kingdom would not exist. Honest, which is also very indispensable, the second main point in this animation. Abu didn't obey the word and touch a diamond, then they almost died in the hole. Forgetting the promise, Aladdin went to doom and nearly lost everything. Being honest, as the return, it is the forgiveness we see at the end of the story. Contentment, also can be seen from the movie. The fool Jafar failed to learn this, waiting for him is the depriving of freedom the most precious thing to a life. Kindness, which I thought is the first main point showing here makes this film a awesome one. Aladdin is the one who possesses this kind of quality, feeding the street children, making justice for them, saving the princess from blade, and did not be beaten by desire. That is what I thought the most significant quality individual should have. Finally, I want to say, although it is a little bit old animation, please let your children watch it, learn from it, that's the worth of a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Aladdin" is a worthy follow-up to the Disney Studios' previous feature "Beauty and the Beast"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After their previous feature Beauty and the Beast (1991) was the first animated feature in Oscar history to be nominated for Best Picture, the Disney Studios would have a tough act to follow with their next animated picture. In able for this next film to at least be in the same league as Beauty and the Beast, it would have to contain characters, songs, music and a story that are just as memorable as what the prior film offered. As it turns out, the result was the Disney Studio's 31st full-length animated feature, Aladdin (1992). This is another highly entertaining Disney animated feature from the Disney Renaissance which contains pretty much everything you could wish for from a Disney flick whether it would be good laughs, thrilling action, cool animation or awesome songs. We follow a young man named Aladdin and his pet monkey Abu who are sick of being poor and always having to dodge the guards all for the sake of stolen food. They dream that one day they'll be rich enough to put an end to all their troubles. But when they meet a princess named Jasmine who doesn't care for life in the palace because she never goes anywhere and is being forced to marry another prince, things change. After a series of events occur, Aladdin is thrown in the dungeon and a fellow prisoner offers him a way to escape in exchange for doing a task for him. Now, Aladdin has to go to a secret place outside the city of Agrabah called the Cave of Wonders where he must retrieve a magic lamp. This magic lamp contains a highly energetic and fully animated genie (Robin Williams) who can grant Aladdin almost any three wishes he would like. So Aladdin wishes that he was a prince, that way he can try and marry Jasmine. But an evil sorcerer named Jafar and his parrot Iago want Aladdin's lamp and will do anything to get it. Will Aladdin be able to outsmart Jafar and win the princess or not? Want me to summarize why to see Aladdin, if you still haven't, in two words? Well, than those two words would be Robin Williams. Robin Williams was naturally born to voice the genie in this film and I'd guarantee that no matter how hard you tried, you couldn't find another actor that could compete with the high energy and witty comedic style that Williams incorporates into the Genie character. It's been said that much of the dialogue by Robin Williams was improvised or added in even though it wasn't in the original script. To be honest, I couldn't tell the difference between what was and what wasn't in the script since Williams does such a great job at making all of it sound natural. That is precisely how inspired the casting of Robin Williams in this role is. It's not just Williams that makes Aladdin such an entertaining Disney flick, but I also thought that Aladdin and Jasmine had good chemistry between each other. I like the conversations they share with one another regarding how frustrated they are with the lives they're currently living. I don't know about you guys, but when Jasmine basically states that her life of luxury is similar to prison since she can't go outside the palace walls, that's when I thought "maybe being a prince or princess isn't such a good idea". The reason being that in some areas of the world, there's a good possibility that some prince or princess may have no choice but to live that lifestyle. If that somehow wasn't enough to steer you guys away from living a royal life like Jasmine, she's also being forced to get married against her will. Suddenly, a normal lifestyle is sounding excellent to most of us, isn't it? Jafar is another worthy addition to a list of the best Disney villains out there. I admire how he basically enjoys being the most diabolical douchebag to everyone he is around. If there is one thing about some of the greatest Disney villains out there that makes them great including Jafar, it's that they enjoy whatever evil things they're doing. Because they're able to get so much thrill and enjoyment out of what they're doing, that makes us all the more entertained by them in the process. You'll practically love to hate this guy. If there's one thing about this picture that I didn't care for story wise, it would be in regards to Aladdin lying to Jasmine about him being a prince in general. I didn't really care for this part of the story much since most of the dialogue that results from it can be a little too cringe worthy and painfully obvious for my taste. Also, the clich&eacute;d conflict between Aladdin and the genie that results from this part of the story feels forced and unnecessary. I simply felt that it was one routine plot device that didn't need to be in this part of the story at all. Given that it's one of the highest grossing animated features of all time, I think it's safe to say that there's little more to explain about why Aladdin is such a great Disney animated feature. We all know how great the songs by Alan Menken, the late Howard Ashman, and Tim Rice are especially "Friend Like Me", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World". The fast paced, highly energetic, and colorful animation is perfectly suited for a film of this style. I've already gone into detail about Robin Williams' performance, the character of Jafar, and the relationship between Aladdin and Jasmine. You guys have probably seen it many times before, and as far as I'm concerned, you guys deserve to continue seeing it a few times more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watched this Disney's optimal animation in its BluRay form, a stock-in-trade family crowd- pleaser which has been engineered with an impeccable technique and what's more impressive, it oozes an unceasing force of genuineness to edify both children and adults, no condescending doctrine nor feckless naivety, and Robin Williams' voice-performance as the Genie is a great bonus and plays a big part in the film's classic status among its genre. To enumerate Genie's potpourri of imitations alone could be cogent enough to showcase the finesse both for the animators and the voice cast, Robin Williams is deadly hilarious, the motormouthed omnipotent servant, massively steals the thunder from everyone else. But it is not a pejorative remark to other players, on the contrary, it has the most effervescent ensemble including a usually trite class-defying mutual attraction between a princess with a lower-status prince charming. Jafar and Iago pair is another hoot apart from Genie, laughters galore! The plot line entwines pretty much in Disney's safe pattern, a romantic encounter, an abrupt departure, a reunion under the pretense as a legitimate suitor, fighting the evil enemy and happy forever ending, while it really pushes Aladdin to the edge of the cliff since Jafar's invincibility seems to be unbreakable, and the eleventh hour turnover is nothing less than a satisfactory one. 2D animation surely has been largely outcast from the lucrative market, but one can never ascertain there will be a wave of coming back in some years ahead, like Black and White films, their unique aestheticism is the wellspring of their vitality, after watching ALADDIN, it perfectly suffices to originate great mojo of satisfaction for an adult first-time viewer, so the last rites seem to be unnecessary, but a niche market-planning should be conducted for the sake of the laborious craftsmanship. The film currently sits at No.2 at my top 10 film of 1992, and Williams earns him a fifth slot in the supporting actor race, the one and only voice-performance on my own Oscar list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid Gold Disney Classic!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is Disney's 31st full-length animated feature film released in 1992. Based on the popular Arab folktale, the film follows a young peasant boy named Aladdin (voice by Scott Weinger) and his sidekick Abu (voiced by Frank Welker) who are in search of a life outside of the streets from stealing food and dodging guards every day. Then one day, they meet the beautiful Princess Jasmine (voiced by Linda Larkin) in the marketplace and after they save her life, they take her to their place and realize that she wants the exact opposite of what they want; a normal life outside of the palace walls. Then, after Aladdin is thrown into prison by the evil Sorcerer Jafar (voiced by Jonathan Freeman), he is unknowingly taken to the Cave of Wonders by Jafar (disguised as an old beggar man) and his wisecracking sidekick Iago to find an ancient magic lamp that unleashes a genie that grants three wishes. After Aladdin and Abu find the lamp and narrowly escape the Cave on the Magic Carpet, they are thrown back into the cave as it crumbles in the ground. In the process however, Abu grabs the magic lamp, gives it to Aladdin and he accidentally rubs the lamp and unleashes the energetic, hilariously funny Genie (voiced by Robin Williams from "Good Morning, Vietnam", "Mrs. Doubtfire") and chaos ensues!!! This was Disney's fourth film of the Renaissance Era and it's has every element of a classic Disney movie present: great story, unforgettable characters (including one of the best Disney villains of all-time, Jafar), great animation, suspense, great climax, and an awesome score/songs composed by famed Disney composers Alan Menken and Tim Rice (stepping in place of Howard Ashman). The best songs in the movie are "One Jump Ahead", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World", played during the magic carpet ride scene. This is yet another one of my favorite Disney movies and my favorite character is the Genie! If you by any chance haven't seen this classic American animated film in the last 20+ years it's been out, all I have to say is: WATCH IT!!! If you need a good Disney film to watch with the family, then I highly recommend this one! Rating: 10/10!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin belongs to a clan of Disney's magical movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know what Disney is capable of. Disney has produced some of the greatest films of all time like the Lion King but 2 years prior to that, Disney released Aladdin which is also widely regarded as one of Disney's best. Aladdin follows the story of a young streeboy named Aladdin who falls in love with Princess Jasmine and attempts to win her heart by using a genie to make him a prince. However, an evil sorcerer named Jafar is after Aladdin in order to gain his hands on the lamp in order to rule the world and marry Jasmine. Okay, we all know what the story is about and we all know the characters in the film. The story of Aladdin is extremely rich and unforgettable filled with magical characters that just warm our heart. The voice acting is brilliant and it makes for an extremely enjoyable film. The songs in the film aren't as good as, say Beauty and the Beast but they are still pretty remarkable. The script is good and gives us plenty of great laughs. The pacing of the film is brilliant and it never really slows down. In fact, the last twenty minutes is filled with excitement and tension over what will happen. This is definitely a MUST SEE Disney classic for all :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Disney's best post-modern era films of the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I have to admit that I was only born in 1994 when The Lion King was released, but my older sister was born before me in 1992 before Disney released this. Sadly, though, we never saw it in the theaters and waited to watch it on video. Our dreams had finally come true and we loved it as much as anyone else who had seen it and grew up with it. Now, I never read the story "One Thousand Arabian Nights", but I think that this classic did some extreme justice to it. Sure, it does start off a bit slow, but as the film progresses, it has it's heart just in the right place thanks to it's being well thought out. The characters, much like the story, are engaging and likable with the likes of Aladdin, the beautiful Princess Jasmine, Abu, the monkey, Iago, the parrot, the Sultan, Jafar (who is by far one of Disney's best villains in history) and Genie, who, thanks to Robin Williams' solid voice-work, steals every scene with his hilarious moments and the comedy is both timeless and unforgettable. In fact, the voice acting isn't that bad at all especially Scott Weinger, Linda Larkin, Jonathan Freeman, and let's not forget Jim Cummings as the leader of the palace guards. I was like, "Winnie The Pooh/Tigger as a palace guard? Top-notch!" The music from Alan Menken is the epitome of brilliance and the songs were timeless and were not to be long forgotten including one of my favorites "A Whole New World". The script is excellent and flawless with witty and hilarious dialog and the pacing is brisk and moves along very nicely. The strongest aspect, however, goes to the animation due to it's beautiful visual look of Agrabah and solid character designs. Overall, this is one of the few movies that I grew up with as a kid back at the 90s and this will not be forgotten by not only families and their children, but long-time Disney fans as well. Totally recommended and uh... Happy 20th Anniversary, Aladdin!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you never had a friend like me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is a Disney cartoon with a character that we all wish we had as friend, the genie. Aladdin is filled with endless thrills, table turning plans and music that you can't help to like and sing along to. The movie's intro is in form of a narrative, where a merchant tells us the tale of Aladdin and his magic lamp. This 1992 Disney classic is based on an Arab folktale of Aladdin and the magic lamp from One Thousand and One Nights. The idea to make the movie was pitched in by the Late Howard Ashman (who died before the film's release) Ashman has been behind a lot of Disney classics from Oliver & Company, Little Mermaid and Beauty and the Beast. He was a writer, lyricist and producer and he was the lyricist for "Arabian Nights", "Friend Like Me", and "Prince Ali" used in this movie. Aladdin's story is about a street boy, who runs into a princess named Jasmine who escaped the palace to see what life was outside the palace walls where you are not told what to do. While they were together Aladdin gets captured by soldiers under the orders of Jafar, the Grand Vizier to the Sultan of Agrabah (Jasmine's father). Jafar needs Aladdin to retrieve a magical oil lamp containing a genie from the Cave of Wonders. The movie's story now grows on what happened when Jafar didn't get the lamp but Aladdin did in an attempt to read the inscriptions on the lamp, released the genie and he is given 3 wishes. As the song goes, you never had a friend like me So it has been, because all through Disney toon history we never found anyone more appealing to have around, Genie is just the best person to have in at corner. The movie's screenplay explores fantasy, world travel, fireworks and action scenes. Aladdin was a box office hit, making over $ 500 million dollars in its theatrical run and also gave birth to two direct to DVD sequels and a TV series. Aladdin won numerous awards, especially for its music, it won only two Academy Awards, Best Original Score and Best Original Song for "A Whole New World" and it also won four Grammy Awards, Best Soundtrack Album, Song of the Year for "A Whole New World", Best Pop Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal for "A Whole New World" and Best Song Written for a Motion Picture, Television or Other Visual Media for "A Whole New World". Like it or not, Aladdin boast of the best of the best music, and it was also funny and fun to watch, so if you don't own this DVD you Disney collection is not complete yet. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Disney at their finest.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Starr
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like most kids, I also grew up with Disney films, and Aladdin came out the year I was born. However, that did not stop me from watching this film many times during my life. Ever since I was little, this was my favorite Disney movie. This is an excellent film. It teaches great morals, and executes them very well. The story is about Aladdin falling in love with Princess Jasmine, but finds out she can only marry a prince, due to the law. He acquires a lamp with the Genie inside, and he wishes to become a prince, or should I say, look like one. This is my only problem with the film, but this can be overlooked. Why can't he wish he WAS a prince instead of looking like one? But it moves very well into the moral, so I can excuse this. After finding out he would become Sultan after marrying Jasmine, he decides to try and tell her the truth that he's not actually a prince. It's actually before the villain fight and not at the exact end where we have a moral. I like that. He learns that he needs to be truthful, and was trying to tell Jasmine before Jafar exposes him for who he really is. He also learns to keep promises. Before his first wish with the Genie, he promises him he would use his 3rd wish to free him, and even at the end, the Genie tries to talk him into wishing into a prince again, but Aladdin still frees him, despite unlikely being able to marry Jasmine. Nice guy. That is a fantastic way of telling your morals. Not only are the morals amazing, but so are the characters, especially Aladdin himself. He starts off as a homeless person on the streets of Agrabah, but he has very impressive smarts. Not only for thievery, but anything in general. I mainly say this because when he defeats Jafar, he says that the Genie has more power than he does, and he can take away his powers. This convinces Jafar to use his third wish to become a genie himself, but gets stuck in his own lamp. I love this guy. He is the textbook definition of genius. Speaking of smart characters, we also have Jasmine. Her father, the sultan of Agrabah, is trying to rush her into getting married, and tries to bring in many princes to marry her. She hates every single one of them. She doesn't care about the law. If she is to marry, she wants it to be for love. She won't marry anyone. She has to actually care for them. I wouldn't marry someone who attempts to whip little kids either. She also nearly figures out Aladdin not being a prince after the Whole New World song, and Aladdin figures out a good excuse. She's another smart and enjoyable character. I also think she's very hot, but I digress. The most important part of this love story is that the two have great chemistry. They have things in common, and want to help each other out. Not only that, but when Aladdin is Prince Ali, Jasmine actually hates him at first. However, Aladdin builds up the relationship again, and gets Jasmine to fall in love with him again. This may not be on quite the level Beauty and the Beast was with building up a relationship, but it works fine here. Jasmine does suspect that it's actually Aladdin and not a prince before the carpet ride, and she already cared for him, so this is not rushed. It does well for its own love story, but the film is not just that. It's also an adventure, especially since Jafar tries to kill Aladdin a lot. He tries to in the Cave of Wonders when Aladdin is hanging off a cliff and he gets the lamp, he tries to when Aladdin is with Jasmine, and he does after he becomes a sorcerer, along with after Aladdin returns to the palace. In conclusion, the film has many things to like about it. It has many great elements in it, and focuses on them in a very coherent manner. It has a great love story, great adventure, great characters, amazing comic relief, and wonderful animation and colors. This is something you can truly call a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion this film and The Lion King are the best animated films Disney has ever produced. And they're surprisingly similar, yet different enough for us to not get bored even if we watched them back to back. They both deal with the realities of power and the responsibility that comes along with it. In The Lion King, Simba doesn't want the power, he feels like he isn't worthy enough to wield it. Whereas in this film, Aladdin isn't the heir to the power (prophecy notwithstanding), but receives it anyway and is willing to use it, but only to a certain point. And in both films that power falls into the hands of someone who least deserves it, which builds up the main conflict in both films. This is pretty heavy stuff for a film that's aimed primarily for kids, but I absolutely love it because of it. Kids need to learn this stuff sooner or later and I'd personally much rather learn it from a film like this than from bitter experience. And it's not like the whole film is one big gloomfest, designed to depress our kids or to show them material way beyond their years. No, it's bright and festive, pretty to look at with great characters and even greater musical numbers. And the story, based on the old Middle-East tale, is a great one. It has underdogs, it has fight scenes, it has love, betrayal, friendship, magic, wonder, ancient entities, treasure hunts, miracles  it has it all. I fell in love with this film when I first saw it as a kid, and I still love it. It has withstood the test of time and it still remains as one of the best films ever made, animated or live-action. If you haven't seen it already Well, it must have been a nice rock to live under.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End of Disney's Golden Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin, a street urchin, accidentally meets Princess Jasmine, who is in the city undercover. They quickly grow to love each other, but she can only marry a prince. Disney's golden years were 1989-1992, which were unfortunately quite brief. Of course they had hits before that and after that, but for these few years every film was an instant classic. "Aladdin", with its excellent music and the inclusion of Robin Williams, just hit home so hard (and spawned multiple sequels and a television show). How do you critique a film that everyone loves? You simply do not. I guess if I was forced to say anything negative, it would be that Aladdin and Jasmine look a tad too similar and some think they are siblings separated at birth -- and that would not be right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great sense of educational!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film fulling of educational information. Brave, it should be the first, without brave Aladdin cannot play the guardians as fools, he would not bring the lamp out of the hole. Of course, the prince saving the kingdom would not exist. Honest, which is also very indispensable, the second main point in this animation. Abu didn't obey the word and touch a diamond, then they almost died in the hole. Forgetting the promise, Aladdin went to doom and nearly lost everything. Being honest, as the return, it is the forgiveness we see at the end of the story. Contentment, also can be seen from the movie. The fool Jafar failed to learn this, waiting for him is the depriving of freedom the most precious thing to a life. Kindness, which I thought is the first main point showing here makes this film a awesome one. Aladdin is the one who possesses this kind of quality, feeding the street children, making justice for them, saving the princess from blade, and did not be beaten by desire. That is what I thought the most significant quality individual should have. Finally, I want to say, although it is a little bit old animation, please let your children watch it, learn from it, that's the worth of a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Aladdin" is a worthy follow-up to the Disney Studios' previous feature "Beauty and the Beast"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After their previous feature Beauty and the Beast (1991) was the first animated feature in Oscar history to be nominated for Best Picture, the Disney Studios would have a tough act to follow with their next animated picture. In able for this next film to at least be in the same league as Beauty and the Beast, it would have to contain characters, songs, music and a story that are just as memorable as what the prior film offered. As it turns out, the result was the Disney Studio's 31st full-length animated feature, Aladdin (1992). This is another highly entertaining Disney animated feature from the Disney Renaissance which contains pretty much everything you could wish for from a Disney flick whether it would be good laughs, thrilling action, cool animation or awesome songs. We follow a young man named Aladdin and his pet monkey Abu who are sick of being poor and always having to dodge the guards all for the sake of stolen food. They dream that one day they'll be rich enough to put an end to all their troubles. But when they meet a princess named Jasmine who doesn't care for life in the palace because she never goes anywhere and is being forced to marry another prince, things change. After a series of events occur, Aladdin is thrown in the dungeon and a fellow prisoner offers him a way to escape in exchange for doing a task for him. Now, Aladdin has to go to a secret place outside the city of Agrabah called the Cave of Wonders where he must retrieve a magic lamp. This magic lamp contains a highly energetic and fully animated genie (Robin Williams) who can grant Aladdin almost any three wishes he would like. So Aladdin wishes that he was a prince, that way he can try and marry Jasmine. But an evil sorcerer named Jafar and his parrot Iago want Aladdin's lamp and will do anything to get it. Will Aladdin be able to outsmart Jafar and win the princess or not? Want me to summarize why to see Aladdin, if you still haven't, in two words? Well, than those two words would be Robin Williams. Robin Williams was naturally born to voice the genie in this film and I'd guarantee that no matter how hard you tried, you couldn't find another actor that could compete with the high energy and witty comedic style that Williams incorporates into the Genie character. It's been said that much of the dialogue by Robin Williams was improvised or added in even though it wasn't in the original script. To be honest, I couldn't tell the difference between what was and what wasn't in the script since Williams does such a great job at making all of it sound natural. That is precisely how inspired the casting of Robin Williams in this role is. It's not just Williams that makes Aladdin such an entertaining Disney flick, but I also thought that Aladdin and Jasmine had good chemistry between each other. I like the conversations they share with one another regarding how frustrated they are with the lives they're currently living. I don't know about you guys, but when Jasmine basically states that her life of luxury is similar to prison since she can't go outside the palace walls, that's when I thought "maybe being a prince or princess isn't such a good idea". The reason being that in some areas of the world, there's a good possibility that some prince or princess may have no choice but to live that lifestyle. If that somehow wasn't enough to steer you guys away from living a royal life like Jasmine, she's also being forced to get married against her will. Suddenly, a normal lifestyle is sounding excellent to most of us, isn't it? Jafar is another worthy addition to a list of the best Disney villains out there. I admire how he basically enjoys being the most diabolical douchebag to everyone he is around. If there is one thing about some of the greatest Disney villains out there that makes them great including Jafar, it's that they enjoy whatever evil things they're doing. Because they're able to get so much thrill and enjoyment out of what they're doing, that makes us all the more entertained by them in the process. You'll practically love to hate this guy. If there's one thing about this picture that I didn't care for story wise, it would be in regards to Aladdin lying to Jasmine about him being a prince in general. I didn't really care for this part of the story much since most of the dialogue that results from it can be a little too cringe worthy and painfully obvious for my taste. Also, the clich&eacute;d conflict between Aladdin and the genie that results from this part of the story feels forced and unnecessary. I simply felt that it was one routine plot device that didn't need to be in this part of the story at all. Given that it's one of the highest grossing animated features of all time, I think it's safe to say that there's little more to explain about why Aladdin is such a great Disney animated feature. We all know how great the songs by Alan Menken, the late Howard Ashman, and Tim Rice are especially "Friend Like Me", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World". The fast paced, highly energetic, and colorful animation is perfectly suited for a film of this style. I've already gone into detail about Robin Williams' performance, the character of Jafar, and the relationship between Aladdin and Jasmine. You guys have probably seen it many times before, and as far as I'm concerned, you guys deserve to continue seeing it a few times more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watched this Disney's optimal animation in its BluRay form, a stock-in-trade family crowd- pleaser which has been engineered with an impeccable technique and what's more impressive, it oozes an unceasing force of genuineness to edify both children and adults, no condescending doctrine nor feckless naivety, and Robin Williams' voice-performance as the Genie is a great bonus and plays a big part in the film's classic status among its genre. To enumerate Genie's potpourri of imitations alone could be cogent enough to showcase the finesse both for the animators and the voice cast, Robin Williams is deadly hilarious, the motormouthed omnipotent servant, massively steals the thunder from everyone else. But it is not a pejorative remark to other players, on the contrary, it has the most effervescent ensemble including a usually trite class-defying mutual attraction between a princess with a lower-status prince charming. Jafar and Iago pair is another hoot apart from Genie, laughters galore! The plot line entwines pretty much in Disney's safe pattern, a romantic encounter, an abrupt departure, a reunion under the pretense as a legitimate suitor, fighting the evil enemy and happy forever ending, while it really pushes Aladdin to the edge of the cliff since Jafar's invincibility seems to be unbreakable, and the eleventh hour turnover is nothing less than a satisfactory one. 2D animation surely has been largely outcast from the lucrative market, but one can never ascertain there will be a wave of coming back in some years ahead, like Black and White films, their unique aestheticism is the wellspring of their vitality, after watching ALADDIN, it perfectly suffices to originate great mojo of satisfaction for an adult first-time viewer, so the last rites seem to be unnecessary, but a niche market-planning should be conducted for the sake of the laborious craftsmanship. The film currently sits at No.2 at my top 10 film of 1992, and Williams earns him a fifth slot in the supporting actor race, the one and only voice-performance on my own Oscar list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid Gold Disney Classic!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is Disney's 31st full-length animated feature film released in 1992. Based on the popular Arab folktale, the film follows a young peasant boy named Aladdin (voice by Scott Weinger) and his sidekick Abu (voiced by Frank Welker) who are in search of a life outside of the streets from stealing food and dodging guards every day. Then one day, they meet the beautiful Princess Jasmine (voiced by Linda Larkin) in the marketplace and after they save her life, they take her to their place and realize that she wants the exact opposite of what they want; a normal life outside of the palace walls. Then, after Aladdin is thrown into prison by the evil Sorcerer Jafar (voiced by Jonathan Freeman), he is unknowingly taken to the Cave of Wonders by Jafar (disguised as an old beggar man) and his wisecracking sidekick Iago to find an ancient magic lamp that unleashes a genie that grants three wishes. After Aladdin and Abu find the lamp and narrowly escape the Cave on the Magic Carpet, they are thrown back into the cave as it crumbles in the ground. In the process however, Abu grabs the magic lamp, gives it to Aladdin and he accidentally rubs the lamp and unleashes the energetic, hilariously funny Genie (voiced by Robin Williams from "Good Morning, Vietnam", "Mrs. Doubtfire") and chaos ensues!!! This was Disney's fourth film of the Renaissance Era and it's has every element of a classic Disney movie present: great story, unforgettable characters (including one of the best Disney villains of all-time, Jafar), great animation, suspense, great climax, and an awesome score/songs composed by famed Disney composers Alan Menken and Tim Rice (stepping in place of Howard Ashman). The best songs in the movie are "One Jump Ahead", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World", played during the magic carpet ride scene. This is yet another one of my favorite Disney movies and my favorite character is the Genie! If you by any chance haven't seen this classic American animated film in the last 20+ years it's been out, all I have to say is: WATCH IT!!! If you need a good Disney film to watch with the family, then I highly recommend this one! Rating: 10/10!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin belongs to a clan of Disney's magical movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know what Disney is capable of. Disney has produced some of the greatest films of all time like the Lion King but 2 years prior to that, Disney released Aladdin which is also widely regarded as one of Disney's best. Aladdin follows the story of a young streeboy named Aladdin who falls in love with Princess Jasmine and attempts to win her heart by using a genie to make him a prince. However, an evil sorcerer named Jafar is after Aladdin in order to gain his hands on the lamp in order to rule the world and marry Jasmine. Okay, we all know what the story is about and we all know the characters in the film. The story of Aladdin is extremely rich and unforgettable filled with magical characters that just warm our heart. The voice acting is brilliant and it makes for an extremely enjoyable film. The songs in the film aren't as good as, say Beauty and the Beast but they are still pretty remarkable. The script is good and gives us plenty of great laughs. The pacing of the film is brilliant and it never really slows down. In fact, the last twenty minutes is filled with excitement and tension over what will happen. This is definitely a MUST SEE Disney classic for all :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Disney's best post-modern era films of the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I have to admit that I was only born in 1994 when The Lion King was released, but my older sister was born before me in 1992 before Disney released this. Sadly, though, we never saw it in the theaters and waited to watch it on video. Our dreams had finally come true and we loved it as much as anyone else who had seen it and grew up with it. Now, I never read the story "One Thousand Arabian Nights", but I think that this classic did some extreme justice to it. Sure, it does start off a bit slow, but as the film progresses, it has it's heart just in the right place thanks to it's being well thought out. The characters, much like the story, are engaging and likable with the likes of Aladdin, the beautiful Princess Jasmine, Abu, the monkey, Iago, the parrot, the Sultan, Jafar (who is by far one of Disney's best villains in history) and Genie, who, thanks to Robin Williams' solid voice-work, steals every scene with his hilarious moments and the comedy is both timeless and unforgettable. In fact, the voice acting isn't that bad at all especially Scott Weinger, Linda Larkin, Jonathan Freeman, and let's not forget Jim Cummings as the leader of the palace guards. I was like, "Winnie The Pooh/Tigger as a palace guard? Top-notch!" The music from Alan Menken is the epitome of brilliance and the songs were timeless and were not to be long forgotten including one of my favorites "A Whole New World". The script is excellent and flawless with witty and hilarious dialog and the pacing is brisk and moves along very nicely. The strongest aspect, however, goes to the animation due to it's beautiful visual look of Agrabah and solid character designs. Overall, this is one of the few movies that I grew up with as a kid back at the 90s and this will not be forgotten by not only families and their children, but long-time Disney fans as well. Totally recommended and uh... Happy 20th Anniversary, Aladdin!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you never had a friend like me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is a Disney cartoon with a character that we all wish we had as friend, the genie. Aladdin is filled with endless thrills, table turning plans and music that you can't help to like and sing along to. The movie's intro is in form of a narrative, where a merchant tells us the tale of Aladdin and his magic lamp. This 1992 Disney classic is based on an Arab folktale of Aladdin and the magic lamp from One Thousand and One Nights. The idea to make the movie was pitched in by the Late Howard Ashman (who died before the film's release) Ashman has been behind a lot of Disney classics from Oliver & Company, Little Mermaid and Beauty and the Beast. He was a writer, lyricist and producer and he was the lyricist for "Arabian Nights", "Friend Like Me", and "Prince Ali" used in this movie. Aladdin's story is about a street boy, who runs into a princess named Jasmine who escaped the palace to see what life was outside the palace walls where you are not told what to do. While they were together Aladdin gets captured by soldiers under the orders of Jafar, the Grand Vizier to the Sultan of Agrabah (Jasmine's father). Jafar needs Aladdin to retrieve a magical oil lamp containing a genie from the Cave of Wonders. The movie's story now grows on what happened when Jafar didn't get the lamp but Aladdin did in an attempt to read the inscriptions on the lamp, released the genie and he is given 3 wishes. As the song goes, you never had a friend like me So it has been, because all through Disney toon history we never found anyone more appealing to have around, Genie is just the best person to have in at corner. The movie's screenplay explores fantasy, world travel, fireworks and action scenes. Aladdin was a box office hit, making over $ 500 million dollars in its theatrical run and also gave birth to two direct to DVD sequels and a TV series. Aladdin won numerous awards, especially for its music, it won only two Academy Awards, Best Original Score and Best Original Song for "A Whole New World" and it also won four Grammy Awards, Best Soundtrack Album, Song of the Year for "A Whole New World", Best Pop Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal for "A Whole New World" and Best Song Written for a Motion Picture, Television or Other Visual Media for "A Whole New World". Like it or not, Aladdin boast of the best of the best music, and it was also funny and fun to watch, so if you don't own this DVD you Disney collection is not complete yet. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Disney at their finest.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Starr
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like most kids, I also grew up with Disney films, and Aladdin came out the year I was born. However, that did not stop me from watching this film many times during my life. Ever since I was little, this was my favorite Disney movie. This is an excellent film. It teaches great morals, and executes them very well. The story is about Aladdin falling in love with Princess Jasmine, but finds out she can only marry a prince, due to the law. He acquires a lamp with the Genie inside, and he wishes to become a prince, or should I say, look like one. This is my only problem with the film, but this can be overlooked. Why can't he wish he WAS a prince instead of looking like one? But it moves very well into the moral, so I can excuse this. After finding out he would become Sultan after marrying Jasmine, he decides to try and tell her the truth that he's not actually a prince. It's actually before the villain fight and not at the exact end where we have a moral. I like that. He learns that he needs to be truthful, and was trying to tell Jasmine before Jafar exposes him for who he really is. He also learns to keep promises. Before his first wish with the Genie, he promises him he would use his 3rd wish to free him, and even at the end, the Genie tries to talk him into wishing into a prince again, but Aladdin still frees him, despite unlikely being able to marry Jasmine. Nice guy. That is a fantastic way of telling your morals. Not only are the morals amazing, but so are the characters, especially Aladdin himself. He starts off as a homeless person on the streets of Agrabah, but he has very impressive smarts. Not only for thievery, but anything in general. I mainly say this because when he defeats Jafar, he says that the Genie has more power than he does, and he can take away his powers. This convinces Jafar to use his third wish to become a genie himself, but gets stuck in his own lamp. I love this guy. He is the textbook definition of genius. Speaking of smart characters, we also have Jasmine. Her father, the sultan of Agrabah, is trying to rush her into getting married, and tries to bring in many princes to marry her. She hates every single one of them. She doesn't care about the law. If she is to marry, she wants it to be for love. She won't marry anyone. She has to actually care for them. I wouldn't marry someone who attempts to whip little kids either. She also nearly figures out Aladdin not being a prince after the Whole New World song, and Aladdin figures out a good excuse. She's another smart and enjoyable character. I also think she's very hot, but I digress. The most important part of this love story is that the two have great chemistry. They have things in common, and want to help each other out. Not only that, but when Aladdin is Prince Ali, Jasmine actually hates him at first. However, Aladdin builds up the relationship again, and gets Jasmine to fall in love with him again. This may not be on quite the level Beauty and the Beast was with building up a relationship, but it works fine here. Jasmine does suspect that it's actually Aladdin and not a prince before the carpet ride, and she already cared for him, so this is not rushed. It does well for its own love story, but the film is not just that. It's also an adventure, especially since Jafar tries to kill Aladdin a lot. He tries to in the Cave of Wonders when Aladdin is hanging off a cliff and he gets the lamp, he tries to when Aladdin is with Jasmine, and he does after he becomes a sorcerer, along with after Aladdin returns to the palace. In conclusion, the film has many things to like about it. It has many great elements in it, and focuses on them in a very coherent manner. It has a great love story, great adventure, great characters, amazing comic relief, and wonderful animation and colors. This is something you can truly call a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion this film and The Lion King are the best animated films Disney has ever produced. And they're surprisingly similar, yet different enough for us to not get bored even if we watched them back to back. They both deal with the realities of power and the responsibility that comes along with it. In The Lion King, Simba doesn't want the power, he feels like he isn't worthy enough to wield it. Whereas in this film, Aladdin isn't the heir to the power (prophecy notwithstanding), but receives it anyway and is willing to use it, but only to a certain point. And in both films that power falls into the hands of someone who least deserves it, which builds up the main conflict in both films. This is pretty heavy stuff for a film that's aimed primarily for kids, but I absolutely love it because of it. Kids need to learn this stuff sooner or later and I'd personally much rather learn it from a film like this than from bitter experience. And it's not like the whole film is one big gloomfest, designed to depress our kids or to show them material way beyond their years. No, it's bright and festive, pretty to look at with great characters and even greater musical numbers. And the story, based on the old Middle-East tale, is a great one. It has underdogs, it has fight scenes, it has love, betrayal, friendship, magic, wonder, ancient entities, treasure hunts, miracles  it has it all. I fell in love with this film when I first saw it as a kid, and I still love it. It has withstood the test of time and it still remains as one of the best films ever made, animated or live-action. If you haven't seen it already Well, it must have been a nice rock to live under.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End of Disney's Golden Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin, a street urchin, accidentally meets Princess Jasmine, who is in the city undercover. They quickly grow to love each other, but she can only marry a prince. Disney's golden years were 1989-1992, which were unfortunately quite brief. Of course they had hits before that and after that, but for these few years every film was an instant classic. "Aladdin", with its excellent music and the inclusion of Robin Williams, just hit home so hard (and spawned multiple sequels and a television show). How do you critique a film that everyone loves? You simply do not. I guess if I was forced to say anything negative, it would be that Aladdin and Jasmine look a tad too similar and some think they are siblings separated at birth -- and that would not be right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great sense of educational!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film fulling of educational information. Brave, it should be the first, without brave Aladdin cannot play the guardians as fools, he would not bring the lamp out of the hole. Of course, the prince saving the kingdom would not exist. Honest, which is also very indispensable, the second main point in this animation. Abu didn't obey the word and touch a diamond, then they almost died in the hole. Forgetting the promise, Aladdin went to doom and nearly lost everything. Being honest, as the return, it is the forgiveness we see at the end of the story. Contentment, also can be seen from the movie. The fool Jafar failed to learn this, waiting for him is the depriving of freedom the most precious thing to a life. Kindness, which I thought is the first main point showing here makes this film a awesome one. Aladdin is the one who possesses this kind of quality, feeding the street children, making justice for them, saving the princess from blade, and did not be beaten by desire. That is what I thought the most significant quality individual should have. Finally, I want to say, although it is a little bit old animation, please let your children watch it, learn from it, that's the worth of a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Aladdin" is a worthy follow-up to the Disney Studios' previous feature "Beauty and the Beast"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After their previous feature Beauty and the Beast (1991) was the first animated feature in Oscar history to be nominated for Best Picture, the Disney Studios would have a tough act to follow with their next animated picture. In able for this next film to at least be in the same league as Beauty and the Beast, it would have to contain characters, songs, music and a story that are just as memorable as what the prior film offered. As it turns out, the result was the Disney Studio's 31st full-length animated feature, Aladdin (1992). This is another highly entertaining Disney animated feature from the Disney Renaissance which contains pretty much everything you could wish for from a Disney flick whether it would be good laughs, thrilling action, cool animation or awesome songs. We follow a young man named Aladdin and his pet monkey Abu who are sick of being poor and always having to dodge the guards all for the sake of stolen food. They dream that one day they'll be rich enough to put an end to all their troubles. But when they meet a princess named Jasmine who doesn't care for life in the palace because she never goes anywhere and is being forced to marry another prince, things change. After a series of events occur, Aladdin is thrown in the dungeon and a fellow prisoner offers him a way to escape in exchange for doing a task for him. Now, Aladdin has to go to a secret place outside the city of Agrabah called the Cave of Wonders where he must retrieve a magic lamp. This magic lamp contains a highly energetic and fully animated genie (Robin Williams) who can grant Aladdin almost any three wishes he would like. So Aladdin wishes that he was a prince, that way he can try and marry Jasmine. But an evil sorcerer named Jafar and his parrot Iago want Aladdin's lamp and will do anything to get it. Will Aladdin be able to outsmart Jafar and win the princess or not? Want me to summarize why to see Aladdin, if you still haven't, in two words? Well, than those two words would be Robin Williams. Robin Williams was naturally born to voice the genie in this film and I'd guarantee that no matter how hard you tried, you couldn't find another actor that could compete with the high energy and witty comedic style that Williams incorporates into the Genie character. It's been said that much of the dialogue by Robin Williams was improvised or added in even though it wasn't in the original script. To be honest, I couldn't tell the difference between what was and what wasn't in the script since Williams does such a great job at making all of it sound natural. That is precisely how inspired the casting of Robin Williams in this role is. It's not just Williams that makes Aladdin such an entertaining Disney flick, but I also thought that Aladdin and Jasmine had good chemistry between each other. I like the conversations they share with one another regarding how frustrated they are with the lives they're currently living. I don't know about you guys, but when Jasmine basically states that her life of luxury is similar to prison since she can't go outside the palace walls, that's when I thought "maybe being a prince or princess isn't such a good idea". The reason being that in some areas of the world, there's a good possibility that some prince or princess may have no choice but to live that lifestyle. If that somehow wasn't enough to steer you guys away from living a royal life like Jasmine, she's also being forced to get married against her will. Suddenly, a normal lifestyle is sounding excellent to most of us, isn't it? Jafar is another worthy addition to a list of the best Disney villains out there. I admire how he basically enjoys being the most diabolical douchebag to everyone he is around. If there is one thing about some of the greatest Disney villains out there that makes them great including Jafar, it's that they enjoy whatever evil things they're doing. Because they're able to get so much thrill and enjoyment out of what they're doing, that makes us all the more entertained by them in the process. You'll practically love to hate this guy. If there's one thing about this picture that I didn't care for story wise, it would be in regards to Aladdin lying to Jasmine about him being a prince in general. I didn't really care for this part of the story much since most of the dialogue that results from it can be a little too cringe worthy and painfully obvious for my taste. Also, the clich&eacute;d conflict between Aladdin and the genie that results from this part of the story feels forced and unnecessary. I simply felt that it was one routine plot device that didn't need to be in this part of the story at all. Given that it's one of the highest grossing animated features of all time, I think it's safe to say that there's little more to explain about why Aladdin is such a great Disney animated feature. We all know how great the songs by Alan Menken, the late Howard Ashman, and Tim Rice are especially "Friend Like Me", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World". The fast paced, highly energetic, and colorful animation is perfectly suited for a film of this style. I've already gone into detail about Robin Williams' performance, the character of Jafar, and the relationship between Aladdin and Jasmine. You guys have probably seen it many times before, and as far as I'm concerned, you guys deserve to continue seeing it a few times more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watched this Disney's optimal animation in its BluRay form, a stock-in-trade family crowd- pleaser which has been engineered with an impeccable technique and what's more impressive, it oozes an unceasing force of genuineness to edify both children and adults, no condescending doctrine nor feckless naivety, and Robin Williams' voice-performance as the Genie is a great bonus and plays a big part in the film's classic status among its genre. To enumerate Genie's potpourri of imitations alone could be cogent enough to showcase the finesse both for the animators and the voice cast, Robin Williams is deadly hilarious, the motormouthed omnipotent servant, massively steals the thunder from everyone else. But it is not a pejorative remark to other players, on the contrary, it has the most effervescent ensemble including a usually trite class-defying mutual attraction between a princess with a lower-status prince charming. Jafar and Iago pair is another hoot apart from Genie, laughters galore! The plot line entwines pretty much in Disney's safe pattern, a romantic encounter, an abrupt departure, a reunion under the pretense as a legitimate suitor, fighting the evil enemy and happy forever ending, while it really pushes Aladdin to the edge of the cliff since Jafar's invincibility seems to be unbreakable, and the eleventh hour turnover is nothing less than a satisfactory one. 2D animation surely has been largely outcast from the lucrative market, but one can never ascertain there will be a wave of coming back in some years ahead, like Black and White films, their unique aestheticism is the wellspring of their vitality, after watching ALADDIN, it perfectly suffices to originate great mojo of satisfaction for an adult first-time viewer, so the last rites seem to be unnecessary, but a niche market-planning should be conducted for the sake of the laborious craftsmanship. The film currently sits at No.2 at my top 10 film of 1992, and Williams earns him a fifth slot in the supporting actor race, the one and only voice-performance on my own Oscar list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid Gold Disney Classic!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is Disney's 31st full-length animated feature film released in 1992. Based on the popular Arab folktale, the film follows a young peasant boy named Aladdin (voice by Scott Weinger) and his sidekick Abu (voiced by Frank Welker) who are in search of a life outside of the streets from stealing food and dodging guards every day. Then one day, they meet the beautiful Princess Jasmine (voiced by Linda Larkin) in the marketplace and after they save her life, they take her to their place and realize that she wants the exact opposite of what they want; a normal life outside of the palace walls. Then, after Aladdin is thrown into prison by the evil Sorcerer Jafar (voiced by Jonathan Freeman), he is unknowingly taken to the Cave of Wonders by Jafar (disguised as an old beggar man) and his wisecracking sidekick Iago to find an ancient magic lamp that unleashes a genie that grants three wishes. After Aladdin and Abu find the lamp and narrowly escape the Cave on the Magic Carpet, they are thrown back into the cave as it crumbles in the ground. In the process however, Abu grabs the magic lamp, gives it to Aladdin and he accidentally rubs the lamp and unleashes the energetic, hilariously funny Genie (voiced by Robin Williams from "Good Morning, Vietnam", "Mrs. Doubtfire") and chaos ensues!!! This was Disney's fourth film of the Renaissance Era and it's has every element of a classic Disney movie present: great story, unforgettable characters (including one of the best Disney villains of all-time, Jafar), great animation, suspense, great climax, and an awesome score/songs composed by famed Disney composers Alan Menken and Tim Rice (stepping in place of Howard Ashman). The best songs in the movie are "One Jump Ahead", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World", played during the magic carpet ride scene. This is yet another one of my favorite Disney movies and my favorite character is the Genie! If you by any chance haven't seen this classic American animated film in the last 20+ years it's been out, all I have to say is: WATCH IT!!! If you need a good Disney film to watch with the family, then I highly recommend this one! Rating: 10/10!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin belongs to a clan of Disney's magical movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know what Disney is capable of. Disney has produced some of the greatest films of all time like the Lion King but 2 years prior to that, Disney released Aladdin which is also widely regarded as one of Disney's best. Aladdin follows the story of a young streeboy named Aladdin who falls in love with Princess Jasmine and attempts to win her heart by using a genie to make him a prince. However, an evil sorcerer named Jafar is after Aladdin in order to gain his hands on the lamp in order to rule the world and marry Jasmine. Okay, we all know what the story is about and we all know the characters in the film. The story of Aladdin is extremely rich and unforgettable filled with magical characters that just warm our heart. The voice acting is brilliant and it makes for an extremely enjoyable film. The songs in the film aren't as good as, say Beauty and the Beast but they are still pretty remarkable. The script is good and gives us plenty of great laughs. The pacing of the film is brilliant and it never really slows down. In fact, the last twenty minutes is filled with excitement and tension over what will happen. This is definitely a MUST SEE Disney classic for all :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Disney's best post-modern era films of the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I have to admit that I was only born in 1994 when The Lion King was released, but my older sister was born before me in 1992 before Disney released this. Sadly, though, we never saw it in the theaters and waited to watch it on video. Our dreams had finally come true and we loved it as much as anyone else who had seen it and grew up with it. Now, I never read the story "One Thousand Arabian Nights", but I think that this classic did some extreme justice to it. Sure, it does start off a bit slow, but as the film progresses, it has it's heart just in the right place thanks to it's being well thought out. The characters, much like the story, are engaging and likable with the likes of Aladdin, the beautiful Princess Jasmine, Abu, the monkey, Iago, the parrot, the Sultan, Jafar (who is by far one of Disney's best villains in history) and Genie, who, thanks to Robin Williams' solid voice-work, steals every scene with his hilarious moments and the comedy is both timeless and unforgettable. In fact, the voice acting isn't that bad at all especially Scott Weinger, Linda Larkin, Jonathan Freeman, and let's not forget Jim Cummings as the leader of the palace guards. I was like, "Winnie The Pooh/Tigger as a palace guard? Top-notch!" The music from Alan Menken is the epitome of brilliance and the songs were timeless and were not to be long forgotten including one of my favorites "A Whole New World". The script is excellent and flawless with witty and hilarious dialog and the pacing is brisk and moves along very nicely. The strongest aspect, however, goes to the animation due to it's beautiful visual look of Agrabah and solid character designs. Overall, this is one of the few movies that I grew up with as a kid back at the 90s and this will not be forgotten by not only families and their children, but long-time Disney fans as well. Totally recommended and uh... Happy 20th Anniversary, Aladdin!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you never had a friend like me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is a Disney cartoon with a character that we all wish we had as friend, the genie. Aladdin is filled with endless thrills, table turning plans and music that you can't help to like and sing along to. The movie's intro is in form of a narrative, where a merchant tells us the tale of Aladdin and his magic lamp. This 1992 Disney classic is based on an Arab folktale of Aladdin and the magic lamp from One Thousand and One Nights. The idea to make the movie was pitched in by the Late Howard Ashman (who died before the film's release) Ashman has been behind a lot of Disney classics from Oliver & Company, Little Mermaid and Beauty and the Beast. He was a writer, lyricist and producer and he was the lyricist for "Arabian Nights", "Friend Like Me", and "Prince Ali" used in this movie. Aladdin's story is about a street boy, who runs into a princess named Jasmine who escaped the palace to see what life was outside the palace walls where you are not told what to do. While they were together Aladdin gets captured by soldiers under the orders of Jafar, the Grand Vizier to the Sultan of Agrabah (Jasmine's father). Jafar needs Aladdin to retrieve a magical oil lamp containing a genie from the Cave of Wonders. The movie's story now grows on what happened when Jafar didn't get the lamp but Aladdin did in an attempt to read the inscriptions on the lamp, released the genie and he is given 3 wishes. As the song goes, you never had a friend like me So it has been, because all through Disney toon history we never found anyone more appealing to have around, Genie is just the best person to have in at corner. The movie's screenplay explores fantasy, world travel, fireworks and action scenes. Aladdin was a box office hit, making over $ 500 million dollars in its theatrical run and also gave birth to two direct to DVD sequels and a TV series. Aladdin won numerous awards, especially for its music, it won only two Academy Awards, Best Original Score and Best Original Song for "A Whole New World" and it also won four Grammy Awards, Best Soundtrack Album, Song of the Year for "A Whole New World", Best Pop Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal for "A Whole New World" and Best Song Written for a Motion Picture, Television or Other Visual Media for "A Whole New World". Like it or not, Aladdin boast of the best of the best music, and it was also funny and fun to watch, so if you don't own this DVD you Disney collection is not complete yet. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Disney at their finest.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Starr
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like most kids, I also grew up with Disney films, and Aladdin came out the year I was born. However, that did not stop me from watching this film many times during my life. Ever since I was little, this was my favorite Disney movie. This is an excellent film. It teaches great morals, and executes them very well. The story is about Aladdin falling in love with Princess Jasmine, but finds out she can only marry a prince, due to the law. He acquires a lamp with the Genie inside, and he wishes to become a prince, or should I say, look like one. This is my only problem with the film, but this can be overlooked. Why can't he wish he WAS a prince instead of looking like one? But it moves very well into the moral, so I can excuse this. After finding out he would become Sultan after marrying Jasmine, he decides to try and tell her the truth that he's not actually a prince. It's actually before the villain fight and not at the exact end where we have a moral. I like that. He learns that he needs to be truthful, and was trying to tell Jasmine before Jafar exposes him for who he really is. He also learns to keep promises. Before his first wish with the Genie, he promises him he would use his 3rd wish to free him, and even at the end, the Genie tries to talk him into wishing into a prince again, but Aladdin still frees him, despite unlikely being able to marry Jasmine. Nice guy. That is a fantastic way of telling your morals. Not only are the morals amazing, but so are the characters, especially Aladdin himself. He starts off as a homeless person on the streets of Agrabah, but he has very impressive smarts. Not only for thievery, but anything in general. I mainly say this because when he defeats Jafar, he says that the Genie has more power than he does, and he can take away his powers. This convinces Jafar to use his third wish to become a genie himself, but gets stuck in his own lamp. I love this guy. He is the textbook definition of genius. Speaking of smart characters, we also have Jasmine. Her father, the sultan of Agrabah, is trying to rush her into getting married, and tries to bring in many princes to marry her. She hates every single one of them. She doesn't care about the law. If she is to marry, she wants it to be for love. She won't marry anyone. She has to actually care for them. I wouldn't marry someone who attempts to whip little kids either. She also nearly figures out Aladdin not being a prince after the Whole New World song, and Aladdin figures out a good excuse. She's another smart and enjoyable character. I also think she's very hot, but I digress. The most important part of this love story is that the two have great chemistry. They have things in common, and want to help each other out. Not only that, but when Aladdin is Prince Ali, Jasmine actually hates him at first. However, Aladdin builds up the relationship again, and gets Jasmine to fall in love with him again. This may not be on quite the level Beauty and the Beast was with building up a relationship, but it works fine here. Jasmine does suspect that it's actually Aladdin and not a prince before the carpet ride, and she already cared for him, so this is not rushed. It does well for its own love story, but the film is not just that. It's also an adventure, especially since Jafar tries to kill Aladdin a lot. He tries to in the Cave of Wonders when Aladdin is hanging off a cliff and he gets the lamp, he tries to when Aladdin is with Jasmine, and he does after he becomes a sorcerer, along with after Aladdin returns to the palace. In conclusion, the film has many things to like about it. It has many great elements in it, and focuses on them in a very coherent manner. It has a great love story, great adventure, great characters, amazing comic relief, and wonderful animation and colors. This is something you can truly call a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion this film and The Lion King are the best animated films Disney has ever produced. And they're surprisingly similar, yet different enough for us to not get bored even if we watched them back to back. They both deal with the realities of power and the responsibility that comes along with it. In The Lion King, Simba doesn't want the power, he feels like he isn't worthy enough to wield it. Whereas in this film, Aladdin isn't the heir to the power (prophecy notwithstanding), but receives it anyway and is willing to use it, but only to a certain point. And in both films that power falls into the hands of someone who least deserves it, which builds up the main conflict in both films. This is pretty heavy stuff for a film that's aimed primarily for kids, but I absolutely love it because of it. Kids need to learn this stuff sooner or later and I'd personally much rather learn it from a film like this than from bitter experience. And it's not like the whole film is one big gloomfest, designed to depress our kids or to show them material way beyond their years. No, it's bright and festive, pretty to look at with great characters and even greater musical numbers. And the story, based on the old Middle-East tale, is a great one. It has underdogs, it has fight scenes, it has love, betrayal, friendship, magic, wonder, ancient entities, treasure hunts, miracles  it has it all. I fell in love with this film when I first saw it as a kid, and I still love it. It has withstood the test of time and it still remains as one of the best films ever made, animated or live-action. If you haven't seen it already Well, it must have been a nice rock to live under.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End of Disney's Golden Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin, a street urchin, accidentally meets Princess Jasmine, who is in the city undercover. They quickly grow to love each other, but she can only marry a prince. Disney's golden years were 1989-1992, which were unfortunately quite brief. Of course they had hits before that and after that, but for these few years every film was an instant classic. "Aladdin", with its excellent music and the inclusion of Robin Williams, just hit home so hard (and spawned multiple sequels and a television show). How do you critique a film that everyone loves? You simply do not. I guess if I was forced to say anything negative, it would be that Aladdin and Jasmine look a tad too similar and some think they are siblings separated at birth -- and that would not be right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great sense of educational!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film fulling of educational information. Brave, it should be the first, without brave Aladdin cannot play the guardians as fools, he would not bring the lamp out of the hole. Of course, the prince saving the kingdom would not exist. Honest, which is also very indispensable, the second main point in this animation. Abu didn't obey the word and touch a diamond, then they almost died in the hole. Forgetting the promise, Aladdin went to doom and nearly lost everything. Being honest, as the return, it is the forgiveness we see at the end of the story. Contentment, also can be seen from the movie. The fool Jafar failed to learn this, waiting for him is the depriving of freedom the most precious thing to a life. Kindness, which I thought is the first main point showing here makes this film a awesome one. Aladdin is the one who possesses this kind of quality, feeding the street children, making justice for them, saving the princess from blade, and did not be beaten by desire. That is what I thought the most significant quality individual should have. Finally, I want to say, although it is a little bit old animation, please let your children watch it, learn from it, that's the worth of a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Aladdin" is a worthy follow-up to the Disney Studios' previous feature "Beauty and the Beast"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After their previous feature Beauty and the Beast (1991) was the first animated feature in Oscar history to be nominated for Best Picture, the Disney Studios would have a tough act to follow with their next animated picture. In able for this next film to at least be in the same league as Beauty and the Beast, it would have to contain characters, songs, music and a story that are just as memorable as what the prior film offered. As it turns out, the result was the Disney Studio's 31st full-length animated feature, Aladdin (1992). This is another highly entertaining Disney animated feature from the Disney Renaissance which contains pretty much everything you could wish for from a Disney flick whether it would be good laughs, thrilling action, cool animation or awesome songs. We follow a young man named Aladdin and his pet monkey Abu who are sick of being poor and always having to dodge the guards all for the sake of stolen food. They dream that one day they'll be rich enough to put an end to all their troubles. But when they meet a princess named Jasmine who doesn't care for life in the palace because she never goes anywhere and is being forced to marry another prince, things change. After a series of events occur, Aladdin is thrown in the dungeon and a fellow prisoner offers him a way to escape in exchange for doing a task for him. Now, Aladdin has to go to a secret place outside the city of Agrabah called the Cave of Wonders where he must retrieve a magic lamp. This magic lamp contains a highly energetic and fully animated genie (Robin Williams) who can grant Aladdin almost any three wishes he would like. So Aladdin wishes that he was a prince, that way he can try and marry Jasmine. But an evil sorcerer named Jafar and his parrot Iago want Aladdin's lamp and will do anything to get it. Will Aladdin be able to outsmart Jafar and win the princess or not? Want me to summarize why to see Aladdin, if you still haven't, in two words? Well, than those two words would be Robin Williams. Robin Williams was naturally born to voice the genie in this film and I'd guarantee that no matter how hard you tried, you couldn't find another actor that could compete with the high energy and witty comedic style that Williams incorporates into the Genie character. It's been said that much of the dialogue by Robin Williams was improvised or added in even though it wasn't in the original script. To be honest, I couldn't tell the difference between what was and what wasn't in the script since Williams does such a great job at making all of it sound natural. That is precisely how inspired the casting of Robin Williams in this role is. It's not just Williams that makes Aladdin such an entertaining Disney flick, but I also thought that Aladdin and Jasmine had good chemistry between each other. I like the conversations they share with one another regarding how frustrated they are with the lives they're currently living. I don't know about you guys, but when Jasmine basically states that her life of luxury is similar to prison since she can't go outside the palace walls, that's when I thought "maybe being a prince or princess isn't such a good idea". The reason being that in some areas of the world, there's a good possibility that some prince or princess may have no choice but to live that lifestyle. If that somehow wasn't enough to steer you guys away from living a royal life like Jasmine, she's also being forced to get married against her will. Suddenly, a normal lifestyle is sounding excellent to most of us, isn't it? Jafar is another worthy addition to a list of the best Disney villains out there. I admire how he basically enjoys being the most diabolical douchebag to everyone he is around. If there is one thing about some of the greatest Disney villains out there that makes them great including Jafar, it's that they enjoy whatever evil things they're doing. Because they're able to get so much thrill and enjoyment out of what they're doing, that makes us all the more entertained by them in the process. You'll practically love to hate this guy. If there's one thing about this picture that I didn't care for story wise, it would be in regards to Aladdin lying to Jasmine about him being a prince in general. I didn't really care for this part of the story much since most of the dialogue that results from it can be a little too cringe worthy and painfully obvious for my taste. Also, the clich&eacute;d conflict between Aladdin and the genie that results from this part of the story feels forced and unnecessary. I simply felt that it was one routine plot device that didn't need to be in this part of the story at all. Given that it's one of the highest grossing animated features of all time, I think it's safe to say that there's little more to explain about why Aladdin is such a great Disney animated feature. We all know how great the songs by Alan Menken, the late Howard Ashman, and Tim Rice are especially "Friend Like Me", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World". The fast paced, highly energetic, and colorful animation is perfectly suited for a film of this style. I've already gone into detail about Robin Williams' performance, the character of Jafar, and the relationship between Aladdin and Jasmine. You guys have probably seen it many times before, and as far as I'm concerned, you guys deserve to continue seeing it a few times more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watched this Disney's optimal animation in its BluRay form, a stock-in-trade family crowd- pleaser which has been engineered with an impeccable technique and what's more impressive, it oozes an unceasing force of genuineness to edify both children and adults, no condescending doctrine nor feckless naivety, and Robin Williams' voice-performance as the Genie is a great bonus and plays a big part in the film's classic status among its genre. To enumerate Genie's potpourri of imitations alone could be cogent enough to showcase the finesse both for the animators and the voice cast, Robin Williams is deadly hilarious, the motormouthed omnipotent servant, massively steals the thunder from everyone else. But it is not a pejorative remark to other players, on the contrary, it has the most effervescent ensemble including a usually trite class-defying mutual attraction between a princess with a lower-status prince charming. Jafar and Iago pair is another hoot apart from Genie, laughters galore! The plot line entwines pretty much in Disney's safe pattern, a romantic encounter, an abrupt departure, a reunion under the pretense as a legitimate suitor, fighting the evil enemy and happy forever ending, while it really pushes Aladdin to the edge of the cliff since Jafar's invincibility seems to be unbreakable, and the eleventh hour turnover is nothing less than a satisfactory one. 2D animation surely has been largely outcast from the lucrative market, but one can never ascertain there will be a wave of coming back in some years ahead, like Black and White films, their unique aestheticism is the wellspring of their vitality, after watching ALADDIN, it perfectly suffices to originate great mojo of satisfaction for an adult first-time viewer, so the last rites seem to be unnecessary, but a niche market-planning should be conducted for the sake of the laborious craftsmanship. The film currently sits at No.2 at my top 10 film of 1992, and Williams earns him a fifth slot in the supporting actor race, the one and only voice-performance on my own Oscar list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid Gold Disney Classic!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is Disney's 31st full-length animated feature film released in 1992. Based on the popular Arab folktale, the film follows a young peasant boy named Aladdin (voice by Scott Weinger) and his sidekick Abu (voiced by Frank Welker) who are in search of a life outside of the streets from stealing food and dodging guards every day. Then one day, they meet the beautiful Princess Jasmine (voiced by Linda Larkin) in the marketplace and after they save her life, they take her to their place and realize that she wants the exact opposite of what they want; a normal life outside of the palace walls. Then, after Aladdin is thrown into prison by the evil Sorcerer Jafar (voiced by Jonathan Freeman), he is unknowingly taken to the Cave of Wonders by Jafar (disguised as an old beggar man) and his wisecracking sidekick Iago to find an ancient magic lamp that unleashes a genie that grants three wishes. After Aladdin and Abu find the lamp and narrowly escape the Cave on the Magic Carpet, they are thrown back into the cave as it crumbles in the ground. In the process however, Abu grabs the magic lamp, gives it to Aladdin and he accidentally rubs the lamp and unleashes the energetic, hilariously funny Genie (voiced by Robin Williams from "Good Morning, Vietnam", "Mrs. Doubtfire") and chaos ensues!!! This was Disney's fourth film of the Renaissance Era and it's has every element of a classic Disney movie present: great story, unforgettable characters (including one of the best Disney villains of all-time, Jafar), great animation, suspense, great climax, and an awesome score/songs composed by famed Disney composers Alan Menken and Tim Rice (stepping in place of Howard Ashman). The best songs in the movie are "One Jump Ahead", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World", played during the magic carpet ride scene. This is yet another one of my favorite Disney movies and my favorite character is the Genie! If you by any chance haven't seen this classic American animated film in the last 20+ years it's been out, all I have to say is: WATCH IT!!! If you need a good Disney film to watch with the family, then I highly recommend this one! Rating: 10/10!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin belongs to a clan of Disney's magical movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know what Disney is capable of. Disney has produced some of the greatest films of all time like the Lion King but 2 years prior to that, Disney released Aladdin which is also widely regarded as one of Disney's best. Aladdin follows the story of a young streeboy named Aladdin who falls in love with Princess Jasmine and attempts to win her heart by using a genie to make him a prince. However, an evil sorcerer named Jafar is after Aladdin in order to gain his hands on the lamp in order to rule the world and marry Jasmine. Okay, we all know what the story is about and we all know the characters in the film. The story of Aladdin is extremely rich and unforgettable filled with magical characters that just warm our heart. The voice acting is brilliant and it makes for an extremely enjoyable film. The songs in the film aren't as good as, say Beauty and the Beast but they are still pretty remarkable. The script is good and gives us plenty of great laughs. The pacing of the film is brilliant and it never really slows down. In fact, the last twenty minutes is filled with excitement and tension over what will happen. This is definitely a MUST SEE Disney classic for all :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Disney's best post-modern era films of the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I have to admit that I was only born in 1994 when The Lion King was released, but my older sister was born before me in 1992 before Disney released this. Sadly, though, we never saw it in the theaters and waited to watch it on video. Our dreams had finally come true and we loved it as much as anyone else who had seen it and grew up with it. Now, I never read the story "One Thousand Arabian Nights", but I think that this classic did some extreme justice to it. Sure, it does start off a bit slow, but as the film progresses, it has it's heart just in the right place thanks to it's being well thought out. The characters, much like the story, are engaging and likable with the likes of Aladdin, the beautiful Princess Jasmine, Abu, the monkey, Iago, the parrot, the Sultan, Jafar (who is by far one of Disney's best villains in history) and Genie, who, thanks to Robin Williams' solid voice-work, steals every scene with his hilarious moments and the comedy is both timeless and unforgettable. In fact, the voice acting isn't that bad at all especially Scott Weinger, Linda Larkin, Jonathan Freeman, and let's not forget Jim Cummings as the leader of the palace guards. I was like, "Winnie The Pooh/Tigger as a palace guard? Top-notch!" The music from Alan Menken is the epitome of brilliance and the songs were timeless and were not to be long forgotten including one of my favorites "A Whole New World". The script is excellent and flawless with witty and hilarious dialog and the pacing is brisk and moves along very nicely. The strongest aspect, however, goes to the animation due to it's beautiful visual look of Agrabah and solid character designs. Overall, this is one of the few movies that I grew up with as a kid back at the 90s and this will not be forgotten by not only families and their children, but long-time Disney fans as well. Totally recommended and uh... Happy 20th Anniversary, Aladdin!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you never had a friend like me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is a Disney cartoon with a character that we all wish we had as friend, the genie. Aladdin is filled with endless thrills, table turning plans and music that you can't help to like and sing along to. The movie's intro is in form of a narrative, where a merchant tells us the tale of Aladdin and his magic lamp. This 1992 Disney classic is based on an Arab folktale of Aladdin and the magic lamp from One Thousand and One Nights. The idea to make the movie was pitched in by the Late Howard Ashman (who died before the film's release) Ashman has been behind a lot of Disney classics from Oliver & Company, Little Mermaid and Beauty and the Beast. He was a writer, lyricist and producer and he was the lyricist for "Arabian Nights", "Friend Like Me", and "Prince Ali" used in this movie. Aladdin's story is about a street boy, who runs into a princess named Jasmine who escaped the palace to see what life was outside the palace walls where you are not told what to do. While they were together Aladdin gets captured by soldiers under the orders of Jafar, the Grand Vizier to the Sultan of Agrabah (Jasmine's father). Jafar needs Aladdin to retrieve a magical oil lamp containing a genie from the Cave of Wonders. The movie's story now grows on what happened when Jafar didn't get the lamp but Aladdin did in an attempt to read the inscriptions on the lamp, released the genie and he is given 3 wishes. As the song goes, you never had a friend like me So it has been, because all through Disney toon history we never found anyone more appealing to have around, Genie is just the best person to have in at corner. The movie's screenplay explores fantasy, world travel, fireworks and action scenes. Aladdin was a box office hit, making over $ 500 million dollars in its theatrical run and also gave birth to two direct to DVD sequels and a TV series. Aladdin won numerous awards, especially for its music, it won only two Academy Awards, Best Original Score and Best Original Song for "A Whole New World" and it also won four Grammy Awards, Best Soundtrack Album, Song of the Year for "A Whole New World", Best Pop Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal for "A Whole New World" and Best Song Written for a Motion Picture, Television or Other Visual Media for "A Whole New World". Like it or not, Aladdin boast of the best of the best music, and it was also funny and fun to watch, so if you don't own this DVD you Disney collection is not complete yet. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Disney at their finest.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Starr
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like most kids, I also grew up with Disney films, and Aladdin came out the year I was born. However, that did not stop me from watching this film many times during my life. Ever since I was little, this was my favorite Disney movie. This is an excellent film. It teaches great morals, and executes them very well. The story is about Aladdin falling in love with Princess Jasmine, but finds out she can only marry a prince, due to the law. He acquires a lamp with the Genie inside, and he wishes to become a prince, or should I say, look like one. This is my only problem with the film, but this can be overlooked. Why can't he wish he WAS a prince instead of looking like one? But it moves very well into the moral, so I can excuse this. After finding out he would become Sultan after marrying Jasmine, he decides to try and tell her the truth that he's not actually a prince. It's actually before the villain fight and not at the exact end where we have a moral. I like that. He learns that he needs to be truthful, and was trying to tell Jasmine before Jafar exposes him for who he really is. He also learns to keep promises. Before his first wish with the Genie, he promises him he would use his 3rd wish to free him, and even at the end, the Genie tries to talk him into wishing into a prince again, but Aladdin still frees him, despite unlikely being able to marry Jasmine. Nice guy. That is a fantastic way of telling your morals. Not only are the morals amazing, but so are the characters, especially Aladdin himself. He starts off as a homeless person on the streets of Agrabah, but he has very impressive smarts. Not only for thievery, but anything in general. I mainly say this because when he defeats Jafar, he says that the Genie has more power than he does, and he can take away his powers. This convinces Jafar to use his third wish to become a genie himself, but gets stuck in his own lamp. I love this guy. He is the textbook definition of genius. Speaking of smart characters, we also have Jasmine. Her father, the sultan of Agrabah, is trying to rush her into getting married, and tries to bring in many princes to marry her. She hates every single one of them. She doesn't care about the law. If she is to marry, she wants it to be for love. She won't marry anyone. She has to actually care for them. I wouldn't marry someone who attempts to whip little kids either. She also nearly figures out Aladdin not being a prince after the Whole New World song, and Aladdin figures out a good excuse. She's another smart and enjoyable character. I also think she's very hot, but I digress. The most important part of this love story is that the two have great chemistry. They have things in common, and want to help each other out. Not only that, but when Aladdin is Prince Ali, Jasmine actually hates him at first. However, Aladdin builds up the relationship again, and gets Jasmine to fall in love with him again. This may not be on quite the level Beauty and the Beast was with building up a relationship, but it works fine here. Jasmine does suspect that it's actually Aladdin and not a prince before the carpet ride, and she already cared for him, so this is not rushed. It does well for its own love story, but the film is not just that. It's also an adventure, especially since Jafar tries to kill Aladdin a lot. He tries to in the Cave of Wonders when Aladdin is hanging off a cliff and he gets the lamp, he tries to when Aladdin is with Jasmine, and he does after he becomes a sorcerer, along with after Aladdin returns to the palace. In conclusion, the film has many things to like about it. It has many great elements in it, and focuses on them in a very coherent manner. It has a great love story, great adventure, great characters, amazing comic relief, and wonderful animation and colors. This is something you can truly call a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion this film and The Lion King are the best animated films Disney has ever produced. And they're surprisingly similar, yet different enough for us to not get bored even if we watched them back to back. They both deal with the realities of power and the responsibility that comes along with it. In The Lion King, Simba doesn't want the power, he feels like he isn't worthy enough to wield it. Whereas in this film, Aladdin isn't the heir to the power (prophecy notwithstanding), but receives it anyway and is willing to use it, but only to a certain point. And in both films that power falls into the hands of someone who least deserves it, which builds up the main conflict in both films. This is pretty heavy stuff for a film that's aimed primarily for kids, but I absolutely love it because of it. Kids need to learn this stuff sooner or later and I'd personally much rather learn it from a film like this than from bitter experience. And it's not like the whole film is one big gloomfest, designed to depress our kids or to show them material way beyond their years. No, it's bright and festive, pretty to look at with great characters and even greater musical numbers. And the story, based on the old Middle-East tale, is a great one. It has underdogs, it has fight scenes, it has love, betrayal, friendship, magic, wonder, ancient entities, treasure hunts, miracles  it has it all. I fell in love with this film when I first saw it as a kid, and I still love it. It has withstood the test of time and it still remains as one of the best films ever made, animated or live-action. If you haven't seen it already Well, it must have been a nice rock to live under.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End of Disney's Golden Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin, a street urchin, accidentally meets Princess Jasmine, who is in the city undercover. They quickly grow to love each other, but she can only marry a prince. Disney's golden years were 1989-1992, which were unfortunately quite brief. Of course they had hits before that and after that, but for these few years every film was an instant classic. "Aladdin", with its excellent music and the inclusion of Robin Williams, just hit home so hard (and spawned multiple sequels and a television show). How do you critique a film that everyone loves? You simply do not. I guess if I was forced to say anything negative, it would be that Aladdin and Jasmine look a tad too similar and some think they are siblings separated at birth -- and that would not be right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great sense of educational!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film fulling of educational information. Brave, it should be the first, without brave Aladdin cannot play the guardians as fools, he would not bring the lamp out of the hole. Of course, the prince saving the kingdom would not exist. Honest, which is also very indispensable, the second main point in this animation. Abu didn't obey the word and touch a diamond, then they almost died in the hole. Forgetting the promise, Aladdin went to doom and nearly lost everything. Being honest, as the return, it is the forgiveness we see at the end of the story. Contentment, also can be seen from the movie. The fool Jafar failed to learn this, waiting for him is the depriving of freedom the most precious thing to a life. Kindness, which I thought is the first main point showing here makes this film a awesome one. Aladdin is the one who possesses this kind of quality, feeding the street children, making justice for them, saving the princess from blade, and did not be beaten by desire. That is what I thought the most significant quality individual should have. Finally, I want to say, although it is a little bit old animation, please let your children watch it, learn from it, that's the worth of a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Aladdin" is a worthy follow-up to the Disney Studios' previous feature "Beauty and the Beast"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After their previous feature Beauty and the Beast (1991) was the first animated feature in Oscar history to be nominated for Best Picture, the Disney Studios would have a tough act to follow with their next animated picture. In able for this next film to at least be in the same league as Beauty and the Beast, it would have to contain characters, songs, music and a story that are just as memorable as what the prior film offered. As it turns out, the result was the Disney Studio's 31st full-length animated feature, Aladdin (1992). This is another highly entertaining Disney animated feature from the Disney Renaissance which contains pretty much everything you could wish for from a Disney flick whether it would be good laughs, thrilling action, cool animation or awesome songs. We follow a young man named Aladdin and his pet monkey Abu who are sick of being poor and always having to dodge the guards all for the sake of stolen food. They dream that one day they'll be rich enough to put an end to all their troubles. But when they meet a princess named Jasmine who doesn't care for life in the palace because she never goes anywhere and is being forced to marry another prince, things change. After a series of events occur, Aladdin is thrown in the dungeon and a fellow prisoner offers him a way to escape in exchange for doing a task for him. Now, Aladdin has to go to a secret place outside the city of Agrabah called the Cave of Wonders where he must retrieve a magic lamp. This magic lamp contains a highly energetic and fully animated genie (Robin Williams) who can grant Aladdin almost any three wishes he would like. So Aladdin wishes that he was a prince, that way he can try and marry Jasmine. But an evil sorcerer named Jafar and his parrot Iago want Aladdin's lamp and will do anything to get it. Will Aladdin be able to outsmart Jafar and win the princess or not? Want me to summarize why to see Aladdin, if you still haven't, in two words? Well, than those two words would be Robin Williams. Robin Williams was naturally born to voice the genie in this film and I'd guarantee that no matter how hard you tried, you couldn't find another actor that could compete with the high energy and witty comedic style that Williams incorporates into the Genie character. It's been said that much of the dialogue by Robin Williams was improvised or added in even though it wasn't in the original script. To be honest, I couldn't tell the difference between what was and what wasn't in the script since Williams does such a great job at making all of it sound natural. That is precisely how inspired the casting of Robin Williams in this role is. It's not just Williams that makes Aladdin such an entertaining Disney flick, but I also thought that Aladdin and Jasmine had good chemistry between each other. I like the conversations they share with one another regarding how frustrated they are with the lives they're currently living. I don't know about you guys, but when Jasmine basically states that her life of luxury is similar to prison since she can't go outside the palace walls, that's when I thought "maybe being a prince or princess isn't such a good idea". The reason being that in some areas of the world, there's a good possibility that some prince or princess may have no choice but to live that lifestyle. If that somehow wasn't enough to steer you guys away from living a royal life like Jasmine, she's also being forced to get married against her will. Suddenly, a normal lifestyle is sounding excellent to most of us, isn't it? Jafar is another worthy addition to a list of the best Disney villains out there. I admire how he basically enjoys being the most diabolical douchebag to everyone he is around. If there is one thing about some of the greatest Disney villains out there that makes them great including Jafar, it's that they enjoy whatever evil things they're doing. Because they're able to get so much thrill and enjoyment out of what they're doing, that makes us all the more entertained by them in the process. You'll practically love to hate this guy. If there's one thing about this picture that I didn't care for story wise, it would be in regards to Aladdin lying to Jasmine about him being a prince in general. I didn't really care for this part of the story much since most of the dialogue that results from it can be a little too cringe worthy and painfully obvious for my taste. Also, the clich&eacute;d conflict between Aladdin and the genie that results from this part of the story feels forced and unnecessary. I simply felt that it was one routine plot device that didn't need to be in this part of the story at all. Given that it's one of the highest grossing animated features of all time, I think it's safe to say that there's little more to explain about why Aladdin is such a great Disney animated feature. We all know how great the songs by Alan Menken, the late Howard Ashman, and Tim Rice are especially "Friend Like Me", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World". The fast paced, highly energetic, and colorful animation is perfectly suited for a film of this style. I've already gone into detail about Robin Williams' performance, the character of Jafar, and the relationship between Aladdin and Jasmine. You guys have probably seen it many times before, and as far as I'm concerned, you guys deserve to continue seeing it a few times more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watched this Disney's optimal animation in its BluRay form, a stock-in-trade family crowd- pleaser which has been engineered with an impeccable technique and what's more impressive, it oozes an unceasing force of genuineness to edify both children and adults, no condescending doctrine nor feckless naivety, and Robin Williams' voice-performance as the Genie is a great bonus and plays a big part in the film's classic status among its genre. To enumerate Genie's potpourri of imitations alone could be cogent enough to showcase the finesse both for the animators and the voice cast, Robin Williams is deadly hilarious, the motormouthed omnipotent servant, massively steals the thunder from everyone else. But it is not a pejorative remark to other players, on the contrary, it has the most effervescent ensemble including a usually trite class-defying mutual attraction between a princess with a lower-status prince charming. Jafar and Iago pair is another hoot apart from Genie, laughters galore! The plot line entwines pretty much in Disney's safe pattern, a romantic encounter, an abrupt departure, a reunion under the pretense as a legitimate suitor, fighting the evil enemy and happy forever ending, while it really pushes Aladdin to the edge of the cliff since Jafar's invincibility seems to be unbreakable, and the eleventh hour turnover is nothing less than a satisfactory one. 2D animation surely has been largely outcast from the lucrative market, but one can never ascertain there will be a wave of coming back in some years ahead, like Black and White films, their unique aestheticism is the wellspring of their vitality, after watching ALADDIN, it perfectly suffices to originate great mojo of satisfaction for an adult first-time viewer, so the last rites seem to be unnecessary, but a niche market-planning should be conducted for the sake of the laborious craftsmanship. The film currently sits at No.2 at my top 10 film of 1992, and Williams earns him a fifth slot in the supporting actor race, the one and only voice-performance on my own Oscar list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid Gold Disney Classic!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is Disney's 31st full-length animated feature film released in 1992. Based on the popular Arab folktale, the film follows a young peasant boy named Aladdin (voice by Scott Weinger) and his sidekick Abu (voiced by Frank Welker) who are in search of a life outside of the streets from stealing food and dodging guards every day. Then one day, they meet the beautiful Princess Jasmine (voiced by Linda Larkin) in the marketplace and after they save her life, they take her to their place and realize that she wants the exact opposite of what they want; a normal life outside of the palace walls. Then, after Aladdin is thrown into prison by the evil Sorcerer Jafar (voiced by Jonathan Freeman), he is unknowingly taken to the Cave of Wonders by Jafar (disguised as an old beggar man) and his wisecracking sidekick Iago to find an ancient magic lamp that unleashes a genie that grants three wishes. After Aladdin and Abu find the lamp and narrowly escape the Cave on the Magic Carpet, they are thrown back into the cave as it crumbles in the ground. In the process however, Abu grabs the magic lamp, gives it to Aladdin and he accidentally rubs the lamp and unleashes the energetic, hilariously funny Genie (voiced by Robin Williams from "Good Morning, Vietnam", "Mrs. Doubtfire") and chaos ensues!!! This was Disney's fourth film of the Renaissance Era and it's has every element of a classic Disney movie present: great story, unforgettable characters (including one of the best Disney villains of all-time, Jafar), great animation, suspense, great climax, and an awesome score/songs composed by famed Disney composers Alan Menken and Tim Rice (stepping in place of Howard Ashman). The best songs in the movie are "One Jump Ahead", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World", played during the magic carpet ride scene. This is yet another one of my favorite Disney movies and my favorite character is the Genie! If you by any chance haven't seen this classic American animated film in the last 20+ years it's been out, all I have to say is: WATCH IT!!! If you need a good Disney film to watch with the family, then I highly recommend this one! Rating: 10/10!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin belongs to a clan of Disney's magical movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know what Disney is capable of. Disney has produced some of the greatest films of all time like the Lion King but 2 years prior to that, Disney released Aladdin which is also widely regarded as one of Disney's best. Aladdin follows the story of a young streeboy named Aladdin who falls in love with Princess Jasmine and attempts to win her heart by using a genie to make him a prince. However, an evil sorcerer named Jafar is after Aladdin in order to gain his hands on the lamp in order to rule the world and marry Jasmine. Okay, we all know what the story is about and we all know the characters in the film. The story of Aladdin is extremely rich and unforgettable filled with magical characters that just warm our heart. The voice acting is brilliant and it makes for an extremely enjoyable film. The songs in the film aren't as good as, say Beauty and the Beast but they are still pretty remarkable. The script is good and gives us plenty of great laughs. The pacing of the film is brilliant and it never really slows down. In fact, the last twenty minutes is filled with excitement and tension over what will happen. This is definitely a MUST SEE Disney classic for all :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Disney's best post-modern era films of the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I have to admit that I was only born in 1994 when The Lion King was released, but my older sister was born before me in 1992 before Disney released this. Sadly, though, we never saw it in the theaters and waited to watch it on video. Our dreams had finally come true and we loved it as much as anyone else who had seen it and grew up with it. Now, I never read the story "One Thousand Arabian Nights", but I think that this classic did some extreme justice to it. Sure, it does start off a bit slow, but as the film progresses, it has it's heart just in the right place thanks to it's being well thought out. The characters, much like the story, are engaging and likable with the likes of Aladdin, the beautiful Princess Jasmine, Abu, the monkey, Iago, the parrot, the Sultan, Jafar (who is by far one of Disney's best villains in history) and Genie, who, thanks to Robin Williams' solid voice-work, steals every scene with his hilarious moments and the comedy is both timeless and unforgettable. In fact, the voice acting isn't that bad at all especially Scott Weinger, Linda Larkin, Jonathan Freeman, and let's not forget Jim Cummings as the leader of the palace guards. I was like, "Winnie The Pooh/Tigger as a palace guard? Top-notch!" The music from Alan Menken is the epitome of brilliance and the songs were timeless and were not to be long forgotten including one of my favorites "A Whole New World". The script is excellent and flawless with witty and hilarious dialog and the pacing is brisk and moves along very nicely. The strongest aspect, however, goes to the animation due to it's beautiful visual look of Agrabah and solid character designs. Overall, this is one of the few movies that I grew up with as a kid back at the 90s and this will not be forgotten by not only families and their children, but long-time Disney fans as well. Totally recommended and uh... Happy 20th Anniversary, Aladdin!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you never had a friend like me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is a Disney cartoon with a character that we all wish we had as friend, the genie. Aladdin is filled with endless thrills, table turning plans and music that you can't help to like and sing along to. The movie's intro is in form of a narrative, where a merchant tells us the tale of Aladdin and his magic lamp. This 1992 Disney classic is based on an Arab folktale of Aladdin and the magic lamp from One Thousand and One Nights. The idea to make the movie was pitched in by the Late Howard Ashman (who died before the film's release) Ashman has been behind a lot of Disney classics from Oliver & Company, Little Mermaid and Beauty and the Beast. He was a writer, lyricist and producer and he was the lyricist for "Arabian Nights", "Friend Like Me", and "Prince Ali" used in this movie. Aladdin's story is about a street boy, who runs into a princess named Jasmine who escaped the palace to see what life was outside the palace walls where you are not told what to do. While they were together Aladdin gets captured by soldiers under the orders of Jafar, the Grand Vizier to the Sultan of Agrabah (Jasmine's father). Jafar needs Aladdin to retrieve a magical oil lamp containing a genie from the Cave of Wonders. The movie's story now grows on what happened when Jafar didn't get the lamp but Aladdin did in an attempt to read the inscriptions on the lamp, released the genie and he is given 3 wishes. As the song goes, you never had a friend like me So it has been, because all through Disney toon history we never found anyone more appealing to have around, Genie is just the best person to have in at corner. The movie's screenplay explores fantasy, world travel, fireworks and action scenes. Aladdin was a box office hit, making over $ 500 million dollars in its theatrical run and also gave birth to two direct to DVD sequels and a TV series. Aladdin won numerous awards, especially for its music, it won only two Academy Awards, Best Original Score and Best Original Song for "A Whole New World" and it also won four Grammy Awards, Best Soundtrack Album, Song of the Year for "A Whole New World", Best Pop Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal for "A Whole New World" and Best Song Written for a Motion Picture, Television or Other Visual Media for "A Whole New World". Like it or not, Aladdin boast of the best of the best music, and it was also funny and fun to watch, so if you don't own this DVD you Disney collection is not complete yet. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Disney at their finest.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Starr
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like most kids, I also grew up with Disney films, and Aladdin came out the year I was born. However, that did not stop me from watching this film many times during my life. Ever since I was little, this was my favorite Disney movie. This is an excellent film. It teaches great morals, and executes them very well. The story is about Aladdin falling in love with Princess Jasmine, but finds out she can only marry a prince, due to the law. He acquires a lamp with the Genie inside, and he wishes to become a prince, or should I say, look like one. This is my only problem with the film, but this can be overlooked. Why can't he wish he WAS a prince instead of looking like one? But it moves very well into the moral, so I can excuse this. After finding out he would become Sultan after marrying Jasmine, he decides to try and tell her the truth that he's not actually a prince. It's actually before the villain fight and not at the exact end where we have a moral. I like that. He learns that he needs to be truthful, and was trying to tell Jasmine before Jafar exposes him for who he really is. He also learns to keep promises. Before his first wish with the Genie, he promises him he would use his 3rd wish to free him, and even at the end, the Genie tries to talk him into wishing into a prince again, but Aladdin still frees him, despite unlikely being able to marry Jasmine. Nice guy. That is a fantastic way of telling your morals. Not only are the morals amazing, but so are the characters, especially Aladdin himself. He starts off as a homeless person on the streets of Agrabah, but he has very impressive smarts. Not only for thievery, but anything in general. I mainly say this because when he defeats Jafar, he says that the Genie has more power than he does, and he can take away his powers. This convinces Jafar to use his third wish to become a genie himself, but gets stuck in his own lamp. I love this guy. He is the textbook definition of genius. Speaking of smart characters, we also have Jasmine. Her father, the sultan of Agrabah, is trying to rush her into getting married, and tries to bring in many princes to marry her. She hates every single one of them. She doesn't care about the law. If she is to marry, she wants it to be for love. She won't marry anyone. She has to actually care for them. I wouldn't marry someone who attempts to whip little kids either. She also nearly figures out Aladdin not being a prince after the Whole New World song, and Aladdin figures out a good excuse. She's another smart and enjoyable character. I also think she's very hot, but I digress. The most important part of this love story is that the two have great chemistry. They have things in common, and want to help each other out. Not only that, but when Aladdin is Prince Ali, Jasmine actually hates him at first. However, Aladdin builds up the relationship again, and gets Jasmine to fall in love with him again. This may not be on quite the level Beauty and the Beast was with building up a relationship, but it works fine here. Jasmine does suspect that it's actually Aladdin and not a prince before the carpet ride, and she already cared for him, so this is not rushed. It does well for its own love story, but the film is not just that. It's also an adventure, especially since Jafar tries to kill Aladdin a lot. He tries to in the Cave of Wonders when Aladdin is hanging off a cliff and he gets the lamp, he tries to when Aladdin is with Jasmine, and he does after he becomes a sorcerer, along with after Aladdin returns to the palace. In conclusion, the film has many things to like about it. It has many great elements in it, and focuses on them in a very coherent manner. It has a great love story, great adventure, great characters, amazing comic relief, and wonderful animation and colors. This is something you can truly call a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion this film and The Lion King are the best animated films Disney has ever produced. And they're surprisingly similar, yet different enough for us to not get bored even if we watched them back to back. They both deal with the realities of power and the responsibility that comes along with it. In The Lion King, Simba doesn't want the power, he feels like he isn't worthy enough to wield it. Whereas in this film, Aladdin isn't the heir to the power (prophecy notwithstanding), but receives it anyway and is willing to use it, but only to a certain point. And in both films that power falls into the hands of someone who least deserves it, which builds up the main conflict in both films. This is pretty heavy stuff for a film that's aimed primarily for kids, but I absolutely love it because of it. Kids need to learn this stuff sooner or later and I'd personally much rather learn it from a film like this than from bitter experience. And it's not like the whole film is one big gloomfest, designed to depress our kids or to show them material way beyond their years. No, it's bright and festive, pretty to look at with great characters and even greater musical numbers. And the story, based on the old Middle-East tale, is a great one. It has underdogs, it has fight scenes, it has love, betrayal, friendship, magic, wonder, ancient entities, treasure hunts, miracles  it has it all. I fell in love with this film when I first saw it as a kid, and I still love it. It has withstood the test of time and it still remains as one of the best films ever made, animated or live-action. If you haven't seen it already Well, it must have been a nice rock to live under.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End of Disney's Golden Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin, a street urchin, accidentally meets Princess Jasmine, who is in the city undercover. They quickly grow to love each other, but she can only marry a prince. Disney's golden years were 1989-1992, which were unfortunately quite brief. Of course they had hits before that and after that, but for these few years every film was an instant classic. "Aladdin", with its excellent music and the inclusion of Robin Williams, just hit home so hard (and spawned multiple sequels and a television show). How do you critique a film that everyone loves? You simply do not. I guess if I was forced to say anything negative, it would be that Aladdin and Jasmine look a tad too similar and some think they are siblings separated at birth -- and that would not be right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great sense of educational!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film fulling of educational information. Brave, it should be the first, without brave Aladdin cannot play the guardians as fools, he would not bring the lamp out of the hole. Of course, the prince saving the kingdom would not exist. Honest, which is also very indispensable, the second main point in this animation. Abu didn't obey the word and touch a diamond, then they almost died in the hole. Forgetting the promise, Aladdin went to doom and nearly lost everything. Being honest, as the return, it is the forgiveness we see at the end of the story. Contentment, also can be seen from the movie. The fool Jafar failed to learn this, waiting for him is the depriving of freedom the most precious thing to a life. Kindness, which I thought is the first main point showing here makes this film a awesome one. Aladdin is the one who possesses this kind of quality, feeding the street children, making justice for them, saving the princess from blade, and did not be beaten by desire. That is what I thought the most significant quality individual should have. Finally, I want to say, although it is a little bit old animation, please let your children watch it, learn from it, that's the worth of a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Aladdin" is a worthy follow-up to the Disney Studios' previous feature "Beauty and the Beast"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After their previous feature Beauty and the Beast (1991) was the first animated feature in Oscar history to be nominated for Best Picture, the Disney Studios would have a tough act to follow with their next animated picture. In able for this next film to at least be in the same league as Beauty and the Beast, it would have to contain characters, songs, music and a story that are just as memorable as what the prior film offered. As it turns out, the result was the Disney Studio's 31st full-length animated feature, Aladdin (1992). This is another highly entertaining Disney animated feature from the Disney Renaissance which contains pretty much everything you could wish for from a Disney flick whether it would be good laughs, thrilling action, cool animation or awesome songs. We follow a young man named Aladdin and his pet monkey Abu who are sick of being poor and always having to dodge the guards all for the sake of stolen food. They dream that one day they'll be rich enough to put an end to all their troubles. But when they meet a princess named Jasmine who doesn't care for life in the palace because she never goes anywhere and is being forced to marry another prince, things change. After a series of events occur, Aladdin is thrown in the dungeon and a fellow prisoner offers him a way to escape in exchange for doing a task for him. Now, Aladdin has to go to a secret place outside the city of Agrabah called the Cave of Wonders where he must retrieve a magic lamp. This magic lamp contains a highly energetic and fully animated genie (Robin Williams) who can grant Aladdin almost any three wishes he would like. So Aladdin wishes that he was a prince, that way he can try and marry Jasmine. But an evil sorcerer named Jafar and his parrot Iago want Aladdin's lamp and will do anything to get it. Will Aladdin be able to outsmart Jafar and win the princess or not? Want me to summarize why to see Aladdin, if you still haven't, in two words? Well, than those two words would be Robin Williams. Robin Williams was naturally born to voice the genie in this film and I'd guarantee that no matter how hard you tried, you couldn't find another actor that could compete with the high energy and witty comedic style that Williams incorporates into the Genie character. It's been said that much of the dialogue by Robin Williams was improvised or added in even though it wasn't in the original script. To be honest, I couldn't tell the difference between what was and what wasn't in the script since Williams does such a great job at making all of it sound natural. That is precisely how inspired the casting of Robin Williams in this role is. It's not just Williams that makes Aladdin such an entertaining Disney flick, but I also thought that Aladdin and Jasmine had good chemistry between each other. I like the conversations they share with one another regarding how frustrated they are with the lives they're currently living. I don't know about you guys, but when Jasmine basically states that her life of luxury is similar to prison since she can't go outside the palace walls, that's when I thought "maybe being a prince or princess isn't such a good idea". The reason being that in some areas of the world, there's a good possibility that some prince or princess may have no choice but to live that lifestyle. If that somehow wasn't enough to steer you guys away from living a royal life like Jasmine, she's also being forced to get married against her will. Suddenly, a normal lifestyle is sounding excellent to most of us, isn't it? Jafar is another worthy addition to a list of the best Disney villains out there. I admire how he basically enjoys being the most diabolical douchebag to everyone he is around. If there is one thing about some of the greatest Disney villains out there that makes them great including Jafar, it's that they enjoy whatever evil things they're doing. Because they're able to get so much thrill and enjoyment out of what they're doing, that makes us all the more entertained by them in the process. You'll practically love to hate this guy. If there's one thing about this picture that I didn't care for story wise, it would be in regards to Aladdin lying to Jasmine about him being a prince in general. I didn't really care for this part of the story much since most of the dialogue that results from it can be a little too cringe worthy and painfully obvious for my taste. Also, the clich&eacute;d conflict between Aladdin and the genie that results from this part of the story feels forced and unnecessary. I simply felt that it was one routine plot device that didn't need to be in this part of the story at all. Given that it's one of the highest grossing animated features of all time, I think it's safe to say that there's little more to explain about why Aladdin is such a great Disney animated feature. We all know how great the songs by Alan Menken, the late Howard Ashman, and Tim Rice are especially "Friend Like Me", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World". The fast paced, highly energetic, and colorful animation is perfectly suited for a film of this style. I've already gone into detail about Robin Williams' performance, the character of Jafar, and the relationship between Aladdin and Jasmine. You guys have probably seen it many times before, and as far as I'm concerned, you guys deserve to continue seeing it a few times more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watched this Disney's optimal animation in its BluRay form, a stock-in-trade family crowd- pleaser which has been engineered with an impeccable technique and what's more impressive, it oozes an unceasing force of genuineness to edify both children and adults, no condescending doctrine nor feckless naivety, and Robin Williams' voice-performance as the Genie is a great bonus and plays a big part in the film's classic status among its genre. To enumerate Genie's potpourri of imitations alone could be cogent enough to showcase the finesse both for the animators and the voice cast, Robin Williams is deadly hilarious, the motormouthed omnipotent servant, massively steals the thunder from everyone else. But it is not a pejorative remark to other players, on the contrary, it has the most effervescent ensemble including a usually trite class-defying mutual attraction between a princess with a lower-status prince charming. Jafar and Iago pair is another hoot apart from Genie, laughters galore! The plot line entwines pretty much in Disney's safe pattern, a romantic encounter, an abrupt departure, a reunion under the pretense as a legitimate suitor, fighting the evil enemy and happy forever ending, while it really pushes Aladdin to the edge of the cliff since Jafar's invincibility seems to be unbreakable, and the eleventh hour turnover is nothing less than a satisfactory one. 2D animation surely has been largely outcast from the lucrative market, but one can never ascertain there will be a wave of coming back in some years ahead, like Black and White films, their unique aestheticism is the wellspring of their vitality, after watching ALADDIN, it perfectly suffices to originate great mojo of satisfaction for an adult first-time viewer, so the last rites seem to be unnecessary, but a niche market-planning should be conducted for the sake of the laborious craftsmanship. The film currently sits at No.2 at my top 10 film of 1992, and Williams earns him a fifth slot in the supporting actor race, the one and only voice-performance on my own Oscar list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid Gold Disney Classic!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is Disney's 31st full-length animated feature film released in 1992. Based on the popular Arab folktale, the film follows a young peasant boy named Aladdin (voice by Scott Weinger) and his sidekick Abu (voiced by Frank Welker) who are in search of a life outside of the streets from stealing food and dodging guards every day. Then one day, they meet the beautiful Princess Jasmine (voiced by Linda Larkin) in the marketplace and after they save her life, they take her to their place and realize that she wants the exact opposite of what they want; a normal life outside of the palace walls. Then, after Aladdin is thrown into prison by the evil Sorcerer Jafar (voiced by Jonathan Freeman), he is unknowingly taken to the Cave of Wonders by Jafar (disguised as an old beggar man) and his wisecracking sidekick Iago to find an ancient magic lamp that unleashes a genie that grants three wishes. After Aladdin and Abu find the lamp and narrowly escape the Cave on the Magic Carpet, they are thrown back into the cave as it crumbles in the ground. In the process however, Abu grabs the magic lamp, gives it to Aladdin and he accidentally rubs the lamp and unleashes the energetic, hilariously funny Genie (voiced by Robin Williams from "Good Morning, Vietnam", "Mrs. Doubtfire") and chaos ensues!!! This was Disney's fourth film of the Renaissance Era and it's has every element of a classic Disney movie present: great story, unforgettable characters (including one of the best Disney villains of all-time, Jafar), great animation, suspense, great climax, and an awesome score/songs composed by famed Disney composers Alan Menken and Tim Rice (stepping in place of Howard Ashman). The best songs in the movie are "One Jump Ahead", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World", played during the magic carpet ride scene. This is yet another one of my favorite Disney movies and my favorite character is the Genie! If you by any chance haven't seen this classic American animated film in the last 20+ years it's been out, all I have to say is: WATCH IT!!! If you need a good Disney film to watch with the family, then I highly recommend this one! Rating: 10/10!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin belongs to a clan of Disney's magical movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know what Disney is capable of. Disney has produced some of the greatest films of all time like the Lion King but 2 years prior to that, Disney released Aladdin which is also widely regarded as one of Disney's best. Aladdin follows the story of a young streeboy named Aladdin who falls in love with Princess Jasmine and attempts to win her heart by using a genie to make him a prince. However, an evil sorcerer named Jafar is after Aladdin in order to gain his hands on the lamp in order to rule the world and marry Jasmine. Okay, we all know what the story is about and we all know the characters in the film. The story of Aladdin is extremely rich and unforgettable filled with magical characters that just warm our heart. The voice acting is brilliant and it makes for an extremely enjoyable film. The songs in the film aren't as good as, say Beauty and the Beast but they are still pretty remarkable. The script is good and gives us plenty of great laughs. The pacing of the film is brilliant and it never really slows down. In fact, the last twenty minutes is filled with excitement and tension over what will happen. This is definitely a MUST SEE Disney classic for all :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Disney's best post-modern era films of the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I have to admit that I was only born in 1994 when The Lion King was released, but my older sister was born before me in 1992 before Disney released this. Sadly, though, we never saw it in the theaters and waited to watch it on video. Our dreams had finally come true and we loved it as much as anyone else who had seen it and grew up with it. Now, I never read the story "One Thousand Arabian Nights", but I think that this classic did some extreme justice to it. Sure, it does start off a bit slow, but as the film progresses, it has it's heart just in the right place thanks to it's being well thought out. The characters, much like the story, are engaging and likable with the likes of Aladdin, the beautiful Princess Jasmine, Abu, the monkey, Iago, the parrot, the Sultan, Jafar (who is by far one of Disney's best villains in history) and Genie, who, thanks to Robin Williams' solid voice-work, steals every scene with his hilarious moments and the comedy is both timeless and unforgettable. In fact, the voice acting isn't that bad at all especially Scott Weinger, Linda Larkin, Jonathan Freeman, and let's not forget Jim Cummings as the leader of the palace guards. I was like, "Winnie The Pooh/Tigger as a palace guard? Top-notch!" The music from Alan Menken is the epitome of brilliance and the songs were timeless and were not to be long forgotten including one of my favorites "A Whole New World". The script is excellent and flawless with witty and hilarious dialog and the pacing is brisk and moves along very nicely. The strongest aspect, however, goes to the animation due to it's beautiful visual look of Agrabah and solid character designs. Overall, this is one of the few movies that I grew up with as a kid back at the 90s and this will not be forgotten by not only families and their children, but long-time Disney fans as well. Totally recommended and uh... Happy 20th Anniversary, Aladdin!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you never had a friend like me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is a Disney cartoon with a character that we all wish we had as friend, the genie. Aladdin is filled with endless thrills, table turning plans and music that you can't help to like and sing along to. The movie's intro is in form of a narrative, where a merchant tells us the tale of Aladdin and his magic lamp. This 1992 Disney classic is based on an Arab folktale of Aladdin and the magic lamp from One Thousand and One Nights. The idea to make the movie was pitched in by the Late Howard Ashman (who died before the film's release) Ashman has been behind a lot of Disney classics from Oliver & Company, Little Mermaid and Beauty and the Beast. He was a writer, lyricist and producer and he was the lyricist for "Arabian Nights", "Friend Like Me", and "Prince Ali" used in this movie. Aladdin's story is about a street boy, who runs into a princess named Jasmine who escaped the palace to see what life was outside the palace walls where you are not told what to do. While they were together Aladdin gets captured by soldiers under the orders of Jafar, the Grand Vizier to the Sultan of Agrabah (Jasmine's father). Jafar needs Aladdin to retrieve a magical oil lamp containing a genie from the Cave of Wonders. The movie's story now grows on what happened when Jafar didn't get the lamp but Aladdin did in an attempt to read the inscriptions on the lamp, released the genie and he is given 3 wishes. As the song goes, you never had a friend like me So it has been, because all through Disney toon history we never found anyone more appealing to have around, Genie is just the best person to have in at corner. The movie's screenplay explores fantasy, world travel, fireworks and action scenes. Aladdin was a box office hit, making over $ 500 million dollars in its theatrical run and also gave birth to two direct to DVD sequels and a TV series. Aladdin won numerous awards, especially for its music, it won only two Academy Awards, Best Original Score and Best Original Song for "A Whole New World" and it also won four Grammy Awards, Best Soundtrack Album, Song of the Year for "A Whole New World", Best Pop Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal for "A Whole New World" and Best Song Written for a Motion Picture, Television or Other Visual Media for "A Whole New World". Like it or not, Aladdin boast of the best of the best music, and it was also funny and fun to watch, so if you don't own this DVD you Disney collection is not complete yet. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Disney at their finest.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Starr
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like most kids, I also grew up with Disney films, and Aladdin came out the year I was born. However, that did not stop me from watching this film many times during my life. Ever since I was little, this was my favorite Disney movie. This is an excellent film. It teaches great morals, and executes them very well. The story is about Aladdin falling in love with Princess Jasmine, but finds out she can only marry a prince, due to the law. He acquires a lamp with the Genie inside, and he wishes to become a prince, or should I say, look like one. This is my only problem with the film, but this can be overlooked. Why can't he wish he WAS a prince instead of looking like one? But it moves very well into the moral, so I can excuse this. After finding out he would become Sultan after marrying Jasmine, he decides to try and tell her the truth that he's not actually a prince. It's actually before the villain fight and not at the exact end where we have a moral. I like that. He learns that he needs to be truthful, and was trying to tell Jasmine before Jafar exposes him for who he really is. He also learns to keep promises. Before his first wish with the Genie, he promises him he would use his 3rd wish to free him, and even at the end, the Genie tries to talk him into wishing into a prince again, but Aladdin still frees him, despite unlikely being able to marry Jasmine. Nice guy. That is a fantastic way of telling your morals. Not only are the morals amazing, but so are the characters, especially Aladdin himself. He starts off as a homeless person on the streets of Agrabah, but he has very impressive smarts. Not only for thievery, but anything in general. I mainly say this because when he defeats Jafar, he says that the Genie has more power than he does, and he can take away his powers. This convinces Jafar to use his third wish to become a genie himself, but gets stuck in his own lamp. I love this guy. He is the textbook definition of genius. Speaking of smart characters, we also have Jasmine. Her father, the sultan of Agrabah, is trying to rush her into getting married, and tries to bring in many princes to marry her. She hates every single one of them. She doesn't care about the law. If she is to marry, she wants it to be for love. She won't marry anyone. She has to actually care for them. I wouldn't marry someone who attempts to whip little kids either. She also nearly figures out Aladdin not being a prince after the Whole New World song, and Aladdin figures out a good excuse. She's another smart and enjoyable character. I also think she's very hot, but I digress. The most important part of this love story is that the two have great chemistry. They have things in common, and want to help each other out. Not only that, but when Aladdin is Prince Ali, Jasmine actually hates him at first. However, Aladdin builds up the relationship again, and gets Jasmine to fall in love with him again. This may not be on quite the level Beauty and the Beast was with building up a relationship, but it works fine here. Jasmine does suspect that it's actually Aladdin and not a prince before the carpet ride, and she already cared for him, so this is not rushed. It does well for its own love story, but the film is not just that. It's also an adventure, especially since Jafar tries to kill Aladdin a lot. He tries to in the Cave of Wonders when Aladdin is hanging off a cliff and he gets the lamp, he tries to when Aladdin is with Jasmine, and he does after he becomes a sorcerer, along with after Aladdin returns to the palace. In conclusion, the film has many things to like about it. It has many great elements in it, and focuses on them in a very coherent manner. It has a great love story, great adventure, great characters, amazing comic relief, and wonderful animation and colors. This is something you can truly call a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion this film and The Lion King are the best animated films Disney has ever produced. And they're surprisingly similar, yet different enough for us to not get bored even if we watched them back to back. They both deal with the realities of power and the responsibility that comes along with it. In The Lion King, Simba doesn't want the power, he feels like he isn't worthy enough to wield it. Whereas in this film, Aladdin isn't the heir to the power (prophecy notwithstanding), but receives it anyway and is willing to use it, but only to a certain point. And in both films that power falls into the hands of someone who least deserves it, which builds up the main conflict in both films. This is pretty heavy stuff for a film that's aimed primarily for kids, but I absolutely love it because of it. Kids need to learn this stuff sooner or later and I'd personally much rather learn it from a film like this than from bitter experience. And it's not like the whole film is one big gloomfest, designed to depress our kids or to show them material way beyond their years. No, it's bright and festive, pretty to look at with great characters and even greater musical numbers. And the story, based on the old Middle-East tale, is a great one. It has underdogs, it has fight scenes, it has love, betrayal, friendship, magic, wonder, ancient entities, treasure hunts, miracles  it has it all. I fell in love with this film when I first saw it as a kid, and I still love it. It has withstood the test of time and it still remains as one of the best films ever made, animated or live-action. If you haven't seen it already Well, it must have been a nice rock to live under.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End of Disney's Golden Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin, a street urchin, accidentally meets Princess Jasmine, who is in the city undercover. They quickly grow to love each other, but she can only marry a prince. Disney's golden years were 1989-1992, which were unfortunately quite brief. Of course they had hits before that and after that, but for these few years every film was an instant classic. "Aladdin", with its excellent music and the inclusion of Robin Williams, just hit home so hard (and spawned multiple sequels and a television show). How do you critique a film that everyone loves? You simply do not. I guess if I was forced to say anything negative, it would be that Aladdin and Jasmine look a tad too similar and some think they are siblings separated at birth -- and that would not be right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great sense of educational!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film fulling of educational information. Brave, it should be the first, without brave Aladdin cannot play the guardians as fools, he would not bring the lamp out of the hole. Of course, the prince saving the kingdom would not exist. Honest, which is also very indispensable, the second main point in this animation. Abu didn't obey the word and touch a diamond, then they almost died in the hole. Forgetting the promise, Aladdin went to doom and nearly lost everything. Being honest, as the return, it is the forgiveness we see at the end of the story. Contentment, also can be seen from the movie. The fool Jafar failed to learn this, waiting for him is the depriving of freedom the most precious thing to a life. Kindness, which I thought is the first main point showing here makes this film a awesome one. Aladdin is the one who possesses this kind of quality, feeding the street children, making justice for them, saving the princess from blade, and did not be beaten by desire. That is what I thought the most significant quality individual should have. Finally, I want to say, although it is a little bit old animation, please let your children watch it, learn from it, that's the worth of a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Aladdin" is a worthy follow-up to the Disney Studios' previous feature "Beauty and the Beast"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After their previous feature Beauty and the Beast (1991) was the first animated feature in Oscar history to be nominated for Best Picture, the Disney Studios would have a tough act to follow with their next animated picture. In able for this next film to at least be in the same league as Beauty and the Beast, it would have to contain characters, songs, music and a story that are just as memorable as what the prior film offered. As it turns out, the result was the Disney Studio's 31st full-length animated feature, Aladdin (1992). This is another highly entertaining Disney animated feature from the Disney Renaissance which contains pretty much everything you could wish for from a Disney flick whether it would be good laughs, thrilling action, cool animation or awesome songs. We follow a young man named Aladdin and his pet monkey Abu who are sick of being poor and always having to dodge the guards all for the sake of stolen food. They dream that one day they'll be rich enough to put an end to all their troubles. But when they meet a princess named Jasmine who doesn't care for life in the palace because she never goes anywhere and is being forced to marry another prince, things change. After a series of events occur, Aladdin is thrown in the dungeon and a fellow prisoner offers him a way to escape in exchange for doing a task for him. Now, Aladdin has to go to a secret place outside the city of Agrabah called the Cave of Wonders where he must retrieve a magic lamp. This magic lamp contains a highly energetic and fully animated genie (Robin Williams) who can grant Aladdin almost any three wishes he would like. So Aladdin wishes that he was a prince, that way he can try and marry Jasmine. But an evil sorcerer named Jafar and his parrot Iago want Aladdin's lamp and will do anything to get it. Will Aladdin be able to outsmart Jafar and win the princess or not? Want me to summarize why to see Aladdin, if you still haven't, in two words? Well, than those two words would be Robin Williams. Robin Williams was naturally born to voice the genie in this film and I'd guarantee that no matter how hard you tried, you couldn't find another actor that could compete with the high energy and witty comedic style that Williams incorporates into the Genie character. It's been said that much of the dialogue by Robin Williams was improvised or added in even though it wasn't in the original script. To be honest, I couldn't tell the difference between what was and what wasn't in the script since Williams does such a great job at making all of it sound natural. That is precisely how inspired the casting of Robin Williams in this role is. It's not just Williams that makes Aladdin such an entertaining Disney flick, but I also thought that Aladdin and Jasmine had good chemistry between each other. I like the conversations they share with one another regarding how frustrated they are with the lives they're currently living. I don't know about you guys, but when Jasmine basically states that her life of luxury is similar to prison since she can't go outside the palace walls, that's when I thought "maybe being a prince or princess isn't such a good idea". The reason being that in some areas of the world, there's a good possibility that some prince or princess may have no choice but to live that lifestyle. If that somehow wasn't enough to steer you guys away from living a royal life like Jasmine, she's also being forced to get married against her will. Suddenly, a normal lifestyle is sounding excellent to most of us, isn't it? Jafar is another worthy addition to a list of the best Disney villains out there. I admire how he basically enjoys being the most diabolical douchebag to everyone he is around. If there is one thing about some of the greatest Disney villains out there that makes them great including Jafar, it's that they enjoy whatever evil things they're doing. Because they're able to get so much thrill and enjoyment out of what they're doing, that makes us all the more entertained by them in the process. You'll practically love to hate this guy. If there's one thing about this picture that I didn't care for story wise, it would be in regards to Aladdin lying to Jasmine about him being a prince in general. I didn't really care for this part of the story much since most of the dialogue that results from it can be a little too cringe worthy and painfully obvious for my taste. Also, the clich&eacute;d conflict between Aladdin and the genie that results from this part of the story feels forced and unnecessary. I simply felt that it was one routine plot device that didn't need to be in this part of the story at all. Given that it's one of the highest grossing animated features of all time, I think it's safe to say that there's little more to explain about why Aladdin is such a great Disney animated feature. We all know how great the songs by Alan Menken, the late Howard Ashman, and Tim Rice are especially "Friend Like Me", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World". The fast paced, highly energetic, and colorful animation is perfectly suited for a film of this style. I've already gone into detail about Robin Williams' performance, the character of Jafar, and the relationship between Aladdin and Jasmine. You guys have probably seen it many times before, and as far as I'm concerned, you guys deserve to continue seeing it a few times more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watched this Disney's optimal animation in its BluRay form, a stock-in-trade family crowd- pleaser which has been engineered with an impeccable technique and what's more impressive, it oozes an unceasing force of genuineness to edify both children and adults, no condescending doctrine nor feckless naivety, and Robin Williams' voice-performance as the Genie is a great bonus and plays a big part in the film's classic status among its genre. To enumerate Genie's potpourri of imitations alone could be cogent enough to showcase the finesse both for the animators and the voice cast, Robin Williams is deadly hilarious, the motormouthed omnipotent servant, massively steals the thunder from everyone else. But it is not a pejorative remark to other players, on the contrary, it has the most effervescent ensemble including a usually trite class-defying mutual attraction between a princess with a lower-status prince charming. Jafar and Iago pair is another hoot apart from Genie, laughters galore! The plot line entwines pretty much in Disney's safe pattern, a romantic encounter, an abrupt departure, a reunion under the pretense as a legitimate suitor, fighting the evil enemy and happy forever ending, while it really pushes Aladdin to the edge of the cliff since Jafar's invincibility seems to be unbreakable, and the eleventh hour turnover is nothing less than a satisfactory one. 2D animation surely has been largely outcast from the lucrative market, but one can never ascertain there will be a wave of coming back in some years ahead, like Black and White films, their unique aestheticism is the wellspring of their vitality, after watching ALADDIN, it perfectly suffices to originate great mojo of satisfaction for an adult first-time viewer, so the last rites seem to be unnecessary, but a niche market-planning should be conducted for the sake of the laborious craftsmanship. The film currently sits at No.2 at my top 10 film of 1992, and Williams earns him a fifth slot in the supporting actor race, the one and only voice-performance on my own Oscar list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid Gold Disney Classic!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is Disney's 31st full-length animated feature film released in 1992. Based on the popular Arab folktale, the film follows a young peasant boy named Aladdin (voice by Scott Weinger) and his sidekick Abu (voiced by Frank Welker) who are in search of a life outside of the streets from stealing food and dodging guards every day. Then one day, they meet the beautiful Princess Jasmine (voiced by Linda Larkin) in the marketplace and after they save her life, they take her to their place and realize that she wants the exact opposite of what they want; a normal life outside of the palace walls. Then, after Aladdin is thrown into prison by the evil Sorcerer Jafar (voiced by Jonathan Freeman), he is unknowingly taken to the Cave of Wonders by Jafar (disguised as an old beggar man) and his wisecracking sidekick Iago to find an ancient magic lamp that unleashes a genie that grants three wishes. After Aladdin and Abu find the lamp and narrowly escape the Cave on the Magic Carpet, they are thrown back into the cave as it crumbles in the ground. In the process however, Abu grabs the magic lamp, gives it to Aladdin and he accidentally rubs the lamp and unleashes the energetic, hilariously funny Genie (voiced by Robin Williams from "Good Morning, Vietnam", "Mrs. Doubtfire") and chaos ensues!!! This was Disney's fourth film of the Renaissance Era and it's has every element of a classic Disney movie present: great story, unforgettable characters (including one of the best Disney villains of all-time, Jafar), great animation, suspense, great climax, and an awesome score/songs composed by famed Disney composers Alan Menken and Tim Rice (stepping in place of Howard Ashman). The best songs in the movie are "One Jump Ahead", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World", played during the magic carpet ride scene. This is yet another one of my favorite Disney movies and my favorite character is the Genie! If you by any chance haven't seen this classic American animated film in the last 20+ years it's been out, all I have to say is: WATCH IT!!! If you need a good Disney film to watch with the family, then I highly recommend this one! Rating: 10/10!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin belongs to a clan of Disney's magical movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know what Disney is capable of. Disney has produced some of the greatest films of all time like the Lion King but 2 years prior to that, Disney released Aladdin which is also widely regarded as one of Disney's best. Aladdin follows the story of a young streeboy named Aladdin who falls in love with Princess Jasmine and attempts to win her heart by using a genie to make him a prince. However, an evil sorcerer named Jafar is after Aladdin in order to gain his hands on the lamp in order to rule the world and marry Jasmine. Okay, we all know what the story is about and we all know the characters in the film. The story of Aladdin is extremely rich and unforgettable filled with magical characters that just warm our heart. The voice acting is brilliant and it makes for an extremely enjoyable film. The songs in the film aren't as good as, say Beauty and the Beast but they are still pretty remarkable. The script is good and gives us plenty of great laughs. The pacing of the film is brilliant and it never really slows down. In fact, the last twenty minutes is filled with excitement and tension over what will happen. This is definitely a MUST SEE Disney classic for all :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Disney's best post-modern era films of the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I have to admit that I was only born in 1994 when The Lion King was released, but my older sister was born before me in 1992 before Disney released this. Sadly, though, we never saw it in the theaters and waited to watch it on video. Our dreams had finally come true and we loved it as much as anyone else who had seen it and grew up with it. Now, I never read the story "One Thousand Arabian Nights", but I think that this classic did some extreme justice to it. Sure, it does start off a bit slow, but as the film progresses, it has it's heart just in the right place thanks to it's being well thought out. The characters, much like the story, are engaging and likable with the likes of Aladdin, the beautiful Princess Jasmine, Abu, the monkey, Iago, the parrot, the Sultan, Jafar (who is by far one of Disney's best villains in history) and Genie, who, thanks to Robin Williams' solid voice-work, steals every scene with his hilarious moments and the comedy is both timeless and unforgettable. In fact, the voice acting isn't that bad at all especially Scott Weinger, Linda Larkin, Jonathan Freeman, and let's not forget Jim Cummings as the leader of the palace guards. I was like, "Winnie The Pooh/Tigger as a palace guard? Top-notch!" The music from Alan Menken is the epitome of brilliance and the songs were timeless and were not to be long forgotten including one of my favorites "A Whole New World". The script is excellent and flawless with witty and hilarious dialog and the pacing is brisk and moves along very nicely. The strongest aspect, however, goes to the animation due to it's beautiful visual look of Agrabah and solid character designs. Overall, this is one of the few movies that I grew up with as a kid back at the 90s and this will not be forgotten by not only families and their children, but long-time Disney fans as well. Totally recommended and uh... Happy 20th Anniversary, Aladdin!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you never had a friend like me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is a Disney cartoon with a character that we all wish we had as friend, the genie. Aladdin is filled with endless thrills, table turning plans and music that you can't help to like and sing along to. The movie's intro is in form of a narrative, where a merchant tells us the tale of Aladdin and his magic lamp. This 1992 Disney classic is based on an Arab folktale of Aladdin and the magic lamp from One Thousand and One Nights. The idea to make the movie was pitched in by the Late Howard Ashman (who died before the film's release) Ashman has been behind a lot of Disney classics from Oliver & Company, Little Mermaid and Beauty and the Beast. He was a writer, lyricist and producer and he was the lyricist for "Arabian Nights", "Friend Like Me", and "Prince Ali" used in this movie. Aladdin's story is about a street boy, who runs into a princess named Jasmine who escaped the palace to see what life was outside the palace walls where you are not told what to do. While they were together Aladdin gets captured by soldiers under the orders of Jafar, the Grand Vizier to the Sultan of Agrabah (Jasmine's father). Jafar needs Aladdin to retrieve a magical oil lamp containing a genie from the Cave of Wonders. The movie's story now grows on what happened when Jafar didn't get the lamp but Aladdin did in an attempt to read the inscriptions on the lamp, released the genie and he is given 3 wishes. As the song goes, you never had a friend like me So it has been, because all through Disney toon history we never found anyone more appealing to have around, Genie is just the best person to have in at corner. The movie's screenplay explores fantasy, world travel, fireworks and action scenes. Aladdin was a box office hit, making over $ 500 million dollars in its theatrical run and also gave birth to two direct to DVD sequels and a TV series. Aladdin won numerous awards, especially for its music, it won only two Academy Awards, Best Original Score and Best Original Song for "A Whole New World" and it also won four Grammy Awards, Best Soundtrack Album, Song of the Year for "A Whole New World", Best Pop Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal for "A Whole New World" and Best Song Written for a Motion Picture, Television or Other Visual Media for "A Whole New World". Like it or not, Aladdin boast of the best of the best music, and it was also funny and fun to watch, so if you don't own this DVD you Disney collection is not complete yet. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Disney at their finest.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Starr
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like most kids, I also grew up with Disney films, and Aladdin came out the year I was born. However, that did not stop me from watching this film many times during my life. Ever since I was little, this was my favorite Disney movie. This is an excellent film. It teaches great morals, and executes them very well. The story is about Aladdin falling in love with Princess Jasmine, but finds out she can only marry a prince, due to the law. He acquires a lamp with the Genie inside, and he wishes to become a prince, or should I say, look like one. This is my only problem with the film, but this can be overlooked. Why can't he wish he WAS a prince instead of looking like one? But it moves very well into the moral, so I can excuse this. After finding out he would become Sultan after marrying Jasmine, he decides to try and tell her the truth that he's not actually a prince. It's actually before the villain fight and not at the exact end where we have a moral. I like that. He learns that he needs to be truthful, and was trying to tell Jasmine before Jafar exposes him for who he really is. He also learns to keep promises. Before his first wish with the Genie, he promises him he would use his 3rd wish to free him, and even at the end, the Genie tries to talk him into wishing into a prince again, but Aladdin still frees him, despite unlikely being able to marry Jasmine. Nice guy. That is a fantastic way of telling your morals. Not only are the morals amazing, but so are the characters, especially Aladdin himself. He starts off as a homeless person on the streets of Agrabah, but he has very impressive smarts. Not only for thievery, but anything in general. I mainly say this because when he defeats Jafar, he says that the Genie has more power than he does, and he can take away his powers. This convinces Jafar to use his third wish to become a genie himself, but gets stuck in his own lamp. I love this guy. He is the textbook definition of genius. Speaking of smart characters, we also have Jasmine. Her father, the sultan of Agrabah, is trying to rush her into getting married, and tries to bring in many princes to marry her. She hates every single one of them. She doesn't care about the law. If she is to marry, she wants it to be for love. She won't marry anyone. She has to actually care for them. I wouldn't marry someone who attempts to whip little kids either. She also nearly figures out Aladdin not being a prince after the Whole New World song, and Aladdin figures out a good excuse. She's another smart and enjoyable character. I also think she's very hot, but I digress. The most important part of this love story is that the two have great chemistry. They have things in common, and want to help each other out. Not only that, but when Aladdin is Prince Ali, Jasmine actually hates him at first. However, Aladdin builds up the relationship again, and gets Jasmine to fall in love with him again. This may not be on quite the level Beauty and the Beast was with building up a relationship, but it works fine here. Jasmine does suspect that it's actually Aladdin and not a prince before the carpet ride, and she already cared for him, so this is not rushed. It does well for its own love story, but the film is not just that. It's also an adventure, especially since Jafar tries to kill Aladdin a lot. He tries to in the Cave of Wonders when Aladdin is hanging off a cliff and he gets the lamp, he tries to when Aladdin is with Jasmine, and he does after he becomes a sorcerer, along with after Aladdin returns to the palace. In conclusion, the film has many things to like about it. It has many great elements in it, and focuses on them in a very coherent manner. It has a great love story, great adventure, great characters, amazing comic relief, and wonderful animation and colors. This is something you can truly call a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my opinion this film and The Lion King are the best animated films Disney has ever produced. And they're surprisingly similar, yet different enough for us to not get bored even if we watched them back to back. They both deal with the realities of power and the responsibility that comes along with it. In The Lion King, Simba doesn't want the power, he feels like he isn't worthy enough to wield it. Whereas in this film, Aladdin isn't the heir to the power (prophecy notwithstanding), but receives it anyway and is willing to use it, but only to a certain point. And in both films that power falls into the hands of someone who least deserves it, which builds up the main conflict in both films. This is pretty heavy stuff for a film that's aimed primarily for kids, but I absolutely love it because of it. Kids need to learn this stuff sooner or later and I'd personally much rather learn it from a film like this than from bitter experience. And it's not like the whole film is one big gloomfest, designed to depress our kids or to show them material way beyond their years. No, it's bright and festive, pretty to look at with great characters and even greater musical numbers. And the story, based on the old Middle-East tale, is a great one. It has underdogs, it has fight scenes, it has love, betrayal, friendship, magic, wonder, ancient entities, treasure hunts, miracles  it has it all. I fell in love with this film when I first saw it as a kid, and I still love it. It has withstood the test of time and it still remains as one of the best films ever made, animated or live-action. If you haven't seen it already Well, it must have been a nice rock to live under.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End of Disney's Golden Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin, a street urchin, accidentally meets Princess Jasmine, who is in the city undercover. They quickly grow to love each other, but she can only marry a prince. Disney's golden years were 1989-1992, which were unfortunately quite brief. Of course they had hits before that and after that, but for these few years every film was an instant classic. "Aladdin", with its excellent music and the inclusion of Robin Williams, just hit home so hard (and spawned multiple sequels and a television show). How do you critique a film that everyone loves? You simply do not. I guess if I was forced to say anything negative, it would be that Aladdin and Jasmine look a tad too similar and some think they are siblings separated at birth -- and that would not be right.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great sense of educational!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JolinKnight
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a film fulling of educational information. Brave, it should be the first, without brave Aladdin cannot play the guardians as fools, he would not bring the lamp out of the hole. Of course, the prince saving the kingdom would not exist. Honest, which is also very indispensable, the second main point in this animation. Abu didn't obey the word and touch a diamond, then they almost died in the hole. Forgetting the promise, Aladdin went to doom and nearly lost everything. Being honest, as the return, it is the forgiveness we see at the end of the story. Contentment, also can be seen from the movie. The fool Jafar failed to learn this, waiting for him is the depriving of freedom the most precious thing to a life. Kindness, which I thought is the first main point showing here makes this film a awesome one. Aladdin is the one who possesses this kind of quality, feeding the street children, making justice for them, saving the princess from blade, and did not be beaten by desire. That is what I thought the most significant quality individual should have. Finally, I want to say, although it is a little bit old animation, please let your children watch it, learn from it, that's the worth of a film like this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Aladdin" is a worthy follow-up to the Disney Studios' previous feature "Beauty and the Beast"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After their previous feature Beauty and the Beast (1991) was the first animated feature in Oscar history to be nominated for Best Picture, the Disney Studios would have a tough act to follow with their next animated picture. In able for this next film to at least be in the same league as Beauty and the Beast, it would have to contain characters, songs, music and a story that are just as memorable as what the prior film offered. As it turns out, the result was the Disney Studio's 31st full-length animated feature, Aladdin (1992). This is another highly entertaining Disney animated feature from the Disney Renaissance which contains pretty much everything you could wish for from a Disney flick whether it would be good laughs, thrilling action, cool animation or awesome songs. We follow a young man named Aladdin and his pet monkey Abu who are sick of being poor and always having to dodge the guards all for the sake of stolen food. They dream that one day they'll be rich enough to put an end to all their troubles. But when they meet a princess named Jasmine who doesn't care for life in the palace because she never goes anywhere and is being forced to marry another prince, things change. After a series of events occur, Aladdin is thrown in the dungeon and a fellow prisoner offers him a way to escape in exchange for doing a task for him. Now, Aladdin has to go to a secret place outside the city of Agrabah called the Cave of Wonders where he must retrieve a magic lamp. This magic lamp contains a highly energetic and fully animated genie (Robin Williams) who can grant Aladdin almost any three wishes he would like. So Aladdin wishes that he was a prince, that way he can try and marry Jasmine. But an evil sorcerer named Jafar and his parrot Iago want Aladdin's lamp and will do anything to get it. Will Aladdin be able to outsmart Jafar and win the princess or not? Want me to summarize why to see Aladdin, if you still haven't, in two words? Well, than those two words would be Robin Williams. Robin Williams was naturally born to voice the genie in this film and I'd guarantee that no matter how hard you tried, you couldn't find another actor that could compete with the high energy and witty comedic style that Williams incorporates into the Genie character. It's been said that much of the dialogue by Robin Williams was improvised or added in even though it wasn't in the original script. To be honest, I couldn't tell the difference between what was and what wasn't in the script since Williams does such a great job at making all of it sound natural. That is precisely how inspired the casting of Robin Williams in this role is. It's not just Williams that makes Aladdin such an entertaining Disney flick, but I also thought that Aladdin and Jasmine had good chemistry between each other. I like the conversations they share with one another regarding how frustrated they are with the lives they're currently living. I don't know about you guys, but when Jasmine basically states that her life of luxury is similar to prison since she can't go outside the palace walls, that's when I thought "maybe being a prince or princess isn't such a good idea". The reason being that in some areas of the world, there's a good possibility that some prince or princess may have no choice but to live that lifestyle. If that somehow wasn't enough to steer you guys away from living a royal life like Jasmine, she's also being forced to get married against her will. Suddenly, a normal lifestyle is sounding excellent to most of us, isn't it? Jafar is another worthy addition to a list of the best Disney villains out there. I admire how he basically enjoys being the most diabolical douchebag to everyone he is around. If there is one thing about some of the greatest Disney villains out there that makes them great including Jafar, it's that they enjoy whatever evil things they're doing. Because they're able to get so much thrill and enjoyment out of what they're doing, that makes us all the more entertained by them in the process. You'll practically love to hate this guy. If there's one thing about this picture that I didn't care for story wise, it would be in regards to Aladdin lying to Jasmine about him being a prince in general. I didn't really care for this part of the story much since most of the dialogue that results from it can be a little too cringe worthy and painfully obvious for my taste. Also, the clich&eacute;d conflict between Aladdin and the genie that results from this part of the story feels forced and unnecessary. I simply felt that it was one routine plot device that didn't need to be in this part of the story at all. Given that it's one of the highest grossing animated features of all time, I think it's safe to say that there's little more to explain about why Aladdin is such a great Disney animated feature. We all know how great the songs by Alan Menken, the late Howard Ashman, and Tim Rice are especially "Friend Like Me", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World". The fast paced, highly energetic, and colorful animation is perfectly suited for a film of this style. I've already gone into detail about Robin Williams' performance, the character of Jafar, and the relationship between Aladdin and Jasmine. You guys have probably seen it many times before, and as far as I'm concerned, you guys deserve to continue seeing it a few times more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    junkielee
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watched this Disney's optimal animation in its BluRay form, a stock-in-trade family crowd- pleaser which has been engineered with an impeccable technique and what's more impressive, it oozes an unceasing force of genuineness to edify both children and adults, no condescending doctrine nor feckless naivety, and Robin Williams' voice-performance as the Genie is a great bonus and plays a big part in the film's classic status among its genre. To enumerate Genie's potpourri of imitations alone could be cogent enough to showcase the finesse both for the animators and the voice cast, Robin Williams is deadly hilarious, the motormouthed omnipotent servant, massively steals the thunder from everyone else. But it is not a pejorative remark to other players, on the contrary, it has the most effervescent ensemble including a usually trite class-defying mutual attraction between a princess with a lower-status prince charming. Jafar and Iago pair is another hoot apart from Genie, laughters galore! The plot line entwines pretty much in Disney's safe pattern, a romantic encounter, an abrupt departure, a reunion under the pretense as a legitimate suitor, fighting the evil enemy and happy forever ending, while it really pushes Aladdin to the edge of the cliff since Jafar's invincibility seems to be unbreakable, and the eleventh hour turnover is nothing less than a satisfactory one. 2D animation surely has been largely outcast from the lucrative market, but one can never ascertain there will be a wave of coming back in some years ahead, like Black and White films, their unique aestheticism is the wellspring of their vitality, after watching ALADDIN, it perfectly suffices to originate great mojo of satisfaction for an adult first-time viewer, so the last rites seem to be unnecessary, but a niche market-planning should be conducted for the sake of the laborious craftsmanship. The film currently sits at No.2 at my top 10 film of 1992, and Williams earns him a fifth slot in the supporting actor race, the one and only voice-performance on my own Oscar list!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid Gold Disney Classic!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    braves-5
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is Disney's 31st full-length animated feature film released in 1992. Based on the popular Arab folktale, the film follows a young peasant boy named Aladdin (voice by Scott Weinger) and his sidekick Abu (voiced by Frank Welker) who are in search of a life outside of the streets from stealing food and dodging guards every day. Then one day, they meet the beautiful Princess Jasmine (voiced by Linda Larkin) in the marketplace and after they save her life, they take her to their place and realize that she wants the exact opposite of what they want; a normal life outside of the palace walls. Then, after Aladdin is thrown into prison by the evil Sorcerer Jafar (voiced by Jonathan Freeman), he is unknowingly taken to the Cave of Wonders by Jafar (disguised as an old beggar man) and his wisecracking sidekick Iago to find an ancient magic lamp that unleashes a genie that grants three wishes. After Aladdin and Abu find the lamp and narrowly escape the Cave on the Magic Carpet, they are thrown back into the cave as it crumbles in the ground. In the process however, Abu grabs the magic lamp, gives it to Aladdin and he accidentally rubs the lamp and unleashes the energetic, hilariously funny Genie (voiced by Robin Williams from "Good Morning, Vietnam", "Mrs. Doubtfire") and chaos ensues!!! This was Disney's fourth film of the Renaissance Era and it's has every element of a classic Disney movie present: great story, unforgettable characters (including one of the best Disney villains of all-time, Jafar), great animation, suspense, great climax, and an awesome score/songs composed by famed Disney composers Alan Menken and Tim Rice (stepping in place of Howard Ashman). The best songs in the movie are "One Jump Ahead", "Prince Ali", and "A Whole New World", played during the magic carpet ride scene. This is yet another one of my favorite Disney movies and my favorite character is the Genie! If you by any chance haven't seen this classic American animated film in the last 20+ years it's been out, all I have to say is: WATCH IT!!! If you need a good Disney film to watch with the family, then I highly recommend this one! Rating: 10/10!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Aladdin belongs to a clan of Disney's magical movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    illbebackreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We all know what Disney is capable of. Disney has produced some of the greatest films of all time like the Lion King but 2 years prior to that, Disney released Aladdin which is also widely regarded as one of Disney's best. Aladdin follows the story of a young streeboy named Aladdin who falls in love with Princess Jasmine and attempts to win her heart by using a genie to make him a prince. However, an evil sorcerer named Jafar is after Aladdin in order to gain his hands on the lamp in order to rule the world and marry Jasmine. Okay, we all know what the story is about and we all know the characters in the film. The story of Aladdin is extremely rich and unforgettable filled with magical characters that just warm our heart. The voice acting is brilliant and it makes for an extremely enjoyable film. The songs in the film aren't as good as, say Beauty and the Beast but they are still pretty remarkable. The script is good and gives us plenty of great laughs. The pacing of the film is brilliant and it never really slows down. In fact, the last twenty minutes is filled with excitement and tension over what will happen. This is definitely a MUST SEE Disney classic for all :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Disney's best post-modern era films of the 90s
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I have to admit that I was only born in 1994 when The Lion King was released, but my older sister was born before me in 1992 before Disney released this. Sadly, though, we never saw it in the theaters and waited to watch it on video. Our dreams had finally come true and we loved it as much as anyone else who had seen it and grew up with it. Now, I never read the story "One Thousand Arabian Nights", but I think that this classic did some extreme justice to it. Sure, it does start off a bit slow, but as the film progresses, it has it's heart just in the right place thanks to it's being well thought out. The characters, much like the story, are engaging and likable with the likes of Aladdin, the beautiful Princess Jasmine, Abu, the monkey, Iago, the parrot, the Sultan, Jafar (who is by far one of Disney's best villains in history) and Genie, who, thanks to Robin Williams' solid voice-work, steals every scene with his hilarious moments and the comedy is both timeless and unforgettable. In fact, the voice acting isn't that bad at all especially Scott Weinger, Linda Larkin, Jonathan Freeman, and let's not forget Jim Cummings as the leader of the palace guards. I was like, "Winnie The Pooh/Tigger as a palace guard? Top-notch!" The music from Alan Menken is the epitome of brilliance and the songs were timeless and were not to be long forgotten including one of my favorites "A Whole New World". The script is excellent and flawless with witty and hilarious dialog and the pacing is brisk and moves along very nicely. The strongest aspect, however, goes to the animation due to it's beautiful visual look of Agrabah and solid character designs. Overall, this is one of the few movies that I grew up with as a kid back at the 90s and this will not be forgotten by not only families and their children, but long-time Disney fans as well. Totally recommended and uh... Happy 20th Anniversary, Aladdin!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you never had a friend like me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Aladdin is a Disney cartoon with a character that we all wish we had as friend, the genie. Aladdin is filled with endless thrills, table turning plans and music that you can't help to like and sing along to. The movie's intro is in form of a narrative, where a merchant tells us the tale of Aladdin and his magic lamp. This 1992 Disney classic is based on an Arab folktale of Aladdin and the magic lamp from One Thousand and One Nights. The idea to make the movie was pitched in by the Late Howard Ashman (who died before the film's release) Ashman has been behind a lot of Disney classics from Oliver & Company, Little Mermaid and Beauty and the Beast. He was a writer, lyricist and producer and he was the lyricist for "Arabian Nights", "Friend Like Me", and "Prince Ali" used in this movie. Aladdin's story is about a street boy, who runs into a princess named Jasmine who escaped the palace to see what life was outside the palace walls where you are not told what to do. While they were together Aladdin gets captured by soldiers under the orders of Jafar, the Grand Vizier to the Sultan of Agrabah (Jasmine's father). Jafar needs Aladdin to retrieve a magical oil lamp containing a genie from the Cave of Wonders. The movie's story now grows on what happened when Jafar didn't get the lamp but Aladdin did in an attempt to read the inscriptions on the lamp, released the genie and he is given 3 wishes. As the song goes, you never had a friend like me So it has been, because all through Disney toon history we never found anyone more appealing to have around, Genie is just the best person to have in at corner. The movie's screenplay explores fantasy, world travel, fireworks and action scenes. Aladdin was a box office hit, making over $ 500 million dollars in its theatrical run and also gave birth to two direct to DVD sequels and a TV series. Aladdin won numerous awards, especially for its music, it won only two Academy Awards, Best Original Score and Best Original Song for "A Whole New World" and it also won four Grammy Awards, Best Soundtrack Album, Song of the Year for "A Whole New World", Best Pop Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal for "A Whole New World" and Best Song Written for a Motion Picture, Television or Other Visual Media for "A Whole New World". Like it or not, Aladdin boast of the best of the best music, and it was also funny and fun to watch, so if you don't own this DVD you Disney collection is not complete yet. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Truly Disney at their finest.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Starr
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like most kids, I also grew up with Disney films, and Aladdin came out the year I was born. However, that did not stop me from watching this film many times during my life. Ever since I was little, this was my favorite Disney movie. This is an excellent film. It teaches great morals, and executes them very well. The story is about Aladdin falling in love with Princess Jasmine, but finds out she can only marry a prince, due to the law. He acquires a lamp with the Genie inside, and he wishes to become a prince, or should I say, look like one. This is my only problem with the film, but this can be overlooked. Why can't he wish he WAS a prince instead of looking like one? But it moves very well into the moral, so I can excuse this. After finding out he would become Sultan after marrying Jasmine, he decides to try and tell her the truth that he's not actually a prince. It's actually before the villain fight and not at the exact end where we have a moral. I like that. He learns that he needs to be truthful, and was trying to tell Jasmine before Jafar exposes him for who he really is. He also learns to keep promises. Before his first wish with the Genie, he promises him he would use his 3rd wish to free him, and even at the end, the Genie tries to talk him into wishing into a prince again, but Aladdin still frees him, despite unlikely being able to marry Jasmine. Nice guy. That is a fantastic way of telling your morals. Not only are the morals amazing, but so are the characters, especially Aladdin himself. He starts off as a homeless person on the streets of Agrabah, but he has very impressive smarts. Not only for thievery, but anything in general. I mainly say this because when he defeats Jafar, he says that the Genie has more power than he does, and he can take away his powers. This convinces Jafar to use his third wish to become a genie himself, but gets stuck in his own lamp. I love this guy. He is the textbook definition of genius. Speaking of smart characters, we also have Jasmine. Her father, the sultan of Agrabah, is trying to rush her into getting married, and tries to bring in many princes to marry her. She hates every single one of them. She doesn't care about the law. If she is to marry, she wants it to be for love. She won't marry anyone. She has to actually care for them. I wouldn't marry someone who attempts to whip little kids either. She also nearly figures out Aladdin not being a prince after the Whole New World song, and Aladdin figures out a good excuse. She's another smart and enjoyable character. I also think she's very hot, but I digress. The most important part of this love story is that the two have great chemistry. They have things in common, and want to help each other out. Not only that, but when Aladdin is Prince Ali, Jasmine actually hates him at first. However, Aladdin builds up the relationship again, and gets Jasmine to fall in love with him again. This may not be on quite the level Beauty and the Beast was with building up a relationship, but it works fine here. Jasmine does suspect that it's actually Aladdin and not a prince before the carpet ride, and she already cared for him, so this is not rushed. It does well for its own love story, but the film is not just that. It's also an adventure, especially since Jafar tries to kill Aladdin a lot. He tries to in the Cave of Wonders when Aladdin is hanging off a cliff and he gets the lamp, he tries to when Aladdin is with Jasmine, and he does after he becomes a sorcerer, along with after Aladdin returns to the palace. In conclusion, the film has many things to like about it. It has many great elements in it, and focuses on them in a very coherent manner. It has a great love story, great adventure, great characters, amazing comic relief, and wonderful animation and colors. This is something you can truly call a masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
