<filme>
 <id>
  951
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113419
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Chave M&aacute;gica
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  On his ninth birthday a boy receives many presents. Two of them first seem to be less important: an old cupboard from his brother and a little Indian figure made of plastic from his best ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  On his ninth birthday a boy receives many presents. Two of them first seem to be less important: an old cupboard from his brother and a little Indian figure made of plastic from his best friend. But these two presents turn out to be much more magic than the rest...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   birthday
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   best friend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   boy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   magic
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Frank Oz
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Lynne Reid Banks
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Melissa Mathison
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Hal Scardino
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Litefoot
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lindsay Crouse
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agreeable family film filled with imagination and in which adventure comes to life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On his ninth birthday a young boy (Hal Scardino) named Omri (it means "The Lord is my life" and was the name of a Hebrew king whose story is told in I Kings 16) receives various presents from his parents (Richard Jenkins , Lindsay Crouse) and brothers . Two of them first seem to be less important : an old cupboard -a wooden medicine cabinet - from his brother and a little Indian figure made of plastic . Then there happens the biggest adventure of his childhood , the magical cupboard brings his toy action figures to life and Omri watches him become flesh and blood ; there also appear a soldier (Steve Coogan) from WWII . Three-inch plastic Indian named Little Bear (Lifefoot) undertaking several adventures and teaching him important lessons . Thing go worse , however , when the boy's best friend brings a toy gunfighter (David Keith) to life and pursuit starts . Events turn nasty and might be frightened for young children , by some scenes involving a rather vicious mouse . Enjoyable and well-intentioned film plenty of good feeling , marvelous adventure , fantasy and sense of wonder . This is a nice movie with heart that amuses and has something to tell . The picture is pretty good but suffers of claustrophobic scenario , as it is mostly set in room , exception some brief scenes in courtyard . Intelligent as well as sensitive screenplay by Melissa Matheson , Harrison Ford's real-life first wife , based on the best-selling children's book by Lynne Reid Banks who wrote her original novel as a bedtime story for her son , Omri . Cool special effects , as blue screen techniques allow them to appear together-on-screen although they were really filmed together only once . Emotive as well as evocative musical score by Randy Edelman . Colorful and adequate cinematography by Russell Carpenter . The motion picture well produced by Kathleen Kennedy and Frank Marshall was professionally directed by Frank Oz , though he stated he was reluctant to direct this movie, as he doesn't think he's a children's director. Frank began forming team with the great Jim Henson filming known titles such as &uml;The Dark Crystal&uml; and &uml;Muppets take Manhattan&uml;. Frank subsequently directed a lot of comedies as &uml;Little shop of horrors&uml;, &uml;Dirty rotten scoundrels&uml;, &uml;What about Bob?&uml;, &uml;House sitter&uml;, &uml;In and out&uml;, &uml;Bowfinger&uml;and a thriller titled &uml;The score&uml;. And this &uml;Indian in cupboard&uml;, it results to be one of his most sensitive films . Rating : 6'5/10 . Better than average . Well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You should not do magic you do not understand, movie! Still, it was worth checking out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now that I've grown and educated myself, I can't stop thinking about how politically incorrect the title is. People say it should be called 'the Native American in the cupboard'. This is a very very common misconception in America. Yes, for a while they were called Indians. Christopher Columbus did not call them Indians because he thought they were from India. He called them "Gods people". The word in his language for "God's people" sounds very similar to the word Indian that we use today. It's just that the pronunciation we use now has changed a little after all this time. As for people saying that the "correct" term is "Native American" is highly offensive and frankly kind of stupid. How is it that taking the name from which the conquerors's gave them(American) supposed to be the correct term? That makes absolutely no sense. The word American has no relation whatsoever to Indian culture. Therefore "Native American" is utterly ridiculous, as well. If there is to be a title, it's should be call 'The Iroquois in the Cupboard'. No matter, what it is, call. The movie and book is not racist. The movie and book is trying to show tolerance through it's metaphor for how ignorant people have subjugated and marginalized the Indian populations of America by refusing to understand, listen to, or accommodate Indian heritage. The film opens up, a lot of things that people rarely knew about Native Americans. The film starts with a young boy, Omri (Hal Scardino), receives a cupboard. He uses a "magical" key, which belonged to his great-grandmother, to bring a plastic 18th century Native American figurine to life with the cupboard. The now-living Iroquois reveals his name as Little Bear (Litefoot). Litefoot, a real rapper does a great job in teaching role, not only in teaching the child about Iroquois's culture, but also the morality of playing God. There is a Frankenstein feel to the film. My favorite line in the film "God does play with little men'. Author Lynne Reid Banks and Director Frank Oz did an excellent job conveying the worry and angst the young boy felt for for his little toy come to life. I appreciate how the author had the boy evolve from seeing the Indian as a plaything to realizing that, regardless of his size, the Indian was a person with needs, feelings, and a right to live his life. What struck me about it was not that it was racist, or dated (it didn't feel so as much as you'd think,) but that it is a deconstruction of the idea that magical toys would be fun to have, and possibly of imagination as well. Omri seem just the typical kid protagonist, kinda generic if you ask me. But I still think his acting was unintentionally funny. Just weird out with all the close ups on Omri's face, the odd relationship between him and Little Bear, the weird fears, and how he reacts to others. Examples when Omri's dad confronts him about the saw blades, and Omri says he buried them. Odd lying by him and his parent accept that lame excuse. What kid can cuss to his mom as well? What is with his relationship with brothers being super cool in the beginning of the film and then for no reason Omri turns into a complete jerk with him? The worst thing, the kid does is abuse an animal. That poor thing was abused through the whole film. Whether it was real or not, it was still animal abuse and shouldn't be shown in this movie. The treatment of that rat was appalling. Omri still wasn't nearly as annoying as his friend, Patrick. One minute he's Omri's best friend, and all docile and quiet, and then like a switch, he's evil and defiant with seeing them as nothing more than animated toys. He brings in Boone (David Keith), a bigot Injun hating cowboy whom at first conflict with Little Bear, but grows to be friends with him, once they got to know each other. One of the odd things about the film is scenes that go nowhere or has nothing to do with the story like the Mohawk bully. Another thing is the degrading of women in the film, from the kids watching Montley Crue 'Girls' music video (it's the 1990's, why were they watching it anyways?) to Bear demanding a wife so she can cook. I put aside my critiques and squelched my inner squirming and found much to like about the film. The special effects were top notch, and it was really neat to see Little Bear, Boone and Tommy (Steve Coogan) the medic brought to life on the screen. It was pretty cool to see the Star Wars, Jurrasic Park, G.I Joe, and Robo-Cop reference. The movie is pretty close to the book, minus little changes such as the toy shop. I laugh at the kid that loves JFK. While the movie isn't that bad, it's not going to hurt the kids watching it. I like it when I was a kid and still kinda do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Indian in the Cupboard (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underrated and highly involving movie for kids. A young boy finds out that his cupboard has magical powers and can turn plastic into reality. He first turns a plastic Indian into a real human being. The movie teaches about responsibility but in an understandable way. It isn't patronizing nor childish, which means older audiences should relate to it also. It also mediates on life and death at certain points, and was the first film in a long time to be genuinely emotionally shocking. The relationship between the Indian and the cowboy was very well developed as they started to bond over their tragedies. The film does have a number of loose edges. Rishi Bhat was particularly annoying at times, but in a way he was necessary to play off Scardino. Even Scardino wasn't always a lovable protagonist. In one scene he kicks his brother's pet rat down the stairs, in an event where the rat clearly would have died. As the film hadn't relied on cartoon logic up until that point it was a bit out of place. Great effects, and seeing Darth Vader vs. a T-Rex kind of made up for those moments. A more innocent time when children's movies didn't have to be loud and crass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Movie For Kids
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-english
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forget reviews saying this is not as good as the book. No films are are a good as the book! Watch this movie with an 8 year old child and you will see how good the film is. Thank you Frank Oz for a wonderful film. The acting from the young children is above average and the tearful ending just right for a young audience. Interesting to note Steve Coogan plays a miniature model come to life - something he repeats later in his career in A Night At The Museum. Typecasting? The effects are also very good. Remember this is 1995 when CGI was in it's infancy - but the miniaturisation of the cast is flawless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting film with childish and mature characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dean Richard Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though I rated this plucky movie a 4, it doesn't mean I hate it, my dear friends. I liked it but it doesn't have the stuff to make it to my higher favoritism of movies. Frank Oz is imaginative, but I have to say that this film to me is not so Frank Oz, and movies that are adapted from books are quite impressive, but I can only say I was slightly impressed. For one thing, the cast is inadequate, I never heard of David Keith and Litefoot. This story follows Omri, an extremely childish youngster who, for his birthday, receives a MAGICAL (ooh!) cupboard. The Cupboard lacks its key so Omri's mother (actress Lindsay Crouse, never heard of her), gives him her collection of keys, and guess what? He finds the certain key on his second try! That part always took me aback. He puts in an antique Iroquois figure in the cupboard, and later in the morning he opens it to find the figure alive as a small Iroquois man. The pair has many tedious adventures, some including an idiotic rat ball and a down-right scruffy cowboy who was a toy figure too. The cupboard MAGICALLY turns plastic (plaz-teck!) things into their real life counterparts, only smaller. The pair soon learns that every boy must become a man (a typical, yet true moral). Omri's character really is childish, yet endearing; his parents seem to pamper him, he's afraid of the dark, and he has lame 90's action figures; but he does mellow out in the end of the movie. I liked the acting, but it was no To Kill a Mocking Bird, even at moving parts. The Iroquois man was different from other Indian movies; he was a guru in a way. The music was just moderate and odd, though with one exception you'll know when you hear it. Be warned, my dear readers, this movie contains slight profanity (embarrassing really); simulative killing and some ladies do a loathsome dance on TV at one point (they call this a kid movie, how embarrassing. Let's hope Omri was sleeping at that adultish scene). And no the kid does not play God, its just a story, have fun. Other than the 3 points I pointed out, the movie is plucky and it has a rather moving ending. It's an poorish if okay movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Indian in the Cupboard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terrific! First we took their land, then we confined them to reserves, now we've forced Native Americans to live inside of our furniture. Fortunately, this kids' movie is not about constricting a Cree to a credenza  it's about an Iroquois. For his 9th birthday, Omri (Hal Scardino) receives a cupboard and a plastic Indian figurine (Litefoot). When he locks the statuette in the sideboard using a magic key, he opens to find that the toy has come to life. Next, he places a plastic cowboy (David Keith) into the cupboard. And later, he must animate a plastic medic (Steve Coogan); unfortunately, he has lost the key. Based on the beloved children's book, The Indian in the Cupboard may have its faults but at heart it's a compassionate account of growing up. However, wouldn't it be more enlightening for a maturing young man to bring his sister's Bratz dolls to life? (Yellow Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little surprised at the low rating...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gannont
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On this one, I am surprised that viewers are so critical as to miss the big picture of the magical moments and concepts of the movie. I agree, there are quite a few flaws overall, but some are just direction or editing oversights. However, this film deserves to be recognized as a really good family film as is. There are so many good "teaching moments" for parents regarding what kids go through growing up. The effects were well done for the time, playing the small vs. big people visuals. I was absorbed in the story well beyond picking on every detail. Omri was decent, not great, but believable as the kid star; the casting and scripting both for Little Bear are compelling, fascinating, and wonderful. I would recommend this film to almost anyone, if their reality can be suspended for 96 minutes. It is a great story, if only a good film. Entertaining and more gripping than many films since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Totally Boring, A Waste Of Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first read the book, The Indian in the Cupboard with my Reading Class when I was in sixth grade, and I enjoyed it. But then we decided to watch this movie, I really became excited because I thought that the movie was really going to be like the book. But when I saw it, I almost fell asleep, I thought that it was really boring! I thought that it was nothing like the book, I thought that it was totally boring, that you will want to fall asleep when you watch it. First off, the mistakes that they made with the movie. The movie was updated, instead of taking place in England, like it does in the book, it takes place in the United States, you can tell that it is New York because you can see the World Trade Center towers in one scene! Another big mistake was changing were Omri had gotten the characters from. He got some in the book by buying them at the store, in this movie, he got them by swapping them with some of his other toys at an Indian exhibit in school. You can go ahead and watch it if you please, but I sort of would not highly recommend it to you, because of the tedious arrangements they made with the plot. But if you want to watch it, go on and watch it, I am not going to stop you from doing it, though I did not like this movie. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cowboys and Indians
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For his ninth birthday, slightly geeky but wholly appealing Hal Scardino (as Omri) receives cool wooden cupboard from his brother. There is no key to lock the cupboard, but mother Lindsay Crouse lets young Mr. Scardino try some stray keys from her collection. Happily, it turns out that Scardino's great-grandmother gifted a key to his mother, which perfectly fits the cupboard. Scardino locks up a Native American Indian toy figure, a "antique" gift from best friend Rishi Bhat (as Patrick), overnight. When he wakes up, Scardino discovers that Iroquois Litefoot (as Little Bear) has come to life, in miniature form, from the year 1761. The simple but effective special effects used throughout "The Indian in the Cupboard" have, surprisingly, made this film seem more natural looking than the special effects extravaganzas which blew it out of the theaters, back in the 1990s. Michael Lantieri, Eric Brevig, director Frank Oz, and their team make Scardino's little friends look very real. The story is based on a charming series of books by Lynne Reid Banks; the several sequels blunt the impact of the final door closing on the magical years of childhood, but the additional stories have no impact on this charming children's story. Grown-ups and some kids should see subtleties. ******* The Indian in the Cupboard (7/14/95) Frank Oz ~ Hal Scardino, Litefoot, Rishi Bhat, David Keith
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not entirely bad, but suffers from more than one significant flaw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sometimes nice to revisit movies from childhood, and that's just what I did with this one, an adaptation of the children's novel of the same name by Lynne Reid Banks. I think my first viewing of "The Indian in the Cupboard" was on the big screen, and then I saw it at school twice at two different times within the next few years. So, I saw this film twice during childhood, and a third time in my early adolescent years. Just yesterday, I rented it so I could see it again for the first time in nine years. By this time, I had seen its rating and number of votes here, so I could tell that it wasn't highly regarded as a family classic. For that reason, I did not have high expectations, and basically, this PG-rated family movie turned out to be a mixed blessing, which was probably the best I could hope for. When a young boy named Omri celebrates his ninth birthday, one of the presents he gets is a cupboard from his older brother, and another is a little plastic Indian figure from his friend. With both of these presents, he is in for a surprise. After placing the plastic figure in the cupboard, locking it up, and then opening it again, he sees that the figure, still the same size, has come to life! He soon learns that this is what happens when one places a figure in there, locks the door, and opens it again! That plastic figure has been replaced by a real 18th century Iroquois Indian named Little Bear, interrupted from his life and brought to Omri's room, where he is the size of an action figure! He agrees to stay for a while, but during his stay, he and the young modern-day boy are headed for adventure and conflict, and their cultural differences turn out to be one of their problems. One criticism of this movie I agree with is the acting, especially Hal Scardino's acting in the lead role of Omri. He wasn't the greatest child actor to ever make it to the silver screen, that's for sure. Another severe flaw in the film is sometimes the musical score. It tends to be pretty sappy, and really seems unreasonable at times, such as the music in the scene where Omri first sees Little Bear alive in the cupboard. More still, there's some very poor dialogue, and there also may be some humour here, but that also usually fails, with the likes of Boo-hoo Boone, a goofy cowboy who also comes from the cupboard. Now, not everything about this film is bad. Little Bear is a likable character, even if Litefoot doesn't do the greatest job playing him. I can't say I was completely bored throughout the entire film, as there were parts that intrigued me to a certain degree, but this did not hide the blatant flaws. I vaguely remember reading the book back in the late 90's, but can't remember it too well, so I don't know how it compares. However, it does seem to be more popular than this adaptation. This movie is one of those which was never one of my favourites as a kid, and I'm not sure exactly what I thought of it at the time, but I guess I liked it somewhat. During my last viewing, much later than the rest of them, I could definitely see more flaws in it than I used to (I don't think I used to see any real flaws in it at all). This 1995 adaptation of "The Indian in the Cupboard" does have a few redeeming features, but I'm sure they could have tried harder to make it really good family entertainment, and if only they had avoided the negative things I've pointed out, there would have been a good chance that they could have made it happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agreeable family film filled with imagination and in which adventure comes to life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On his ninth birthday a young boy (Hal Scardino) named Omri (it means "The Lord is my life" and was the name of a Hebrew king whose story is told in I Kings 16) receives various presents from his parents (Richard Jenkins , Lindsay Crouse) and brothers . Two of them first seem to be less important : an old cupboard -a wooden medicine cabinet - from his brother and a little Indian figure made of plastic . Then there happens the biggest adventure of his childhood , the magical cupboard brings his toy action figures to life and Omri watches him become flesh and blood ; there also appear a soldier (Steve Coogan) from WWII . Three-inch plastic Indian named Little Bear (Lifefoot) undertaking several adventures and teaching him important lessons . Thing go worse , however , when the boy's best friend brings a toy gunfighter (David Keith) to life and pursuit starts . Events turn nasty and might be frightened for young children , by some scenes involving a rather vicious mouse . Enjoyable and well-intentioned film plenty of good feeling , marvelous adventure , fantasy and sense of wonder . This is a nice movie with heart that amuses and has something to tell . The picture is pretty good but suffers of claustrophobic scenario , as it is mostly set in room , exception some brief scenes in courtyard . Intelligent as well as sensitive screenplay by Melissa Matheson , Harrison Ford's real-life first wife , based on the best-selling children's book by Lynne Reid Banks who wrote her original novel as a bedtime story for her son , Omri . Cool special effects , as blue screen techniques allow them to appear together-on-screen although they were really filmed together only once . Emotive as well as evocative musical score by Randy Edelman . Colorful and adequate cinematography by Russell Carpenter . The motion picture well produced by Kathleen Kennedy and Frank Marshall was professionally directed by Frank Oz , though he stated he was reluctant to direct this movie, as he doesn't think he's a children's director. Frank began forming team with the great Jim Henson filming known titles such as &uml;The Dark Crystal&uml; and &uml;Muppets take Manhattan&uml;. Frank subsequently directed a lot of comedies as &uml;Little shop of horrors&uml;, &uml;Dirty rotten scoundrels&uml;, &uml;What about Bob?&uml;, &uml;House sitter&uml;, &uml;In and out&uml;, &uml;Bowfinger&uml;and a thriller titled &uml;The score&uml;. And this &uml;Indian in cupboard&uml;, it results to be one of his most sensitive films . Rating : 6'5/10 . Better than average . Well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You should not do magic you do not understand, movie! Still, it was worth checking out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now that I've grown and educated myself, I can't stop thinking about how politically incorrect the title is. People say it should be called 'the Native American in the cupboard'. This is a very very common misconception in America. Yes, for a while they were called Indians. Christopher Columbus did not call them Indians because he thought they were from India. He called them "Gods people". The word in his language for "God's people" sounds very similar to the word Indian that we use today. It's just that the pronunciation we use now has changed a little after all this time. As for people saying that the "correct" term is "Native American" is highly offensive and frankly kind of stupid. How is it that taking the name from which the conquerors's gave them(American) supposed to be the correct term? That makes absolutely no sense. The word American has no relation whatsoever to Indian culture. Therefore "Native American" is utterly ridiculous, as well. If there is to be a title, it's should be call 'The Iroquois in the Cupboard'. No matter, what it is, call. The movie and book is not racist. The movie and book is trying to show tolerance through it's metaphor for how ignorant people have subjugated and marginalized the Indian populations of America by refusing to understand, listen to, or accommodate Indian heritage. The film opens up, a lot of things that people rarely knew about Native Americans. The film starts with a young boy, Omri (Hal Scardino), receives a cupboard. He uses a "magical" key, which belonged to his great-grandmother, to bring a plastic 18th century Native American figurine to life with the cupboard. The now-living Iroquois reveals his name as Little Bear (Litefoot). Litefoot, a real rapper does a great job in teaching role, not only in teaching the child about Iroquois's culture, but also the morality of playing God. There is a Frankenstein feel to the film. My favorite line in the film "God does play with little men'. Author Lynne Reid Banks and Director Frank Oz did an excellent job conveying the worry and angst the young boy felt for for his little toy come to life. I appreciate how the author had the boy evolve from seeing the Indian as a plaything to realizing that, regardless of his size, the Indian was a person with needs, feelings, and a right to live his life. What struck me about it was not that it was racist, or dated (it didn't feel so as much as you'd think,) but that it is a deconstruction of the idea that magical toys would be fun to have, and possibly of imagination as well. Omri seem just the typical kid protagonist, kinda generic if you ask me. But I still think his acting was unintentionally funny. Just weird out with all the close ups on Omri's face, the odd relationship between him and Little Bear, the weird fears, and how he reacts to others. Examples when Omri's dad confronts him about the saw blades, and Omri says he buried them. Odd lying by him and his parent accept that lame excuse. What kid can cuss to his mom as well? What is with his relationship with brothers being super cool in the beginning of the film and then for no reason Omri turns into a complete jerk with him? The worst thing, the kid does is abuse an animal. That poor thing was abused through the whole film. Whether it was real or not, it was still animal abuse and shouldn't be shown in this movie. The treatment of that rat was appalling. Omri still wasn't nearly as annoying as his friend, Patrick. One minute he's Omri's best friend, and all docile and quiet, and then like a switch, he's evil and defiant with seeing them as nothing more than animated toys. He brings in Boone (David Keith), a bigot Injun hating cowboy whom at first conflict with Little Bear, but grows to be friends with him, once they got to know each other. One of the odd things about the film is scenes that go nowhere or has nothing to do with the story like the Mohawk bully. Another thing is the degrading of women in the film, from the kids watching Montley Crue 'Girls' music video (it's the 1990's, why were they watching it anyways?) to Bear demanding a wife so she can cook. I put aside my critiques and squelched my inner squirming and found much to like about the film. The special effects were top notch, and it was really neat to see Little Bear, Boone and Tommy (Steve Coogan) the medic brought to life on the screen. It was pretty cool to see the Star Wars, Jurrasic Park, G.I Joe, and Robo-Cop reference. The movie is pretty close to the book, minus little changes such as the toy shop. I laugh at the kid that loves JFK. While the movie isn't that bad, it's not going to hurt the kids watching it. I like it when I was a kid and still kinda do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Indian in the Cupboard (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underrated and highly involving movie for kids. A young boy finds out that his cupboard has magical powers and can turn plastic into reality. He first turns a plastic Indian into a real human being. The movie teaches about responsibility but in an understandable way. It isn't patronizing nor childish, which means older audiences should relate to it also. It also mediates on life and death at certain points, and was the first film in a long time to be genuinely emotionally shocking. The relationship between the Indian and the cowboy was very well developed as they started to bond over their tragedies. The film does have a number of loose edges. Rishi Bhat was particularly annoying at times, but in a way he was necessary to play off Scardino. Even Scardino wasn't always a lovable protagonist. In one scene he kicks his brother's pet rat down the stairs, in an event where the rat clearly would have died. As the film hadn't relied on cartoon logic up until that point it was a bit out of place. Great effects, and seeing Darth Vader vs. a T-Rex kind of made up for those moments. A more innocent time when children's movies didn't have to be loud and crass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Movie For Kids
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-english
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forget reviews saying this is not as good as the book. No films are are a good as the book! Watch this movie with an 8 year old child and you will see how good the film is. Thank you Frank Oz for a wonderful film. The acting from the young children is above average and the tearful ending just right for a young audience. Interesting to note Steve Coogan plays a miniature model come to life - something he repeats later in his career in A Night At The Museum. Typecasting? The effects are also very good. Remember this is 1995 when CGI was in it's infancy - but the miniaturisation of the cast is flawless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting film with childish and mature characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dean Richard Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though I rated this plucky movie a 4, it doesn't mean I hate it, my dear friends. I liked it but it doesn't have the stuff to make it to my higher favoritism of movies. Frank Oz is imaginative, but I have to say that this film to me is not so Frank Oz, and movies that are adapted from books are quite impressive, but I can only say I was slightly impressed. For one thing, the cast is inadequate, I never heard of David Keith and Litefoot. This story follows Omri, an extremely childish youngster who, for his birthday, receives a MAGICAL (ooh!) cupboard. The Cupboard lacks its key so Omri's mother (actress Lindsay Crouse, never heard of her), gives him her collection of keys, and guess what? He finds the certain key on his second try! That part always took me aback. He puts in an antique Iroquois figure in the cupboard, and later in the morning he opens it to find the figure alive as a small Iroquois man. The pair has many tedious adventures, some including an idiotic rat ball and a down-right scruffy cowboy who was a toy figure too. The cupboard MAGICALLY turns plastic (plaz-teck!) things into their real life counterparts, only smaller. The pair soon learns that every boy must become a man (a typical, yet true moral). Omri's character really is childish, yet endearing; his parents seem to pamper him, he's afraid of the dark, and he has lame 90's action figures; but he does mellow out in the end of the movie. I liked the acting, but it was no To Kill a Mocking Bird, even at moving parts. The Iroquois man was different from other Indian movies; he was a guru in a way. The music was just moderate and odd, though with one exception you'll know when you hear it. Be warned, my dear readers, this movie contains slight profanity (embarrassing really); simulative killing and some ladies do a loathsome dance on TV at one point (they call this a kid movie, how embarrassing. Let's hope Omri was sleeping at that adultish scene). And no the kid does not play God, its just a story, have fun. Other than the 3 points I pointed out, the movie is plucky and it has a rather moving ending. It's an poorish if okay movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Indian in the Cupboard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terrific! First we took their land, then we confined them to reserves, now we've forced Native Americans to live inside of our furniture. Fortunately, this kids' movie is not about constricting a Cree to a credenza  it's about an Iroquois. For his 9th birthday, Omri (Hal Scardino) receives a cupboard and a plastic Indian figurine (Litefoot). When he locks the statuette in the sideboard using a magic key, he opens to find that the toy has come to life. Next, he places a plastic cowboy (David Keith) into the cupboard. And later, he must animate a plastic medic (Steve Coogan); unfortunately, he has lost the key. Based on the beloved children's book, The Indian in the Cupboard may have its faults but at heart it's a compassionate account of growing up. However, wouldn't it be more enlightening for a maturing young man to bring his sister's Bratz dolls to life? (Yellow Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little surprised at the low rating...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gannont
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On this one, I am surprised that viewers are so critical as to miss the big picture of the magical moments and concepts of the movie. I agree, there are quite a few flaws overall, but some are just direction or editing oversights. However, this film deserves to be recognized as a really good family film as is. There are so many good "teaching moments" for parents regarding what kids go through growing up. The effects were well done for the time, playing the small vs. big people visuals. I was absorbed in the story well beyond picking on every detail. Omri was decent, not great, but believable as the kid star; the casting and scripting both for Little Bear are compelling, fascinating, and wonderful. I would recommend this film to almost anyone, if their reality can be suspended for 96 minutes. It is a great story, if only a good film. Entertaining and more gripping than many films since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Totally Boring, A Waste Of Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first read the book, The Indian in the Cupboard with my Reading Class when I was in sixth grade, and I enjoyed it. But then we decided to watch this movie, I really became excited because I thought that the movie was really going to be like the book. But when I saw it, I almost fell asleep, I thought that it was really boring! I thought that it was nothing like the book, I thought that it was totally boring, that you will want to fall asleep when you watch it. First off, the mistakes that they made with the movie. The movie was updated, instead of taking place in England, like it does in the book, it takes place in the United States, you can tell that it is New York because you can see the World Trade Center towers in one scene! Another big mistake was changing were Omri had gotten the characters from. He got some in the book by buying them at the store, in this movie, he got them by swapping them with some of his other toys at an Indian exhibit in school. You can go ahead and watch it if you please, but I sort of would not highly recommend it to you, because of the tedious arrangements they made with the plot. But if you want to watch it, go on and watch it, I am not going to stop you from doing it, though I did not like this movie. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cowboys and Indians
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For his ninth birthday, slightly geeky but wholly appealing Hal Scardino (as Omri) receives cool wooden cupboard from his brother. There is no key to lock the cupboard, but mother Lindsay Crouse lets young Mr. Scardino try some stray keys from her collection. Happily, it turns out that Scardino's great-grandmother gifted a key to his mother, which perfectly fits the cupboard. Scardino locks up a Native American Indian toy figure, a "antique" gift from best friend Rishi Bhat (as Patrick), overnight. When he wakes up, Scardino discovers that Iroquois Litefoot (as Little Bear) has come to life, in miniature form, from the year 1761. The simple but effective special effects used throughout "The Indian in the Cupboard" have, surprisingly, made this film seem more natural looking than the special effects extravaganzas which blew it out of the theaters, back in the 1990s. Michael Lantieri, Eric Brevig, director Frank Oz, and their team make Scardino's little friends look very real. The story is based on a charming series of books by Lynne Reid Banks; the several sequels blunt the impact of the final door closing on the magical years of childhood, but the additional stories have no impact on this charming children's story. Grown-ups and some kids should see subtleties. ******* The Indian in the Cupboard (7/14/95) Frank Oz ~ Hal Scardino, Litefoot, Rishi Bhat, David Keith
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not entirely bad, but suffers from more than one significant flaw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sometimes nice to revisit movies from childhood, and that's just what I did with this one, an adaptation of the children's novel of the same name by Lynne Reid Banks. I think my first viewing of "The Indian in the Cupboard" was on the big screen, and then I saw it at school twice at two different times within the next few years. So, I saw this film twice during childhood, and a third time in my early adolescent years. Just yesterday, I rented it so I could see it again for the first time in nine years. By this time, I had seen its rating and number of votes here, so I could tell that it wasn't highly regarded as a family classic. For that reason, I did not have high expectations, and basically, this PG-rated family movie turned out to be a mixed blessing, which was probably the best I could hope for. When a young boy named Omri celebrates his ninth birthday, one of the presents he gets is a cupboard from his older brother, and another is a little plastic Indian figure from his friend. With both of these presents, he is in for a surprise. After placing the plastic figure in the cupboard, locking it up, and then opening it again, he sees that the figure, still the same size, has come to life! He soon learns that this is what happens when one places a figure in there, locks the door, and opens it again! That plastic figure has been replaced by a real 18th century Iroquois Indian named Little Bear, interrupted from his life and brought to Omri's room, where he is the size of an action figure! He agrees to stay for a while, but during his stay, he and the young modern-day boy are headed for adventure and conflict, and their cultural differences turn out to be one of their problems. One criticism of this movie I agree with is the acting, especially Hal Scardino's acting in the lead role of Omri. He wasn't the greatest child actor to ever make it to the silver screen, that's for sure. Another severe flaw in the film is sometimes the musical score. It tends to be pretty sappy, and really seems unreasonable at times, such as the music in the scene where Omri first sees Little Bear alive in the cupboard. More still, there's some very poor dialogue, and there also may be some humour here, but that also usually fails, with the likes of Boo-hoo Boone, a goofy cowboy who also comes from the cupboard. Now, not everything about this film is bad. Little Bear is a likable character, even if Litefoot doesn't do the greatest job playing him. I can't say I was completely bored throughout the entire film, as there were parts that intrigued me to a certain degree, but this did not hide the blatant flaws. I vaguely remember reading the book back in the late 90's, but can't remember it too well, so I don't know how it compares. However, it does seem to be more popular than this adaptation. This movie is one of those which was never one of my favourites as a kid, and I'm not sure exactly what I thought of it at the time, but I guess I liked it somewhat. During my last viewing, much later than the rest of them, I could definitely see more flaws in it than I used to (I don't think I used to see any real flaws in it at all). This 1995 adaptation of "The Indian in the Cupboard" does have a few redeeming features, but I'm sure they could have tried harder to make it really good family entertainment, and if only they had avoided the negative things I've pointed out, there would have been a good chance that they could have made it happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agreeable family film filled with imagination and in which adventure comes to life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On his ninth birthday a young boy (Hal Scardino) named Omri (it means "The Lord is my life" and was the name of a Hebrew king whose story is told in I Kings 16) receives various presents from his parents (Richard Jenkins , Lindsay Crouse) and brothers . Two of them first seem to be less important : an old cupboard -a wooden medicine cabinet - from his brother and a little Indian figure made of plastic . Then there happens the biggest adventure of his childhood , the magical cupboard brings his toy action figures to life and Omri watches him become flesh and blood ; there also appear a soldier (Steve Coogan) from WWII . Three-inch plastic Indian named Little Bear (Lifefoot) undertaking several adventures and teaching him important lessons . Thing go worse , however , when the boy's best friend brings a toy gunfighter (David Keith) to life and pursuit starts . Events turn nasty and might be frightened for young children , by some scenes involving a rather vicious mouse . Enjoyable and well-intentioned film plenty of good feeling , marvelous adventure , fantasy and sense of wonder . This is a nice movie with heart that amuses and has something to tell . The picture is pretty good but suffers of claustrophobic scenario , as it is mostly set in room , exception some brief scenes in courtyard . Intelligent as well as sensitive screenplay by Melissa Matheson , Harrison Ford's real-life first wife , based on the best-selling children's book by Lynne Reid Banks who wrote her original novel as a bedtime story for her son , Omri . Cool special effects , as blue screen techniques allow them to appear together-on-screen although they were really filmed together only once . Emotive as well as evocative musical score by Randy Edelman . Colorful and adequate cinematography by Russell Carpenter . The motion picture well produced by Kathleen Kennedy and Frank Marshall was professionally directed by Frank Oz , though he stated he was reluctant to direct this movie, as he doesn't think he's a children's director. Frank began forming team with the great Jim Henson filming known titles such as &uml;The Dark Crystal&uml; and &uml;Muppets take Manhattan&uml;. Frank subsequently directed a lot of comedies as &uml;Little shop of horrors&uml;, &uml;Dirty rotten scoundrels&uml;, &uml;What about Bob?&uml;, &uml;House sitter&uml;, &uml;In and out&uml;, &uml;Bowfinger&uml;and a thriller titled &uml;The score&uml;. And this &uml;Indian in cupboard&uml;, it results to be one of his most sensitive films . Rating : 6'5/10 . Better than average . Well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You should not do magic you do not understand, movie! Still, it was worth checking out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now that I've grown and educated myself, I can't stop thinking about how politically incorrect the title is. People say it should be called 'the Native American in the cupboard'. This is a very very common misconception in America. Yes, for a while they were called Indians. Christopher Columbus did not call them Indians because he thought they were from India. He called them "Gods people". The word in his language for "God's people" sounds very similar to the word Indian that we use today. It's just that the pronunciation we use now has changed a little after all this time. As for people saying that the "correct" term is "Native American" is highly offensive and frankly kind of stupid. How is it that taking the name from which the conquerors's gave them(American) supposed to be the correct term? That makes absolutely no sense. The word American has no relation whatsoever to Indian culture. Therefore "Native American" is utterly ridiculous, as well. If there is to be a title, it's should be call 'The Iroquois in the Cupboard'. No matter, what it is, call. The movie and book is not racist. The movie and book is trying to show tolerance through it's metaphor for how ignorant people have subjugated and marginalized the Indian populations of America by refusing to understand, listen to, or accommodate Indian heritage. The film opens up, a lot of things that people rarely knew about Native Americans. The film starts with a young boy, Omri (Hal Scardino), receives a cupboard. He uses a "magical" key, which belonged to his great-grandmother, to bring a plastic 18th century Native American figurine to life with the cupboard. The now-living Iroquois reveals his name as Little Bear (Litefoot). Litefoot, a real rapper does a great job in teaching role, not only in teaching the child about Iroquois's culture, but also the morality of playing God. There is a Frankenstein feel to the film. My favorite line in the film "God does play with little men'. Author Lynne Reid Banks and Director Frank Oz did an excellent job conveying the worry and angst the young boy felt for for his little toy come to life. I appreciate how the author had the boy evolve from seeing the Indian as a plaything to realizing that, regardless of his size, the Indian was a person with needs, feelings, and a right to live his life. What struck me about it was not that it was racist, or dated (it didn't feel so as much as you'd think,) but that it is a deconstruction of the idea that magical toys would be fun to have, and possibly of imagination as well. Omri seem just the typical kid protagonist, kinda generic if you ask me. But I still think his acting was unintentionally funny. Just weird out with all the close ups on Omri's face, the odd relationship between him and Little Bear, the weird fears, and how he reacts to others. Examples when Omri's dad confronts him about the saw blades, and Omri says he buried them. Odd lying by him and his parent accept that lame excuse. What kid can cuss to his mom as well? What is with his relationship with brothers being super cool in the beginning of the film and then for no reason Omri turns into a complete jerk with him? The worst thing, the kid does is abuse an animal. That poor thing was abused through the whole film. Whether it was real or not, it was still animal abuse and shouldn't be shown in this movie. The treatment of that rat was appalling. Omri still wasn't nearly as annoying as his friend, Patrick. One minute he's Omri's best friend, and all docile and quiet, and then like a switch, he's evil and defiant with seeing them as nothing more than animated toys. He brings in Boone (David Keith), a bigot Injun hating cowboy whom at first conflict with Little Bear, but grows to be friends with him, once they got to know each other. One of the odd things about the film is scenes that go nowhere or has nothing to do with the story like the Mohawk bully. Another thing is the degrading of women in the film, from the kids watching Montley Crue 'Girls' music video (it's the 1990's, why were they watching it anyways?) to Bear demanding a wife so she can cook. I put aside my critiques and squelched my inner squirming and found much to like about the film. The special effects were top notch, and it was really neat to see Little Bear, Boone and Tommy (Steve Coogan) the medic brought to life on the screen. It was pretty cool to see the Star Wars, Jurrasic Park, G.I Joe, and Robo-Cop reference. The movie is pretty close to the book, minus little changes such as the toy shop. I laugh at the kid that loves JFK. While the movie isn't that bad, it's not going to hurt the kids watching it. I like it when I was a kid and still kinda do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Indian in the Cupboard (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underrated and highly involving movie for kids. A young boy finds out that his cupboard has magical powers and can turn plastic into reality. He first turns a plastic Indian into a real human being. The movie teaches about responsibility but in an understandable way. It isn't patronizing nor childish, which means older audiences should relate to it also. It also mediates on life and death at certain points, and was the first film in a long time to be genuinely emotionally shocking. The relationship between the Indian and the cowboy was very well developed as they started to bond over their tragedies. The film does have a number of loose edges. Rishi Bhat was particularly annoying at times, but in a way he was necessary to play off Scardino. Even Scardino wasn't always a lovable protagonist. In one scene he kicks his brother's pet rat down the stairs, in an event where the rat clearly would have died. As the film hadn't relied on cartoon logic up until that point it was a bit out of place. Great effects, and seeing Darth Vader vs. a T-Rex kind of made up for those moments. A more innocent time when children's movies didn't have to be loud and crass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Movie For Kids
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-english
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forget reviews saying this is not as good as the book. No films are are a good as the book! Watch this movie with an 8 year old child and you will see how good the film is. Thank you Frank Oz for a wonderful film. The acting from the young children is above average and the tearful ending just right for a young audience. Interesting to note Steve Coogan plays a miniature model come to life - something he repeats later in his career in A Night At The Museum. Typecasting? The effects are also very good. Remember this is 1995 when CGI was in it's infancy - but the miniaturisation of the cast is flawless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting film with childish and mature characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dean Richard Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though I rated this plucky movie a 4, it doesn't mean I hate it, my dear friends. I liked it but it doesn't have the stuff to make it to my higher favoritism of movies. Frank Oz is imaginative, but I have to say that this film to me is not so Frank Oz, and movies that are adapted from books are quite impressive, but I can only say I was slightly impressed. For one thing, the cast is inadequate, I never heard of David Keith and Litefoot. This story follows Omri, an extremely childish youngster who, for his birthday, receives a MAGICAL (ooh!) cupboard. The Cupboard lacks its key so Omri's mother (actress Lindsay Crouse, never heard of her), gives him her collection of keys, and guess what? He finds the certain key on his second try! That part always took me aback. He puts in an antique Iroquois figure in the cupboard, and later in the morning he opens it to find the figure alive as a small Iroquois man. The pair has many tedious adventures, some including an idiotic rat ball and a down-right scruffy cowboy who was a toy figure too. The cupboard MAGICALLY turns plastic (plaz-teck!) things into their real life counterparts, only smaller. The pair soon learns that every boy must become a man (a typical, yet true moral). Omri's character really is childish, yet endearing; his parents seem to pamper him, he's afraid of the dark, and he has lame 90's action figures; but he does mellow out in the end of the movie. I liked the acting, but it was no To Kill a Mocking Bird, even at moving parts. The Iroquois man was different from other Indian movies; he was a guru in a way. The music was just moderate and odd, though with one exception you'll know when you hear it. Be warned, my dear readers, this movie contains slight profanity (embarrassing really); simulative killing and some ladies do a loathsome dance on TV at one point (they call this a kid movie, how embarrassing. Let's hope Omri was sleeping at that adultish scene). And no the kid does not play God, its just a story, have fun. Other than the 3 points I pointed out, the movie is plucky and it has a rather moving ending. It's an poorish if okay movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Indian in the Cupboard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terrific! First we took their land, then we confined them to reserves, now we've forced Native Americans to live inside of our furniture. Fortunately, this kids' movie is not about constricting a Cree to a credenza  it's about an Iroquois. For his 9th birthday, Omri (Hal Scardino) receives a cupboard and a plastic Indian figurine (Litefoot). When he locks the statuette in the sideboard using a magic key, he opens to find that the toy has come to life. Next, he places a plastic cowboy (David Keith) into the cupboard. And later, he must animate a plastic medic (Steve Coogan); unfortunately, he has lost the key. Based on the beloved children's book, The Indian in the Cupboard may have its faults but at heart it's a compassionate account of growing up. However, wouldn't it be more enlightening for a maturing young man to bring his sister's Bratz dolls to life? (Yellow Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little surprised at the low rating...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gannont
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On this one, I am surprised that viewers are so critical as to miss the big picture of the magical moments and concepts of the movie. I agree, there are quite a few flaws overall, but some are just direction or editing oversights. However, this film deserves to be recognized as a really good family film as is. There are so many good "teaching moments" for parents regarding what kids go through growing up. The effects were well done for the time, playing the small vs. big people visuals. I was absorbed in the story well beyond picking on every detail. Omri was decent, not great, but believable as the kid star; the casting and scripting both for Little Bear are compelling, fascinating, and wonderful. I would recommend this film to almost anyone, if their reality can be suspended for 96 minutes. It is a great story, if only a good film. Entertaining and more gripping than many films since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Totally Boring, A Waste Of Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first read the book, The Indian in the Cupboard with my Reading Class when I was in sixth grade, and I enjoyed it. But then we decided to watch this movie, I really became excited because I thought that the movie was really going to be like the book. But when I saw it, I almost fell asleep, I thought that it was really boring! I thought that it was nothing like the book, I thought that it was totally boring, that you will want to fall asleep when you watch it. First off, the mistakes that they made with the movie. The movie was updated, instead of taking place in England, like it does in the book, it takes place in the United States, you can tell that it is New York because you can see the World Trade Center towers in one scene! Another big mistake was changing were Omri had gotten the characters from. He got some in the book by buying them at the store, in this movie, he got them by swapping them with some of his other toys at an Indian exhibit in school. You can go ahead and watch it if you please, but I sort of would not highly recommend it to you, because of the tedious arrangements they made with the plot. But if you want to watch it, go on and watch it, I am not going to stop you from doing it, though I did not like this movie. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cowboys and Indians
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For his ninth birthday, slightly geeky but wholly appealing Hal Scardino (as Omri) receives cool wooden cupboard from his brother. There is no key to lock the cupboard, but mother Lindsay Crouse lets young Mr. Scardino try some stray keys from her collection. Happily, it turns out that Scardino's great-grandmother gifted a key to his mother, which perfectly fits the cupboard. Scardino locks up a Native American Indian toy figure, a "antique" gift from best friend Rishi Bhat (as Patrick), overnight. When he wakes up, Scardino discovers that Iroquois Litefoot (as Little Bear) has come to life, in miniature form, from the year 1761. The simple but effective special effects used throughout "The Indian in the Cupboard" have, surprisingly, made this film seem more natural looking than the special effects extravaganzas which blew it out of the theaters, back in the 1990s. Michael Lantieri, Eric Brevig, director Frank Oz, and their team make Scardino's little friends look very real. The story is based on a charming series of books by Lynne Reid Banks; the several sequels blunt the impact of the final door closing on the magical years of childhood, but the additional stories have no impact on this charming children's story. Grown-ups and some kids should see subtleties. ******* The Indian in the Cupboard (7/14/95) Frank Oz ~ Hal Scardino, Litefoot, Rishi Bhat, David Keith
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not entirely bad, but suffers from more than one significant flaw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sometimes nice to revisit movies from childhood, and that's just what I did with this one, an adaptation of the children's novel of the same name by Lynne Reid Banks. I think my first viewing of "The Indian in the Cupboard" was on the big screen, and then I saw it at school twice at two different times within the next few years. So, I saw this film twice during childhood, and a third time in my early adolescent years. Just yesterday, I rented it so I could see it again for the first time in nine years. By this time, I had seen its rating and number of votes here, so I could tell that it wasn't highly regarded as a family classic. For that reason, I did not have high expectations, and basically, this PG-rated family movie turned out to be a mixed blessing, which was probably the best I could hope for. When a young boy named Omri celebrates his ninth birthday, one of the presents he gets is a cupboard from his older brother, and another is a little plastic Indian figure from his friend. With both of these presents, he is in for a surprise. After placing the plastic figure in the cupboard, locking it up, and then opening it again, he sees that the figure, still the same size, has come to life! He soon learns that this is what happens when one places a figure in there, locks the door, and opens it again! That plastic figure has been replaced by a real 18th century Iroquois Indian named Little Bear, interrupted from his life and brought to Omri's room, where he is the size of an action figure! He agrees to stay for a while, but during his stay, he and the young modern-day boy are headed for adventure and conflict, and their cultural differences turn out to be one of their problems. One criticism of this movie I agree with is the acting, especially Hal Scardino's acting in the lead role of Omri. He wasn't the greatest child actor to ever make it to the silver screen, that's for sure. Another severe flaw in the film is sometimes the musical score. It tends to be pretty sappy, and really seems unreasonable at times, such as the music in the scene where Omri first sees Little Bear alive in the cupboard. More still, there's some very poor dialogue, and there also may be some humour here, but that also usually fails, with the likes of Boo-hoo Boone, a goofy cowboy who also comes from the cupboard. Now, not everything about this film is bad. Little Bear is a likable character, even if Litefoot doesn't do the greatest job playing him. I can't say I was completely bored throughout the entire film, as there were parts that intrigued me to a certain degree, but this did not hide the blatant flaws. I vaguely remember reading the book back in the late 90's, but can't remember it too well, so I don't know how it compares. However, it does seem to be more popular than this adaptation. This movie is one of those which was never one of my favourites as a kid, and I'm not sure exactly what I thought of it at the time, but I guess I liked it somewhat. During my last viewing, much later than the rest of them, I could definitely see more flaws in it than I used to (I don't think I used to see any real flaws in it at all). This 1995 adaptation of "The Indian in the Cupboard" does have a few redeeming features, but I'm sure they could have tried harder to make it really good family entertainment, and if only they had avoided the negative things I've pointed out, there would have been a good chance that they could have made it happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agreeable family film filled with imagination and in which adventure comes to life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On his ninth birthday a young boy (Hal Scardino) named Omri (it means "The Lord is my life" and was the name of a Hebrew king whose story is told in I Kings 16) receives various presents from his parents (Richard Jenkins , Lindsay Crouse) and brothers . Two of them first seem to be less important : an old cupboard -a wooden medicine cabinet - from his brother and a little Indian figure made of plastic . Then there happens the biggest adventure of his childhood , the magical cupboard brings his toy action figures to life and Omri watches him become flesh and blood ; there also appear a soldier (Steve Coogan) from WWII . Three-inch plastic Indian named Little Bear (Lifefoot) undertaking several adventures and teaching him important lessons . Thing go worse , however , when the boy's best friend brings a toy gunfighter (David Keith) to life and pursuit starts . Events turn nasty and might be frightened for young children , by some scenes involving a rather vicious mouse . Enjoyable and well-intentioned film plenty of good feeling , marvelous adventure , fantasy and sense of wonder . This is a nice movie with heart that amuses and has something to tell . The picture is pretty good but suffers of claustrophobic scenario , as it is mostly set in room , exception some brief scenes in courtyard . Intelligent as well as sensitive screenplay by Melissa Matheson , Harrison Ford's real-life first wife , based on the best-selling children's book by Lynne Reid Banks who wrote her original novel as a bedtime story for her son , Omri . Cool special effects , as blue screen techniques allow them to appear together-on-screen although they were really filmed together only once . Emotive as well as evocative musical score by Randy Edelman . Colorful and adequate cinematography by Russell Carpenter . The motion picture well produced by Kathleen Kennedy and Frank Marshall was professionally directed by Frank Oz , though he stated he was reluctant to direct this movie, as he doesn't think he's a children's director. Frank began forming team with the great Jim Henson filming known titles such as &uml;The Dark Crystal&uml; and &uml;Muppets take Manhattan&uml;. Frank subsequently directed a lot of comedies as &uml;Little shop of horrors&uml;, &uml;Dirty rotten scoundrels&uml;, &uml;What about Bob?&uml;, &uml;House sitter&uml;, &uml;In and out&uml;, &uml;Bowfinger&uml;and a thriller titled &uml;The score&uml;. And this &uml;Indian in cupboard&uml;, it results to be one of his most sensitive films . Rating : 6'5/10 . Better than average . Well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You should not do magic you do not understand, movie! Still, it was worth checking out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now that I've grown and educated myself, I can't stop thinking about how politically incorrect the title is. People say it should be called 'the Native American in the cupboard'. This is a very very common misconception in America. Yes, for a while they were called Indians. Christopher Columbus did not call them Indians because he thought they were from India. He called them "Gods people". The word in his language for "God's people" sounds very similar to the word Indian that we use today. It's just that the pronunciation we use now has changed a little after all this time. As for people saying that the "correct" term is "Native American" is highly offensive and frankly kind of stupid. How is it that taking the name from which the conquerors's gave them(American) supposed to be the correct term? That makes absolutely no sense. The word American has no relation whatsoever to Indian culture. Therefore "Native American" is utterly ridiculous, as well. If there is to be a title, it's should be call 'The Iroquois in the Cupboard'. No matter, what it is, call. The movie and book is not racist. The movie and book is trying to show tolerance through it's metaphor for how ignorant people have subjugated and marginalized the Indian populations of America by refusing to understand, listen to, or accommodate Indian heritage. The film opens up, a lot of things that people rarely knew about Native Americans. The film starts with a young boy, Omri (Hal Scardino), receives a cupboard. He uses a "magical" key, which belonged to his great-grandmother, to bring a plastic 18th century Native American figurine to life with the cupboard. The now-living Iroquois reveals his name as Little Bear (Litefoot). Litefoot, a real rapper does a great job in teaching role, not only in teaching the child about Iroquois's culture, but also the morality of playing God. There is a Frankenstein feel to the film. My favorite line in the film "God does play with little men'. Author Lynne Reid Banks and Director Frank Oz did an excellent job conveying the worry and angst the young boy felt for for his little toy come to life. I appreciate how the author had the boy evolve from seeing the Indian as a plaything to realizing that, regardless of his size, the Indian was a person with needs, feelings, and a right to live his life. What struck me about it was not that it was racist, or dated (it didn't feel so as much as you'd think,) but that it is a deconstruction of the idea that magical toys would be fun to have, and possibly of imagination as well. Omri seem just the typical kid protagonist, kinda generic if you ask me. But I still think his acting was unintentionally funny. Just weird out with all the close ups on Omri's face, the odd relationship between him and Little Bear, the weird fears, and how he reacts to others. Examples when Omri's dad confronts him about the saw blades, and Omri says he buried them. Odd lying by him and his parent accept that lame excuse. What kid can cuss to his mom as well? What is with his relationship with brothers being super cool in the beginning of the film and then for no reason Omri turns into a complete jerk with him? The worst thing, the kid does is abuse an animal. That poor thing was abused through the whole film. Whether it was real or not, it was still animal abuse and shouldn't be shown in this movie. The treatment of that rat was appalling. Omri still wasn't nearly as annoying as his friend, Patrick. One minute he's Omri's best friend, and all docile and quiet, and then like a switch, he's evil and defiant with seeing them as nothing more than animated toys. He brings in Boone (David Keith), a bigot Injun hating cowboy whom at first conflict with Little Bear, but grows to be friends with him, once they got to know each other. One of the odd things about the film is scenes that go nowhere or has nothing to do with the story like the Mohawk bully. Another thing is the degrading of women in the film, from the kids watching Montley Crue 'Girls' music video (it's the 1990's, why were they watching it anyways?) to Bear demanding a wife so she can cook. I put aside my critiques and squelched my inner squirming and found much to like about the film. The special effects were top notch, and it was really neat to see Little Bear, Boone and Tommy (Steve Coogan) the medic brought to life on the screen. It was pretty cool to see the Star Wars, Jurrasic Park, G.I Joe, and Robo-Cop reference. The movie is pretty close to the book, minus little changes such as the toy shop. I laugh at the kid that loves JFK. While the movie isn't that bad, it's not going to hurt the kids watching it. I like it when I was a kid and still kinda do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Indian in the Cupboard (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underrated and highly involving movie for kids. A young boy finds out that his cupboard has magical powers and can turn plastic into reality. He first turns a plastic Indian into a real human being. The movie teaches about responsibility but in an understandable way. It isn't patronizing nor childish, which means older audiences should relate to it also. It also mediates on life and death at certain points, and was the first film in a long time to be genuinely emotionally shocking. The relationship between the Indian and the cowboy was very well developed as they started to bond over their tragedies. The film does have a number of loose edges. Rishi Bhat was particularly annoying at times, but in a way he was necessary to play off Scardino. Even Scardino wasn't always a lovable protagonist. In one scene he kicks his brother's pet rat down the stairs, in an event where the rat clearly would have died. As the film hadn't relied on cartoon logic up until that point it was a bit out of place. Great effects, and seeing Darth Vader vs. a T-Rex kind of made up for those moments. A more innocent time when children's movies didn't have to be loud and crass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Movie For Kids
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-english
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forget reviews saying this is not as good as the book. No films are are a good as the book! Watch this movie with an 8 year old child and you will see how good the film is. Thank you Frank Oz for a wonderful film. The acting from the young children is above average and the tearful ending just right for a young audience. Interesting to note Steve Coogan plays a miniature model come to life - something he repeats later in his career in A Night At The Museum. Typecasting? The effects are also very good. Remember this is 1995 when CGI was in it's infancy - but the miniaturisation of the cast is flawless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting film with childish and mature characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dean Richard Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though I rated this plucky movie a 4, it doesn't mean I hate it, my dear friends. I liked it but it doesn't have the stuff to make it to my higher favoritism of movies. Frank Oz is imaginative, but I have to say that this film to me is not so Frank Oz, and movies that are adapted from books are quite impressive, but I can only say I was slightly impressed. For one thing, the cast is inadequate, I never heard of David Keith and Litefoot. This story follows Omri, an extremely childish youngster who, for his birthday, receives a MAGICAL (ooh!) cupboard. The Cupboard lacks its key so Omri's mother (actress Lindsay Crouse, never heard of her), gives him her collection of keys, and guess what? He finds the certain key on his second try! That part always took me aback. He puts in an antique Iroquois figure in the cupboard, and later in the morning he opens it to find the figure alive as a small Iroquois man. The pair has many tedious adventures, some including an idiotic rat ball and a down-right scruffy cowboy who was a toy figure too. The cupboard MAGICALLY turns plastic (plaz-teck!) things into their real life counterparts, only smaller. The pair soon learns that every boy must become a man (a typical, yet true moral). Omri's character really is childish, yet endearing; his parents seem to pamper him, he's afraid of the dark, and he has lame 90's action figures; but he does mellow out in the end of the movie. I liked the acting, but it was no To Kill a Mocking Bird, even at moving parts. The Iroquois man was different from other Indian movies; he was a guru in a way. The music was just moderate and odd, though with one exception you'll know when you hear it. Be warned, my dear readers, this movie contains slight profanity (embarrassing really); simulative killing and some ladies do a loathsome dance on TV at one point (they call this a kid movie, how embarrassing. Let's hope Omri was sleeping at that adultish scene). And no the kid does not play God, its just a story, have fun. Other than the 3 points I pointed out, the movie is plucky and it has a rather moving ending. It's an poorish if okay movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Indian in the Cupboard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terrific! First we took their land, then we confined them to reserves, now we've forced Native Americans to live inside of our furniture. Fortunately, this kids' movie is not about constricting a Cree to a credenza  it's about an Iroquois. For his 9th birthday, Omri (Hal Scardino) receives a cupboard and a plastic Indian figurine (Litefoot). When he locks the statuette in the sideboard using a magic key, he opens to find that the toy has come to life. Next, he places a plastic cowboy (David Keith) into the cupboard. And later, he must animate a plastic medic (Steve Coogan); unfortunately, he has lost the key. Based on the beloved children's book, The Indian in the Cupboard may have its faults but at heart it's a compassionate account of growing up. However, wouldn't it be more enlightening for a maturing young man to bring his sister's Bratz dolls to life? (Yellow Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little surprised at the low rating...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gannont
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On this one, I am surprised that viewers are so critical as to miss the big picture of the magical moments and concepts of the movie. I agree, there are quite a few flaws overall, but some are just direction or editing oversights. However, this film deserves to be recognized as a really good family film as is. There are so many good "teaching moments" for parents regarding what kids go through growing up. The effects were well done for the time, playing the small vs. big people visuals. I was absorbed in the story well beyond picking on every detail. Omri was decent, not great, but believable as the kid star; the casting and scripting both for Little Bear are compelling, fascinating, and wonderful. I would recommend this film to almost anyone, if their reality can be suspended for 96 minutes. It is a great story, if only a good film. Entertaining and more gripping than many films since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Totally Boring, A Waste Of Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first read the book, The Indian in the Cupboard with my Reading Class when I was in sixth grade, and I enjoyed it. But then we decided to watch this movie, I really became excited because I thought that the movie was really going to be like the book. But when I saw it, I almost fell asleep, I thought that it was really boring! I thought that it was nothing like the book, I thought that it was totally boring, that you will want to fall asleep when you watch it. First off, the mistakes that they made with the movie. The movie was updated, instead of taking place in England, like it does in the book, it takes place in the United States, you can tell that it is New York because you can see the World Trade Center towers in one scene! Another big mistake was changing were Omri had gotten the characters from. He got some in the book by buying them at the store, in this movie, he got them by swapping them with some of his other toys at an Indian exhibit in school. You can go ahead and watch it if you please, but I sort of would not highly recommend it to you, because of the tedious arrangements they made with the plot. But if you want to watch it, go on and watch it, I am not going to stop you from doing it, though I did not like this movie. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cowboys and Indians
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For his ninth birthday, slightly geeky but wholly appealing Hal Scardino (as Omri) receives cool wooden cupboard from his brother. There is no key to lock the cupboard, but mother Lindsay Crouse lets young Mr. Scardino try some stray keys from her collection. Happily, it turns out that Scardino's great-grandmother gifted a key to his mother, which perfectly fits the cupboard. Scardino locks up a Native American Indian toy figure, a "antique" gift from best friend Rishi Bhat (as Patrick), overnight. When he wakes up, Scardino discovers that Iroquois Litefoot (as Little Bear) has come to life, in miniature form, from the year 1761. The simple but effective special effects used throughout "The Indian in the Cupboard" have, surprisingly, made this film seem more natural looking than the special effects extravaganzas which blew it out of the theaters, back in the 1990s. Michael Lantieri, Eric Brevig, director Frank Oz, and their team make Scardino's little friends look very real. The story is based on a charming series of books by Lynne Reid Banks; the several sequels blunt the impact of the final door closing on the magical years of childhood, but the additional stories have no impact on this charming children's story. Grown-ups and some kids should see subtleties. ******* The Indian in the Cupboard (7/14/95) Frank Oz ~ Hal Scardino, Litefoot, Rishi Bhat, David Keith
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not entirely bad, but suffers from more than one significant flaw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sometimes nice to revisit movies from childhood, and that's just what I did with this one, an adaptation of the children's novel of the same name by Lynne Reid Banks. I think my first viewing of "The Indian in the Cupboard" was on the big screen, and then I saw it at school twice at two different times within the next few years. So, I saw this film twice during childhood, and a third time in my early adolescent years. Just yesterday, I rented it so I could see it again for the first time in nine years. By this time, I had seen its rating and number of votes here, so I could tell that it wasn't highly regarded as a family classic. For that reason, I did not have high expectations, and basically, this PG-rated family movie turned out to be a mixed blessing, which was probably the best I could hope for. When a young boy named Omri celebrates his ninth birthday, one of the presents he gets is a cupboard from his older brother, and another is a little plastic Indian figure from his friend. With both of these presents, he is in for a surprise. After placing the plastic figure in the cupboard, locking it up, and then opening it again, he sees that the figure, still the same size, has come to life! He soon learns that this is what happens when one places a figure in there, locks the door, and opens it again! That plastic figure has been replaced by a real 18th century Iroquois Indian named Little Bear, interrupted from his life and brought to Omri's room, where he is the size of an action figure! He agrees to stay for a while, but during his stay, he and the young modern-day boy are headed for adventure and conflict, and their cultural differences turn out to be one of their problems. One criticism of this movie I agree with is the acting, especially Hal Scardino's acting in the lead role of Omri. He wasn't the greatest child actor to ever make it to the silver screen, that's for sure. Another severe flaw in the film is sometimes the musical score. It tends to be pretty sappy, and really seems unreasonable at times, such as the music in the scene where Omri first sees Little Bear alive in the cupboard. More still, there's some very poor dialogue, and there also may be some humour here, but that also usually fails, with the likes of Boo-hoo Boone, a goofy cowboy who also comes from the cupboard. Now, not everything about this film is bad. Little Bear is a likable character, even if Litefoot doesn't do the greatest job playing him. I can't say I was completely bored throughout the entire film, as there were parts that intrigued me to a certain degree, but this did not hide the blatant flaws. I vaguely remember reading the book back in the late 90's, but can't remember it too well, so I don't know how it compares. However, it does seem to be more popular than this adaptation. This movie is one of those which was never one of my favourites as a kid, and I'm not sure exactly what I thought of it at the time, but I guess I liked it somewhat. During my last viewing, much later than the rest of them, I could definitely see more flaws in it than I used to (I don't think I used to see any real flaws in it at all). This 1995 adaptation of "The Indian in the Cupboard" does have a few redeeming features, but I'm sure they could have tried harder to make it really good family entertainment, and if only they had avoided the negative things I've pointed out, there would have been a good chance that they could have made it happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Agreeable family film filled with imagination and in which adventure comes to life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On his ninth birthday a young boy (Hal Scardino) named Omri (it means "The Lord is my life" and was the name of a Hebrew king whose story is told in I Kings 16) receives various presents from his parents (Richard Jenkins , Lindsay Crouse) and brothers . Two of them first seem to be less important : an old cupboard -a wooden medicine cabinet - from his brother and a little Indian figure made of plastic . Then there happens the biggest adventure of his childhood , the magical cupboard brings his toy action figures to life and Omri watches him become flesh and blood ; there also appear a soldier (Steve Coogan) from WWII . Three-inch plastic Indian named Little Bear (Lifefoot) undertaking several adventures and teaching him important lessons . Thing go worse , however , when the boy's best friend brings a toy gunfighter (David Keith) to life and pursuit starts . Events turn nasty and might be frightened for young children , by some scenes involving a rather vicious mouse . Enjoyable and well-intentioned film plenty of good feeling , marvelous adventure , fantasy and sense of wonder . This is a nice movie with heart that amuses and has something to tell . The picture is pretty good but suffers of claustrophobic scenario , as it is mostly set in room , exception some brief scenes in courtyard . Intelligent as well as sensitive screenplay by Melissa Matheson , Harrison Ford's real-life first wife , based on the best-selling children's book by Lynne Reid Banks who wrote her original novel as a bedtime story for her son , Omri . Cool special effects , as blue screen techniques allow them to appear together-on-screen although they were really filmed together only once . Emotive as well as evocative musical score by Randy Edelman . Colorful and adequate cinematography by Russell Carpenter . The motion picture well produced by Kathleen Kennedy and Frank Marshall was professionally directed by Frank Oz , though he stated he was reluctant to direct this movie, as he doesn't think he's a children's director. Frank began forming team with the great Jim Henson filming known titles such as &uml;The Dark Crystal&uml; and &uml;Muppets take Manhattan&uml;. Frank subsequently directed a lot of comedies as &uml;Little shop of horrors&uml;, &uml;Dirty rotten scoundrels&uml;, &uml;What about Bob?&uml;, &uml;House sitter&uml;, &uml;In and out&uml;, &uml;Bowfinger&uml;and a thriller titled &uml;The score&uml;. And this &uml;Indian in cupboard&uml;, it results to be one of his most sensitive films . Rating : 6'5/10 . Better than average . Well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You should not do magic you do not understand, movie! Still, it was worth checking out.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Now that I've grown and educated myself, I can't stop thinking about how politically incorrect the title is. People say it should be called 'the Native American in the cupboard'. This is a very very common misconception in America. Yes, for a while they were called Indians. Christopher Columbus did not call them Indians because he thought they were from India. He called them "Gods people". The word in his language for "God's people" sounds very similar to the word Indian that we use today. It's just that the pronunciation we use now has changed a little after all this time. As for people saying that the "correct" term is "Native American" is highly offensive and frankly kind of stupid. How is it that taking the name from which the conquerors's gave them(American) supposed to be the correct term? That makes absolutely no sense. The word American has no relation whatsoever to Indian culture. Therefore "Native American" is utterly ridiculous, as well. If there is to be a title, it's should be call 'The Iroquois in the Cupboard'. No matter, what it is, call. The movie and book is not racist. The movie and book is trying to show tolerance through it's metaphor for how ignorant people have subjugated and marginalized the Indian populations of America by refusing to understand, listen to, or accommodate Indian heritage. The film opens up, a lot of things that people rarely knew about Native Americans. The film starts with a young boy, Omri (Hal Scardino), receives a cupboard. He uses a "magical" key, which belonged to his great-grandmother, to bring a plastic 18th century Native American figurine to life with the cupboard. The now-living Iroquois reveals his name as Little Bear (Litefoot). Litefoot, a real rapper does a great job in teaching role, not only in teaching the child about Iroquois's culture, but also the morality of playing God. There is a Frankenstein feel to the film. My favorite line in the film "God does play with little men'. Author Lynne Reid Banks and Director Frank Oz did an excellent job conveying the worry and angst the young boy felt for for his little toy come to life. I appreciate how the author had the boy evolve from seeing the Indian as a plaything to realizing that, regardless of his size, the Indian was a person with needs, feelings, and a right to live his life. What struck me about it was not that it was racist, or dated (it didn't feel so as much as you'd think,) but that it is a deconstruction of the idea that magical toys would be fun to have, and possibly of imagination as well. Omri seem just the typical kid protagonist, kinda generic if you ask me. But I still think his acting was unintentionally funny. Just weird out with all the close ups on Omri's face, the odd relationship between him and Little Bear, the weird fears, and how he reacts to others. Examples when Omri's dad confronts him about the saw blades, and Omri says he buried them. Odd lying by him and his parent accept that lame excuse. What kid can cuss to his mom as well? What is with his relationship with brothers being super cool in the beginning of the film and then for no reason Omri turns into a complete jerk with him? The worst thing, the kid does is abuse an animal. That poor thing was abused through the whole film. Whether it was real or not, it was still animal abuse and shouldn't be shown in this movie. The treatment of that rat was appalling. Omri still wasn't nearly as annoying as his friend, Patrick. One minute he's Omri's best friend, and all docile and quiet, and then like a switch, he's evil and defiant with seeing them as nothing more than animated toys. He brings in Boone (David Keith), a bigot Injun hating cowboy whom at first conflict with Little Bear, but grows to be friends with him, once they got to know each other. One of the odd things about the film is scenes that go nowhere or has nothing to do with the story like the Mohawk bully. Another thing is the degrading of women in the film, from the kids watching Montley Crue 'Girls' music video (it's the 1990's, why were they watching it anyways?) to Bear demanding a wife so she can cook. I put aside my critiques and squelched my inner squirming and found much to like about the film. The special effects were top notch, and it was really neat to see Little Bear, Boone and Tommy (Steve Coogan) the medic brought to life on the screen. It was pretty cool to see the Star Wars, Jurrasic Park, G.I Joe, and Robo-Cop reference. The movie is pretty close to the book, minus little changes such as the toy shop. I laugh at the kid that loves JFK. While the movie isn't that bad, it's not going to hurt the kids watching it. I like it when I was a kid and still kinda do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Indian in the Cupboard (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Underrated and highly involving movie for kids. A young boy finds out that his cupboard has magical powers and can turn plastic into reality. He first turns a plastic Indian into a real human being. The movie teaches about responsibility but in an understandable way. It isn't patronizing nor childish, which means older audiences should relate to it also. It also mediates on life and death at certain points, and was the first film in a long time to be genuinely emotionally shocking. The relationship between the Indian and the cowboy was very well developed as they started to bond over their tragedies. The film does have a number of loose edges. Rishi Bhat was particularly annoying at times, but in a way he was necessary to play off Scardino. Even Scardino wasn't always a lovable protagonist. In one scene he kicks his brother's pet rat down the stairs, in an event where the rat clearly would have died. As the film hadn't relied on cartoon logic up until that point it was a bit out of place. Great effects, and seeing Darth Vader vs. a T-Rex kind of made up for those moments. A more innocent time when children's movies didn't have to be loud and crass.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Movie For Kids
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-english
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forget reviews saying this is not as good as the book. No films are are a good as the book! Watch this movie with an 8 year old child and you will see how good the film is. Thank you Frank Oz for a wonderful film. The acting from the young children is above average and the tearful ending just right for a young audience. Interesting to note Steve Coogan plays a miniature model come to life - something he repeats later in his career in A Night At The Museum. Typecasting? The effects are also very good. Remember this is 1995 when CGI was in it's infancy - but the miniaturisation of the cast is flawless.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An interesting film with childish and mature characters
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dean Richard Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Even though I rated this plucky movie a 4, it doesn't mean I hate it, my dear friends. I liked it but it doesn't have the stuff to make it to my higher favoritism of movies. Frank Oz is imaginative, but I have to say that this film to me is not so Frank Oz, and movies that are adapted from books are quite impressive, but I can only say I was slightly impressed. For one thing, the cast is inadequate, I never heard of David Keith and Litefoot. This story follows Omri, an extremely childish youngster who, for his birthday, receives a MAGICAL (ooh!) cupboard. The Cupboard lacks its key so Omri's mother (actress Lindsay Crouse, never heard of her), gives him her collection of keys, and guess what? He finds the certain key on his second try! That part always took me aback. He puts in an antique Iroquois figure in the cupboard, and later in the morning he opens it to find the figure alive as a small Iroquois man. The pair has many tedious adventures, some including an idiotic rat ball and a down-right scruffy cowboy who was a toy figure too. The cupboard MAGICALLY turns plastic (plaz-teck!) things into their real life counterparts, only smaller. The pair soon learns that every boy must become a man (a typical, yet true moral). Omri's character really is childish, yet endearing; his parents seem to pamper him, he's afraid of the dark, and he has lame 90's action figures; but he does mellow out in the end of the movie. I liked the acting, but it was no To Kill a Mocking Bird, even at moving parts. The Iroquois man was different from other Indian movies; he was a guru in a way. The music was just moderate and odd, though with one exception you'll know when you hear it. Be warned, my dear readers, this movie contains slight profanity (embarrassing really); simulative killing and some ladies do a loathsome dance on TV at one point (they call this a kid movie, how embarrassing. Let's hope Omri was sleeping at that adultish scene). And no the kid does not play God, its just a story, have fun. Other than the 3 points I pointed out, the movie is plucky and it has a rather moving ending. It's an poorish if okay movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Indian in the Cupboard
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    capone666
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Terrific! First we took their land, then we confined them to reserves, now we've forced Native Americans to live inside of our furniture. Fortunately, this kids' movie is not about constricting a Cree to a credenza  it's about an Iroquois. For his 9th birthday, Omri (Hal Scardino) receives a cupboard and a plastic Indian figurine (Litefoot). When he locks the statuette in the sideboard using a magic key, he opens to find that the toy has come to life. Next, he places a plastic cowboy (David Keith) into the cupboard. And later, he must animate a plastic medic (Steve Coogan); unfortunately, he has lost the key. Based on the beloved children's book, The Indian in the Cupboard may have its faults but at heart it's a compassionate account of growing up. However, wouldn't it be more enlightening for a maturing young man to bring his sister's Bratz dolls to life? (Yellow Light)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little surprised at the low rating...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gannont
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On this one, I am surprised that viewers are so critical as to miss the big picture of the magical moments and concepts of the movie. I agree, there are quite a few flaws overall, but some are just direction or editing oversights. However, this film deserves to be recognized as a really good family film as is. There are so many good "teaching moments" for parents regarding what kids go through growing up. The effects were well done for the time, playing the small vs. big people visuals. I was absorbed in the story well beyond picking on every detail. Omri was decent, not great, but believable as the kid star; the casting and scripting both for Little Bear are compelling, fascinating, and wonderful. I would recommend this film to almost anyone, if their reality can be suspended for 96 minutes. It is a great story, if only a good film. Entertaining and more gripping than many films since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Totally Boring, A Waste Of Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first read the book, The Indian in the Cupboard with my Reading Class when I was in sixth grade, and I enjoyed it. But then we decided to watch this movie, I really became excited because I thought that the movie was really going to be like the book. But when I saw it, I almost fell asleep, I thought that it was really boring! I thought that it was nothing like the book, I thought that it was totally boring, that you will want to fall asleep when you watch it. First off, the mistakes that they made with the movie. The movie was updated, instead of taking place in England, like it does in the book, it takes place in the United States, you can tell that it is New York because you can see the World Trade Center towers in one scene! Another big mistake was changing were Omri had gotten the characters from. He got some in the book by buying them at the store, in this movie, he got them by swapping them with some of his other toys at an Indian exhibit in school. You can go ahead and watch it if you please, but I sort of would not highly recommend it to you, because of the tedious arrangements they made with the plot. But if you want to watch it, go on and watch it, I am not going to stop you from doing it, though I did not like this movie. 4/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cowboys and Indians
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For his ninth birthday, slightly geeky but wholly appealing Hal Scardino (as Omri) receives cool wooden cupboard from his brother. There is no key to lock the cupboard, but mother Lindsay Crouse lets young Mr. Scardino try some stray keys from her collection. Happily, it turns out that Scardino's great-grandmother gifted a key to his mother, which perfectly fits the cupboard. Scardino locks up a Native American Indian toy figure, a "antique" gift from best friend Rishi Bhat (as Patrick), overnight. When he wakes up, Scardino discovers that Iroquois Litefoot (as Little Bear) has come to life, in miniature form, from the year 1761. The simple but effective special effects used throughout "The Indian in the Cupboard" have, surprisingly, made this film seem more natural looking than the special effects extravaganzas which blew it out of the theaters, back in the 1990s. Michael Lantieri, Eric Brevig, director Frank Oz, and their team make Scardino's little friends look very real. The story is based on a charming series of books by Lynne Reid Banks; the several sequels blunt the impact of the final door closing on the magical years of childhood, but the additional stories have no impact on this charming children's story. Grown-ups and some kids should see subtleties. ******* The Indian in the Cupboard (7/14/95) Frank Oz ~ Hal Scardino, Litefoot, Rishi Bhat, David Keith
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not entirely bad, but suffers from more than one significant flaw
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's sometimes nice to revisit movies from childhood, and that's just what I did with this one, an adaptation of the children's novel of the same name by Lynne Reid Banks. I think my first viewing of "The Indian in the Cupboard" was on the big screen, and then I saw it at school twice at two different times within the next few years. So, I saw this film twice during childhood, and a third time in my early adolescent years. Just yesterday, I rented it so I could see it again for the first time in nine years. By this time, I had seen its rating and number of votes here, so I could tell that it wasn't highly regarded as a family classic. For that reason, I did not have high expectations, and basically, this PG-rated family movie turned out to be a mixed blessing, which was probably the best I could hope for. When a young boy named Omri celebrates his ninth birthday, one of the presents he gets is a cupboard from his older brother, and another is a little plastic Indian figure from his friend. With both of these presents, he is in for a surprise. After placing the plastic figure in the cupboard, locking it up, and then opening it again, he sees that the figure, still the same size, has come to life! He soon learns that this is what happens when one places a figure in there, locks the door, and opens it again! That plastic figure has been replaced by a real 18th century Iroquois Indian named Little Bear, interrupted from his life and brought to Omri's room, where he is the size of an action figure! He agrees to stay for a while, but during his stay, he and the young modern-day boy are headed for adventure and conflict, and their cultural differences turn out to be one of their problems. One criticism of this movie I agree with is the acting, especially Hal Scardino's acting in the lead role of Omri. He wasn't the greatest child actor to ever make it to the silver screen, that's for sure. Another severe flaw in the film is sometimes the musical score. It tends to be pretty sappy, and really seems unreasonable at times, such as the music in the scene where Omri first sees Little Bear alive in the cupboard. More still, there's some very poor dialogue, and there also may be some humour here, but that also usually fails, with the likes of Boo-hoo Boone, a goofy cowboy who also comes from the cupboard. Now, not everything about this film is bad. Little Bear is a likable character, even if Litefoot doesn't do the greatest job playing him. I can't say I was completely bored throughout the entire film, as there were parts that intrigued me to a certain degree, but this did not hide the blatant flaws. I vaguely remember reading the book back in the late 90's, but can't remember it too well, so I don't know how it compares. However, it does seem to be more popular than this adaptation. This movie is one of those which was never one of my favourites as a kid, and I'm not sure exactly what I thought of it at the time, but I guess I liked it somewhat. During my last viewing, much later than the rest of them, I could definitely see more flaws in it than I used to (I don't think I used to see any real flaws in it at all). This 1995 adaptation of "The Indian in the Cupboard" does have a few redeeming features, but I'm sure they could have tried harder to make it really good family entertainment, and if only they had avoided the negative things I've pointed out, there would have been a good chance that they could have made it happen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
