<filme>
 <id>
  957
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0105652
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1992
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Arte de Viver
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  All the while, Master Chu tries to find his place in the foreign American world.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Master Chu, a retired Chinese Tai-Chi master, moves to Westchester, New York to live with his son Alex, his American daughter-in-law Martha, and their son Jeremy. However, Martha's second novel is suffering from severe writers' block brought on by Chu's presence in the house. Alex must struggle to keep his family together as he battles an inner conflict between cultural tradition and his modern American lifestlye.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   tai chi
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   immigration
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   family conflict
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   game of go
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   martial arts
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Ang Lee
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ang Lee
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   James Schamus
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Bo Z. Wang
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sihung Lung
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lai Wang
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Searching for a sense of belonging
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dy158
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It has been a month since Beijing-born Tai Chi master Chu has been living in the suburbs of New York City. But that has caused inconvenience to his American daughter-in-law Martha, who is a writer herself. She is having writer's block while working on her second novel, with the presence of her father-in-law doing his tai chi nearby. She had initially tried to tolerate his presence despite the language barrier between them, but it never stopped her on wanting to find a new home for the family which also includes her Chinese-born husband Alex and son Jeremy, but without the presence of her father-in-law. Chu would come to teach tai chi at a local community centre where he would also meet the cooking teacher Mrs. Chen who specialises in the teaching of making dumplings. There was the skirmishes as the tai chi class has to share their room with the cooking class as the cooking class had often being interrupted by what was going on nearby where one day, one of the students from Chu's tai chi class would knock over a plate of dumplings waiting to be steamed. Chu would come to feel bad about it, as he sets out to find a way to compensate Mrs. Chen. But before that, he would learn from her as they were having the remaining dumplings that she had been living in the United States with her daughter and her family for a year after her second husband has died not long after escaping China to Taiwan from the Cultural Revolution. But back home, the contrasting lifestyles and habits between Chu and Martha has come to put Alex on the spot. For Alex in between those times and beyond, it was relooking into his own family with the presence of his elderly father in the house who had briefly lost his way when having a walk in the street and how he himself would come to settle in the United States. As Chu would come to get along well with Mrs. Chen where the two would come to find themselves being stuck in the similar predicament over the lives their respective children have to come to get used to in the United States, there would be two defining moments for Chu and his family which would shape how Chu come to see his new life in the United States. Trying to tend to Martha who was having stomach pains before she would be admitted to the hospital for a few days and the decision to move out of his own accord before something happens to him at the Chinese restaurant where he worked which would alarm Alex and Martha. The cultural and lifestyle differences references in the film are there from almost the start, as exemplified in Chu and Martha. Chu is trying to cling on what he has always know before he left China to join his now-grown up son Alex in the United States through especially the tai chi he practices and the American daughter-in-law Martha who came from a very different set of upbringing, with both trying to get Alex's attention at the same time who tries to blend in both his American way of life while remembering the presence of his father in the house. There are the comical moments and the tender ones as well, especially on Chu telling Alex of what really happened to the family in Beijing at the height of the Cultural Revolution when Alex would be sent to live in the United States all on his own. It is a film which makes one think especially for those who are straddling in between two different cultures on when is the time to let go and the time to compromise, where the end result for either scenario is something both parties have to come to accept. Anyone who has been through what the Alex in the film has to go through will know the struggles of trying to bridge the past and the present together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Internal arts, lonely souls pushing hands
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Pushing hands' refers to an exercise in tai chi chuan, where lightly touching each other, two practitioners learn to yield to and redirect a shared flow of energy. Standardized by the Chinese government in the form of sports tournaments, 'pushing hands' is neither sport nor martial art, more reasonably it can be said to be the building block of tai chi chuan, in essence a Chinese form of boxing that uses Taoist principles of inter-connected balance of opposites, soft beats hard, emptiness in form. Nearly impossible to make sense of it in film, as is meditation and other internal Eastern arts, because simply showing it, or worse in the light of mystical ability, obscures what it really is about. Ang Lee however tries in his first film, with mixed results. Modeled to the story of an aging tai chi master who comes to America to stay with his son's family, there is what you'd expect from such a film; contrasts between two opposite ways of life, tradition versus modernity, love versus duty. All that is pretty ordinary, and some obvious drama and questionable acting brings it further down. To be fair, for a low-budget student film, Lee shows considerable talent with a camera. All told, I'd rather celebrate his success story than Tarantino's. But let's see something more interesting from the Chinese perspective. The overall point, is finding a still spot in imbalanced life that is constantly in motion, this is the old master's quest for a home and new life in a new country, somewhere to grow roots. This is the tao of balancing in the flow. Life back in China isn't presented as ideal, we find that the old man has been persecuted all his life, and that his taichi and calligraphy is the still spot he cultivates, his center in a moving universe of suffering. See how a phone ringing startles him from meditation, that is life that goes on. In line with tai chi principles, all this means 'hard' in several moments of real life conflict, versus 'soft' in inwards reflection. There is a love interest in Mrs. Chen (soft, as feminine yin to his yang) who's in a similar situation as the old man, and much gentle pushing and yielding to be close to her. So how beautiful, if we could have the film as cinematic 'pushing hands' between lonely souls? And carry the flow from heavy drama to soft inner life, to what these people do to cool and express their ardor, she in her cooking, he in his calligraphy. Kar Wai makes it work, not quite so here. Why is that? There's a scene of the old man watching videotapes of old Chinese kung fu movies, ridiculous from his perspective. The film is meant to offer next to other things a realistic depiction of his arts, fighting or otherwise, tied to realistic human connection as both soft. But there are scenes like with the fat boy or in the restaurant, that in the end are as ridiculous as in those movies, suddenly jerking us to fiction, obscuring what is vital in his art; and mirroring that, there's a sense of inflated drama in emotional moments. But Lee is too talented for us to be able to easily discard the whole work. The Western perspective, introduced later in the film by the son, is that his father's internal arts may be his way of shutting off the outside world, keeping from being touched perhaps related to the tragic loss of his wife. All through the film, we see that he likes Mrs. Chen but is reluctant to be close to her. Now watch again the last scene where he teaches tai chi in the Chinese community center, now the 'hero of Chinatown'. Watch how we first see him doing the motions, and then with a soft flow of the camera materializes behind him as though out of thin air, an entire class of students. And who enters as if by chance? Mrs. Chen. Now 'soft' is what we see of his heart, 'hard' what we imagine as taking place in his head. See how lightly the real and unreal touch, how smooth the parallel flow. So you can afford to miss the rest but not this last moment, it's expertly done and too delicious to ignore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A debut anyone would have been proud of
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ky_chong
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Pushing Hands" was Ang Lee's debut feature and it was made on a small budget soon after he won a national screenplay competition in Taiwan. The Taiwanese government financed part of it, but the movie is still constrained to some degree by its small budget, though the script (co-written with James Schamus) is well sketched out and extremely clever. Basically, the film looks into the conflict between the East and the West as a father from the Mainland China, Beijing (Sihung Lung) visits his son in the USA and ends up experiencing some friction with his Caucasian American daughter-in-law, a writer. Sihung Lung is first rate as the father, bringing gravitas and a certain humor and reserve as the misunderstood Taichi patriarch. The rest of the cast are also up to the mark. Since this movie is shot almost entirely from the point of view of the Chinese father, one can see how this film relates with several other Asian features which also examine father-children relationships (the most prominent being Ozu's "Tokyo Story"). The best that can be said about this debut feature is that it trumps its budget and becomes a sensitive, poignant and often wryly humorous portrait of an old man coming to terms with a foreign culture and his estranged immigrant son. Anyone making such a debut could justifiably be proud. As this movie is essentially small budget, don't expect the huge epic sweep of Lee's later films. This is an excellent and rewarding film, but only if you are patient enough. Unfortunately some non-Chinese may not be patient enough to sit through a family drama as this isn't your usual US$80 million American blockbuster. Its riches are far subtler than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful presentation and analysis of cultural differences
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about an elderly Chinese man moving to America to join his son and family. He faces adjustment problems due to cultural clash. The film is initially dull and boring. 7 minutes into the film and not one word is said! Though silence enhances the cultural rift between Mr Chu and Martha, the silence is probably too long. As the film progresses, more cultural differences are displayed. It is striking that during dinner, Martha and Jeremy uses forks to eat while Mr Chu and Alex uses chopsticks. Another striking scene is when Mr Chu and Mrs Chan talk in the community centre towards the end of the film, behind Mr Chu is an American flag while behind Mrs Chan it is a piece of Chinese calligraphy. Such subtle display of cultural differences is clever. The film is also heavy on Chinese traditional ideas, such as children taking care of parents as a natural duty, parents not wanting to burden children of their troubles etc. Such cultural ideas are beautifully explored. It is a pity that this film is shot with a very low budget. There are even three occasions that the boom mike is visible. Fortunately, such imperfections do not hinder my enjoyment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the shift within a man's life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yunlien Chiang (et_vous2000@yahoo.com.tw)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tuei Sho(Pushing Hands) is Ang Lee's first film after graduation, and the first episode of his "Triad of Father." In spite of its status as an early work, it manifests subtlety, elegance and articulation in narration style constantly seen in his latter works. Everyone, whether seen this film or not, can tell that it's about the bondage and gap of affection, relation and interaction within family, but it's more than that. It also tells about culture, not only the apparent differentiation, but the shift within a man's life, the time and the whole modern history of China. If you understand Chinese(language, culture and history), it is delicately overwhelming. If not, it's still amiable and a bit exotic. Tuei Sho is so worth viewing and contemplating again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Before there was Broke Back Mtn or Crouching Tiger, Ang Lee had a few things to learn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShippedCutOut
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to disagree with many of those who gave this film anything above a 5. Granted it was directed by Ang Lee in 1992, or long before The Hulk or Broke Back Mountain. But still, it looks too much like an earnest but not-too-skillful novice effort. The story does center around the old man newly arrived to Westchester after more than 70 years in China, taken in by his loving son and his almost stereotypical Anglo housewife (Martha), complete with her curly hair, her vegetarianism, her obsessive concern about her weight, her poor parenting skills, her disinterest in sex, her... Lots of clich&eacute;s on the feminine side, although to his credit, Lee does well with his main character-- except for making him a mysterious Kung Fu master (in this case Tai Chi). The opening scene seems interminable, as we watch Martha struggle at her (now seemingly primitive) computer, while Grand Father slowly does his Tai Chi exercises in an adjacent room. He knows no English, she knows no Chinese, so there is no dialog. We wonder, what's happening, where is this film going? Finally, slowly, the story unfolds, and we learn details about their respective lives. But this film may also set some sort of record for Most Visible Boom Mic. I swear it makes more on screen appearances than the couple's son (which is fortunate, because this kid is one of the worst child actors in memory). Yes, this is a story of generations, cultures, ambitions, etc.-- but there are many, better examples. Some scenes show promise, but as a whole, this film does not warrant more than a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lee's debut is competent but not good. The touching intergenerational - cross cultural story is marred by an uneven script, poor acting and shoddy production
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canoarmavirumque
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ang Lee's Pushing Hands is not a good movie. It offers a sometimes touching, sometimes humorous story about a retired Tai Chi master who comes to America from China to live with his son, his son's wife and their young boy. To its credit, the film serves up inter-generational, cross cultural tensions in a way that avoids seeming too clich&eacute; and too trite. Old people and young people are different. Dealing with the difference can be hard. This is the film's plain truth. There's nothing wrong with plain truth, and in some instances it can be refreshing. Unfortunately, the acting, the aimless direction, glaring production mistakes and - most importantly - an uneven screenplay prevent this truth from coming forward with the grace that much of the filmed Tai Chi has. Regarding the performances, all but the Tai Chi master, played by Shihung Lung, are fairly stiff. It's fortunate that the exception is the main character but lacking a strong supporting cast, the film is left uneven. The direction begins interestingly, with shots through windows becoming an early motif, but soon becomes pedestrian; any suggested meaning from interesting framing or mise en scene are lost. The glaring production problem was that on three occasions an overhead microphone was visible in the shots. I'm sure there's an old Chines proverb about this. But the main problem is that one character receives unsympathetic treatment by Lee's screenplay and direction: Martha, the white daughter-in-law to the Tai Chi master. She is written as a self-absorbed and even vicious woman. She's a writer who is shot pouting because she has to share her home with a kind hearted old man. As he seeks inner peace through martial arts, she only sees him as a disturbance to her peaceful home. Characters needn't be sympathetic, but it makes the movie too simple, as if were she nicer, the generational/cultural tensions would disappear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes small productions can give you quite a treat.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bobby Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sihung Lung, the actor who played Master Chu, the aging tai chi master, gave a very convincing and sincere performance in this film. It was no wonder that he won the Golden Horse (Taiwan's equivalent for the Oscars) for Best Actor in this film. His performance was extremely touching, as tears jerked into my eyes as I see an aging and traditional Chinese father trying to get along with his westernized family while also trying to adjust to life in a new place and culture. The film encourages people, especially new immigrants, to emphasize and put themselves in their parents' shoes. Try to understand how difficult it is for them to come and settle in a new place and try not to push them away. Be patient with them, take a step back and everything may be better. The movie title, "Pushing Hands", is very appropriate, as this is the term for an exercise in tai chi in which a person achieves balance by giving up balance. In this non-aggressive exercise between 2 people, a person offers no resistance at all to the pressure or push that the other person is exerting and keeps borrowing this strength until they feel they have fused into one and thus have achieved harmony. This was what Master Chu did. Although his daughter-in-law kept misunderstanding him, causing much discontent and eventually got his son to try to sent him away, he offered no resentment or a temper tantrum. He simply walked away gracefully. This action caused his son to appreciate him and remember why he got his father to live together in the first place in a tear jerking scene and finally they worked out a solution. They decided to give each other space by living separately instead of pushing each other away. In the end everyone was much happier, as even the daughter-in-law learned to accept the father, symbolized by her decorating the guest room for him and asking the question if he would ever visit. The father achieved the balance that he seek in Tai-Chi. Ang Li is simply amazing and sensational. He did what he could with the limited budget and created a very warm and tear jerking film. Although this film was not the highest quality (the version I saw was very unclear and skips sometimes) and it could feel slow at times, especially the beginning sequence, the film was a great work in directing. The film picked up its pace after the slow beginning without any big fighting scenes or explosions and never felt boring afterwards. Also, from the beginning sequence, where he was able to show the dissension and gap between the daughter-in-law and the father by using just different scenes and visuals, to scenes throughout the film where he used lighting and different camera angles to show the internal pain and sadness that the father experience, it was, simply put, a great piece of art considering the budget. It showcased the talent of Li and gave the audience a glimpse of the man who would bring us the memorable Couching Tiger, Hidden Dragon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film demonstrates that an important issue, the aging of one's parents, can be blended with comedy and kung-fu successfully!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bagua-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely have I seen the highest level of martial arts, internal kung-fu, portrayed in it's proper perspective. It is hard these days for people to realize that 'soft' style kung-fu will enable an old man to defeat many young men without much effort. With all the silly 'wire-fu' out there in the movies most people have no idea that there is a subtle way to defeat strength through 'chi energy' power lines. There is no question that Ang Lee has the ability to put kung-fu back at the top of the martial art world. Through his well thought out story line and his perfect blend of drama and comedy he has taken a deep look at the struggle that exists today for thousands of people as they care for their elderly parents. This is truly a movie that can bond many generations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding, Quiet and Personable Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mitch-38
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The adage of "Great things come in small packages" aptly applies to PUSHING HANDS/TUI SHOU. The film deftly tells its story with charm, humor and grace. A son's elderly father is the newest part of the family, and troubles therein lie. Essentially, it's a story of one family, yet could easily fit into many households. So many topics are breached, under the gentle, loving eye of the director (Ang Lee). The leads, the venerable Sihung Lung, Deb Snyder and Bo Z. Wang, do a credible job bringing this story to life. Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Searching for a sense of belonging
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dy158
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It has been a month since Beijing-born Tai Chi master Chu has been living in the suburbs of New York City. But that has caused inconvenience to his American daughter-in-law Martha, who is a writer herself. She is having writer's block while working on her second novel, with the presence of her father-in-law doing his tai chi nearby. She had initially tried to tolerate his presence despite the language barrier between them, but it never stopped her on wanting to find a new home for the family which also includes her Chinese-born husband Alex and son Jeremy, but without the presence of her father-in-law. Chu would come to teach tai chi at a local community centre where he would also meet the cooking teacher Mrs. Chen who specialises in the teaching of making dumplings. There was the skirmishes as the tai chi class has to share their room with the cooking class as the cooking class had often being interrupted by what was going on nearby where one day, one of the students from Chu's tai chi class would knock over a plate of dumplings waiting to be steamed. Chu would come to feel bad about it, as he sets out to find a way to compensate Mrs. Chen. But before that, he would learn from her as they were having the remaining dumplings that she had been living in the United States with her daughter and her family for a year after her second husband has died not long after escaping China to Taiwan from the Cultural Revolution. But back home, the contrasting lifestyles and habits between Chu and Martha has come to put Alex on the spot. For Alex in between those times and beyond, it was relooking into his own family with the presence of his elderly father in the house who had briefly lost his way when having a walk in the street and how he himself would come to settle in the United States. As Chu would come to get along well with Mrs. Chen where the two would come to find themselves being stuck in the similar predicament over the lives their respective children have to come to get used to in the United States, there would be two defining moments for Chu and his family which would shape how Chu come to see his new life in the United States. Trying to tend to Martha who was having stomach pains before she would be admitted to the hospital for a few days and the decision to move out of his own accord before something happens to him at the Chinese restaurant where he worked which would alarm Alex and Martha. The cultural and lifestyle differences references in the film are there from almost the start, as exemplified in Chu and Martha. Chu is trying to cling on what he has always know before he left China to join his now-grown up son Alex in the United States through especially the tai chi he practices and the American daughter-in-law Martha who came from a very different set of upbringing, with both trying to get Alex's attention at the same time who tries to blend in both his American way of life while remembering the presence of his father in the house. There are the comical moments and the tender ones as well, especially on Chu telling Alex of what really happened to the family in Beijing at the height of the Cultural Revolution when Alex would be sent to live in the United States all on his own. It is a film which makes one think especially for those who are straddling in between two different cultures on when is the time to let go and the time to compromise, where the end result for either scenario is something both parties have to come to accept. Anyone who has been through what the Alex in the film has to go through will know the struggles of trying to bridge the past and the present together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Internal arts, lonely souls pushing hands
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Pushing hands' refers to an exercise in tai chi chuan, where lightly touching each other, two practitioners learn to yield to and redirect a shared flow of energy. Standardized by the Chinese government in the form of sports tournaments, 'pushing hands' is neither sport nor martial art, more reasonably it can be said to be the building block of tai chi chuan, in essence a Chinese form of boxing that uses Taoist principles of inter-connected balance of opposites, soft beats hard, emptiness in form. Nearly impossible to make sense of it in film, as is meditation and other internal Eastern arts, because simply showing it, or worse in the light of mystical ability, obscures what it really is about. Ang Lee however tries in his first film, with mixed results. Modeled to the story of an aging tai chi master who comes to America to stay with his son's family, there is what you'd expect from such a film; contrasts between two opposite ways of life, tradition versus modernity, love versus duty. All that is pretty ordinary, and some obvious drama and questionable acting brings it further down. To be fair, for a low-budget student film, Lee shows considerable talent with a camera. All told, I'd rather celebrate his success story than Tarantino's. But let's see something more interesting from the Chinese perspective. The overall point, is finding a still spot in imbalanced life that is constantly in motion, this is the old master's quest for a home and new life in a new country, somewhere to grow roots. This is the tao of balancing in the flow. Life back in China isn't presented as ideal, we find that the old man has been persecuted all his life, and that his taichi and calligraphy is the still spot he cultivates, his center in a moving universe of suffering. See how a phone ringing startles him from meditation, that is life that goes on. In line with tai chi principles, all this means 'hard' in several moments of real life conflict, versus 'soft' in inwards reflection. There is a love interest in Mrs. Chen (soft, as feminine yin to his yang) who's in a similar situation as the old man, and much gentle pushing and yielding to be close to her. So how beautiful, if we could have the film as cinematic 'pushing hands' between lonely souls? And carry the flow from heavy drama to soft inner life, to what these people do to cool and express their ardor, she in her cooking, he in his calligraphy. Kar Wai makes it work, not quite so here. Why is that? There's a scene of the old man watching videotapes of old Chinese kung fu movies, ridiculous from his perspective. The film is meant to offer next to other things a realistic depiction of his arts, fighting or otherwise, tied to realistic human connection as both soft. But there are scenes like with the fat boy or in the restaurant, that in the end are as ridiculous as in those movies, suddenly jerking us to fiction, obscuring what is vital in his art; and mirroring that, there's a sense of inflated drama in emotional moments. But Lee is too talented for us to be able to easily discard the whole work. The Western perspective, introduced later in the film by the son, is that his father's internal arts may be his way of shutting off the outside world, keeping from being touched perhaps related to the tragic loss of his wife. All through the film, we see that he likes Mrs. Chen but is reluctant to be close to her. Now watch again the last scene where he teaches tai chi in the Chinese community center, now the 'hero of Chinatown'. Watch how we first see him doing the motions, and then with a soft flow of the camera materializes behind him as though out of thin air, an entire class of students. And who enters as if by chance? Mrs. Chen. Now 'soft' is what we see of his heart, 'hard' what we imagine as taking place in his head. See how lightly the real and unreal touch, how smooth the parallel flow. So you can afford to miss the rest but not this last moment, it's expertly done and too delicious to ignore.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A debut anyone would have been proud of
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ky_chong
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Pushing Hands" was Ang Lee's debut feature and it was made on a small budget soon after he won a national screenplay competition in Taiwan. The Taiwanese government financed part of it, but the movie is still constrained to some degree by its small budget, though the script (co-written with James Schamus) is well sketched out and extremely clever. Basically, the film looks into the conflict between the East and the West as a father from the Mainland China, Beijing (Sihung Lung) visits his son in the USA and ends up experiencing some friction with his Caucasian American daughter-in-law, a writer. Sihung Lung is first rate as the father, bringing gravitas and a certain humor and reserve as the misunderstood Taichi patriarch. The rest of the cast are also up to the mark. Since this movie is shot almost entirely from the point of view of the Chinese father, one can see how this film relates with several other Asian features which also examine father-children relationships (the most prominent being Ozu's "Tokyo Story"). The best that can be said about this debut feature is that it trumps its budget and becomes a sensitive, poignant and often wryly humorous portrait of an old man coming to terms with a foreign culture and his estranged immigrant son. Anyone making such a debut could justifiably be proud. As this movie is essentially small budget, don't expect the huge epic sweep of Lee's later films. This is an excellent and rewarding film, but only if you are patient enough. Unfortunately some non-Chinese may not be patient enough to sit through a family drama as this isn't your usual US$80 million American blockbuster. Its riches are far subtler than that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautiful presentation and analysis of cultural differences
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about an elderly Chinese man moving to America to join his son and family. He faces adjustment problems due to cultural clash. The film is initially dull and boring. 7 minutes into the film and not one word is said! Though silence enhances the cultural rift between Mr Chu and Martha, the silence is probably too long. As the film progresses, more cultural differences are displayed. It is striking that during dinner, Martha and Jeremy uses forks to eat while Mr Chu and Alex uses chopsticks. Another striking scene is when Mr Chu and Mrs Chan talk in the community centre towards the end of the film, behind Mr Chu is an American flag while behind Mrs Chan it is a piece of Chinese calligraphy. Such subtle display of cultural differences is clever. The film is also heavy on Chinese traditional ideas, such as children taking care of parents as a natural duty, parents not wanting to burden children of their troubles etc. Such cultural ideas are beautifully explored. It is a pity that this film is shot with a very low budget. There are even three occasions that the boom mike is visible. Fortunately, such imperfections do not hinder my enjoyment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the shift within a man's life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Yunlien Chiang (et_vous2000@yahoo.com.tw)
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tuei Sho(Pushing Hands) is Ang Lee's first film after graduation, and the first episode of his "Triad of Father." In spite of its status as an early work, it manifests subtlety, elegance and articulation in narration style constantly seen in his latter works. Everyone, whether seen this film or not, can tell that it's about the bondage and gap of affection, relation and interaction within family, but it's more than that. It also tells about culture, not only the apparent differentiation, but the shift within a man's life, the time and the whole modern history of China. If you understand Chinese(language, culture and history), it is delicately overwhelming. If not, it's still amiable and a bit exotic. Tuei Sho is so worth viewing and contemplating again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Before there was Broke Back Mtn or Crouching Tiger, Ang Lee had a few things to learn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShippedCutOut
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have to disagree with many of those who gave this film anything above a 5. Granted it was directed by Ang Lee in 1992, or long before The Hulk or Broke Back Mountain. But still, it looks too much like an earnest but not-too-skillful novice effort. The story does center around the old man newly arrived to Westchester after more than 70 years in China, taken in by his loving son and his almost stereotypical Anglo housewife (Martha), complete with her curly hair, her vegetarianism, her obsessive concern about her weight, her poor parenting skills, her disinterest in sex, her... Lots of clich&eacute;s on the feminine side, although to his credit, Lee does well with his main character-- except for making him a mysterious Kung Fu master (in this case Tai Chi). The opening scene seems interminable, as we watch Martha struggle at her (now seemingly primitive) computer, while Grand Father slowly does his Tai Chi exercises in an adjacent room. He knows no English, she knows no Chinese, so there is no dialog. We wonder, what's happening, where is this film going? Finally, slowly, the story unfolds, and we learn details about their respective lives. But this film may also set some sort of record for Most Visible Boom Mic. I swear it makes more on screen appearances than the couple's son (which is fortunate, because this kid is one of the worst child actors in memory). Yes, this is a story of generations, cultures, ambitions, etc.-- but there are many, better examples. Some scenes show promise, but as a whole, this film does not warrant more than a 5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lee's debut is competent but not good. The touching intergenerational - cross cultural story is marred by an uneven script, poor acting and shoddy production
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    canoarmavirumque
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ang Lee's Pushing Hands is not a good movie. It offers a sometimes touching, sometimes humorous story about a retired Tai Chi master who comes to America from China to live with his son, his son's wife and their young boy. To its credit, the film serves up inter-generational, cross cultural tensions in a way that avoids seeming too clich&eacute; and too trite. Old people and young people are different. Dealing with the difference can be hard. This is the film's plain truth. There's nothing wrong with plain truth, and in some instances it can be refreshing. Unfortunately, the acting, the aimless direction, glaring production mistakes and - most importantly - an uneven screenplay prevent this truth from coming forward with the grace that much of the filmed Tai Chi has. Regarding the performances, all but the Tai Chi master, played by Shihung Lung, are fairly stiff. It's fortunate that the exception is the main character but lacking a strong supporting cast, the film is left uneven. The direction begins interestingly, with shots through windows becoming an early motif, but soon becomes pedestrian; any suggested meaning from interesting framing or mise en scene are lost. The glaring production problem was that on three occasions an overhead microphone was visible in the shots. I'm sure there's an old Chines proverb about this. But the main problem is that one character receives unsympathetic treatment by Lee's screenplay and direction: Martha, the white daughter-in-law to the Tai Chi master. She is written as a self-absorbed and even vicious woman. She's a writer who is shot pouting because she has to share her home with a kind hearted old man. As he seeks inner peace through martial arts, she only sees him as a disturbance to her peaceful home. Characters needn't be sympathetic, but it makes the movie too simple, as if were she nicer, the generational/cultural tensions would disappear.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes small productions can give you quite a treat.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bobby Bob
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sihung Lung, the actor who played Master Chu, the aging tai chi master, gave a very convincing and sincere performance in this film. It was no wonder that he won the Golden Horse (Taiwan's equivalent for the Oscars) for Best Actor in this film. His performance was extremely touching, as tears jerked into my eyes as I see an aging and traditional Chinese father trying to get along with his westernized family while also trying to adjust to life in a new place and culture. The film encourages people, especially new immigrants, to emphasize and put themselves in their parents' shoes. Try to understand how difficult it is for them to come and settle in a new place and try not to push them away. Be patient with them, take a step back and everything may be better. The movie title, "Pushing Hands", is very appropriate, as this is the term for an exercise in tai chi in which a person achieves balance by giving up balance. In this non-aggressive exercise between 2 people, a person offers no resistance at all to the pressure or push that the other person is exerting and keeps borrowing this strength until they feel they have fused into one and thus have achieved harmony. This was what Master Chu did. Although his daughter-in-law kept misunderstanding him, causing much discontent and eventually got his son to try to sent him away, he offered no resentment or a temper tantrum. He simply walked away gracefully. This action caused his son to appreciate him and remember why he got his father to live together in the first place in a tear jerking scene and finally they worked out a solution. They decided to give each other space by living separately instead of pushing each other away. In the end everyone was much happier, as even the daughter-in-law learned to accept the father, symbolized by her decorating the guest room for him and asking the question if he would ever visit. The father achieved the balance that he seek in Tai-Chi. Ang Li is simply amazing and sensational. He did what he could with the limited budget and created a very warm and tear jerking film. Although this film was not the highest quality (the version I saw was very unclear and skips sometimes) and it could feel slow at times, especially the beginning sequence, the film was a great work in directing. The film picked up its pace after the slow beginning without any big fighting scenes or explosions and never felt boring afterwards. Also, from the beginning sequence, where he was able to show the dissension and gap between the daughter-in-law and the father by using just different scenes and visuals, to scenes throughout the film where he used lighting and different camera angles to show the internal pain and sadness that the father experience, it was, simply put, a great piece of art considering the budget. It showcased the talent of Li and gave the audience a glimpse of the man who would bring us the memorable Couching Tiger, Hidden Dragon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film demonstrates that an important issue, the aging of one's parents, can be blended with comedy and kung-fu successfully!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bagua-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely have I seen the highest level of martial arts, internal kung-fu, portrayed in it's proper perspective. It is hard these days for people to realize that 'soft' style kung-fu will enable an old man to defeat many young men without much effort. With all the silly 'wire-fu' out there in the movies most people have no idea that there is a subtle way to defeat strength through 'chi energy' power lines. There is no question that Ang Lee has the ability to put kung-fu back at the top of the martial art world. Through his well thought out story line and his perfect blend of drama and comedy he has taken a deep look at the struggle that exists today for thousands of people as they care for their elderly parents. This is truly a movie that can bond many generations.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding, Quiet and Personable Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mitch-38
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The adage of "Great things come in small packages" aptly applies to PUSHING HANDS/TUI SHOU. The film deftly tells its story with charm, humor and grace. A son's elderly father is the newest part of the family, and troubles therein lie. Essentially, it's a story of one family, yet could easily fit into many households. So many topics are breached, under the gentle, loving eye of the director (Ang Lee). The leads, the venerable Sihung Lung, Deb Snyder and Bo Z. Wang, do a credible job bringing this story to life. Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
