<filme>
 <id>
  965
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0050419
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1957
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Cinderela em Paris
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An impromptu fashion shoot at a book store brings about a new fashion model discovery in the shop clerk.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Fashion photographer Dick Avery, in search for an intellectual backdrop for an air-headed model, expropriates a Greenwich Village bookstore. When the photo session is over the store is left in a shambles, much to salesgirl Jo Stockton's dismay. Avery stays behind to help her clean up. Later, he examines the photos taken there and sees Jo in the background of one shot. He is intrigued by her unique appearance, as is Maggie Prescott, the editor of a leading fashion magazine. They offer Jo a modeling contract, which she reluctantly accepts only because it includes a trip to Paris. Eventually, her snobbish attitude toward the job softens, and Jo begins to enjoy the work and the company of her handsome photographer.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Musical
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   fashion
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   photographer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fashion magazine
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   model
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   magazine
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Stanley Donen
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Leonard Gershe
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Audrey Hepburn
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Fred Astaire
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kay Thompson
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey is able to turn it, if not into gold, at least into silver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a stage musical entitled "Funny Face", written by&nbsp;George&nbsp;and&nbsp;Ira Gershwin in 1927, but it has a totally different plot to that of the film, although several of its songs are included. Jo Stockton, an assistant in a Greenwich Village&nbsp;bookshop, is discovered as a fashion model by Maggie Prescott, the editor of a prestigious fashion magazine, and&nbsp;Dick Avery, a famous fashion photographer. Jo, however, is something of an amateur intellectual, has a low opinion of the fashion industry and only goes along with Maggie and Dick's plans because they offer her an assignment in Paris, a city she has always wanted to visit because her greatest ambition is to meet the great philosopher&nbsp;Professor Emile Flostre, founder of the doctrine of empathicalism. (Flostre was clearly based upon Jean-Paul Sartre and his doctrine of existentialism). A romance grows up between Jo and Dick in Paris, but Dick finds he has a rival for her affections in the form of the professor, younger and better-looking than his real-life counterpart but no less lecherous. The film was a box-office flop when first released in 1957; it only made a profit when it was re-released seven years later following the huge success of&nbsp;Audrey Hepburn's only other musical, "My Fair Lady". It upset the film critic of "The Times" (aka The Thunderer) who thundered, "There is that in the film's attitude towards the "intellectual", whether in Greenwich Village or Paris, which offends. It is not amiable parody and it is not telling satire; it has its roots in the ill-based instinct to jeer, and its jeers are offensive." When we consider that these words were directed towards a light, frothy musical comedy, this looks like is a particularly po-faced example of a critic taking himself too seriously (although criticisms of the film's supposed "anti-intellectualism" still surface). The film's main target was not intellectuals but hypocrites (although it also sends up some of the inanities of the fashion industry). The point about Flostre is that he does not practise what he preaches; "empathicalism" is supposed to be all about putting oneself in the other person's shoes, but in his dealings with Jo he is only capable of thinking about himself. For all her book-learning, Jo's initial attitude towards Flostre is one of uncritical idol-worship and she still has to learn the important lesson that idols can have feet of clay. The "funny face" of the title is Jo herself, and the implication of the words of the title song is that, although she is not very attractive, Dick still loves her because she has got so much character and personality. So why, then, was, the Divine Audrey, the most luminously beautiful actress of her generation, cast in the role? Was this simply a piece of miscasting? The answer to that question is an emphatic "no". There are a few things wrong with the film, but Audrey is not one of them. The main mistake is the miscasting of the fifty-eight year-old Fred Astaire as the male lead. Although he shows that his advancing years have done little to diminish his dancing skills, away from the dance-floor he looks embarrassingly out-of-place as the lover of the twenty-eight year-old Audrey. Sometimes the teaming of Audrey with an older man paid off, as with Bogart in "Sabrina", but this is one case where it didn't. For all his faults I was rooting for Jo to end up with Flostre rather than Dick. The music is tuneful but not particularly memorable, apart from two songs, "'S Wonderful" and the title song, and the plot is a&nbsp;fairly banal one. There is, however, a good performance from Kay Thompson as the&nbsp;autocratic Maggie. (I wonder if this was the inspiration for Meryl Streep's portrayal of a similar character in "The Devil Wears Prada"). This was Thompson's only film appearance; she was best known in her day as a singer and musician and is best remembered today as a children's author. The dance numbers are well choreographed and the visual look of the film is an attractive one. The film's biggest plus, however, is the presence of Audrey Hepburn. She was one of those rare actresses with true star quality, by which I mean the ability to take any film and make it quite different from what it would have been with anyone else in the leading role. Few will be surprised that Audrey was a great dancer- she did, after all, train as a ballerina- but those who know the story of how she was not allowed to do her own singing in "My Fair Lady" will be surprised by&nbsp;what a melodious voice she had. (Certainly better than Astaire's). Her main contribution here, however, is neither her singing nor her dancing but simply the force of her personality. "Funny Face" is not a great film; it is in nothing like the same class as "My Fair Lady" or its director Stanley Donen's masterpiece "Singin' in the Rain". (Mind you, Donen seemed to spend most of the rest of his career trying to repeat the success of that great film without ever really pulling it off). It could have been a pretty dull musical, but Audrey transforms it into something memorable. Unlike King Midas she couldn't quite manage to turn everything she touched into gold. "Paris When It Sizzles" and "Two for the Road", for example, obstinately remain base metal despite her presence. "Funny Face" might not be pure gold, however, but at least Audrey is able to turn it into silver. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad, but I have seen so much better.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FUNNY FACE It was OK... but I was expecting more. I quite like musicals and when I heard that this one had Audrey Hepburn and Fred Astaire in it I thought it would be really good. The story is OK... it is about a fashion magazine photographer who finds a new model in the form of a book shop assistant. She doesn't want to be a model, but has always wanted to go to Paris to meet a philosopher. When she finds out that to be a model she has to go to Paris, she accepts. Then the photographer falls in love with her. The acting is not very good... but like I have mentioned in previous reviews, the acting is not very good in most musicals... but I like that. It makes the films more fun. Audrey and Fred both do good jobs though... they are both really good at singing and dancing which is what is needed for a musical. The film also stars Kay Thomson. I didn't feel like the songs were very good in this film. The thing I like about musicals is the songs need to be catchy and fun... Not one of the songs in this stuck in my head. I didn't feel like tapping my foot to any of them, but there was some very interesting dancing... especially from Audrey when she starts dancing in a pub. I don't know if I can call that dancing. haha. I will give this film 5 out of 10. It was quite good, but I was slightly disappointed. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Think Pink? Not in the Eisenhower-Nixon Years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dglink
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Splashy colors, Paris locations, Fred Astaire's dancing, Audrey Hepburn's pixie-ish charm, Stanley Donen's direction, and George Gershwin's music should have melded into an enduring musical classic in 1957's "Funny Face." However, the talented individuals involved produced a dated, clumsy film with but a few bright moments. Poor tweedy philosophizing shop girl is transformed into an elegant stylish fashion model, a "My Fair Lady" wannabe. While Audrey Hepburn is never convincing as a mousy clerk garbed in shades of drab, she comes alive in designer clothes, and, quicker than you can say "Givenchy," the character swaps her principles for a haircut and makeover, a walk down the runway, and a trip to Paris. Hepburn was often paired with older men in her films; however, Cary Grant, William Holden, and Gary Cooper had enough masculine sex appeal to be convincing love interest for a young woman. Fred Astaire, however, was never romantic material, even for those of his own age. In "Funny Face," Astaire in his late 50's is about 20 years older than Hepburn and looks it; oddly, neither the age difference nor Astaire's reason for advanced bachelorhood is ever remarked upon or mentioned in the script. Leonard Gershe's screenplay for "Funny Face" is planted firmly in the Eisenhower 1950's. Astaire's chauvinistic attitude, "the man asks the woman to dance," is archaic and would have been poison to a free-thinking young woman like Hepburn's Jo Stockton. Kay Thompson's magazine editor is a post-World War II stereotype of the working woman: unmarried, hard, bossy, mannish, and abrasive. Only in mid-20th-century America would a harem of lemming-like "yes-women" blindly follow Thompson and mindlessly praise her every mundane uttering. Further undermining the film's credibility, the supposed pictorial output of Dick Avery, a successful fashion photographer, and Maggie Prescott, editor of "Quality" magazine, is limp at best; Avery's photos are mediocre, and Prescott's earth-shattering idea is "think pink." As always, Fred Astaire's dancing is worth watching, and, although her singing is more flat than melodic and her dancing mixed, Hepburn is always a winning charmer. However, under Donen's direction, the film does not soar, but rather lumbers from clumsy number to embarrassing parody; bearded beatniks, soul-searching laments, Parisian dives, empathetic philosophers, and even fashion magazines seem so last century. "Funny Face" may be worth a view as a mid-20th-century curiosity piece, but otherwise the film is most suitable as source material to excerpt scenes for documentaries on Astaire and Hepburn. Most viewers will have to think pink to plod through "Funny Face."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some great ideas that get cobbled together with uneven direction...but the best is the best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny Face (1957) I was prepared to love this movie and it let me down even though it has two fabulous leads, the classic musical dance man Fred Astaire and the new star Audrey Hepburn. It even has its photography based on the work of Richard Avedon, and Astaire's character is based on him in his fashion work. I enjoyed it, but it depends too much on common formulas, which I normally don't mind, and it lacks cohesion, flow, and what you might just call magic. That it's partly shot in New York and then Paris (a famously rainy Paris during the shoot) you would think you could hardly go wrong. And in a way it doesn't go wrong overall. But the plot lacks energy, the romantic chemistry is missing (the two are really more like father and daughter), and the series of dance numbers is choppy and uneven. Because of all this, each song goes on too long and you itch for the next scene, and then that scene merely takes us back to the weak plot. If you focus on these weaknesses the movie starts to look almost terrible. Hepburn's transformation from a tweedy intellectual in a bookshop in Manhattan to the premiere runway in Paris sounds like dream come true stuff, but it isn't really convincing (or surprising, of course). The French counter-culture intellectual scene is fun idea but it doesn't push it very far, and the leading voice is played by an actor with no presence at all. Hepburn's interactions in this whole world are forced. Even the opening twenty minutes, which sets the tone, is rough sledding before out two leading actors appear. But focus on the strengths and there are some great moments. Like the series of photo shoots, one after another quickly spreading across the highlights of the city, is fun and stylish. A few of the dance numbers, though short of classic, are great fun, like the modern one in the French smokey bar and the one in the darkroom with the safelights on. In both of these, again, director Stanley Donen (a consummate pro at this stuff) let things drag on just a minute too long, which is a long time in a fast moving movie like this. Then there is Fred Astaire, at ease and warm and really wonderful. He doesn't get a chance to quite blow the doors off any of the dances, but he's still a joy to watch, dancing or just being his warm self. (He was initially a reluctant actor at this point in his life, but was still very active. For a sense of his truer self, perhaps, behind the scenes, see "On the Beach" two years later.) Then there is Audrey Hepburn, by now a stellar and unique star trying to spread her wings into musicals (this was her first). She, as usual in her career, rose above her part and like Astaire was "herself" with such charm she keeps even weaker scenes going. When she's in them, which luckily she is in most of them by the second half. Hepburn also comes across as a superb model (appropriately thin, but not especially tall), and Avedon's photographs of her taken in conjunction with filming are iconic. They get incorporated into the movie directly, both in the scenes where Astaire creates some photos in his role, and in some of the cinematography which imitates Avedon's style (white backdrops, modern styling). In the end it's a great seeming movie with such huge flaws it's just another musical. But that's not fair, quite, so think of it as an up and down ride with some very very fine high points which make it worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable in spire of its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Funny Face" is a far from perfect film. But, considering that it stars Fred Astaire, it's still well worth watching. Anything with Astaire is worth watching! The film begins with an odd montage in which the audience is introduced to Maggie Prescott (Kay Thompson)--a wonderfully annoying lady who is THE expert on fashion. It seems she is out to find a new model with a new look and her photographer (Astaire) notices a lady that Maggie completely overlooked--cute little Jo, the girl at the bookstore (Audrey Hepburn). Jo is then signed with a big contract and goes to Paris for photo shoots and to make her a mega-star. In the process, she and her photographer fall in love. But, minor complications arise and it might just mean the two will go their separate ways. First, the good. A few of the songs are very nice and the film stars Astaire and Hepburn. It also has really lovely footage of Paris. If you've been to this city (like I have), it's a wonderful walk down memory lane and the city really is that beautiful. Now the not so good. The biggest problem is that Astaire is easily old enough to be Audrey's father--and I am sure that many in the audience must have thought that. Thirty years' difference is a lot. Also, while some of the songs were nice (particularly the Gershwin ones), a few of the numbers were pretty bad--such as the Florida song and dance number. Overall, the good does outweigh the bad and I suggest you see it. It's just that both stars did far better work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now we know what the word empathy means
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dimitri44
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a motion picture where Audrey Hepburn stunningly empathizes with the audience as well, more and more, all the way through to the very end of the movie. The lighthearted story line begins with high brow Audrey Hepburn employed as manager of an intellectual type bookstore in Greenwich Village, NYC, and her dream is to go to Paris where she can then attend lectures offered by someone who is said to be a Professor of Empathy. Meanwhile, Fred Astaire, a fashion photographer, also has the opportunity to implore Audrey Hepburn to empathize with his photographic work as well, which then leads to her being provided with free passage to Paris, as she also then becomes a great fashion model in turn. Towards the end, the Professor of Empathy turns out to be quite a bit younger than thought, and with Audrey, his idea of empathy turns out to be something unexpectedly more basic than also thought. Thus, Fred and Audrey certainly empathize with each other in a most dignified way in the end. Yes, in 1957, movies were generally quite a bit more dignified as well. Postscript: I recently bought the Paramount Home Entertainment (UK) DVD version of this movie, and I watched it carefully more than once. I now believe this is the best motion picture that Audrey Hepburn made. It's almost even as though George and Ira Gershwin, even from the hereafter, were waiting for Audrey Hepburn, and then she came.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Astaire makes this musical semi-watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dani-marie
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One would assume that combining the talents of director Stanley Donen, Fred Astaire, and Audrey Hepburn would produce one knockout of a film. The turnout is anything but. From the get go the film left me both disinterested and unimpressed, even as an avid fan of musicals. The only savior of the film was Fred Astaire, who makes the most of each lackluster song and dance. He also holds the only slightly intriguing character and dialogue, standing out from the remaining wreckage of the film, which is mostly fluff without entertainment. The film begins with "Think Pink", an off the wall number which holds zero place in the plot. Donen effectively demonstrates the coldness of Quality magazine and the fashion industry itself through Kay Thompson's character, while the mostly sarcastic and charming dialogue of Astaire's character contribute to the message. The wit in Astaire's dialogue is the writers' only vehicle to humor. Once Hepburn is introduced, her soft face is the only saving grace of her character. The writers have managed to create a leading lady without charm. In short: the writers create a stereotypical facade of an intellectual woman, further cheapening the plot. Hepburn's other musical roles feature her voice dubbed, which might have been the proper choice for this film. Not once does she seem fully immersed in the character or film. However, what could she have done with less than adequate material and a flat character to work with? Chemistry between Audrey and Fred would have helped tons. Despite thoughts in another reviews, age differences do not factor into any type of chemistry. Check out Gene Kelly and Leslie Caron in An American in Paris or Audrey and Cary Grant in Charade in which large age gaps do not get in the way of emotion between the actors. The production design and cinematography are small beauties, but do little to improve the soppy, one dimensional plot. As the plot progresses, our two leads inevitably fall in love (it is not evident of course) and one forgettable song after another only left me waiting for the film to improve. Instead of being amazed by the performers, I only wanted the song to end. Again, Astaire is the only performer that delivers, even through drab choreography. He is the only actor that infuses some form of charm and enthusiasm into both the songs and dances. By the end of the film, all you are left with is Paris eye candy and a flat, uninteresting script. And maybe a little Astaire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fred Snaps! Audrey Crackles! Kay Pops!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This original musical comedy is not based upon the 1927 Broadway Gershwin musical that starred Fred and Adele Astaire on the stage. It has been updated to the 1950's Greenwich Village where photographer Astaire and his merry models take over Audrey Hepburn's book store (long before some computer devise ran most bookstores out of business), leaving her with a huge mess to clean up. Realizing his error, Astaire helps her, and realizes, he too can make her a model. This is sort of a "My Fair Lady"/"Pygmallion" of the modeling industry, with Astaire playing Henry Higgins to Audrey's pre-"My Fair Lady" Eliza. Along with magazine editor Kay Thompson, the trio goes to Paris where Astaire and Rogers fall in love, she checks out the Latin Quarter, and the duo literally skate off into the sunset on a lily pad meant for two. Some people question the pairing of Astaire and Hepburn, citing their almost 30 year age difference as a major problem. I concur that Astaire was way too young for Leslie Caron in the entertaining but overlong "Daddy Long Legs", but his style fits much better with Audrey. Yes, the age difference is quite noticeable, but I don't get that creepy feeling here that I did with the waif-like Caron. Unlike "My Fair Lady", you get to hear Audrey sing here, and her voice fits her character. When she sings "How Long Has This Been Going On?", you really feel for her. Ironically, when Ms. Hepburn passed away, it was this song that helped me celebrate her life, not "Moon River" (which she also sings in "Breakfast at Tiffany's") or her dubbed songs in "My Fair Lady". Seeing this years ago on a double bill at the Castro Theatre with "Breakfast at Tiffany's", I was amused by the audience's reaction to various un-"P.C." remarks, particularly Astaire's rather sexist remark that in a relationship, it is the man who makes the decisions. But irregardless of that, this is still one of the loveliest musicals of the 1950's, and try not to think "music video" when Kay Thompson (all in beige) pops up with her models to sing "Think Pink", which by the way, she wouldn't be caught dead in. Then, in a dark room, Astaire sings the title song to Hepburn, appropriately lit for the song. In Paris, the trio sings (separately) the lively "Bonjour Paris!" which has many great visuals of the city of lights. This is an example of real art deco in movies way past the age of Paramount's classy romantic comedies and musicals. Astaire and Thompson get to become "hip" in an opium den when they break into "Clap Yo' Hands", one of the liveliest 1920's songs still being sung 90 years later. Acting wise, Thompson steals the show, playing a character that "Boosom Buddies"/"Two & a Half Men" supporting player Holland Taylor cut her teeth on. Stanley Donen, a veteran dancer and musical film director, turns a rather ordinary May/December romance into something special that remains as fresh today as it was 55 years ago.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Paris mis-match
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Colourful Stanley Donen movie featuring wonderful Parisian locations and the superb music of the Gershwin brothers...and that's about it. I believe this may have been Fred Astaire's last movie as the romantic lead and on the evidence here, it's easy to see why. His performance is utterly devoid of any passion or even discernible attraction to the young Audrey Hepburn, plus for once his solo dance routines seem just that, routine and while still danced consummately, somehow lacking in dynamism or invention. Hepburn gets a dream ticket herself, decked out in a succession of high-fashion costumes and even getting to sing and dance with the great man, without ever convincing the viewer that she's a natural in either discipline. Otherwise, she gets to mope and loon by turn, pretty much the two main attributes of her acting ability. Her dancing is passable at best, while her solo routine improvising to modern jazz in a smoky West Bank bar is toe-curlingly embarrassing. And we all know, I'm sure that neither of them could be considered outstanding singers and hearing Audrey's not-so-dulcet tones, one can easily see why she was overdubbed (against her wishes) in "My Fair Lady". The story has less substance than the fog over the Seine and hits a lowpoint near the end when an unlikely fellow-suitor emerges to contest Audrey's fair hand, her hero-philosopher who's much better-looking, not to mention much cleverer than old Fred. Yes it's the old why-would-she-fall-for-him conundrum that not unnaturally bedevilled the ageing Astaire's later films, but it's exaggerated even more here when contrasted with the ever-youthful looking Hepburn. The plot seeks to cash in and poke fun at Paris's post-war reputation for fashion and philosophy and certainly the settings, particularly the exteriors are luminously warm, but the humour is forced at best and lacking finesse. Director Donen employs some tricksy cinematography to mixed effect as he strains for modernity, but in the final analysis, like the pairing of the old Astaire with the young Hepburn, the marriage of traditional Hollywood musical characteristics with modern film-making ideas just clashes and doesn't come off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sumptuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-406-125589
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps the most exquisitely art-directed musical of them all, "Funny Face" is sheer delight. Forget the story (for the most part) and enjoy the remarkable Astaire-Hepburn-Thompson magic, the glorious Avedon titles and stills and the breathtaking cinematography. "Think Pink," "Bonjour Paris," "He Loves and She Loves" and many of the other numbers will transport you. It's very much a time capsule -- attitudes toward women are wince-worthy, the sneering at existentialism can be tiresome. The sophistication of the music -- a blend of Gershwin classics with three new songs by Roger Edens -- the dancing, the performances and, most of all, the physical production, more than compensate. Btw, the Edens songs provide some of the films best moments -- "Bonjour Paris, On How to Be Lovely" and the sly, stunning "Think Pink."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey is able to turn it, if not into gold, at least into silver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a stage musical entitled "Funny Face", written by&nbsp;George&nbsp;and&nbsp;Ira Gershwin in 1927, but it has a totally different plot to that of the film, although several of its songs are included. Jo Stockton, an assistant in a Greenwich Village&nbsp;bookshop, is discovered as a fashion model by Maggie Prescott, the editor of a prestigious fashion magazine, and&nbsp;Dick Avery, a famous fashion photographer. Jo, however, is something of an amateur intellectual, has a low opinion of the fashion industry and only goes along with Maggie and Dick's plans because they offer her an assignment in Paris, a city she has always wanted to visit because her greatest ambition is to meet the great philosopher&nbsp;Professor Emile Flostre, founder of the doctrine of empathicalism. (Flostre was clearly based upon Jean-Paul Sartre and his doctrine of existentialism). A romance grows up between Jo and Dick in Paris, but Dick finds he has a rival for her affections in the form of the professor, younger and better-looking than his real-life counterpart but no less lecherous. The film was a box-office flop when first released in 1957; it only made a profit when it was re-released seven years later following the huge success of&nbsp;Audrey Hepburn's only other musical, "My Fair Lady". It upset the film critic of "The Times" (aka The Thunderer) who thundered, "There is that in the film's attitude towards the "intellectual", whether in Greenwich Village or Paris, which offends. It is not amiable parody and it is not telling satire; it has its roots in the ill-based instinct to jeer, and its jeers are offensive." When we consider that these words were directed towards a light, frothy musical comedy, this looks like is a particularly po-faced example of a critic taking himself too seriously (although criticisms of the film's supposed "anti-intellectualism" still surface). The film's main target was not intellectuals but hypocrites (although it also sends up some of the inanities of the fashion industry). The point about Flostre is that he does not practise what he preaches; "empathicalism" is supposed to be all about putting oneself in the other person's shoes, but in his dealings with Jo he is only capable of thinking about himself. For all her book-learning, Jo's initial attitude towards Flostre is one of uncritical idol-worship and she still has to learn the important lesson that idols can have feet of clay. The "funny face" of the title is Jo herself, and the implication of the words of the title song is that, although she is not very attractive, Dick still loves her because she has got so much character and personality. So why, then, was, the Divine Audrey, the most luminously beautiful actress of her generation, cast in the role? Was this simply a piece of miscasting? The answer to that question is an emphatic "no". There are a few things wrong with the film, but Audrey is not one of them. The main mistake is the miscasting of the fifty-eight year-old Fred Astaire as the male lead. Although he shows that his advancing years have done little to diminish his dancing skills, away from the dance-floor he looks embarrassingly out-of-place as the lover of the twenty-eight year-old Audrey. Sometimes the teaming of Audrey with an older man paid off, as with Bogart in "Sabrina", but this is one case where it didn't. For all his faults I was rooting for Jo to end up with Flostre rather than Dick. The music is tuneful but not particularly memorable, apart from two songs, "'S Wonderful" and the title song, and the plot is a&nbsp;fairly banal one. There is, however, a good performance from Kay Thompson as the&nbsp;autocratic Maggie. (I wonder if this was the inspiration for Meryl Streep's portrayal of a similar character in "The Devil Wears Prada"). This was Thompson's only film appearance; she was best known in her day as a singer and musician and is best remembered today as a children's author. The dance numbers are well choreographed and the visual look of the film is an attractive one. The film's biggest plus, however, is the presence of Audrey Hepburn. She was one of those rare actresses with true star quality, by which I mean the ability to take any film and make it quite different from what it would have been with anyone else in the leading role. Few will be surprised that Audrey was a great dancer- she did, after all, train as a ballerina- but those who know the story of how she was not allowed to do her own singing in "My Fair Lady" will be surprised by&nbsp;what a melodious voice she had. (Certainly better than Astaire's). Her main contribution here, however, is neither her singing nor her dancing but simply the force of her personality. "Funny Face" is not a great film; it is in nothing like the same class as "My Fair Lady" or its director Stanley Donen's masterpiece "Singin' in the Rain". (Mind you, Donen seemed to spend most of the rest of his career trying to repeat the success of that great film without ever really pulling it off). It could have been a pretty dull musical, but Audrey transforms it into something memorable. Unlike King Midas she couldn't quite manage to turn everything she touched into gold. "Paris When It Sizzles" and "Two for the Road", for example, obstinately remain base metal despite her presence. "Funny Face" might not be pure gold, however, but at least Audrey is able to turn it into silver. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad, but I have seen so much better.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FUNNY FACE It was OK... but I was expecting more. I quite like musicals and when I heard that this one had Audrey Hepburn and Fred Astaire in it I thought it would be really good. The story is OK... it is about a fashion magazine photographer who finds a new model in the form of a book shop assistant. She doesn't want to be a model, but has always wanted to go to Paris to meet a philosopher. When she finds out that to be a model she has to go to Paris, she accepts. Then the photographer falls in love with her. The acting is not very good... but like I have mentioned in previous reviews, the acting is not very good in most musicals... but I like that. It makes the films more fun. Audrey and Fred both do good jobs though... they are both really good at singing and dancing which is what is needed for a musical. The film also stars Kay Thomson. I didn't feel like the songs were very good in this film. The thing I like about musicals is the songs need to be catchy and fun... Not one of the songs in this stuck in my head. I didn't feel like tapping my foot to any of them, but there was some very interesting dancing... especially from Audrey when she starts dancing in a pub. I don't know if I can call that dancing. haha. I will give this film 5 out of 10. It was quite good, but I was slightly disappointed. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Think Pink? Not in the Eisenhower-Nixon Years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dglink
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Splashy colors, Paris locations, Fred Astaire's dancing, Audrey Hepburn's pixie-ish charm, Stanley Donen's direction, and George Gershwin's music should have melded into an enduring musical classic in 1957's "Funny Face." However, the talented individuals involved produced a dated, clumsy film with but a few bright moments. Poor tweedy philosophizing shop girl is transformed into an elegant stylish fashion model, a "My Fair Lady" wannabe. While Audrey Hepburn is never convincing as a mousy clerk garbed in shades of drab, she comes alive in designer clothes, and, quicker than you can say "Givenchy," the character swaps her principles for a haircut and makeover, a walk down the runway, and a trip to Paris. Hepburn was often paired with older men in her films; however, Cary Grant, William Holden, and Gary Cooper had enough masculine sex appeal to be convincing love interest for a young woman. Fred Astaire, however, was never romantic material, even for those of his own age. In "Funny Face," Astaire in his late 50's is about 20 years older than Hepburn and looks it; oddly, neither the age difference nor Astaire's reason for advanced bachelorhood is ever remarked upon or mentioned in the script. Leonard Gershe's screenplay for "Funny Face" is planted firmly in the Eisenhower 1950's. Astaire's chauvinistic attitude, "the man asks the woman to dance," is archaic and would have been poison to a free-thinking young woman like Hepburn's Jo Stockton. Kay Thompson's magazine editor is a post-World War II stereotype of the working woman: unmarried, hard, bossy, mannish, and abrasive. Only in mid-20th-century America would a harem of lemming-like "yes-women" blindly follow Thompson and mindlessly praise her every mundane uttering. Further undermining the film's credibility, the supposed pictorial output of Dick Avery, a successful fashion photographer, and Maggie Prescott, editor of "Quality" magazine, is limp at best; Avery's photos are mediocre, and Prescott's earth-shattering idea is "think pink." As always, Fred Astaire's dancing is worth watching, and, although her singing is more flat than melodic and her dancing mixed, Hepburn is always a winning charmer. However, under Donen's direction, the film does not soar, but rather lumbers from clumsy number to embarrassing parody; bearded beatniks, soul-searching laments, Parisian dives, empathetic philosophers, and even fashion magazines seem so last century. "Funny Face" may be worth a view as a mid-20th-century curiosity piece, but otherwise the film is most suitable as source material to excerpt scenes for documentaries on Astaire and Hepburn. Most viewers will have to think pink to plod through "Funny Face."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some great ideas that get cobbled together with uneven direction...but the best is the best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny Face (1957) I was prepared to love this movie and it let me down even though it has two fabulous leads, the classic musical dance man Fred Astaire and the new star Audrey Hepburn. It even has its photography based on the work of Richard Avedon, and Astaire's character is based on him in his fashion work. I enjoyed it, but it depends too much on common formulas, which I normally don't mind, and it lacks cohesion, flow, and what you might just call magic. That it's partly shot in New York and then Paris (a famously rainy Paris during the shoot) you would think you could hardly go wrong. And in a way it doesn't go wrong overall. But the plot lacks energy, the romantic chemistry is missing (the two are really more like father and daughter), and the series of dance numbers is choppy and uneven. Because of all this, each song goes on too long and you itch for the next scene, and then that scene merely takes us back to the weak plot. If you focus on these weaknesses the movie starts to look almost terrible. Hepburn's transformation from a tweedy intellectual in a bookshop in Manhattan to the premiere runway in Paris sounds like dream come true stuff, but it isn't really convincing (or surprising, of course). The French counter-culture intellectual scene is fun idea but it doesn't push it very far, and the leading voice is played by an actor with no presence at all. Hepburn's interactions in this whole world are forced. Even the opening twenty minutes, which sets the tone, is rough sledding before out two leading actors appear. But focus on the strengths and there are some great moments. Like the series of photo shoots, one after another quickly spreading across the highlights of the city, is fun and stylish. A few of the dance numbers, though short of classic, are great fun, like the modern one in the French smokey bar and the one in the darkroom with the safelights on. In both of these, again, director Stanley Donen (a consummate pro at this stuff) let things drag on just a minute too long, which is a long time in a fast moving movie like this. Then there is Fred Astaire, at ease and warm and really wonderful. He doesn't get a chance to quite blow the doors off any of the dances, but he's still a joy to watch, dancing or just being his warm self. (He was initially a reluctant actor at this point in his life, but was still very active. For a sense of his truer self, perhaps, behind the scenes, see "On the Beach" two years later.) Then there is Audrey Hepburn, by now a stellar and unique star trying to spread her wings into musicals (this was her first). She, as usual in her career, rose above her part and like Astaire was "herself" with such charm she keeps even weaker scenes going. When she's in them, which luckily she is in most of them by the second half. Hepburn also comes across as a superb model (appropriately thin, but not especially tall), and Avedon's photographs of her taken in conjunction with filming are iconic. They get incorporated into the movie directly, both in the scenes where Astaire creates some photos in his role, and in some of the cinematography which imitates Avedon's style (white backdrops, modern styling). In the end it's a great seeming movie with such huge flaws it's just another musical. But that's not fair, quite, so think of it as an up and down ride with some very very fine high points which make it worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable in spire of its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Funny Face" is a far from perfect film. But, considering that it stars Fred Astaire, it's still well worth watching. Anything with Astaire is worth watching! The film begins with an odd montage in which the audience is introduced to Maggie Prescott (Kay Thompson)--a wonderfully annoying lady who is THE expert on fashion. It seems she is out to find a new model with a new look and her photographer (Astaire) notices a lady that Maggie completely overlooked--cute little Jo, the girl at the bookstore (Audrey Hepburn). Jo is then signed with a big contract and goes to Paris for photo shoots and to make her a mega-star. In the process, she and her photographer fall in love. But, minor complications arise and it might just mean the two will go their separate ways. First, the good. A few of the songs are very nice and the film stars Astaire and Hepburn. It also has really lovely footage of Paris. If you've been to this city (like I have), it's a wonderful walk down memory lane and the city really is that beautiful. Now the not so good. The biggest problem is that Astaire is easily old enough to be Audrey's father--and I am sure that many in the audience must have thought that. Thirty years' difference is a lot. Also, while some of the songs were nice (particularly the Gershwin ones), a few of the numbers were pretty bad--such as the Florida song and dance number. Overall, the good does outweigh the bad and I suggest you see it. It's just that both stars did far better work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now we know what the word empathy means
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dimitri44
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a motion picture where Audrey Hepburn stunningly empathizes with the audience as well, more and more, all the way through to the very end of the movie. The lighthearted story line begins with high brow Audrey Hepburn employed as manager of an intellectual type bookstore in Greenwich Village, NYC, and her dream is to go to Paris where she can then attend lectures offered by someone who is said to be a Professor of Empathy. Meanwhile, Fred Astaire, a fashion photographer, also has the opportunity to implore Audrey Hepburn to empathize with his photographic work as well, which then leads to her being provided with free passage to Paris, as she also then becomes a great fashion model in turn. Towards the end, the Professor of Empathy turns out to be quite a bit younger than thought, and with Audrey, his idea of empathy turns out to be something unexpectedly more basic than also thought. Thus, Fred and Audrey certainly empathize with each other in a most dignified way in the end. Yes, in 1957, movies were generally quite a bit more dignified as well. Postscript: I recently bought the Paramount Home Entertainment (UK) DVD version of this movie, and I watched it carefully more than once. I now believe this is the best motion picture that Audrey Hepburn made. It's almost even as though George and Ira Gershwin, even from the hereafter, were waiting for Audrey Hepburn, and then she came.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Astaire makes this musical semi-watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dani-marie
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One would assume that combining the talents of director Stanley Donen, Fred Astaire, and Audrey Hepburn would produce one knockout of a film. The turnout is anything but. From the get go the film left me both disinterested and unimpressed, even as an avid fan of musicals. The only savior of the film was Fred Astaire, who makes the most of each lackluster song and dance. He also holds the only slightly intriguing character and dialogue, standing out from the remaining wreckage of the film, which is mostly fluff without entertainment. The film begins with "Think Pink", an off the wall number which holds zero place in the plot. Donen effectively demonstrates the coldness of Quality magazine and the fashion industry itself through Kay Thompson's character, while the mostly sarcastic and charming dialogue of Astaire's character contribute to the message. The wit in Astaire's dialogue is the writers' only vehicle to humor. Once Hepburn is introduced, her soft face is the only saving grace of her character. The writers have managed to create a leading lady without charm. In short: the writers create a stereotypical facade of an intellectual woman, further cheapening the plot. Hepburn's other musical roles feature her voice dubbed, which might have been the proper choice for this film. Not once does she seem fully immersed in the character or film. However, what could she have done with less than adequate material and a flat character to work with? Chemistry between Audrey and Fred would have helped tons. Despite thoughts in another reviews, age differences do not factor into any type of chemistry. Check out Gene Kelly and Leslie Caron in An American in Paris or Audrey and Cary Grant in Charade in which large age gaps do not get in the way of emotion between the actors. The production design and cinematography are small beauties, but do little to improve the soppy, one dimensional plot. As the plot progresses, our two leads inevitably fall in love (it is not evident of course) and one forgettable song after another only left me waiting for the film to improve. Instead of being amazed by the performers, I only wanted the song to end. Again, Astaire is the only performer that delivers, even through drab choreography. He is the only actor that infuses some form of charm and enthusiasm into both the songs and dances. By the end of the film, all you are left with is Paris eye candy and a flat, uninteresting script. And maybe a little Astaire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fred Snaps! Audrey Crackles! Kay Pops!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This original musical comedy is not based upon the 1927 Broadway Gershwin musical that starred Fred and Adele Astaire on the stage. It has been updated to the 1950's Greenwich Village where photographer Astaire and his merry models take over Audrey Hepburn's book store (long before some computer devise ran most bookstores out of business), leaving her with a huge mess to clean up. Realizing his error, Astaire helps her, and realizes, he too can make her a model. This is sort of a "My Fair Lady"/"Pygmallion" of the modeling industry, with Astaire playing Henry Higgins to Audrey's pre-"My Fair Lady" Eliza. Along with magazine editor Kay Thompson, the trio goes to Paris where Astaire and Rogers fall in love, she checks out the Latin Quarter, and the duo literally skate off into the sunset on a lily pad meant for two. Some people question the pairing of Astaire and Hepburn, citing their almost 30 year age difference as a major problem. I concur that Astaire was way too young for Leslie Caron in the entertaining but overlong "Daddy Long Legs", but his style fits much better with Audrey. Yes, the age difference is quite noticeable, but I don't get that creepy feeling here that I did with the waif-like Caron. Unlike "My Fair Lady", you get to hear Audrey sing here, and her voice fits her character. When she sings "How Long Has This Been Going On?", you really feel for her. Ironically, when Ms. Hepburn passed away, it was this song that helped me celebrate her life, not "Moon River" (which she also sings in "Breakfast at Tiffany's") or her dubbed songs in "My Fair Lady". Seeing this years ago on a double bill at the Castro Theatre with "Breakfast at Tiffany's", I was amused by the audience's reaction to various un-"P.C." remarks, particularly Astaire's rather sexist remark that in a relationship, it is the man who makes the decisions. But irregardless of that, this is still one of the loveliest musicals of the 1950's, and try not to think "music video" when Kay Thompson (all in beige) pops up with her models to sing "Think Pink", which by the way, she wouldn't be caught dead in. Then, in a dark room, Astaire sings the title song to Hepburn, appropriately lit for the song. In Paris, the trio sings (separately) the lively "Bonjour Paris!" which has many great visuals of the city of lights. This is an example of real art deco in movies way past the age of Paramount's classy romantic comedies and musicals. Astaire and Thompson get to become "hip" in an opium den when they break into "Clap Yo' Hands", one of the liveliest 1920's songs still being sung 90 years later. Acting wise, Thompson steals the show, playing a character that "Boosom Buddies"/"Two & a Half Men" supporting player Holland Taylor cut her teeth on. Stanley Donen, a veteran dancer and musical film director, turns a rather ordinary May/December romance into something special that remains as fresh today as it was 55 years ago.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Paris mis-match
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Colourful Stanley Donen movie featuring wonderful Parisian locations and the superb music of the Gershwin brothers...and that's about it. I believe this may have been Fred Astaire's last movie as the romantic lead and on the evidence here, it's easy to see why. His performance is utterly devoid of any passion or even discernible attraction to the young Audrey Hepburn, plus for once his solo dance routines seem just that, routine and while still danced consummately, somehow lacking in dynamism or invention. Hepburn gets a dream ticket herself, decked out in a succession of high-fashion costumes and even getting to sing and dance with the great man, without ever convincing the viewer that she's a natural in either discipline. Otherwise, she gets to mope and loon by turn, pretty much the two main attributes of her acting ability. Her dancing is passable at best, while her solo routine improvising to modern jazz in a smoky West Bank bar is toe-curlingly embarrassing. And we all know, I'm sure that neither of them could be considered outstanding singers and hearing Audrey's not-so-dulcet tones, one can easily see why she was overdubbed (against her wishes) in "My Fair Lady". The story has less substance than the fog over the Seine and hits a lowpoint near the end when an unlikely fellow-suitor emerges to contest Audrey's fair hand, her hero-philosopher who's much better-looking, not to mention much cleverer than old Fred. Yes it's the old why-would-she-fall-for-him conundrum that not unnaturally bedevilled the ageing Astaire's later films, but it's exaggerated even more here when contrasted with the ever-youthful looking Hepburn. The plot seeks to cash in and poke fun at Paris's post-war reputation for fashion and philosophy and certainly the settings, particularly the exteriors are luminously warm, but the humour is forced at best and lacking finesse. Director Donen employs some tricksy cinematography to mixed effect as he strains for modernity, but in the final analysis, like the pairing of the old Astaire with the young Hepburn, the marriage of traditional Hollywood musical characteristics with modern film-making ideas just clashes and doesn't come off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sumptuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-406-125589
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps the most exquisitely art-directed musical of them all, "Funny Face" is sheer delight. Forget the story (for the most part) and enjoy the remarkable Astaire-Hepburn-Thompson magic, the glorious Avedon titles and stills and the breathtaking cinematography. "Think Pink," "Bonjour Paris," "He Loves and She Loves" and many of the other numbers will transport you. It's very much a time capsule -- attitudes toward women are wince-worthy, the sneering at existentialism can be tiresome. The sophistication of the music -- a blend of Gershwin classics with three new songs by Roger Edens -- the dancing, the performances and, most of all, the physical production, more than compensate. Btw, the Edens songs provide some of the films best moments -- "Bonjour Paris, On How to Be Lovely" and the sly, stunning "Think Pink."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey is able to turn it, if not into gold, at least into silver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a stage musical entitled "Funny Face", written by&nbsp;George&nbsp;and&nbsp;Ira Gershwin in 1927, but it has a totally different plot to that of the film, although several of its songs are included. Jo Stockton, an assistant in a Greenwich Village&nbsp;bookshop, is discovered as a fashion model by Maggie Prescott, the editor of a prestigious fashion magazine, and&nbsp;Dick Avery, a famous fashion photographer. Jo, however, is something of an amateur intellectual, has a low opinion of the fashion industry and only goes along with Maggie and Dick's plans because they offer her an assignment in Paris, a city she has always wanted to visit because her greatest ambition is to meet the great philosopher&nbsp;Professor Emile Flostre, founder of the doctrine of empathicalism. (Flostre was clearly based upon Jean-Paul Sartre and his doctrine of existentialism). A romance grows up between Jo and Dick in Paris, but Dick finds he has a rival for her affections in the form of the professor, younger and better-looking than his real-life counterpart but no less lecherous. The film was a box-office flop when first released in 1957; it only made a profit when it was re-released seven years later following the huge success of&nbsp;Audrey Hepburn's only other musical, "My Fair Lady". It upset the film critic of "The Times" (aka The Thunderer) who thundered, "There is that in the film's attitude towards the "intellectual", whether in Greenwich Village or Paris, which offends. It is not amiable parody and it is not telling satire; it has its roots in the ill-based instinct to jeer, and its jeers are offensive." When we consider that these words were directed towards a light, frothy musical comedy, this looks like is a particularly po-faced example of a critic taking himself too seriously (although criticisms of the film's supposed "anti-intellectualism" still surface). The film's main target was not intellectuals but hypocrites (although it also sends up some of the inanities of the fashion industry). The point about Flostre is that he does not practise what he preaches; "empathicalism" is supposed to be all about putting oneself in the other person's shoes, but in his dealings with Jo he is only capable of thinking about himself. For all her book-learning, Jo's initial attitude towards Flostre is one of uncritical idol-worship and she still has to learn the important lesson that idols can have feet of clay. The "funny face" of the title is Jo herself, and the implication of the words of the title song is that, although she is not very attractive, Dick still loves her because she has got so much character and personality. So why, then, was, the Divine Audrey, the most luminously beautiful actress of her generation, cast in the role? Was this simply a piece of miscasting? The answer to that question is an emphatic "no". There are a few things wrong with the film, but Audrey is not one of them. The main mistake is the miscasting of the fifty-eight year-old Fred Astaire as the male lead. Although he shows that his advancing years have done little to diminish his dancing skills, away from the dance-floor he looks embarrassingly out-of-place as the lover of the twenty-eight year-old Audrey. Sometimes the teaming of Audrey with an older man paid off, as with Bogart in "Sabrina", but this is one case where it didn't. For all his faults I was rooting for Jo to end up with Flostre rather than Dick. The music is tuneful but not particularly memorable, apart from two songs, "'S Wonderful" and the title song, and the plot is a&nbsp;fairly banal one. There is, however, a good performance from Kay Thompson as the&nbsp;autocratic Maggie. (I wonder if this was the inspiration for Meryl Streep's portrayal of a similar character in "The Devil Wears Prada"). This was Thompson's only film appearance; she was best known in her day as a singer and musician and is best remembered today as a children's author. The dance numbers are well choreographed and the visual look of the film is an attractive one. The film's biggest plus, however, is the presence of Audrey Hepburn. She was one of those rare actresses with true star quality, by which I mean the ability to take any film and make it quite different from what it would have been with anyone else in the leading role. Few will be surprised that Audrey was a great dancer- she did, after all, train as a ballerina- but those who know the story of how she was not allowed to do her own singing in "My Fair Lady" will be surprised by&nbsp;what a melodious voice she had. (Certainly better than Astaire's). Her main contribution here, however, is neither her singing nor her dancing but simply the force of her personality. "Funny Face" is not a great film; it is in nothing like the same class as "My Fair Lady" or its director Stanley Donen's masterpiece "Singin' in the Rain". (Mind you, Donen seemed to spend most of the rest of his career trying to repeat the success of that great film without ever really pulling it off). It could have been a pretty dull musical, but Audrey transforms it into something memorable. Unlike King Midas she couldn't quite manage to turn everything she touched into gold. "Paris When It Sizzles" and "Two for the Road", for example, obstinately remain base metal despite her presence. "Funny Face" might not be pure gold, however, but at least Audrey is able to turn it into silver. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad, but I have seen so much better.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FUNNY FACE It was OK... but I was expecting more. I quite like musicals and when I heard that this one had Audrey Hepburn and Fred Astaire in it I thought it would be really good. The story is OK... it is about a fashion magazine photographer who finds a new model in the form of a book shop assistant. She doesn't want to be a model, but has always wanted to go to Paris to meet a philosopher. When she finds out that to be a model she has to go to Paris, she accepts. Then the photographer falls in love with her. The acting is not very good... but like I have mentioned in previous reviews, the acting is not very good in most musicals... but I like that. It makes the films more fun. Audrey and Fred both do good jobs though... they are both really good at singing and dancing which is what is needed for a musical. The film also stars Kay Thomson. I didn't feel like the songs were very good in this film. The thing I like about musicals is the songs need to be catchy and fun... Not one of the songs in this stuck in my head. I didn't feel like tapping my foot to any of them, but there was some very interesting dancing... especially from Audrey when she starts dancing in a pub. I don't know if I can call that dancing. haha. I will give this film 5 out of 10. It was quite good, but I was slightly disappointed. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Think Pink? Not in the Eisenhower-Nixon Years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dglink
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Splashy colors, Paris locations, Fred Astaire's dancing, Audrey Hepburn's pixie-ish charm, Stanley Donen's direction, and George Gershwin's music should have melded into an enduring musical classic in 1957's "Funny Face." However, the talented individuals involved produced a dated, clumsy film with but a few bright moments. Poor tweedy philosophizing shop girl is transformed into an elegant stylish fashion model, a "My Fair Lady" wannabe. While Audrey Hepburn is never convincing as a mousy clerk garbed in shades of drab, she comes alive in designer clothes, and, quicker than you can say "Givenchy," the character swaps her principles for a haircut and makeover, a walk down the runway, and a trip to Paris. Hepburn was often paired with older men in her films; however, Cary Grant, William Holden, and Gary Cooper had enough masculine sex appeal to be convincing love interest for a young woman. Fred Astaire, however, was never romantic material, even for those of his own age. In "Funny Face," Astaire in his late 50's is about 20 years older than Hepburn and looks it; oddly, neither the age difference nor Astaire's reason for advanced bachelorhood is ever remarked upon or mentioned in the script. Leonard Gershe's screenplay for "Funny Face" is planted firmly in the Eisenhower 1950's. Astaire's chauvinistic attitude, "the man asks the woman to dance," is archaic and would have been poison to a free-thinking young woman like Hepburn's Jo Stockton. Kay Thompson's magazine editor is a post-World War II stereotype of the working woman: unmarried, hard, bossy, mannish, and abrasive. Only in mid-20th-century America would a harem of lemming-like "yes-women" blindly follow Thompson and mindlessly praise her every mundane uttering. Further undermining the film's credibility, the supposed pictorial output of Dick Avery, a successful fashion photographer, and Maggie Prescott, editor of "Quality" magazine, is limp at best; Avery's photos are mediocre, and Prescott's earth-shattering idea is "think pink." As always, Fred Astaire's dancing is worth watching, and, although her singing is more flat than melodic and her dancing mixed, Hepburn is always a winning charmer. However, under Donen's direction, the film does not soar, but rather lumbers from clumsy number to embarrassing parody; bearded beatniks, soul-searching laments, Parisian dives, empathetic philosophers, and even fashion magazines seem so last century. "Funny Face" may be worth a view as a mid-20th-century curiosity piece, but otherwise the film is most suitable as source material to excerpt scenes for documentaries on Astaire and Hepburn. Most viewers will have to think pink to plod through "Funny Face."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some great ideas that get cobbled together with uneven direction...but the best is the best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny Face (1957) I was prepared to love this movie and it let me down even though it has two fabulous leads, the classic musical dance man Fred Astaire and the new star Audrey Hepburn. It even has its photography based on the work of Richard Avedon, and Astaire's character is based on him in his fashion work. I enjoyed it, but it depends too much on common formulas, which I normally don't mind, and it lacks cohesion, flow, and what you might just call magic. That it's partly shot in New York and then Paris (a famously rainy Paris during the shoot) you would think you could hardly go wrong. And in a way it doesn't go wrong overall. But the plot lacks energy, the romantic chemistry is missing (the two are really more like father and daughter), and the series of dance numbers is choppy and uneven. Because of all this, each song goes on too long and you itch for the next scene, and then that scene merely takes us back to the weak plot. If you focus on these weaknesses the movie starts to look almost terrible. Hepburn's transformation from a tweedy intellectual in a bookshop in Manhattan to the premiere runway in Paris sounds like dream come true stuff, but it isn't really convincing (or surprising, of course). The French counter-culture intellectual scene is fun idea but it doesn't push it very far, and the leading voice is played by an actor with no presence at all. Hepburn's interactions in this whole world are forced. Even the opening twenty minutes, which sets the tone, is rough sledding before out two leading actors appear. But focus on the strengths and there are some great moments. Like the series of photo shoots, one after another quickly spreading across the highlights of the city, is fun and stylish. A few of the dance numbers, though short of classic, are great fun, like the modern one in the French smokey bar and the one in the darkroom with the safelights on. In both of these, again, director Stanley Donen (a consummate pro at this stuff) let things drag on just a minute too long, which is a long time in a fast moving movie like this. Then there is Fred Astaire, at ease and warm and really wonderful. He doesn't get a chance to quite blow the doors off any of the dances, but he's still a joy to watch, dancing or just being his warm self. (He was initially a reluctant actor at this point in his life, but was still very active. For a sense of his truer self, perhaps, behind the scenes, see "On the Beach" two years later.) Then there is Audrey Hepburn, by now a stellar and unique star trying to spread her wings into musicals (this was her first). She, as usual in her career, rose above her part and like Astaire was "herself" with such charm she keeps even weaker scenes going. When she's in them, which luckily she is in most of them by the second half. Hepburn also comes across as a superb model (appropriately thin, but not especially tall), and Avedon's photographs of her taken in conjunction with filming are iconic. They get incorporated into the movie directly, both in the scenes where Astaire creates some photos in his role, and in some of the cinematography which imitates Avedon's style (white backdrops, modern styling). In the end it's a great seeming movie with such huge flaws it's just another musical. But that's not fair, quite, so think of it as an up and down ride with some very very fine high points which make it worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable in spire of its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Funny Face" is a far from perfect film. But, considering that it stars Fred Astaire, it's still well worth watching. Anything with Astaire is worth watching! The film begins with an odd montage in which the audience is introduced to Maggie Prescott (Kay Thompson)--a wonderfully annoying lady who is THE expert on fashion. It seems she is out to find a new model with a new look and her photographer (Astaire) notices a lady that Maggie completely overlooked--cute little Jo, the girl at the bookstore (Audrey Hepburn). Jo is then signed with a big contract and goes to Paris for photo shoots and to make her a mega-star. In the process, she and her photographer fall in love. But, minor complications arise and it might just mean the two will go their separate ways. First, the good. A few of the songs are very nice and the film stars Astaire and Hepburn. It also has really lovely footage of Paris. If you've been to this city (like I have), it's a wonderful walk down memory lane and the city really is that beautiful. Now the not so good. The biggest problem is that Astaire is easily old enough to be Audrey's father--and I am sure that many in the audience must have thought that. Thirty years' difference is a lot. Also, while some of the songs were nice (particularly the Gershwin ones), a few of the numbers were pretty bad--such as the Florida song and dance number. Overall, the good does outweigh the bad and I suggest you see it. It's just that both stars did far better work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now we know what the word empathy means
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dimitri44
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a motion picture where Audrey Hepburn stunningly empathizes with the audience as well, more and more, all the way through to the very end of the movie. The lighthearted story line begins with high brow Audrey Hepburn employed as manager of an intellectual type bookstore in Greenwich Village, NYC, and her dream is to go to Paris where she can then attend lectures offered by someone who is said to be a Professor of Empathy. Meanwhile, Fred Astaire, a fashion photographer, also has the opportunity to implore Audrey Hepburn to empathize with his photographic work as well, which then leads to her being provided with free passage to Paris, as she also then becomes a great fashion model in turn. Towards the end, the Professor of Empathy turns out to be quite a bit younger than thought, and with Audrey, his idea of empathy turns out to be something unexpectedly more basic than also thought. Thus, Fred and Audrey certainly empathize with each other in a most dignified way in the end. Yes, in 1957, movies were generally quite a bit more dignified as well. Postscript: I recently bought the Paramount Home Entertainment (UK) DVD version of this movie, and I watched it carefully more than once. I now believe this is the best motion picture that Audrey Hepburn made. It's almost even as though George and Ira Gershwin, even from the hereafter, were waiting for Audrey Hepburn, and then she came.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Astaire makes this musical semi-watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dani-marie
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One would assume that combining the talents of director Stanley Donen, Fred Astaire, and Audrey Hepburn would produce one knockout of a film. The turnout is anything but. From the get go the film left me both disinterested and unimpressed, even as an avid fan of musicals. The only savior of the film was Fred Astaire, who makes the most of each lackluster song and dance. He also holds the only slightly intriguing character and dialogue, standing out from the remaining wreckage of the film, which is mostly fluff without entertainment. The film begins with "Think Pink", an off the wall number which holds zero place in the plot. Donen effectively demonstrates the coldness of Quality magazine and the fashion industry itself through Kay Thompson's character, while the mostly sarcastic and charming dialogue of Astaire's character contribute to the message. The wit in Astaire's dialogue is the writers' only vehicle to humor. Once Hepburn is introduced, her soft face is the only saving grace of her character. The writers have managed to create a leading lady without charm. In short: the writers create a stereotypical facade of an intellectual woman, further cheapening the plot. Hepburn's other musical roles feature her voice dubbed, which might have been the proper choice for this film. Not once does she seem fully immersed in the character or film. However, what could she have done with less than adequate material and a flat character to work with? Chemistry between Audrey and Fred would have helped tons. Despite thoughts in another reviews, age differences do not factor into any type of chemistry. Check out Gene Kelly and Leslie Caron in An American in Paris or Audrey and Cary Grant in Charade in which large age gaps do not get in the way of emotion between the actors. The production design and cinematography are small beauties, but do little to improve the soppy, one dimensional plot. As the plot progresses, our two leads inevitably fall in love (it is not evident of course) and one forgettable song after another only left me waiting for the film to improve. Instead of being amazed by the performers, I only wanted the song to end. Again, Astaire is the only performer that delivers, even through drab choreography. He is the only actor that infuses some form of charm and enthusiasm into both the songs and dances. By the end of the film, all you are left with is Paris eye candy and a flat, uninteresting script. And maybe a little Astaire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fred Snaps! Audrey Crackles! Kay Pops!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This original musical comedy is not based upon the 1927 Broadway Gershwin musical that starred Fred and Adele Astaire on the stage. It has been updated to the 1950's Greenwich Village where photographer Astaire and his merry models take over Audrey Hepburn's book store (long before some computer devise ran most bookstores out of business), leaving her with a huge mess to clean up. Realizing his error, Astaire helps her, and realizes, he too can make her a model. This is sort of a "My Fair Lady"/"Pygmallion" of the modeling industry, with Astaire playing Henry Higgins to Audrey's pre-"My Fair Lady" Eliza. Along with magazine editor Kay Thompson, the trio goes to Paris where Astaire and Rogers fall in love, she checks out the Latin Quarter, and the duo literally skate off into the sunset on a lily pad meant for two. Some people question the pairing of Astaire and Hepburn, citing their almost 30 year age difference as a major problem. I concur that Astaire was way too young for Leslie Caron in the entertaining but overlong "Daddy Long Legs", but his style fits much better with Audrey. Yes, the age difference is quite noticeable, but I don't get that creepy feeling here that I did with the waif-like Caron. Unlike "My Fair Lady", you get to hear Audrey sing here, and her voice fits her character. When she sings "How Long Has This Been Going On?", you really feel for her. Ironically, when Ms. Hepburn passed away, it was this song that helped me celebrate her life, not "Moon River" (which she also sings in "Breakfast at Tiffany's") or her dubbed songs in "My Fair Lady". Seeing this years ago on a double bill at the Castro Theatre with "Breakfast at Tiffany's", I was amused by the audience's reaction to various un-"P.C." remarks, particularly Astaire's rather sexist remark that in a relationship, it is the man who makes the decisions. But irregardless of that, this is still one of the loveliest musicals of the 1950's, and try not to think "music video" when Kay Thompson (all in beige) pops up with her models to sing "Think Pink", which by the way, she wouldn't be caught dead in. Then, in a dark room, Astaire sings the title song to Hepburn, appropriately lit for the song. In Paris, the trio sings (separately) the lively "Bonjour Paris!" which has many great visuals of the city of lights. This is an example of real art deco in movies way past the age of Paramount's classy romantic comedies and musicals. Astaire and Thompson get to become "hip" in an opium den when they break into "Clap Yo' Hands", one of the liveliest 1920's songs still being sung 90 years later. Acting wise, Thompson steals the show, playing a character that "Boosom Buddies"/"Two & a Half Men" supporting player Holland Taylor cut her teeth on. Stanley Donen, a veteran dancer and musical film director, turns a rather ordinary May/December romance into something special that remains as fresh today as it was 55 years ago.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Paris mis-match
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Colourful Stanley Donen movie featuring wonderful Parisian locations and the superb music of the Gershwin brothers...and that's about it. I believe this may have been Fred Astaire's last movie as the romantic lead and on the evidence here, it's easy to see why. His performance is utterly devoid of any passion or even discernible attraction to the young Audrey Hepburn, plus for once his solo dance routines seem just that, routine and while still danced consummately, somehow lacking in dynamism or invention. Hepburn gets a dream ticket herself, decked out in a succession of high-fashion costumes and even getting to sing and dance with the great man, without ever convincing the viewer that she's a natural in either discipline. Otherwise, she gets to mope and loon by turn, pretty much the two main attributes of her acting ability. Her dancing is passable at best, while her solo routine improvising to modern jazz in a smoky West Bank bar is toe-curlingly embarrassing. And we all know, I'm sure that neither of them could be considered outstanding singers and hearing Audrey's not-so-dulcet tones, one can easily see why she was overdubbed (against her wishes) in "My Fair Lady". The story has less substance than the fog over the Seine and hits a lowpoint near the end when an unlikely fellow-suitor emerges to contest Audrey's fair hand, her hero-philosopher who's much better-looking, not to mention much cleverer than old Fred. Yes it's the old why-would-she-fall-for-him conundrum that not unnaturally bedevilled the ageing Astaire's later films, but it's exaggerated even more here when contrasted with the ever-youthful looking Hepburn. The plot seeks to cash in and poke fun at Paris's post-war reputation for fashion and philosophy and certainly the settings, particularly the exteriors are luminously warm, but the humour is forced at best and lacking finesse. Director Donen employs some tricksy cinematography to mixed effect as he strains for modernity, but in the final analysis, like the pairing of the old Astaire with the young Hepburn, the marriage of traditional Hollywood musical characteristics with modern film-making ideas just clashes and doesn't come off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sumptuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-406-125589
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps the most exquisitely art-directed musical of them all, "Funny Face" is sheer delight. Forget the story (for the most part) and enjoy the remarkable Astaire-Hepburn-Thompson magic, the glorious Avedon titles and stills and the breathtaking cinematography. "Think Pink," "Bonjour Paris," "He Loves and She Loves" and many of the other numbers will transport you. It's very much a time capsule -- attitudes toward women are wince-worthy, the sneering at existentialism can be tiresome. The sophistication of the music -- a blend of Gershwin classics with three new songs by Roger Edens -- the dancing, the performances and, most of all, the physical production, more than compensate. Btw, the Edens songs provide some of the films best moments -- "Bonjour Paris, On How to Be Lovely" and the sly, stunning "Think Pink."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey is able to turn it, if not into gold, at least into silver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a stage musical entitled "Funny Face", written by&nbsp;George&nbsp;and&nbsp;Ira Gershwin in 1927, but it has a totally different plot to that of the film, although several of its songs are included. Jo Stockton, an assistant in a Greenwich Village&nbsp;bookshop, is discovered as a fashion model by Maggie Prescott, the editor of a prestigious fashion magazine, and&nbsp;Dick Avery, a famous fashion photographer. Jo, however, is something of an amateur intellectual, has a low opinion of the fashion industry and only goes along with Maggie and Dick's plans because they offer her an assignment in Paris, a city she has always wanted to visit because her greatest ambition is to meet the great philosopher&nbsp;Professor Emile Flostre, founder of the doctrine of empathicalism. (Flostre was clearly based upon Jean-Paul Sartre and his doctrine of existentialism). A romance grows up between Jo and Dick in Paris, but Dick finds he has a rival for her affections in the form of the professor, younger and better-looking than his real-life counterpart but no less lecherous. The film was a box-office flop when first released in 1957; it only made a profit when it was re-released seven years later following the huge success of&nbsp;Audrey Hepburn's only other musical, "My Fair Lady". It upset the film critic of "The Times" (aka The Thunderer) who thundered, "There is that in the film's attitude towards the "intellectual", whether in Greenwich Village or Paris, which offends. It is not amiable parody and it is not telling satire; it has its roots in the ill-based instinct to jeer, and its jeers are offensive." When we consider that these words were directed towards a light, frothy musical comedy, this looks like is a particularly po-faced example of a critic taking himself too seriously (although criticisms of the film's supposed "anti-intellectualism" still surface). The film's main target was not intellectuals but hypocrites (although it also sends up some of the inanities of the fashion industry). The point about Flostre is that he does not practise what he preaches; "empathicalism" is supposed to be all about putting oneself in the other person's shoes, but in his dealings with Jo he is only capable of thinking about himself. For all her book-learning, Jo's initial attitude towards Flostre is one of uncritical idol-worship and she still has to learn the important lesson that idols can have feet of clay. The "funny face" of the title is Jo herself, and the implication of the words of the title song is that, although she is not very attractive, Dick still loves her because she has got so much character and personality. So why, then, was, the Divine Audrey, the most luminously beautiful actress of her generation, cast in the role? Was this simply a piece of miscasting? The answer to that question is an emphatic "no". There are a few things wrong with the film, but Audrey is not one of them. The main mistake is the miscasting of the fifty-eight year-old Fred Astaire as the male lead. Although he shows that his advancing years have done little to diminish his dancing skills, away from the dance-floor he looks embarrassingly out-of-place as the lover of the twenty-eight year-old Audrey. Sometimes the teaming of Audrey with an older man paid off, as with Bogart in "Sabrina", but this is one case where it didn't. For all his faults I was rooting for Jo to end up with Flostre rather than Dick. The music is tuneful but not particularly memorable, apart from two songs, "'S Wonderful" and the title song, and the plot is a&nbsp;fairly banal one. There is, however, a good performance from Kay Thompson as the&nbsp;autocratic Maggie. (I wonder if this was the inspiration for Meryl Streep's portrayal of a similar character in "The Devil Wears Prada"). This was Thompson's only film appearance; she was best known in her day as a singer and musician and is best remembered today as a children's author. The dance numbers are well choreographed and the visual look of the film is an attractive one. The film's biggest plus, however, is the presence of Audrey Hepburn. She was one of those rare actresses with true star quality, by which I mean the ability to take any film and make it quite different from what it would have been with anyone else in the leading role. Few will be surprised that Audrey was a great dancer- she did, after all, train as a ballerina- but those who know the story of how she was not allowed to do her own singing in "My Fair Lady" will be surprised by&nbsp;what a melodious voice she had. (Certainly better than Astaire's). Her main contribution here, however, is neither her singing nor her dancing but simply the force of her personality. "Funny Face" is not a great film; it is in nothing like the same class as "My Fair Lady" or its director Stanley Donen's masterpiece "Singin' in the Rain". (Mind you, Donen seemed to spend most of the rest of his career trying to repeat the success of that great film without ever really pulling it off). It could have been a pretty dull musical, but Audrey transforms it into something memorable. Unlike King Midas she couldn't quite manage to turn everything she touched into gold. "Paris When It Sizzles" and "Two for the Road", for example, obstinately remain base metal despite her presence. "Funny Face" might not be pure gold, however, but at least Audrey is able to turn it into silver. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad, but I have seen so much better.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FUNNY FACE It was OK... but I was expecting more. I quite like musicals and when I heard that this one had Audrey Hepburn and Fred Astaire in it I thought it would be really good. The story is OK... it is about a fashion magazine photographer who finds a new model in the form of a book shop assistant. She doesn't want to be a model, but has always wanted to go to Paris to meet a philosopher. When she finds out that to be a model she has to go to Paris, she accepts. Then the photographer falls in love with her. The acting is not very good... but like I have mentioned in previous reviews, the acting is not very good in most musicals... but I like that. It makes the films more fun. Audrey and Fred both do good jobs though... they are both really good at singing and dancing which is what is needed for a musical. The film also stars Kay Thomson. I didn't feel like the songs were very good in this film. The thing I like about musicals is the songs need to be catchy and fun... Not one of the songs in this stuck in my head. I didn't feel like tapping my foot to any of them, but there was some very interesting dancing... especially from Audrey when she starts dancing in a pub. I don't know if I can call that dancing. haha. I will give this film 5 out of 10. It was quite good, but I was slightly disappointed. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Think Pink? Not in the Eisenhower-Nixon Years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dglink
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Splashy colors, Paris locations, Fred Astaire's dancing, Audrey Hepburn's pixie-ish charm, Stanley Donen's direction, and George Gershwin's music should have melded into an enduring musical classic in 1957's "Funny Face." However, the talented individuals involved produced a dated, clumsy film with but a few bright moments. Poor tweedy philosophizing shop girl is transformed into an elegant stylish fashion model, a "My Fair Lady" wannabe. While Audrey Hepburn is never convincing as a mousy clerk garbed in shades of drab, she comes alive in designer clothes, and, quicker than you can say "Givenchy," the character swaps her principles for a haircut and makeover, a walk down the runway, and a trip to Paris. Hepburn was often paired with older men in her films; however, Cary Grant, William Holden, and Gary Cooper had enough masculine sex appeal to be convincing love interest for a young woman. Fred Astaire, however, was never romantic material, even for those of his own age. In "Funny Face," Astaire in his late 50's is about 20 years older than Hepburn and looks it; oddly, neither the age difference nor Astaire's reason for advanced bachelorhood is ever remarked upon or mentioned in the script. Leonard Gershe's screenplay for "Funny Face" is planted firmly in the Eisenhower 1950's. Astaire's chauvinistic attitude, "the man asks the woman to dance," is archaic and would have been poison to a free-thinking young woman like Hepburn's Jo Stockton. Kay Thompson's magazine editor is a post-World War II stereotype of the working woman: unmarried, hard, bossy, mannish, and abrasive. Only in mid-20th-century America would a harem of lemming-like "yes-women" blindly follow Thompson and mindlessly praise her every mundane uttering. Further undermining the film's credibility, the supposed pictorial output of Dick Avery, a successful fashion photographer, and Maggie Prescott, editor of "Quality" magazine, is limp at best; Avery's photos are mediocre, and Prescott's earth-shattering idea is "think pink." As always, Fred Astaire's dancing is worth watching, and, although her singing is more flat than melodic and her dancing mixed, Hepburn is always a winning charmer. However, under Donen's direction, the film does not soar, but rather lumbers from clumsy number to embarrassing parody; bearded beatniks, soul-searching laments, Parisian dives, empathetic philosophers, and even fashion magazines seem so last century. "Funny Face" may be worth a view as a mid-20th-century curiosity piece, but otherwise the film is most suitable as source material to excerpt scenes for documentaries on Astaire and Hepburn. Most viewers will have to think pink to plod through "Funny Face."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some great ideas that get cobbled together with uneven direction...but the best is the best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny Face (1957) I was prepared to love this movie and it let me down even though it has two fabulous leads, the classic musical dance man Fred Astaire and the new star Audrey Hepburn. It even has its photography based on the work of Richard Avedon, and Astaire's character is based on him in his fashion work. I enjoyed it, but it depends too much on common formulas, which I normally don't mind, and it lacks cohesion, flow, and what you might just call magic. That it's partly shot in New York and then Paris (a famously rainy Paris during the shoot) you would think you could hardly go wrong. And in a way it doesn't go wrong overall. But the plot lacks energy, the romantic chemistry is missing (the two are really more like father and daughter), and the series of dance numbers is choppy and uneven. Because of all this, each song goes on too long and you itch for the next scene, and then that scene merely takes us back to the weak plot. If you focus on these weaknesses the movie starts to look almost terrible. Hepburn's transformation from a tweedy intellectual in a bookshop in Manhattan to the premiere runway in Paris sounds like dream come true stuff, but it isn't really convincing (or surprising, of course). The French counter-culture intellectual scene is fun idea but it doesn't push it very far, and the leading voice is played by an actor with no presence at all. Hepburn's interactions in this whole world are forced. Even the opening twenty minutes, which sets the tone, is rough sledding before out two leading actors appear. But focus on the strengths and there are some great moments. Like the series of photo shoots, one after another quickly spreading across the highlights of the city, is fun and stylish. A few of the dance numbers, though short of classic, are great fun, like the modern one in the French smokey bar and the one in the darkroom with the safelights on. In both of these, again, director Stanley Donen (a consummate pro at this stuff) let things drag on just a minute too long, which is a long time in a fast moving movie like this. Then there is Fred Astaire, at ease and warm and really wonderful. He doesn't get a chance to quite blow the doors off any of the dances, but he's still a joy to watch, dancing or just being his warm self. (He was initially a reluctant actor at this point in his life, but was still very active. For a sense of his truer self, perhaps, behind the scenes, see "On the Beach" two years later.) Then there is Audrey Hepburn, by now a stellar and unique star trying to spread her wings into musicals (this was her first). She, as usual in her career, rose above her part and like Astaire was "herself" with such charm she keeps even weaker scenes going. When she's in them, which luckily she is in most of them by the second half. Hepburn also comes across as a superb model (appropriately thin, but not especially tall), and Avedon's photographs of her taken in conjunction with filming are iconic. They get incorporated into the movie directly, both in the scenes where Astaire creates some photos in his role, and in some of the cinematography which imitates Avedon's style (white backdrops, modern styling). In the end it's a great seeming movie with such huge flaws it's just another musical. But that's not fair, quite, so think of it as an up and down ride with some very very fine high points which make it worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable in spire of its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Funny Face" is a far from perfect film. But, considering that it stars Fred Astaire, it's still well worth watching. Anything with Astaire is worth watching! The film begins with an odd montage in which the audience is introduced to Maggie Prescott (Kay Thompson)--a wonderfully annoying lady who is THE expert on fashion. It seems she is out to find a new model with a new look and her photographer (Astaire) notices a lady that Maggie completely overlooked--cute little Jo, the girl at the bookstore (Audrey Hepburn). Jo is then signed with a big contract and goes to Paris for photo shoots and to make her a mega-star. In the process, she and her photographer fall in love. But, minor complications arise and it might just mean the two will go their separate ways. First, the good. A few of the songs are very nice and the film stars Astaire and Hepburn. It also has really lovely footage of Paris. If you've been to this city (like I have), it's a wonderful walk down memory lane and the city really is that beautiful. Now the not so good. The biggest problem is that Astaire is easily old enough to be Audrey's father--and I am sure that many in the audience must have thought that. Thirty years' difference is a lot. Also, while some of the songs were nice (particularly the Gershwin ones), a few of the numbers were pretty bad--such as the Florida song and dance number. Overall, the good does outweigh the bad and I suggest you see it. It's just that both stars did far better work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now we know what the word empathy means
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dimitri44
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a motion picture where Audrey Hepburn stunningly empathizes with the audience as well, more and more, all the way through to the very end of the movie. The lighthearted story line begins with high brow Audrey Hepburn employed as manager of an intellectual type bookstore in Greenwich Village, NYC, and her dream is to go to Paris where she can then attend lectures offered by someone who is said to be a Professor of Empathy. Meanwhile, Fred Astaire, a fashion photographer, also has the opportunity to implore Audrey Hepburn to empathize with his photographic work as well, which then leads to her being provided with free passage to Paris, as she also then becomes a great fashion model in turn. Towards the end, the Professor of Empathy turns out to be quite a bit younger than thought, and with Audrey, his idea of empathy turns out to be something unexpectedly more basic than also thought. Thus, Fred and Audrey certainly empathize with each other in a most dignified way in the end. Yes, in 1957, movies were generally quite a bit more dignified as well. Postscript: I recently bought the Paramount Home Entertainment (UK) DVD version of this movie, and I watched it carefully more than once. I now believe this is the best motion picture that Audrey Hepburn made. It's almost even as though George and Ira Gershwin, even from the hereafter, were waiting for Audrey Hepburn, and then she came.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Astaire makes this musical semi-watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dani-marie
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One would assume that combining the talents of director Stanley Donen, Fred Astaire, and Audrey Hepburn would produce one knockout of a film. The turnout is anything but. From the get go the film left me both disinterested and unimpressed, even as an avid fan of musicals. The only savior of the film was Fred Astaire, who makes the most of each lackluster song and dance. He also holds the only slightly intriguing character and dialogue, standing out from the remaining wreckage of the film, which is mostly fluff without entertainment. The film begins with "Think Pink", an off the wall number which holds zero place in the plot. Donen effectively demonstrates the coldness of Quality magazine and the fashion industry itself through Kay Thompson's character, while the mostly sarcastic and charming dialogue of Astaire's character contribute to the message. The wit in Astaire's dialogue is the writers' only vehicle to humor. Once Hepburn is introduced, her soft face is the only saving grace of her character. The writers have managed to create a leading lady without charm. In short: the writers create a stereotypical facade of an intellectual woman, further cheapening the plot. Hepburn's other musical roles feature her voice dubbed, which might have been the proper choice for this film. Not once does she seem fully immersed in the character or film. However, what could she have done with less than adequate material and a flat character to work with? Chemistry between Audrey and Fred would have helped tons. Despite thoughts in another reviews, age differences do not factor into any type of chemistry. Check out Gene Kelly and Leslie Caron in An American in Paris or Audrey and Cary Grant in Charade in which large age gaps do not get in the way of emotion between the actors. The production design and cinematography are small beauties, but do little to improve the soppy, one dimensional plot. As the plot progresses, our two leads inevitably fall in love (it is not evident of course) and one forgettable song after another only left me waiting for the film to improve. Instead of being amazed by the performers, I only wanted the song to end. Again, Astaire is the only performer that delivers, even through drab choreography. He is the only actor that infuses some form of charm and enthusiasm into both the songs and dances. By the end of the film, all you are left with is Paris eye candy and a flat, uninteresting script. And maybe a little Astaire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fred Snaps! Audrey Crackles! Kay Pops!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This original musical comedy is not based upon the 1927 Broadway Gershwin musical that starred Fred and Adele Astaire on the stage. It has been updated to the 1950's Greenwich Village where photographer Astaire and his merry models take over Audrey Hepburn's book store (long before some computer devise ran most bookstores out of business), leaving her with a huge mess to clean up. Realizing his error, Astaire helps her, and realizes, he too can make her a model. This is sort of a "My Fair Lady"/"Pygmallion" of the modeling industry, with Astaire playing Henry Higgins to Audrey's pre-"My Fair Lady" Eliza. Along with magazine editor Kay Thompson, the trio goes to Paris where Astaire and Rogers fall in love, she checks out the Latin Quarter, and the duo literally skate off into the sunset on a lily pad meant for two. Some people question the pairing of Astaire and Hepburn, citing their almost 30 year age difference as a major problem. I concur that Astaire was way too young for Leslie Caron in the entertaining but overlong "Daddy Long Legs", but his style fits much better with Audrey. Yes, the age difference is quite noticeable, but I don't get that creepy feeling here that I did with the waif-like Caron. Unlike "My Fair Lady", you get to hear Audrey sing here, and her voice fits her character. When she sings "How Long Has This Been Going On?", you really feel for her. Ironically, when Ms. Hepburn passed away, it was this song that helped me celebrate her life, not "Moon River" (which she also sings in "Breakfast at Tiffany's") or her dubbed songs in "My Fair Lady". Seeing this years ago on a double bill at the Castro Theatre with "Breakfast at Tiffany's", I was amused by the audience's reaction to various un-"P.C." remarks, particularly Astaire's rather sexist remark that in a relationship, it is the man who makes the decisions. But irregardless of that, this is still one of the loveliest musicals of the 1950's, and try not to think "music video" when Kay Thompson (all in beige) pops up with her models to sing "Think Pink", which by the way, she wouldn't be caught dead in. Then, in a dark room, Astaire sings the title song to Hepburn, appropriately lit for the song. In Paris, the trio sings (separately) the lively "Bonjour Paris!" which has many great visuals of the city of lights. This is an example of real art deco in movies way past the age of Paramount's classy romantic comedies and musicals. Astaire and Thompson get to become "hip" in an opium den when they break into "Clap Yo' Hands", one of the liveliest 1920's songs still being sung 90 years later. Acting wise, Thompson steals the show, playing a character that "Boosom Buddies"/"Two & a Half Men" supporting player Holland Taylor cut her teeth on. Stanley Donen, a veteran dancer and musical film director, turns a rather ordinary May/December romance into something special that remains as fresh today as it was 55 years ago.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Paris mis-match
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Colourful Stanley Donen movie featuring wonderful Parisian locations and the superb music of the Gershwin brothers...and that's about it. I believe this may have been Fred Astaire's last movie as the romantic lead and on the evidence here, it's easy to see why. His performance is utterly devoid of any passion or even discernible attraction to the young Audrey Hepburn, plus for once his solo dance routines seem just that, routine and while still danced consummately, somehow lacking in dynamism or invention. Hepburn gets a dream ticket herself, decked out in a succession of high-fashion costumes and even getting to sing and dance with the great man, without ever convincing the viewer that she's a natural in either discipline. Otherwise, she gets to mope and loon by turn, pretty much the two main attributes of her acting ability. Her dancing is passable at best, while her solo routine improvising to modern jazz in a smoky West Bank bar is toe-curlingly embarrassing. And we all know, I'm sure that neither of them could be considered outstanding singers and hearing Audrey's not-so-dulcet tones, one can easily see why she was overdubbed (against her wishes) in "My Fair Lady". The story has less substance than the fog over the Seine and hits a lowpoint near the end when an unlikely fellow-suitor emerges to contest Audrey's fair hand, her hero-philosopher who's much better-looking, not to mention much cleverer than old Fred. Yes it's the old why-would-she-fall-for-him conundrum that not unnaturally bedevilled the ageing Astaire's later films, but it's exaggerated even more here when contrasted with the ever-youthful looking Hepburn. The plot seeks to cash in and poke fun at Paris's post-war reputation for fashion and philosophy and certainly the settings, particularly the exteriors are luminously warm, but the humour is forced at best and lacking finesse. Director Donen employs some tricksy cinematography to mixed effect as he strains for modernity, but in the final analysis, like the pairing of the old Astaire with the young Hepburn, the marriage of traditional Hollywood musical characteristics with modern film-making ideas just clashes and doesn't come off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sumptuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-406-125589
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps the most exquisitely art-directed musical of them all, "Funny Face" is sheer delight. Forget the story (for the most part) and enjoy the remarkable Astaire-Hepburn-Thompson magic, the glorious Avedon titles and stills and the breathtaking cinematography. "Think Pink," "Bonjour Paris," "He Loves and She Loves" and many of the other numbers will transport you. It's very much a time capsule -- attitudes toward women are wince-worthy, the sneering at existentialism can be tiresome. The sophistication of the music -- a blend of Gershwin classics with three new songs by Roger Edens -- the dancing, the performances and, most of all, the physical production, more than compensate. Btw, the Edens songs provide some of the films best moments -- "Bonjour Paris, On How to Be Lovely" and the sly, stunning "Think Pink."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey is able to turn it, if not into gold, at least into silver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a stage musical entitled "Funny Face", written by&nbsp;George&nbsp;and&nbsp;Ira Gershwin in 1927, but it has a totally different plot to that of the film, although several of its songs are included. Jo Stockton, an assistant in a Greenwich Village&nbsp;bookshop, is discovered as a fashion model by Maggie Prescott, the editor of a prestigious fashion magazine, and&nbsp;Dick Avery, a famous fashion photographer. Jo, however, is something of an amateur intellectual, has a low opinion of the fashion industry and only goes along with Maggie and Dick's plans because they offer her an assignment in Paris, a city she has always wanted to visit because her greatest ambition is to meet the great philosopher&nbsp;Professor Emile Flostre, founder of the doctrine of empathicalism. (Flostre was clearly based upon Jean-Paul Sartre and his doctrine of existentialism). A romance grows up between Jo and Dick in Paris, but Dick finds he has a rival for her affections in the form of the professor, younger and better-looking than his real-life counterpart but no less lecherous. The film was a box-office flop when first released in 1957; it only made a profit when it was re-released seven years later following the huge success of&nbsp;Audrey Hepburn's only other musical, "My Fair Lady". It upset the film critic of "The Times" (aka The Thunderer) who thundered, "There is that in the film's attitude towards the "intellectual", whether in Greenwich Village or Paris, which offends. It is not amiable parody and it is not telling satire; it has its roots in the ill-based instinct to jeer, and its jeers are offensive." When we consider that these words were directed towards a light, frothy musical comedy, this looks like is a particularly po-faced example of a critic taking himself too seriously (although criticisms of the film's supposed "anti-intellectualism" still surface). The film's main target was not intellectuals but hypocrites (although it also sends up some of the inanities of the fashion industry). The point about Flostre is that he does not practise what he preaches; "empathicalism" is supposed to be all about putting oneself in the other person's shoes, but in his dealings with Jo he is only capable of thinking about himself. For all her book-learning, Jo's initial attitude towards Flostre is one of uncritical idol-worship and she still has to learn the important lesson that idols can have feet of clay. The "funny face" of the title is Jo herself, and the implication of the words of the title song is that, although she is not very attractive, Dick still loves her because she has got so much character and personality. So why, then, was, the Divine Audrey, the most luminously beautiful actress of her generation, cast in the role? Was this simply a piece of miscasting? The answer to that question is an emphatic "no". There are a few things wrong with the film, but Audrey is not one of them. The main mistake is the miscasting of the fifty-eight year-old Fred Astaire as the male lead. Although he shows that his advancing years have done little to diminish his dancing skills, away from the dance-floor he looks embarrassingly out-of-place as the lover of the twenty-eight year-old Audrey. Sometimes the teaming of Audrey with an older man paid off, as with Bogart in "Sabrina", but this is one case where it didn't. For all his faults I was rooting for Jo to end up with Flostre rather than Dick. The music is tuneful but not particularly memorable, apart from two songs, "'S Wonderful" and the title song, and the plot is a&nbsp;fairly banal one. There is, however, a good performance from Kay Thompson as the&nbsp;autocratic Maggie. (I wonder if this was the inspiration for Meryl Streep's portrayal of a similar character in "The Devil Wears Prada"). This was Thompson's only film appearance; she was best known in her day as a singer and musician and is best remembered today as a children's author. The dance numbers are well choreographed and the visual look of the film is an attractive one. The film's biggest plus, however, is the presence of Audrey Hepburn. She was one of those rare actresses with true star quality, by which I mean the ability to take any film and make it quite different from what it would have been with anyone else in the leading role. Few will be surprised that Audrey was a great dancer- she did, after all, train as a ballerina- but those who know the story of how she was not allowed to do her own singing in "My Fair Lady" will be surprised by&nbsp;what a melodious voice she had. (Certainly better than Astaire's). Her main contribution here, however, is neither her singing nor her dancing but simply the force of her personality. "Funny Face" is not a great film; it is in nothing like the same class as "My Fair Lady" or its director Stanley Donen's masterpiece "Singin' in the Rain". (Mind you, Donen seemed to spend most of the rest of his career trying to repeat the success of that great film without ever really pulling it off). It could have been a pretty dull musical, but Audrey transforms it into something memorable. Unlike King Midas she couldn't quite manage to turn everything she touched into gold. "Paris When It Sizzles" and "Two for the Road", for example, obstinately remain base metal despite her presence. "Funny Face" might not be pure gold, however, but at least Audrey is able to turn it into silver. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad, but I have seen so much better.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FUNNY FACE It was OK... but I was expecting more. I quite like musicals and when I heard that this one had Audrey Hepburn and Fred Astaire in it I thought it would be really good. The story is OK... it is about a fashion magazine photographer who finds a new model in the form of a book shop assistant. She doesn't want to be a model, but has always wanted to go to Paris to meet a philosopher. When she finds out that to be a model she has to go to Paris, she accepts. Then the photographer falls in love with her. The acting is not very good... but like I have mentioned in previous reviews, the acting is not very good in most musicals... but I like that. It makes the films more fun. Audrey and Fred both do good jobs though... they are both really good at singing and dancing which is what is needed for a musical. The film also stars Kay Thomson. I didn't feel like the songs were very good in this film. The thing I like about musicals is the songs need to be catchy and fun... Not one of the songs in this stuck in my head. I didn't feel like tapping my foot to any of them, but there was some very interesting dancing... especially from Audrey when she starts dancing in a pub. I don't know if I can call that dancing. haha. I will give this film 5 out of 10. It was quite good, but I was slightly disappointed. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Think Pink? Not in the Eisenhower-Nixon Years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dglink
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Splashy colors, Paris locations, Fred Astaire's dancing, Audrey Hepburn's pixie-ish charm, Stanley Donen's direction, and George Gershwin's music should have melded into an enduring musical classic in 1957's "Funny Face." However, the talented individuals involved produced a dated, clumsy film with but a few bright moments. Poor tweedy philosophizing shop girl is transformed into an elegant stylish fashion model, a "My Fair Lady" wannabe. While Audrey Hepburn is never convincing as a mousy clerk garbed in shades of drab, she comes alive in designer clothes, and, quicker than you can say "Givenchy," the character swaps her principles for a haircut and makeover, a walk down the runway, and a trip to Paris. Hepburn was often paired with older men in her films; however, Cary Grant, William Holden, and Gary Cooper had enough masculine sex appeal to be convincing love interest for a young woman. Fred Astaire, however, was never romantic material, even for those of his own age. In "Funny Face," Astaire in his late 50's is about 20 years older than Hepburn and looks it; oddly, neither the age difference nor Astaire's reason for advanced bachelorhood is ever remarked upon or mentioned in the script. Leonard Gershe's screenplay for "Funny Face" is planted firmly in the Eisenhower 1950's. Astaire's chauvinistic attitude, "the man asks the woman to dance," is archaic and would have been poison to a free-thinking young woman like Hepburn's Jo Stockton. Kay Thompson's magazine editor is a post-World War II stereotype of the working woman: unmarried, hard, bossy, mannish, and abrasive. Only in mid-20th-century America would a harem of lemming-like "yes-women" blindly follow Thompson and mindlessly praise her every mundane uttering. Further undermining the film's credibility, the supposed pictorial output of Dick Avery, a successful fashion photographer, and Maggie Prescott, editor of "Quality" magazine, is limp at best; Avery's photos are mediocre, and Prescott's earth-shattering idea is "think pink." As always, Fred Astaire's dancing is worth watching, and, although her singing is more flat than melodic and her dancing mixed, Hepburn is always a winning charmer. However, under Donen's direction, the film does not soar, but rather lumbers from clumsy number to embarrassing parody; bearded beatniks, soul-searching laments, Parisian dives, empathetic philosophers, and even fashion magazines seem so last century. "Funny Face" may be worth a view as a mid-20th-century curiosity piece, but otherwise the film is most suitable as source material to excerpt scenes for documentaries on Astaire and Hepburn. Most viewers will have to think pink to plod through "Funny Face."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some great ideas that get cobbled together with uneven direction...but the best is the best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny Face (1957) I was prepared to love this movie and it let me down even though it has two fabulous leads, the classic musical dance man Fred Astaire and the new star Audrey Hepburn. It even has its photography based on the work of Richard Avedon, and Astaire's character is based on him in his fashion work. I enjoyed it, but it depends too much on common formulas, which I normally don't mind, and it lacks cohesion, flow, and what you might just call magic. That it's partly shot in New York and then Paris (a famously rainy Paris during the shoot) you would think you could hardly go wrong. And in a way it doesn't go wrong overall. But the plot lacks energy, the romantic chemistry is missing (the two are really more like father and daughter), and the series of dance numbers is choppy and uneven. Because of all this, each song goes on too long and you itch for the next scene, and then that scene merely takes us back to the weak plot. If you focus on these weaknesses the movie starts to look almost terrible. Hepburn's transformation from a tweedy intellectual in a bookshop in Manhattan to the premiere runway in Paris sounds like dream come true stuff, but it isn't really convincing (or surprising, of course). The French counter-culture intellectual scene is fun idea but it doesn't push it very far, and the leading voice is played by an actor with no presence at all. Hepburn's interactions in this whole world are forced. Even the opening twenty minutes, which sets the tone, is rough sledding before out two leading actors appear. But focus on the strengths and there are some great moments. Like the series of photo shoots, one after another quickly spreading across the highlights of the city, is fun and stylish. A few of the dance numbers, though short of classic, are great fun, like the modern one in the French smokey bar and the one in the darkroom with the safelights on. In both of these, again, director Stanley Donen (a consummate pro at this stuff) let things drag on just a minute too long, which is a long time in a fast moving movie like this. Then there is Fred Astaire, at ease and warm and really wonderful. He doesn't get a chance to quite blow the doors off any of the dances, but he's still a joy to watch, dancing or just being his warm self. (He was initially a reluctant actor at this point in his life, but was still very active. For a sense of his truer self, perhaps, behind the scenes, see "On the Beach" two years later.) Then there is Audrey Hepburn, by now a stellar and unique star trying to spread her wings into musicals (this was her first). She, as usual in her career, rose above her part and like Astaire was "herself" with such charm she keeps even weaker scenes going. When she's in them, which luckily she is in most of them by the second half. Hepburn also comes across as a superb model (appropriately thin, but not especially tall), and Avedon's photographs of her taken in conjunction with filming are iconic. They get incorporated into the movie directly, both in the scenes where Astaire creates some photos in his role, and in some of the cinematography which imitates Avedon's style (white backdrops, modern styling). In the end it's a great seeming movie with such huge flaws it's just another musical. But that's not fair, quite, so think of it as an up and down ride with some very very fine high points which make it worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable in spire of its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Funny Face" is a far from perfect film. But, considering that it stars Fred Astaire, it's still well worth watching. Anything with Astaire is worth watching! The film begins with an odd montage in which the audience is introduced to Maggie Prescott (Kay Thompson)--a wonderfully annoying lady who is THE expert on fashion. It seems she is out to find a new model with a new look and her photographer (Astaire) notices a lady that Maggie completely overlooked--cute little Jo, the girl at the bookstore (Audrey Hepburn). Jo is then signed with a big contract and goes to Paris for photo shoots and to make her a mega-star. In the process, she and her photographer fall in love. But, minor complications arise and it might just mean the two will go their separate ways. First, the good. A few of the songs are very nice and the film stars Astaire and Hepburn. It also has really lovely footage of Paris. If you've been to this city (like I have), it's a wonderful walk down memory lane and the city really is that beautiful. Now the not so good. The biggest problem is that Astaire is easily old enough to be Audrey's father--and I am sure that many in the audience must have thought that. Thirty years' difference is a lot. Also, while some of the songs were nice (particularly the Gershwin ones), a few of the numbers were pretty bad--such as the Florida song and dance number. Overall, the good does outweigh the bad and I suggest you see it. It's just that both stars did far better work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now we know what the word empathy means
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dimitri44
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a motion picture where Audrey Hepburn stunningly empathizes with the audience as well, more and more, all the way through to the very end of the movie. The lighthearted story line begins with high brow Audrey Hepburn employed as manager of an intellectual type bookstore in Greenwich Village, NYC, and her dream is to go to Paris where she can then attend lectures offered by someone who is said to be a Professor of Empathy. Meanwhile, Fred Astaire, a fashion photographer, also has the opportunity to implore Audrey Hepburn to empathize with his photographic work as well, which then leads to her being provided with free passage to Paris, as she also then becomes a great fashion model in turn. Towards the end, the Professor of Empathy turns out to be quite a bit younger than thought, and with Audrey, his idea of empathy turns out to be something unexpectedly more basic than also thought. Thus, Fred and Audrey certainly empathize with each other in a most dignified way in the end. Yes, in 1957, movies were generally quite a bit more dignified as well. Postscript: I recently bought the Paramount Home Entertainment (UK) DVD version of this movie, and I watched it carefully more than once. I now believe this is the best motion picture that Audrey Hepburn made. It's almost even as though George and Ira Gershwin, even from the hereafter, were waiting for Audrey Hepburn, and then she came.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Astaire makes this musical semi-watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dani-marie
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One would assume that combining the talents of director Stanley Donen, Fred Astaire, and Audrey Hepburn would produce one knockout of a film. The turnout is anything but. From the get go the film left me both disinterested and unimpressed, even as an avid fan of musicals. The only savior of the film was Fred Astaire, who makes the most of each lackluster song and dance. He also holds the only slightly intriguing character and dialogue, standing out from the remaining wreckage of the film, which is mostly fluff without entertainment. The film begins with "Think Pink", an off the wall number which holds zero place in the plot. Donen effectively demonstrates the coldness of Quality magazine and the fashion industry itself through Kay Thompson's character, while the mostly sarcastic and charming dialogue of Astaire's character contribute to the message. The wit in Astaire's dialogue is the writers' only vehicle to humor. Once Hepburn is introduced, her soft face is the only saving grace of her character. The writers have managed to create a leading lady without charm. In short: the writers create a stereotypical facade of an intellectual woman, further cheapening the plot. Hepburn's other musical roles feature her voice dubbed, which might have been the proper choice for this film. Not once does she seem fully immersed in the character or film. However, what could she have done with less than adequate material and a flat character to work with? Chemistry between Audrey and Fred would have helped tons. Despite thoughts in another reviews, age differences do not factor into any type of chemistry. Check out Gene Kelly and Leslie Caron in An American in Paris or Audrey and Cary Grant in Charade in which large age gaps do not get in the way of emotion between the actors. The production design and cinematography are small beauties, but do little to improve the soppy, one dimensional plot. As the plot progresses, our two leads inevitably fall in love (it is not evident of course) and one forgettable song after another only left me waiting for the film to improve. Instead of being amazed by the performers, I only wanted the song to end. Again, Astaire is the only performer that delivers, even through drab choreography. He is the only actor that infuses some form of charm and enthusiasm into both the songs and dances. By the end of the film, all you are left with is Paris eye candy and a flat, uninteresting script. And maybe a little Astaire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fred Snaps! Audrey Crackles! Kay Pops!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This original musical comedy is not based upon the 1927 Broadway Gershwin musical that starred Fred and Adele Astaire on the stage. It has been updated to the 1950's Greenwich Village where photographer Astaire and his merry models take over Audrey Hepburn's book store (long before some computer devise ran most bookstores out of business), leaving her with a huge mess to clean up. Realizing his error, Astaire helps her, and realizes, he too can make her a model. This is sort of a "My Fair Lady"/"Pygmallion" of the modeling industry, with Astaire playing Henry Higgins to Audrey's pre-"My Fair Lady" Eliza. Along with magazine editor Kay Thompson, the trio goes to Paris where Astaire and Rogers fall in love, she checks out the Latin Quarter, and the duo literally skate off into the sunset on a lily pad meant for two. Some people question the pairing of Astaire and Hepburn, citing their almost 30 year age difference as a major problem. I concur that Astaire was way too young for Leslie Caron in the entertaining but overlong "Daddy Long Legs", but his style fits much better with Audrey. Yes, the age difference is quite noticeable, but I don't get that creepy feeling here that I did with the waif-like Caron. Unlike "My Fair Lady", you get to hear Audrey sing here, and her voice fits her character. When she sings "How Long Has This Been Going On?", you really feel for her. Ironically, when Ms. Hepburn passed away, it was this song that helped me celebrate her life, not "Moon River" (which she also sings in "Breakfast at Tiffany's") or her dubbed songs in "My Fair Lady". Seeing this years ago on a double bill at the Castro Theatre with "Breakfast at Tiffany's", I was amused by the audience's reaction to various un-"P.C." remarks, particularly Astaire's rather sexist remark that in a relationship, it is the man who makes the decisions. But irregardless of that, this is still one of the loveliest musicals of the 1950's, and try not to think "music video" when Kay Thompson (all in beige) pops up with her models to sing "Think Pink", which by the way, she wouldn't be caught dead in. Then, in a dark room, Astaire sings the title song to Hepburn, appropriately lit for the song. In Paris, the trio sings (separately) the lively "Bonjour Paris!" which has many great visuals of the city of lights. This is an example of real art deco in movies way past the age of Paramount's classy romantic comedies and musicals. Astaire and Thompson get to become "hip" in an opium den when they break into "Clap Yo' Hands", one of the liveliest 1920's songs still being sung 90 years later. Acting wise, Thompson steals the show, playing a character that "Boosom Buddies"/"Two & a Half Men" supporting player Holland Taylor cut her teeth on. Stanley Donen, a veteran dancer and musical film director, turns a rather ordinary May/December romance into something special that remains as fresh today as it was 55 years ago.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Paris mis-match
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Colourful Stanley Donen movie featuring wonderful Parisian locations and the superb music of the Gershwin brothers...and that's about it. I believe this may have been Fred Astaire's last movie as the romantic lead and on the evidence here, it's easy to see why. His performance is utterly devoid of any passion or even discernible attraction to the young Audrey Hepburn, plus for once his solo dance routines seem just that, routine and while still danced consummately, somehow lacking in dynamism or invention. Hepburn gets a dream ticket herself, decked out in a succession of high-fashion costumes and even getting to sing and dance with the great man, without ever convincing the viewer that she's a natural in either discipline. Otherwise, she gets to mope and loon by turn, pretty much the two main attributes of her acting ability. Her dancing is passable at best, while her solo routine improvising to modern jazz in a smoky West Bank bar is toe-curlingly embarrassing. And we all know, I'm sure that neither of them could be considered outstanding singers and hearing Audrey's not-so-dulcet tones, one can easily see why she was overdubbed (against her wishes) in "My Fair Lady". The story has less substance than the fog over the Seine and hits a lowpoint near the end when an unlikely fellow-suitor emerges to contest Audrey's fair hand, her hero-philosopher who's much better-looking, not to mention much cleverer than old Fred. Yes it's the old why-would-she-fall-for-him conundrum that not unnaturally bedevilled the ageing Astaire's later films, but it's exaggerated even more here when contrasted with the ever-youthful looking Hepburn. The plot seeks to cash in and poke fun at Paris's post-war reputation for fashion and philosophy and certainly the settings, particularly the exteriors are luminously warm, but the humour is forced at best and lacking finesse. Director Donen employs some tricksy cinematography to mixed effect as he strains for modernity, but in the final analysis, like the pairing of the old Astaire with the young Hepburn, the marriage of traditional Hollywood musical characteristics with modern film-making ideas just clashes and doesn't come off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sumptuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-406-125589
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps the most exquisitely art-directed musical of them all, "Funny Face" is sheer delight. Forget the story (for the most part) and enjoy the remarkable Astaire-Hepburn-Thompson magic, the glorious Avedon titles and stills and the breathtaking cinematography. "Think Pink," "Bonjour Paris," "He Loves and She Loves" and many of the other numbers will transport you. It's very much a time capsule -- attitudes toward women are wince-worthy, the sneering at existentialism can be tiresome. The sophistication of the music -- a blend of Gershwin classics with three new songs by Roger Edens -- the dancing, the performances and, most of all, the physical production, more than compensate. Btw, the Edens songs provide some of the films best moments -- "Bonjour Paris, On How to Be Lovely" and the sly, stunning "Think Pink."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey is able to turn it, if not into gold, at least into silver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a stage musical entitled "Funny Face", written by&nbsp;George&nbsp;and&nbsp;Ira Gershwin in 1927, but it has a totally different plot to that of the film, although several of its songs are included. Jo Stockton, an assistant in a Greenwich Village&nbsp;bookshop, is discovered as a fashion model by Maggie Prescott, the editor of a prestigious fashion magazine, and&nbsp;Dick Avery, a famous fashion photographer. Jo, however, is something of an amateur intellectual, has a low opinion of the fashion industry and only goes along with Maggie and Dick's plans because they offer her an assignment in Paris, a city she has always wanted to visit because her greatest ambition is to meet the great philosopher&nbsp;Professor Emile Flostre, founder of the doctrine of empathicalism. (Flostre was clearly based upon Jean-Paul Sartre and his doctrine of existentialism). A romance grows up between Jo and Dick in Paris, but Dick finds he has a rival for her affections in the form of the professor, younger and better-looking than his real-life counterpart but no less lecherous. The film was a box-office flop when first released in 1957; it only made a profit when it was re-released seven years later following the huge success of&nbsp;Audrey Hepburn's only other musical, "My Fair Lady". It upset the film critic of "The Times" (aka The Thunderer) who thundered, "There is that in the film's attitude towards the "intellectual", whether in Greenwich Village or Paris, which offends. It is not amiable parody and it is not telling satire; it has its roots in the ill-based instinct to jeer, and its jeers are offensive." When we consider that these words were directed towards a light, frothy musical comedy, this looks like is a particularly po-faced example of a critic taking himself too seriously (although criticisms of the film's supposed "anti-intellectualism" still surface). The film's main target was not intellectuals but hypocrites (although it also sends up some of the inanities of the fashion industry). The point about Flostre is that he does not practise what he preaches; "empathicalism" is supposed to be all about putting oneself in the other person's shoes, but in his dealings with Jo he is only capable of thinking about himself. For all her book-learning, Jo's initial attitude towards Flostre is one of uncritical idol-worship and she still has to learn the important lesson that idols can have feet of clay. The "funny face" of the title is Jo herself, and the implication of the words of the title song is that, although she is not very attractive, Dick still loves her because she has got so much character and personality. So why, then, was, the Divine Audrey, the most luminously beautiful actress of her generation, cast in the role? Was this simply a piece of miscasting? The answer to that question is an emphatic "no". There are a few things wrong with the film, but Audrey is not one of them. The main mistake is the miscasting of the fifty-eight year-old Fred Astaire as the male lead. Although he shows that his advancing years have done little to diminish his dancing skills, away from the dance-floor he looks embarrassingly out-of-place as the lover of the twenty-eight year-old Audrey. Sometimes the teaming of Audrey with an older man paid off, as with Bogart in "Sabrina", but this is one case where it didn't. For all his faults I was rooting for Jo to end up with Flostre rather than Dick. The music is tuneful but not particularly memorable, apart from two songs, "'S Wonderful" and the title song, and the plot is a&nbsp;fairly banal one. There is, however, a good performance from Kay Thompson as the&nbsp;autocratic Maggie. (I wonder if this was the inspiration for Meryl Streep's portrayal of a similar character in "The Devil Wears Prada"). This was Thompson's only film appearance; she was best known in her day as a singer and musician and is best remembered today as a children's author. The dance numbers are well choreographed and the visual look of the film is an attractive one. The film's biggest plus, however, is the presence of Audrey Hepburn. She was one of those rare actresses with true star quality, by which I mean the ability to take any film and make it quite different from what it would have been with anyone else in the leading role. Few will be surprised that Audrey was a great dancer- she did, after all, train as a ballerina- but those who know the story of how she was not allowed to do her own singing in "My Fair Lady" will be surprised by&nbsp;what a melodious voice she had. (Certainly better than Astaire's). Her main contribution here, however, is neither her singing nor her dancing but simply the force of her personality. "Funny Face" is not a great film; it is in nothing like the same class as "My Fair Lady" or its director Stanley Donen's masterpiece "Singin' in the Rain". (Mind you, Donen seemed to spend most of the rest of his career trying to repeat the success of that great film without ever really pulling it off). It could have been a pretty dull musical, but Audrey transforms it into something memorable. Unlike King Midas she couldn't quite manage to turn everything she touched into gold. "Paris When It Sizzles" and "Two for the Road", for example, obstinately remain base metal despite her presence. "Funny Face" might not be pure gold, however, but at least Audrey is able to turn it into silver. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad, but I have seen so much better.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FUNNY FACE It was OK... but I was expecting more. I quite like musicals and when I heard that this one had Audrey Hepburn and Fred Astaire in it I thought it would be really good. The story is OK... it is about a fashion magazine photographer who finds a new model in the form of a book shop assistant. She doesn't want to be a model, but has always wanted to go to Paris to meet a philosopher. When she finds out that to be a model she has to go to Paris, she accepts. Then the photographer falls in love with her. The acting is not very good... but like I have mentioned in previous reviews, the acting is not very good in most musicals... but I like that. It makes the films more fun. Audrey and Fred both do good jobs though... they are both really good at singing and dancing which is what is needed for a musical. The film also stars Kay Thomson. I didn't feel like the songs were very good in this film. The thing I like about musicals is the songs need to be catchy and fun... Not one of the songs in this stuck in my head. I didn't feel like tapping my foot to any of them, but there was some very interesting dancing... especially from Audrey when she starts dancing in a pub. I don't know if I can call that dancing. haha. I will give this film 5 out of 10. It was quite good, but I was slightly disappointed. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Think Pink? Not in the Eisenhower-Nixon Years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dglink
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Splashy colors, Paris locations, Fred Astaire's dancing, Audrey Hepburn's pixie-ish charm, Stanley Donen's direction, and George Gershwin's music should have melded into an enduring musical classic in 1957's "Funny Face." However, the talented individuals involved produced a dated, clumsy film with but a few bright moments. Poor tweedy philosophizing shop girl is transformed into an elegant stylish fashion model, a "My Fair Lady" wannabe. While Audrey Hepburn is never convincing as a mousy clerk garbed in shades of drab, she comes alive in designer clothes, and, quicker than you can say "Givenchy," the character swaps her principles for a haircut and makeover, a walk down the runway, and a trip to Paris. Hepburn was often paired with older men in her films; however, Cary Grant, William Holden, and Gary Cooper had enough masculine sex appeal to be convincing love interest for a young woman. Fred Astaire, however, was never romantic material, even for those of his own age. In "Funny Face," Astaire in his late 50's is about 20 years older than Hepburn and looks it; oddly, neither the age difference nor Astaire's reason for advanced bachelorhood is ever remarked upon or mentioned in the script. Leonard Gershe's screenplay for "Funny Face" is planted firmly in the Eisenhower 1950's. Astaire's chauvinistic attitude, "the man asks the woman to dance," is archaic and would have been poison to a free-thinking young woman like Hepburn's Jo Stockton. Kay Thompson's magazine editor is a post-World War II stereotype of the working woman: unmarried, hard, bossy, mannish, and abrasive. Only in mid-20th-century America would a harem of lemming-like "yes-women" blindly follow Thompson and mindlessly praise her every mundane uttering. Further undermining the film's credibility, the supposed pictorial output of Dick Avery, a successful fashion photographer, and Maggie Prescott, editor of "Quality" magazine, is limp at best; Avery's photos are mediocre, and Prescott's earth-shattering idea is "think pink." As always, Fred Astaire's dancing is worth watching, and, although her singing is more flat than melodic and her dancing mixed, Hepburn is always a winning charmer. However, under Donen's direction, the film does not soar, but rather lumbers from clumsy number to embarrassing parody; bearded beatniks, soul-searching laments, Parisian dives, empathetic philosophers, and even fashion magazines seem so last century. "Funny Face" may be worth a view as a mid-20th-century curiosity piece, but otherwise the film is most suitable as source material to excerpt scenes for documentaries on Astaire and Hepburn. Most viewers will have to think pink to plod through "Funny Face."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some great ideas that get cobbled together with uneven direction...but the best is the best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny Face (1957) I was prepared to love this movie and it let me down even though it has two fabulous leads, the classic musical dance man Fred Astaire and the new star Audrey Hepburn. It even has its photography based on the work of Richard Avedon, and Astaire's character is based on him in his fashion work. I enjoyed it, but it depends too much on common formulas, which I normally don't mind, and it lacks cohesion, flow, and what you might just call magic. That it's partly shot in New York and then Paris (a famously rainy Paris during the shoot) you would think you could hardly go wrong. And in a way it doesn't go wrong overall. But the plot lacks energy, the romantic chemistry is missing (the two are really more like father and daughter), and the series of dance numbers is choppy and uneven. Because of all this, each song goes on too long and you itch for the next scene, and then that scene merely takes us back to the weak plot. If you focus on these weaknesses the movie starts to look almost terrible. Hepburn's transformation from a tweedy intellectual in a bookshop in Manhattan to the premiere runway in Paris sounds like dream come true stuff, but it isn't really convincing (or surprising, of course). The French counter-culture intellectual scene is fun idea but it doesn't push it very far, and the leading voice is played by an actor with no presence at all. Hepburn's interactions in this whole world are forced. Even the opening twenty minutes, which sets the tone, is rough sledding before out two leading actors appear. But focus on the strengths and there are some great moments. Like the series of photo shoots, one after another quickly spreading across the highlights of the city, is fun and stylish. A few of the dance numbers, though short of classic, are great fun, like the modern one in the French smokey bar and the one in the darkroom with the safelights on. In both of these, again, director Stanley Donen (a consummate pro at this stuff) let things drag on just a minute too long, which is a long time in a fast moving movie like this. Then there is Fred Astaire, at ease and warm and really wonderful. He doesn't get a chance to quite blow the doors off any of the dances, but he's still a joy to watch, dancing or just being his warm self. (He was initially a reluctant actor at this point in his life, but was still very active. For a sense of his truer self, perhaps, behind the scenes, see "On the Beach" two years later.) Then there is Audrey Hepburn, by now a stellar and unique star trying to spread her wings into musicals (this was her first). She, as usual in her career, rose above her part and like Astaire was "herself" with such charm she keeps even weaker scenes going. When she's in them, which luckily she is in most of them by the second half. Hepburn also comes across as a superb model (appropriately thin, but not especially tall), and Avedon's photographs of her taken in conjunction with filming are iconic. They get incorporated into the movie directly, both in the scenes where Astaire creates some photos in his role, and in some of the cinematography which imitates Avedon's style (white backdrops, modern styling). In the end it's a great seeming movie with such huge flaws it's just another musical. But that's not fair, quite, so think of it as an up and down ride with some very very fine high points which make it worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable in spire of its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Funny Face" is a far from perfect film. But, considering that it stars Fred Astaire, it's still well worth watching. Anything with Astaire is worth watching! The film begins with an odd montage in which the audience is introduced to Maggie Prescott (Kay Thompson)--a wonderfully annoying lady who is THE expert on fashion. It seems she is out to find a new model with a new look and her photographer (Astaire) notices a lady that Maggie completely overlooked--cute little Jo, the girl at the bookstore (Audrey Hepburn). Jo is then signed with a big contract and goes to Paris for photo shoots and to make her a mega-star. In the process, she and her photographer fall in love. But, minor complications arise and it might just mean the two will go their separate ways. First, the good. A few of the songs are very nice and the film stars Astaire and Hepburn. It also has really lovely footage of Paris. If you've been to this city (like I have), it's a wonderful walk down memory lane and the city really is that beautiful. Now the not so good. The biggest problem is that Astaire is easily old enough to be Audrey's father--and I am sure that many in the audience must have thought that. Thirty years' difference is a lot. Also, while some of the songs were nice (particularly the Gershwin ones), a few of the numbers were pretty bad--such as the Florida song and dance number. Overall, the good does outweigh the bad and I suggest you see it. It's just that both stars did far better work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now we know what the word empathy means
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dimitri44
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a motion picture where Audrey Hepburn stunningly empathizes with the audience as well, more and more, all the way through to the very end of the movie. The lighthearted story line begins with high brow Audrey Hepburn employed as manager of an intellectual type bookstore in Greenwich Village, NYC, and her dream is to go to Paris where she can then attend lectures offered by someone who is said to be a Professor of Empathy. Meanwhile, Fred Astaire, a fashion photographer, also has the opportunity to implore Audrey Hepburn to empathize with his photographic work as well, which then leads to her being provided with free passage to Paris, as she also then becomes a great fashion model in turn. Towards the end, the Professor of Empathy turns out to be quite a bit younger than thought, and with Audrey, his idea of empathy turns out to be something unexpectedly more basic than also thought. Thus, Fred and Audrey certainly empathize with each other in a most dignified way in the end. Yes, in 1957, movies were generally quite a bit more dignified as well. Postscript: I recently bought the Paramount Home Entertainment (UK) DVD version of this movie, and I watched it carefully more than once. I now believe this is the best motion picture that Audrey Hepburn made. It's almost even as though George and Ira Gershwin, even from the hereafter, were waiting for Audrey Hepburn, and then she came.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Astaire makes this musical semi-watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dani-marie
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One would assume that combining the talents of director Stanley Donen, Fred Astaire, and Audrey Hepburn would produce one knockout of a film. The turnout is anything but. From the get go the film left me both disinterested and unimpressed, even as an avid fan of musicals. The only savior of the film was Fred Astaire, who makes the most of each lackluster song and dance. He also holds the only slightly intriguing character and dialogue, standing out from the remaining wreckage of the film, which is mostly fluff without entertainment. The film begins with "Think Pink", an off the wall number which holds zero place in the plot. Donen effectively demonstrates the coldness of Quality magazine and the fashion industry itself through Kay Thompson's character, while the mostly sarcastic and charming dialogue of Astaire's character contribute to the message. The wit in Astaire's dialogue is the writers' only vehicle to humor. Once Hepburn is introduced, her soft face is the only saving grace of her character. The writers have managed to create a leading lady without charm. In short: the writers create a stereotypical facade of an intellectual woman, further cheapening the plot. Hepburn's other musical roles feature her voice dubbed, which might have been the proper choice for this film. Not once does she seem fully immersed in the character or film. However, what could she have done with less than adequate material and a flat character to work with? Chemistry between Audrey and Fred would have helped tons. Despite thoughts in another reviews, age differences do not factor into any type of chemistry. Check out Gene Kelly and Leslie Caron in An American in Paris or Audrey and Cary Grant in Charade in which large age gaps do not get in the way of emotion between the actors. The production design and cinematography are small beauties, but do little to improve the soppy, one dimensional plot. As the plot progresses, our two leads inevitably fall in love (it is not evident of course) and one forgettable song after another only left me waiting for the film to improve. Instead of being amazed by the performers, I only wanted the song to end. Again, Astaire is the only performer that delivers, even through drab choreography. He is the only actor that infuses some form of charm and enthusiasm into both the songs and dances. By the end of the film, all you are left with is Paris eye candy and a flat, uninteresting script. And maybe a little Astaire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fred Snaps! Audrey Crackles! Kay Pops!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This original musical comedy is not based upon the 1927 Broadway Gershwin musical that starred Fred and Adele Astaire on the stage. It has been updated to the 1950's Greenwich Village where photographer Astaire and his merry models take over Audrey Hepburn's book store (long before some computer devise ran most bookstores out of business), leaving her with a huge mess to clean up. Realizing his error, Astaire helps her, and realizes, he too can make her a model. This is sort of a "My Fair Lady"/"Pygmallion" of the modeling industry, with Astaire playing Henry Higgins to Audrey's pre-"My Fair Lady" Eliza. Along with magazine editor Kay Thompson, the trio goes to Paris where Astaire and Rogers fall in love, she checks out the Latin Quarter, and the duo literally skate off into the sunset on a lily pad meant for two. Some people question the pairing of Astaire and Hepburn, citing their almost 30 year age difference as a major problem. I concur that Astaire was way too young for Leslie Caron in the entertaining but overlong "Daddy Long Legs", but his style fits much better with Audrey. Yes, the age difference is quite noticeable, but I don't get that creepy feeling here that I did with the waif-like Caron. Unlike "My Fair Lady", you get to hear Audrey sing here, and her voice fits her character. When she sings "How Long Has This Been Going On?", you really feel for her. Ironically, when Ms. Hepburn passed away, it was this song that helped me celebrate her life, not "Moon River" (which she also sings in "Breakfast at Tiffany's") or her dubbed songs in "My Fair Lady". Seeing this years ago on a double bill at the Castro Theatre with "Breakfast at Tiffany's", I was amused by the audience's reaction to various un-"P.C." remarks, particularly Astaire's rather sexist remark that in a relationship, it is the man who makes the decisions. But irregardless of that, this is still one of the loveliest musicals of the 1950's, and try not to think "music video" when Kay Thompson (all in beige) pops up with her models to sing "Think Pink", which by the way, she wouldn't be caught dead in. Then, in a dark room, Astaire sings the title song to Hepburn, appropriately lit for the song. In Paris, the trio sings (separately) the lively "Bonjour Paris!" which has many great visuals of the city of lights. This is an example of real art deco in movies way past the age of Paramount's classy romantic comedies and musicals. Astaire and Thompson get to become "hip" in an opium den when they break into "Clap Yo' Hands", one of the liveliest 1920's songs still being sung 90 years later. Acting wise, Thompson steals the show, playing a character that "Boosom Buddies"/"Two & a Half Men" supporting player Holland Taylor cut her teeth on. Stanley Donen, a veteran dancer and musical film director, turns a rather ordinary May/December romance into something special that remains as fresh today as it was 55 years ago.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Paris mis-match
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Colourful Stanley Donen movie featuring wonderful Parisian locations and the superb music of the Gershwin brothers...and that's about it. I believe this may have been Fred Astaire's last movie as the romantic lead and on the evidence here, it's easy to see why. His performance is utterly devoid of any passion or even discernible attraction to the young Audrey Hepburn, plus for once his solo dance routines seem just that, routine and while still danced consummately, somehow lacking in dynamism or invention. Hepburn gets a dream ticket herself, decked out in a succession of high-fashion costumes and even getting to sing and dance with the great man, without ever convincing the viewer that she's a natural in either discipline. Otherwise, she gets to mope and loon by turn, pretty much the two main attributes of her acting ability. Her dancing is passable at best, while her solo routine improvising to modern jazz in a smoky West Bank bar is toe-curlingly embarrassing. And we all know, I'm sure that neither of them could be considered outstanding singers and hearing Audrey's not-so-dulcet tones, one can easily see why she was overdubbed (against her wishes) in "My Fair Lady". The story has less substance than the fog over the Seine and hits a lowpoint near the end when an unlikely fellow-suitor emerges to contest Audrey's fair hand, her hero-philosopher who's much better-looking, not to mention much cleverer than old Fred. Yes it's the old why-would-she-fall-for-him conundrum that not unnaturally bedevilled the ageing Astaire's later films, but it's exaggerated even more here when contrasted with the ever-youthful looking Hepburn. The plot seeks to cash in and poke fun at Paris's post-war reputation for fashion and philosophy and certainly the settings, particularly the exteriors are luminously warm, but the humour is forced at best and lacking finesse. Director Donen employs some tricksy cinematography to mixed effect as he strains for modernity, but in the final analysis, like the pairing of the old Astaire with the young Hepburn, the marriage of traditional Hollywood musical characteristics with modern film-making ideas just clashes and doesn't come off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sumptuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-406-125589
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps the most exquisitely art-directed musical of them all, "Funny Face" is sheer delight. Forget the story (for the most part) and enjoy the remarkable Astaire-Hepburn-Thompson magic, the glorious Avedon titles and stills and the breathtaking cinematography. "Think Pink," "Bonjour Paris," "He Loves and She Loves" and many of the other numbers will transport you. It's very much a time capsule -- attitudes toward women are wince-worthy, the sneering at existentialism can be tiresome. The sophistication of the music -- a blend of Gershwin classics with three new songs by Roger Edens -- the dancing, the performances and, most of all, the physical production, more than compensate. Btw, the Edens songs provide some of the films best moments -- "Bonjour Paris, On How to Be Lovely" and the sly, stunning "Think Pink."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey is able to turn it, if not into gold, at least into silver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a stage musical entitled "Funny Face", written by&nbsp;George&nbsp;and&nbsp;Ira Gershwin in 1927, but it has a totally different plot to that of the film, although several of its songs are included. Jo Stockton, an assistant in a Greenwich Village&nbsp;bookshop, is discovered as a fashion model by Maggie Prescott, the editor of a prestigious fashion magazine, and&nbsp;Dick Avery, a famous fashion photographer. Jo, however, is something of an amateur intellectual, has a low opinion of the fashion industry and only goes along with Maggie and Dick's plans because they offer her an assignment in Paris, a city she has always wanted to visit because her greatest ambition is to meet the great philosopher&nbsp;Professor Emile Flostre, founder of the doctrine of empathicalism. (Flostre was clearly based upon Jean-Paul Sartre and his doctrine of existentialism). A romance grows up between Jo and Dick in Paris, but Dick finds he has a rival for her affections in the form of the professor, younger and better-looking than his real-life counterpart but no less lecherous. The film was a box-office flop when first released in 1957; it only made a profit when it was re-released seven years later following the huge success of&nbsp;Audrey Hepburn's only other musical, "My Fair Lady". It upset the film critic of "The Times" (aka The Thunderer) who thundered, "There is that in the film's attitude towards the "intellectual", whether in Greenwich Village or Paris, which offends. It is not amiable parody and it is not telling satire; it has its roots in the ill-based instinct to jeer, and its jeers are offensive." When we consider that these words were directed towards a light, frothy musical comedy, this looks like is a particularly po-faced example of a critic taking himself too seriously (although criticisms of the film's supposed "anti-intellectualism" still surface). The film's main target was not intellectuals but hypocrites (although it also sends up some of the inanities of the fashion industry). The point about Flostre is that he does not practise what he preaches; "empathicalism" is supposed to be all about putting oneself in the other person's shoes, but in his dealings with Jo he is only capable of thinking about himself. For all her book-learning, Jo's initial attitude towards Flostre is one of uncritical idol-worship and she still has to learn the important lesson that idols can have feet of clay. The "funny face" of the title is Jo herself, and the implication of the words of the title song is that, although she is not very attractive, Dick still loves her because she has got so much character and personality. So why, then, was, the Divine Audrey, the most luminously beautiful actress of her generation, cast in the role? Was this simply a piece of miscasting? The answer to that question is an emphatic "no". There are a few things wrong with the film, but Audrey is not one of them. The main mistake is the miscasting of the fifty-eight year-old Fred Astaire as the male lead. Although he shows that his advancing years have done little to diminish his dancing skills, away from the dance-floor he looks embarrassingly out-of-place as the lover of the twenty-eight year-old Audrey. Sometimes the teaming of Audrey with an older man paid off, as with Bogart in "Sabrina", but this is one case where it didn't. For all his faults I was rooting for Jo to end up with Flostre rather than Dick. The music is tuneful but not particularly memorable, apart from two songs, "'S Wonderful" and the title song, and the plot is a&nbsp;fairly banal one. There is, however, a good performance from Kay Thompson as the&nbsp;autocratic Maggie. (I wonder if this was the inspiration for Meryl Streep's portrayal of a similar character in "The Devil Wears Prada"). This was Thompson's only film appearance; she was best known in her day as a singer and musician and is best remembered today as a children's author. The dance numbers are well choreographed and the visual look of the film is an attractive one. The film's biggest plus, however, is the presence of Audrey Hepburn. She was one of those rare actresses with true star quality, by which I mean the ability to take any film and make it quite different from what it would have been with anyone else in the leading role. Few will be surprised that Audrey was a great dancer- she did, after all, train as a ballerina- but those who know the story of how she was not allowed to do her own singing in "My Fair Lady" will be surprised by&nbsp;what a melodious voice she had. (Certainly better than Astaire's). Her main contribution here, however, is neither her singing nor her dancing but simply the force of her personality. "Funny Face" is not a great film; it is in nothing like the same class as "My Fair Lady" or its director Stanley Donen's masterpiece "Singin' in the Rain". (Mind you, Donen seemed to spend most of the rest of his career trying to repeat the success of that great film without ever really pulling it off). It could have been a pretty dull musical, but Audrey transforms it into something memorable. Unlike King Midas she couldn't quite manage to turn everything she touched into gold. "Paris When It Sizzles" and "Two for the Road", for example, obstinately remain base metal despite her presence. "Funny Face" might not be pure gold, however, but at least Audrey is able to turn it into silver. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad, but I have seen so much better.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FUNNY FACE It was OK... but I was expecting more. I quite like musicals and when I heard that this one had Audrey Hepburn and Fred Astaire in it I thought it would be really good. The story is OK... it is about a fashion magazine photographer who finds a new model in the form of a book shop assistant. She doesn't want to be a model, but has always wanted to go to Paris to meet a philosopher. When she finds out that to be a model she has to go to Paris, she accepts. Then the photographer falls in love with her. The acting is not very good... but like I have mentioned in previous reviews, the acting is not very good in most musicals... but I like that. It makes the films more fun. Audrey and Fred both do good jobs though... they are both really good at singing and dancing which is what is needed for a musical. The film also stars Kay Thomson. I didn't feel like the songs were very good in this film. The thing I like about musicals is the songs need to be catchy and fun... Not one of the songs in this stuck in my head. I didn't feel like tapping my foot to any of them, but there was some very interesting dancing... especially from Audrey when she starts dancing in a pub. I don't know if I can call that dancing. haha. I will give this film 5 out of 10. It was quite good, but I was slightly disappointed. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Think Pink? Not in the Eisenhower-Nixon Years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dglink
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Splashy colors, Paris locations, Fred Astaire's dancing, Audrey Hepburn's pixie-ish charm, Stanley Donen's direction, and George Gershwin's music should have melded into an enduring musical classic in 1957's "Funny Face." However, the talented individuals involved produced a dated, clumsy film with but a few bright moments. Poor tweedy philosophizing shop girl is transformed into an elegant stylish fashion model, a "My Fair Lady" wannabe. While Audrey Hepburn is never convincing as a mousy clerk garbed in shades of drab, she comes alive in designer clothes, and, quicker than you can say "Givenchy," the character swaps her principles for a haircut and makeover, a walk down the runway, and a trip to Paris. Hepburn was often paired with older men in her films; however, Cary Grant, William Holden, and Gary Cooper had enough masculine sex appeal to be convincing love interest for a young woman. Fred Astaire, however, was never romantic material, even for those of his own age. In "Funny Face," Astaire in his late 50's is about 20 years older than Hepburn and looks it; oddly, neither the age difference nor Astaire's reason for advanced bachelorhood is ever remarked upon or mentioned in the script. Leonard Gershe's screenplay for "Funny Face" is planted firmly in the Eisenhower 1950's. Astaire's chauvinistic attitude, "the man asks the woman to dance," is archaic and would have been poison to a free-thinking young woman like Hepburn's Jo Stockton. Kay Thompson's magazine editor is a post-World War II stereotype of the working woman: unmarried, hard, bossy, mannish, and abrasive. Only in mid-20th-century America would a harem of lemming-like "yes-women" blindly follow Thompson and mindlessly praise her every mundane uttering. Further undermining the film's credibility, the supposed pictorial output of Dick Avery, a successful fashion photographer, and Maggie Prescott, editor of "Quality" magazine, is limp at best; Avery's photos are mediocre, and Prescott's earth-shattering idea is "think pink." As always, Fred Astaire's dancing is worth watching, and, although her singing is more flat than melodic and her dancing mixed, Hepburn is always a winning charmer. However, under Donen's direction, the film does not soar, but rather lumbers from clumsy number to embarrassing parody; bearded beatniks, soul-searching laments, Parisian dives, empathetic philosophers, and even fashion magazines seem so last century. "Funny Face" may be worth a view as a mid-20th-century curiosity piece, but otherwise the film is most suitable as source material to excerpt scenes for documentaries on Astaire and Hepburn. Most viewers will have to think pink to plod through "Funny Face."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some great ideas that get cobbled together with uneven direction...but the best is the best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny Face (1957) I was prepared to love this movie and it let me down even though it has two fabulous leads, the classic musical dance man Fred Astaire and the new star Audrey Hepburn. It even has its photography based on the work of Richard Avedon, and Astaire's character is based on him in his fashion work. I enjoyed it, but it depends too much on common formulas, which I normally don't mind, and it lacks cohesion, flow, and what you might just call magic. That it's partly shot in New York and then Paris (a famously rainy Paris during the shoot) you would think you could hardly go wrong. And in a way it doesn't go wrong overall. But the plot lacks energy, the romantic chemistry is missing (the two are really more like father and daughter), and the series of dance numbers is choppy and uneven. Because of all this, each song goes on too long and you itch for the next scene, and then that scene merely takes us back to the weak plot. If you focus on these weaknesses the movie starts to look almost terrible. Hepburn's transformation from a tweedy intellectual in a bookshop in Manhattan to the premiere runway in Paris sounds like dream come true stuff, but it isn't really convincing (or surprising, of course). The French counter-culture intellectual scene is fun idea but it doesn't push it very far, and the leading voice is played by an actor with no presence at all. Hepburn's interactions in this whole world are forced. Even the opening twenty minutes, which sets the tone, is rough sledding before out two leading actors appear. But focus on the strengths and there are some great moments. Like the series of photo shoots, one after another quickly spreading across the highlights of the city, is fun and stylish. A few of the dance numbers, though short of classic, are great fun, like the modern one in the French smokey bar and the one in the darkroom with the safelights on. In both of these, again, director Stanley Donen (a consummate pro at this stuff) let things drag on just a minute too long, which is a long time in a fast moving movie like this. Then there is Fred Astaire, at ease and warm and really wonderful. He doesn't get a chance to quite blow the doors off any of the dances, but he's still a joy to watch, dancing or just being his warm self. (He was initially a reluctant actor at this point in his life, but was still very active. For a sense of his truer self, perhaps, behind the scenes, see "On the Beach" two years later.) Then there is Audrey Hepburn, by now a stellar and unique star trying to spread her wings into musicals (this was her first). She, as usual in her career, rose above her part and like Astaire was "herself" with such charm she keeps even weaker scenes going. When she's in them, which luckily she is in most of them by the second half. Hepburn also comes across as a superb model (appropriately thin, but not especially tall), and Avedon's photographs of her taken in conjunction with filming are iconic. They get incorporated into the movie directly, both in the scenes where Astaire creates some photos in his role, and in some of the cinematography which imitates Avedon's style (white backdrops, modern styling). In the end it's a great seeming movie with such huge flaws it's just another musical. But that's not fair, quite, so think of it as an up and down ride with some very very fine high points which make it worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable in spire of its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Funny Face" is a far from perfect film. But, considering that it stars Fred Astaire, it's still well worth watching. Anything with Astaire is worth watching! The film begins with an odd montage in which the audience is introduced to Maggie Prescott (Kay Thompson)--a wonderfully annoying lady who is THE expert on fashion. It seems she is out to find a new model with a new look and her photographer (Astaire) notices a lady that Maggie completely overlooked--cute little Jo, the girl at the bookstore (Audrey Hepburn). Jo is then signed with a big contract and goes to Paris for photo shoots and to make her a mega-star. In the process, she and her photographer fall in love. But, minor complications arise and it might just mean the two will go their separate ways. First, the good. A few of the songs are very nice and the film stars Astaire and Hepburn. It also has really lovely footage of Paris. If you've been to this city (like I have), it's a wonderful walk down memory lane and the city really is that beautiful. Now the not so good. The biggest problem is that Astaire is easily old enough to be Audrey's father--and I am sure that many in the audience must have thought that. Thirty years' difference is a lot. Also, while some of the songs were nice (particularly the Gershwin ones), a few of the numbers were pretty bad--such as the Florida song and dance number. Overall, the good does outweigh the bad and I suggest you see it. It's just that both stars did far better work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now we know what the word empathy means
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dimitri44
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a motion picture where Audrey Hepburn stunningly empathizes with the audience as well, more and more, all the way through to the very end of the movie. The lighthearted story line begins with high brow Audrey Hepburn employed as manager of an intellectual type bookstore in Greenwich Village, NYC, and her dream is to go to Paris where she can then attend lectures offered by someone who is said to be a Professor of Empathy. Meanwhile, Fred Astaire, a fashion photographer, also has the opportunity to implore Audrey Hepburn to empathize with his photographic work as well, which then leads to her being provided with free passage to Paris, as she also then becomes a great fashion model in turn. Towards the end, the Professor of Empathy turns out to be quite a bit younger than thought, and with Audrey, his idea of empathy turns out to be something unexpectedly more basic than also thought. Thus, Fred and Audrey certainly empathize with each other in a most dignified way in the end. Yes, in 1957, movies were generally quite a bit more dignified as well. Postscript: I recently bought the Paramount Home Entertainment (UK) DVD version of this movie, and I watched it carefully more than once. I now believe this is the best motion picture that Audrey Hepburn made. It's almost even as though George and Ira Gershwin, even from the hereafter, were waiting for Audrey Hepburn, and then she came.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Astaire makes this musical semi-watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dani-marie
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One would assume that combining the talents of director Stanley Donen, Fred Astaire, and Audrey Hepburn would produce one knockout of a film. The turnout is anything but. From the get go the film left me both disinterested and unimpressed, even as an avid fan of musicals. The only savior of the film was Fred Astaire, who makes the most of each lackluster song and dance. He also holds the only slightly intriguing character and dialogue, standing out from the remaining wreckage of the film, which is mostly fluff without entertainment. The film begins with "Think Pink", an off the wall number which holds zero place in the plot. Donen effectively demonstrates the coldness of Quality magazine and the fashion industry itself through Kay Thompson's character, while the mostly sarcastic and charming dialogue of Astaire's character contribute to the message. The wit in Astaire's dialogue is the writers' only vehicle to humor. Once Hepburn is introduced, her soft face is the only saving grace of her character. The writers have managed to create a leading lady without charm. In short: the writers create a stereotypical facade of an intellectual woman, further cheapening the plot. Hepburn's other musical roles feature her voice dubbed, which might have been the proper choice for this film. Not once does she seem fully immersed in the character or film. However, what could she have done with less than adequate material and a flat character to work with? Chemistry between Audrey and Fred would have helped tons. Despite thoughts in another reviews, age differences do not factor into any type of chemistry. Check out Gene Kelly and Leslie Caron in An American in Paris or Audrey and Cary Grant in Charade in which large age gaps do not get in the way of emotion between the actors. The production design and cinematography are small beauties, but do little to improve the soppy, one dimensional plot. As the plot progresses, our two leads inevitably fall in love (it is not evident of course) and one forgettable song after another only left me waiting for the film to improve. Instead of being amazed by the performers, I only wanted the song to end. Again, Astaire is the only performer that delivers, even through drab choreography. He is the only actor that infuses some form of charm and enthusiasm into both the songs and dances. By the end of the film, all you are left with is Paris eye candy and a flat, uninteresting script. And maybe a little Astaire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fred Snaps! Audrey Crackles! Kay Pops!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This original musical comedy is not based upon the 1927 Broadway Gershwin musical that starred Fred and Adele Astaire on the stage. It has been updated to the 1950's Greenwich Village where photographer Astaire and his merry models take over Audrey Hepburn's book store (long before some computer devise ran most bookstores out of business), leaving her with a huge mess to clean up. Realizing his error, Astaire helps her, and realizes, he too can make her a model. This is sort of a "My Fair Lady"/"Pygmallion" of the modeling industry, with Astaire playing Henry Higgins to Audrey's pre-"My Fair Lady" Eliza. Along with magazine editor Kay Thompson, the trio goes to Paris where Astaire and Rogers fall in love, she checks out the Latin Quarter, and the duo literally skate off into the sunset on a lily pad meant for two. Some people question the pairing of Astaire and Hepburn, citing their almost 30 year age difference as a major problem. I concur that Astaire was way too young for Leslie Caron in the entertaining but overlong "Daddy Long Legs", but his style fits much better with Audrey. Yes, the age difference is quite noticeable, but I don't get that creepy feeling here that I did with the waif-like Caron. Unlike "My Fair Lady", you get to hear Audrey sing here, and her voice fits her character. When she sings "How Long Has This Been Going On?", you really feel for her. Ironically, when Ms. Hepburn passed away, it was this song that helped me celebrate her life, not "Moon River" (which she also sings in "Breakfast at Tiffany's") or her dubbed songs in "My Fair Lady". Seeing this years ago on a double bill at the Castro Theatre with "Breakfast at Tiffany's", I was amused by the audience's reaction to various un-"P.C." remarks, particularly Astaire's rather sexist remark that in a relationship, it is the man who makes the decisions. But irregardless of that, this is still one of the loveliest musicals of the 1950's, and try not to think "music video" when Kay Thompson (all in beige) pops up with her models to sing "Think Pink", which by the way, she wouldn't be caught dead in. Then, in a dark room, Astaire sings the title song to Hepburn, appropriately lit for the song. In Paris, the trio sings (separately) the lively "Bonjour Paris!" which has many great visuals of the city of lights. This is an example of real art deco in movies way past the age of Paramount's classy romantic comedies and musicals. Astaire and Thompson get to become "hip" in an opium den when they break into "Clap Yo' Hands", one of the liveliest 1920's songs still being sung 90 years later. Acting wise, Thompson steals the show, playing a character that "Boosom Buddies"/"Two & a Half Men" supporting player Holland Taylor cut her teeth on. Stanley Donen, a veteran dancer and musical film director, turns a rather ordinary May/December romance into something special that remains as fresh today as it was 55 years ago.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Paris mis-match
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Colourful Stanley Donen movie featuring wonderful Parisian locations and the superb music of the Gershwin brothers...and that's about it. I believe this may have been Fred Astaire's last movie as the romantic lead and on the evidence here, it's easy to see why. His performance is utterly devoid of any passion or even discernible attraction to the young Audrey Hepburn, plus for once his solo dance routines seem just that, routine and while still danced consummately, somehow lacking in dynamism or invention. Hepburn gets a dream ticket herself, decked out in a succession of high-fashion costumes and even getting to sing and dance with the great man, without ever convincing the viewer that she's a natural in either discipline. Otherwise, she gets to mope and loon by turn, pretty much the two main attributes of her acting ability. Her dancing is passable at best, while her solo routine improvising to modern jazz in a smoky West Bank bar is toe-curlingly embarrassing. And we all know, I'm sure that neither of them could be considered outstanding singers and hearing Audrey's not-so-dulcet tones, one can easily see why she was overdubbed (against her wishes) in "My Fair Lady". The story has less substance than the fog over the Seine and hits a lowpoint near the end when an unlikely fellow-suitor emerges to contest Audrey's fair hand, her hero-philosopher who's much better-looking, not to mention much cleverer than old Fred. Yes it's the old why-would-she-fall-for-him conundrum that not unnaturally bedevilled the ageing Astaire's later films, but it's exaggerated even more here when contrasted with the ever-youthful looking Hepburn. The plot seeks to cash in and poke fun at Paris's post-war reputation for fashion and philosophy and certainly the settings, particularly the exteriors are luminously warm, but the humour is forced at best and lacking finesse. Director Donen employs some tricksy cinematography to mixed effect as he strains for modernity, but in the final analysis, like the pairing of the old Astaire with the young Hepburn, the marriage of traditional Hollywood musical characteristics with modern film-making ideas just clashes and doesn't come off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sumptuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-406-125589
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps the most exquisitely art-directed musical of them all, "Funny Face" is sheer delight. Forget the story (for the most part) and enjoy the remarkable Astaire-Hepburn-Thompson magic, the glorious Avedon titles and stills and the breathtaking cinematography. "Think Pink," "Bonjour Paris," "He Loves and She Loves" and many of the other numbers will transport you. It's very much a time capsule -- attitudes toward women are wince-worthy, the sneering at existentialism can be tiresome. The sophistication of the music -- a blend of Gershwin classics with three new songs by Roger Edens -- the dancing, the performances and, most of all, the physical production, more than compensate. Btw, the Edens songs provide some of the films best moments -- "Bonjour Paris, On How to Be Lovely" and the sly, stunning "Think Pink."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey is able to turn it, if not into gold, at least into silver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a stage musical entitled "Funny Face", written by&nbsp;George&nbsp;and&nbsp;Ira Gershwin in 1927, but it has a totally different plot to that of the film, although several of its songs are included. Jo Stockton, an assistant in a Greenwich Village&nbsp;bookshop, is discovered as a fashion model by Maggie Prescott, the editor of a prestigious fashion magazine, and&nbsp;Dick Avery, a famous fashion photographer. Jo, however, is something of an amateur intellectual, has a low opinion of the fashion industry and only goes along with Maggie and Dick's plans because they offer her an assignment in Paris, a city she has always wanted to visit because her greatest ambition is to meet the great philosopher&nbsp;Professor Emile Flostre, founder of the doctrine of empathicalism. (Flostre was clearly based upon Jean-Paul Sartre and his doctrine of existentialism). A romance grows up between Jo and Dick in Paris, but Dick finds he has a rival for her affections in the form of the professor, younger and better-looking than his real-life counterpart but no less lecherous. The film was a box-office flop when first released in 1957; it only made a profit when it was re-released seven years later following the huge success of&nbsp;Audrey Hepburn's only other musical, "My Fair Lady". It upset the film critic of "The Times" (aka The Thunderer) who thundered, "There is that in the film's attitude towards the "intellectual", whether in Greenwich Village or Paris, which offends. It is not amiable parody and it is not telling satire; it has its roots in the ill-based instinct to jeer, and its jeers are offensive." When we consider that these words were directed towards a light, frothy musical comedy, this looks like is a particularly po-faced example of a critic taking himself too seriously (although criticisms of the film's supposed "anti-intellectualism" still surface). The film's main target was not intellectuals but hypocrites (although it also sends up some of the inanities of the fashion industry). The point about Flostre is that he does not practise what he preaches; "empathicalism" is supposed to be all about putting oneself in the other person's shoes, but in his dealings with Jo he is only capable of thinking about himself. For all her book-learning, Jo's initial attitude towards Flostre is one of uncritical idol-worship and she still has to learn the important lesson that idols can have feet of clay. The "funny face" of the title is Jo herself, and the implication of the words of the title song is that, although she is not very attractive, Dick still loves her because she has got so much character and personality. So why, then, was, the Divine Audrey, the most luminously beautiful actress of her generation, cast in the role? Was this simply a piece of miscasting? The answer to that question is an emphatic "no". There are a few things wrong with the film, but Audrey is not one of them. The main mistake is the miscasting of the fifty-eight year-old Fred Astaire as the male lead. Although he shows that his advancing years have done little to diminish his dancing skills, away from the dance-floor he looks embarrassingly out-of-place as the lover of the twenty-eight year-old Audrey. Sometimes the teaming of Audrey with an older man paid off, as with Bogart in "Sabrina", but this is one case where it didn't. For all his faults I was rooting for Jo to end up with Flostre rather than Dick. The music is tuneful but not particularly memorable, apart from two songs, "'S Wonderful" and the title song, and the plot is a&nbsp;fairly banal one. There is, however, a good performance from Kay Thompson as the&nbsp;autocratic Maggie. (I wonder if this was the inspiration for Meryl Streep's portrayal of a similar character in "The Devil Wears Prada"). This was Thompson's only film appearance; she was best known in her day as a singer and musician and is best remembered today as a children's author. The dance numbers are well choreographed and the visual look of the film is an attractive one. The film's biggest plus, however, is the presence of Audrey Hepburn. She was one of those rare actresses with true star quality, by which I mean the ability to take any film and make it quite different from what it would have been with anyone else in the leading role. Few will be surprised that Audrey was a great dancer- she did, after all, train as a ballerina- but those who know the story of how she was not allowed to do her own singing in "My Fair Lady" will be surprised by&nbsp;what a melodious voice she had. (Certainly better than Astaire's). Her main contribution here, however, is neither her singing nor her dancing but simply the force of her personality. "Funny Face" is not a great film; it is in nothing like the same class as "My Fair Lady" or its director Stanley Donen's masterpiece "Singin' in the Rain". (Mind you, Donen seemed to spend most of the rest of his career trying to repeat the success of that great film without ever really pulling it off). It could have been a pretty dull musical, but Audrey transforms it into something memorable. Unlike King Midas she couldn't quite manage to turn everything she touched into gold. "Paris When It Sizzles" and "Two for the Road", for example, obstinately remain base metal despite her presence. "Funny Face" might not be pure gold, however, but at least Audrey is able to turn it into silver. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad, but I have seen so much better.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FUNNY FACE It was OK... but I was expecting more. I quite like musicals and when I heard that this one had Audrey Hepburn and Fred Astaire in it I thought it would be really good. The story is OK... it is about a fashion magazine photographer who finds a new model in the form of a book shop assistant. She doesn't want to be a model, but has always wanted to go to Paris to meet a philosopher. When she finds out that to be a model she has to go to Paris, she accepts. Then the photographer falls in love with her. The acting is not very good... but like I have mentioned in previous reviews, the acting is not very good in most musicals... but I like that. It makes the films more fun. Audrey and Fred both do good jobs though... they are both really good at singing and dancing which is what is needed for a musical. The film also stars Kay Thomson. I didn't feel like the songs were very good in this film. The thing I like about musicals is the songs need to be catchy and fun... Not one of the songs in this stuck in my head. I didn't feel like tapping my foot to any of them, but there was some very interesting dancing... especially from Audrey when she starts dancing in a pub. I don't know if I can call that dancing. haha. I will give this film 5 out of 10. It was quite good, but I was slightly disappointed. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Think Pink? Not in the Eisenhower-Nixon Years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dglink
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Splashy colors, Paris locations, Fred Astaire's dancing, Audrey Hepburn's pixie-ish charm, Stanley Donen's direction, and George Gershwin's music should have melded into an enduring musical classic in 1957's "Funny Face." However, the talented individuals involved produced a dated, clumsy film with but a few bright moments. Poor tweedy philosophizing shop girl is transformed into an elegant stylish fashion model, a "My Fair Lady" wannabe. While Audrey Hepburn is never convincing as a mousy clerk garbed in shades of drab, she comes alive in designer clothes, and, quicker than you can say "Givenchy," the character swaps her principles for a haircut and makeover, a walk down the runway, and a trip to Paris. Hepburn was often paired with older men in her films; however, Cary Grant, William Holden, and Gary Cooper had enough masculine sex appeal to be convincing love interest for a young woman. Fred Astaire, however, was never romantic material, even for those of his own age. In "Funny Face," Astaire in his late 50's is about 20 years older than Hepburn and looks it; oddly, neither the age difference nor Astaire's reason for advanced bachelorhood is ever remarked upon or mentioned in the script. Leonard Gershe's screenplay for "Funny Face" is planted firmly in the Eisenhower 1950's. Astaire's chauvinistic attitude, "the man asks the woman to dance," is archaic and would have been poison to a free-thinking young woman like Hepburn's Jo Stockton. Kay Thompson's magazine editor is a post-World War II stereotype of the working woman: unmarried, hard, bossy, mannish, and abrasive. Only in mid-20th-century America would a harem of lemming-like "yes-women" blindly follow Thompson and mindlessly praise her every mundane uttering. Further undermining the film's credibility, the supposed pictorial output of Dick Avery, a successful fashion photographer, and Maggie Prescott, editor of "Quality" magazine, is limp at best; Avery's photos are mediocre, and Prescott's earth-shattering idea is "think pink." As always, Fred Astaire's dancing is worth watching, and, although her singing is more flat than melodic and her dancing mixed, Hepburn is always a winning charmer. However, under Donen's direction, the film does not soar, but rather lumbers from clumsy number to embarrassing parody; bearded beatniks, soul-searching laments, Parisian dives, empathetic philosophers, and even fashion magazines seem so last century. "Funny Face" may be worth a view as a mid-20th-century curiosity piece, but otherwise the film is most suitable as source material to excerpt scenes for documentaries on Astaire and Hepburn. Most viewers will have to think pink to plod through "Funny Face."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some great ideas that get cobbled together with uneven direction...but the best is the best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny Face (1957) I was prepared to love this movie and it let me down even though it has two fabulous leads, the classic musical dance man Fred Astaire and the new star Audrey Hepburn. It even has its photography based on the work of Richard Avedon, and Astaire's character is based on him in his fashion work. I enjoyed it, but it depends too much on common formulas, which I normally don't mind, and it lacks cohesion, flow, and what you might just call magic. That it's partly shot in New York and then Paris (a famously rainy Paris during the shoot) you would think you could hardly go wrong. And in a way it doesn't go wrong overall. But the plot lacks energy, the romantic chemistry is missing (the two are really more like father and daughter), and the series of dance numbers is choppy and uneven. Because of all this, each song goes on too long and you itch for the next scene, and then that scene merely takes us back to the weak plot. If you focus on these weaknesses the movie starts to look almost terrible. Hepburn's transformation from a tweedy intellectual in a bookshop in Manhattan to the premiere runway in Paris sounds like dream come true stuff, but it isn't really convincing (or surprising, of course). The French counter-culture intellectual scene is fun idea but it doesn't push it very far, and the leading voice is played by an actor with no presence at all. Hepburn's interactions in this whole world are forced. Even the opening twenty minutes, which sets the tone, is rough sledding before out two leading actors appear. But focus on the strengths and there are some great moments. Like the series of photo shoots, one after another quickly spreading across the highlights of the city, is fun and stylish. A few of the dance numbers, though short of classic, are great fun, like the modern one in the French smokey bar and the one in the darkroom with the safelights on. In both of these, again, director Stanley Donen (a consummate pro at this stuff) let things drag on just a minute too long, which is a long time in a fast moving movie like this. Then there is Fred Astaire, at ease and warm and really wonderful. He doesn't get a chance to quite blow the doors off any of the dances, but he's still a joy to watch, dancing or just being his warm self. (He was initially a reluctant actor at this point in his life, but was still very active. For a sense of his truer self, perhaps, behind the scenes, see "On the Beach" two years later.) Then there is Audrey Hepburn, by now a stellar and unique star trying to spread her wings into musicals (this was her first). She, as usual in her career, rose above her part and like Astaire was "herself" with such charm she keeps even weaker scenes going. When she's in them, which luckily she is in most of them by the second half. Hepburn also comes across as a superb model (appropriately thin, but not especially tall), and Avedon's photographs of her taken in conjunction with filming are iconic. They get incorporated into the movie directly, both in the scenes where Astaire creates some photos in his role, and in some of the cinematography which imitates Avedon's style (white backdrops, modern styling). In the end it's a great seeming movie with such huge flaws it's just another musical. But that's not fair, quite, so think of it as an up and down ride with some very very fine high points which make it worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable in spire of its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Funny Face" is a far from perfect film. But, considering that it stars Fred Astaire, it's still well worth watching. Anything with Astaire is worth watching! The film begins with an odd montage in which the audience is introduced to Maggie Prescott (Kay Thompson)--a wonderfully annoying lady who is THE expert on fashion. It seems she is out to find a new model with a new look and her photographer (Astaire) notices a lady that Maggie completely overlooked--cute little Jo, the girl at the bookstore (Audrey Hepburn). Jo is then signed with a big contract and goes to Paris for photo shoots and to make her a mega-star. In the process, she and her photographer fall in love. But, minor complications arise and it might just mean the two will go their separate ways. First, the good. A few of the songs are very nice and the film stars Astaire and Hepburn. It also has really lovely footage of Paris. If you've been to this city (like I have), it's a wonderful walk down memory lane and the city really is that beautiful. Now the not so good. The biggest problem is that Astaire is easily old enough to be Audrey's father--and I am sure that many in the audience must have thought that. Thirty years' difference is a lot. Also, while some of the songs were nice (particularly the Gershwin ones), a few of the numbers were pretty bad--such as the Florida song and dance number. Overall, the good does outweigh the bad and I suggest you see it. It's just that both stars did far better work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now we know what the word empathy means
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dimitri44
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a motion picture where Audrey Hepburn stunningly empathizes with the audience as well, more and more, all the way through to the very end of the movie. The lighthearted story line begins with high brow Audrey Hepburn employed as manager of an intellectual type bookstore in Greenwich Village, NYC, and her dream is to go to Paris where she can then attend lectures offered by someone who is said to be a Professor of Empathy. Meanwhile, Fred Astaire, a fashion photographer, also has the opportunity to implore Audrey Hepburn to empathize with his photographic work as well, which then leads to her being provided with free passage to Paris, as she also then becomes a great fashion model in turn. Towards the end, the Professor of Empathy turns out to be quite a bit younger than thought, and with Audrey, his idea of empathy turns out to be something unexpectedly more basic than also thought. Thus, Fred and Audrey certainly empathize with each other in a most dignified way in the end. Yes, in 1957, movies were generally quite a bit more dignified as well. Postscript: I recently bought the Paramount Home Entertainment (UK) DVD version of this movie, and I watched it carefully more than once. I now believe this is the best motion picture that Audrey Hepburn made. It's almost even as though George and Ira Gershwin, even from the hereafter, were waiting for Audrey Hepburn, and then she came.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Astaire makes this musical semi-watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dani-marie
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One would assume that combining the talents of director Stanley Donen, Fred Astaire, and Audrey Hepburn would produce one knockout of a film. The turnout is anything but. From the get go the film left me both disinterested and unimpressed, even as an avid fan of musicals. The only savior of the film was Fred Astaire, who makes the most of each lackluster song and dance. He also holds the only slightly intriguing character and dialogue, standing out from the remaining wreckage of the film, which is mostly fluff without entertainment. The film begins with "Think Pink", an off the wall number which holds zero place in the plot. Donen effectively demonstrates the coldness of Quality magazine and the fashion industry itself through Kay Thompson's character, while the mostly sarcastic and charming dialogue of Astaire's character contribute to the message. The wit in Astaire's dialogue is the writers' only vehicle to humor. Once Hepburn is introduced, her soft face is the only saving grace of her character. The writers have managed to create a leading lady without charm. In short: the writers create a stereotypical facade of an intellectual woman, further cheapening the plot. Hepburn's other musical roles feature her voice dubbed, which might have been the proper choice for this film. Not once does she seem fully immersed in the character or film. However, what could she have done with less than adequate material and a flat character to work with? Chemistry between Audrey and Fred would have helped tons. Despite thoughts in another reviews, age differences do not factor into any type of chemistry. Check out Gene Kelly and Leslie Caron in An American in Paris or Audrey and Cary Grant in Charade in which large age gaps do not get in the way of emotion between the actors. The production design and cinematography are small beauties, but do little to improve the soppy, one dimensional plot. As the plot progresses, our two leads inevitably fall in love (it is not evident of course) and one forgettable song after another only left me waiting for the film to improve. Instead of being amazed by the performers, I only wanted the song to end. Again, Astaire is the only performer that delivers, even through drab choreography. He is the only actor that infuses some form of charm and enthusiasm into both the songs and dances. By the end of the film, all you are left with is Paris eye candy and a flat, uninteresting script. And maybe a little Astaire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fred Snaps! Audrey Crackles! Kay Pops!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This original musical comedy is not based upon the 1927 Broadway Gershwin musical that starred Fred and Adele Astaire on the stage. It has been updated to the 1950's Greenwich Village where photographer Astaire and his merry models take over Audrey Hepburn's book store (long before some computer devise ran most bookstores out of business), leaving her with a huge mess to clean up. Realizing his error, Astaire helps her, and realizes, he too can make her a model. This is sort of a "My Fair Lady"/"Pygmallion" of the modeling industry, with Astaire playing Henry Higgins to Audrey's pre-"My Fair Lady" Eliza. Along with magazine editor Kay Thompson, the trio goes to Paris where Astaire and Rogers fall in love, she checks out the Latin Quarter, and the duo literally skate off into the sunset on a lily pad meant for two. Some people question the pairing of Astaire and Hepburn, citing their almost 30 year age difference as a major problem. I concur that Astaire was way too young for Leslie Caron in the entertaining but overlong "Daddy Long Legs", but his style fits much better with Audrey. Yes, the age difference is quite noticeable, but I don't get that creepy feeling here that I did with the waif-like Caron. Unlike "My Fair Lady", you get to hear Audrey sing here, and her voice fits her character. When she sings "How Long Has This Been Going On?", you really feel for her. Ironically, when Ms. Hepburn passed away, it was this song that helped me celebrate her life, not "Moon River" (which she also sings in "Breakfast at Tiffany's") or her dubbed songs in "My Fair Lady". Seeing this years ago on a double bill at the Castro Theatre with "Breakfast at Tiffany's", I was amused by the audience's reaction to various un-"P.C." remarks, particularly Astaire's rather sexist remark that in a relationship, it is the man who makes the decisions. But irregardless of that, this is still one of the loveliest musicals of the 1950's, and try not to think "music video" when Kay Thompson (all in beige) pops up with her models to sing "Think Pink", which by the way, she wouldn't be caught dead in. Then, in a dark room, Astaire sings the title song to Hepburn, appropriately lit for the song. In Paris, the trio sings (separately) the lively "Bonjour Paris!" which has many great visuals of the city of lights. This is an example of real art deco in movies way past the age of Paramount's classy romantic comedies and musicals. Astaire and Thompson get to become "hip" in an opium den when they break into "Clap Yo' Hands", one of the liveliest 1920's songs still being sung 90 years later. Acting wise, Thompson steals the show, playing a character that "Boosom Buddies"/"Two & a Half Men" supporting player Holland Taylor cut her teeth on. Stanley Donen, a veteran dancer and musical film director, turns a rather ordinary May/December romance into something special that remains as fresh today as it was 55 years ago.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Paris mis-match
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Colourful Stanley Donen movie featuring wonderful Parisian locations and the superb music of the Gershwin brothers...and that's about it. I believe this may have been Fred Astaire's last movie as the romantic lead and on the evidence here, it's easy to see why. His performance is utterly devoid of any passion or even discernible attraction to the young Audrey Hepburn, plus for once his solo dance routines seem just that, routine and while still danced consummately, somehow lacking in dynamism or invention. Hepburn gets a dream ticket herself, decked out in a succession of high-fashion costumes and even getting to sing and dance with the great man, without ever convincing the viewer that she's a natural in either discipline. Otherwise, she gets to mope and loon by turn, pretty much the two main attributes of her acting ability. Her dancing is passable at best, while her solo routine improvising to modern jazz in a smoky West Bank bar is toe-curlingly embarrassing. And we all know, I'm sure that neither of them could be considered outstanding singers and hearing Audrey's not-so-dulcet tones, one can easily see why she was overdubbed (against her wishes) in "My Fair Lady". The story has less substance than the fog over the Seine and hits a lowpoint near the end when an unlikely fellow-suitor emerges to contest Audrey's fair hand, her hero-philosopher who's much better-looking, not to mention much cleverer than old Fred. Yes it's the old why-would-she-fall-for-him conundrum that not unnaturally bedevilled the ageing Astaire's later films, but it's exaggerated even more here when contrasted with the ever-youthful looking Hepburn. The plot seeks to cash in and poke fun at Paris's post-war reputation for fashion and philosophy and certainly the settings, particularly the exteriors are luminously warm, but the humour is forced at best and lacking finesse. Director Donen employs some tricksy cinematography to mixed effect as he strains for modernity, but in the final analysis, like the pairing of the old Astaire with the young Hepburn, the marriage of traditional Hollywood musical characteristics with modern film-making ideas just clashes and doesn't come off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sumptuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-406-125589
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps the most exquisitely art-directed musical of them all, "Funny Face" is sheer delight. Forget the story (for the most part) and enjoy the remarkable Astaire-Hepburn-Thompson magic, the glorious Avedon titles and stills and the breathtaking cinematography. "Think Pink," "Bonjour Paris," "He Loves and She Loves" and many of the other numbers will transport you. It's very much a time capsule -- attitudes toward women are wince-worthy, the sneering at existentialism can be tiresome. The sophistication of the music -- a blend of Gershwin classics with three new songs by Roger Edens -- the dancing, the performances and, most of all, the physical production, more than compensate. Btw, the Edens songs provide some of the films best moments -- "Bonjour Paris, On How to Be Lovely" and the sly, stunning "Think Pink."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey is able to turn it, if not into gold, at least into silver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a stage musical entitled "Funny Face", written by&nbsp;George&nbsp;and&nbsp;Ira Gershwin in 1927, but it has a totally different plot to that of the film, although several of its songs are included. Jo Stockton, an assistant in a Greenwich Village&nbsp;bookshop, is discovered as a fashion model by Maggie Prescott, the editor of a prestigious fashion magazine, and&nbsp;Dick Avery, a famous fashion photographer. Jo, however, is something of an amateur intellectual, has a low opinion of the fashion industry and only goes along with Maggie and Dick's plans because they offer her an assignment in Paris, a city she has always wanted to visit because her greatest ambition is to meet the great philosopher&nbsp;Professor Emile Flostre, founder of the doctrine of empathicalism. (Flostre was clearly based upon Jean-Paul Sartre and his doctrine of existentialism). A romance grows up between Jo and Dick in Paris, but Dick finds he has a rival for her affections in the form of the professor, younger and better-looking than his real-life counterpart but no less lecherous. The film was a box-office flop when first released in 1957; it only made a profit when it was re-released seven years later following the huge success of&nbsp;Audrey Hepburn's only other musical, "My Fair Lady". It upset the film critic of "The Times" (aka The Thunderer) who thundered, "There is that in the film's attitude towards the "intellectual", whether in Greenwich Village or Paris, which offends. It is not amiable parody and it is not telling satire; it has its roots in the ill-based instinct to jeer, and its jeers are offensive." When we consider that these words were directed towards a light, frothy musical comedy, this looks like is a particularly po-faced example of a critic taking himself too seriously (although criticisms of the film's supposed "anti-intellectualism" still surface). The film's main target was not intellectuals but hypocrites (although it also sends up some of the inanities of the fashion industry). The point about Flostre is that he does not practise what he preaches; "empathicalism" is supposed to be all about putting oneself in the other person's shoes, but in his dealings with Jo he is only capable of thinking about himself. For all her book-learning, Jo's initial attitude towards Flostre is one of uncritical idol-worship and she still has to learn the important lesson that idols can have feet of clay. The "funny face" of the title is Jo herself, and the implication of the words of the title song is that, although she is not very attractive, Dick still loves her because she has got so much character and personality. So why, then, was, the Divine Audrey, the most luminously beautiful actress of her generation, cast in the role? Was this simply a piece of miscasting? The answer to that question is an emphatic "no". There are a few things wrong with the film, but Audrey is not one of them. The main mistake is the miscasting of the fifty-eight year-old Fred Astaire as the male lead. Although he shows that his advancing years have done little to diminish his dancing skills, away from the dance-floor he looks embarrassingly out-of-place as the lover of the twenty-eight year-old Audrey. Sometimes the teaming of Audrey with an older man paid off, as with Bogart in "Sabrina", but this is one case where it didn't. For all his faults I was rooting for Jo to end up with Flostre rather than Dick. The music is tuneful but not particularly memorable, apart from two songs, "'S Wonderful" and the title song, and the plot is a&nbsp;fairly banal one. There is, however, a good performance from Kay Thompson as the&nbsp;autocratic Maggie. (I wonder if this was the inspiration for Meryl Streep's portrayal of a similar character in "The Devil Wears Prada"). This was Thompson's only film appearance; she was best known in her day as a singer and musician and is best remembered today as a children's author. The dance numbers are well choreographed and the visual look of the film is an attractive one. The film's biggest plus, however, is the presence of Audrey Hepburn. She was one of those rare actresses with true star quality, by which I mean the ability to take any film and make it quite different from what it would have been with anyone else in the leading role. Few will be surprised that Audrey was a great dancer- she did, after all, train as a ballerina- but those who know the story of how she was not allowed to do her own singing in "My Fair Lady" will be surprised by&nbsp;what a melodious voice she had. (Certainly better than Astaire's). Her main contribution here, however, is neither her singing nor her dancing but simply the force of her personality. "Funny Face" is not a great film; it is in nothing like the same class as "My Fair Lady" or its director Stanley Donen's masterpiece "Singin' in the Rain". (Mind you, Donen seemed to spend most of the rest of his career trying to repeat the success of that great film without ever really pulling it off). It could have been a pretty dull musical, but Audrey transforms it into something memorable. Unlike King Midas she couldn't quite manage to turn everything she touched into gold. "Paris When It Sizzles" and "Two for the Road", for example, obstinately remain base metal despite her presence. "Funny Face" might not be pure gold, however, but at least Audrey is able to turn it into silver. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad, but I have seen so much better.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FUNNY FACE It was OK... but I was expecting more. I quite like musicals and when I heard that this one had Audrey Hepburn and Fred Astaire in it I thought it would be really good. The story is OK... it is about a fashion magazine photographer who finds a new model in the form of a book shop assistant. She doesn't want to be a model, but has always wanted to go to Paris to meet a philosopher. When she finds out that to be a model she has to go to Paris, she accepts. Then the photographer falls in love with her. The acting is not very good... but like I have mentioned in previous reviews, the acting is not very good in most musicals... but I like that. It makes the films more fun. Audrey and Fred both do good jobs though... they are both really good at singing and dancing which is what is needed for a musical. The film also stars Kay Thomson. I didn't feel like the songs were very good in this film. The thing I like about musicals is the songs need to be catchy and fun... Not one of the songs in this stuck in my head. I didn't feel like tapping my foot to any of them, but there was some very interesting dancing... especially from Audrey when she starts dancing in a pub. I don't know if I can call that dancing. haha. I will give this film 5 out of 10. It was quite good, but I was slightly disappointed. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Think Pink? Not in the Eisenhower-Nixon Years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dglink
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Splashy colors, Paris locations, Fred Astaire's dancing, Audrey Hepburn's pixie-ish charm, Stanley Donen's direction, and George Gershwin's music should have melded into an enduring musical classic in 1957's "Funny Face." However, the talented individuals involved produced a dated, clumsy film with but a few bright moments. Poor tweedy philosophizing shop girl is transformed into an elegant stylish fashion model, a "My Fair Lady" wannabe. While Audrey Hepburn is never convincing as a mousy clerk garbed in shades of drab, she comes alive in designer clothes, and, quicker than you can say "Givenchy," the character swaps her principles for a haircut and makeover, a walk down the runway, and a trip to Paris. Hepburn was often paired with older men in her films; however, Cary Grant, William Holden, and Gary Cooper had enough masculine sex appeal to be convincing love interest for a young woman. Fred Astaire, however, was never romantic material, even for those of his own age. In "Funny Face," Astaire in his late 50's is about 20 years older than Hepburn and looks it; oddly, neither the age difference nor Astaire's reason for advanced bachelorhood is ever remarked upon or mentioned in the script. Leonard Gershe's screenplay for "Funny Face" is planted firmly in the Eisenhower 1950's. Astaire's chauvinistic attitude, "the man asks the woman to dance," is archaic and would have been poison to a free-thinking young woman like Hepburn's Jo Stockton. Kay Thompson's magazine editor is a post-World War II stereotype of the working woman: unmarried, hard, bossy, mannish, and abrasive. Only in mid-20th-century America would a harem of lemming-like "yes-women" blindly follow Thompson and mindlessly praise her every mundane uttering. Further undermining the film's credibility, the supposed pictorial output of Dick Avery, a successful fashion photographer, and Maggie Prescott, editor of "Quality" magazine, is limp at best; Avery's photos are mediocre, and Prescott's earth-shattering idea is "think pink." As always, Fred Astaire's dancing is worth watching, and, although her singing is more flat than melodic and her dancing mixed, Hepburn is always a winning charmer. However, under Donen's direction, the film does not soar, but rather lumbers from clumsy number to embarrassing parody; bearded beatniks, soul-searching laments, Parisian dives, empathetic philosophers, and even fashion magazines seem so last century. "Funny Face" may be worth a view as a mid-20th-century curiosity piece, but otherwise the film is most suitable as source material to excerpt scenes for documentaries on Astaire and Hepburn. Most viewers will have to think pink to plod through "Funny Face."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some great ideas that get cobbled together with uneven direction...but the best is the best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny Face (1957) I was prepared to love this movie and it let me down even though it has two fabulous leads, the classic musical dance man Fred Astaire and the new star Audrey Hepburn. It even has its photography based on the work of Richard Avedon, and Astaire's character is based on him in his fashion work. I enjoyed it, but it depends too much on common formulas, which I normally don't mind, and it lacks cohesion, flow, and what you might just call magic. That it's partly shot in New York and then Paris (a famously rainy Paris during the shoot) you would think you could hardly go wrong. And in a way it doesn't go wrong overall. But the plot lacks energy, the romantic chemistry is missing (the two are really more like father and daughter), and the series of dance numbers is choppy and uneven. Because of all this, each song goes on too long and you itch for the next scene, and then that scene merely takes us back to the weak plot. If you focus on these weaknesses the movie starts to look almost terrible. Hepburn's transformation from a tweedy intellectual in a bookshop in Manhattan to the premiere runway in Paris sounds like dream come true stuff, but it isn't really convincing (or surprising, of course). The French counter-culture intellectual scene is fun idea but it doesn't push it very far, and the leading voice is played by an actor with no presence at all. Hepburn's interactions in this whole world are forced. Even the opening twenty minutes, which sets the tone, is rough sledding before out two leading actors appear. But focus on the strengths and there are some great moments. Like the series of photo shoots, one after another quickly spreading across the highlights of the city, is fun and stylish. A few of the dance numbers, though short of classic, are great fun, like the modern one in the French smokey bar and the one in the darkroom with the safelights on. In both of these, again, director Stanley Donen (a consummate pro at this stuff) let things drag on just a minute too long, which is a long time in a fast moving movie like this. Then there is Fred Astaire, at ease and warm and really wonderful. He doesn't get a chance to quite blow the doors off any of the dances, but he's still a joy to watch, dancing or just being his warm self. (He was initially a reluctant actor at this point in his life, but was still very active. For a sense of his truer self, perhaps, behind the scenes, see "On the Beach" two years later.) Then there is Audrey Hepburn, by now a stellar and unique star trying to spread her wings into musicals (this was her first). She, as usual in her career, rose above her part and like Astaire was "herself" with such charm she keeps even weaker scenes going. When she's in them, which luckily she is in most of them by the second half. Hepburn also comes across as a superb model (appropriately thin, but not especially tall), and Avedon's photographs of her taken in conjunction with filming are iconic. They get incorporated into the movie directly, both in the scenes where Astaire creates some photos in his role, and in some of the cinematography which imitates Avedon's style (white backdrops, modern styling). In the end it's a great seeming movie with such huge flaws it's just another musical. But that's not fair, quite, so think of it as an up and down ride with some very very fine high points which make it worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable in spire of its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Funny Face" is a far from perfect film. But, considering that it stars Fred Astaire, it's still well worth watching. Anything with Astaire is worth watching! The film begins with an odd montage in which the audience is introduced to Maggie Prescott (Kay Thompson)--a wonderfully annoying lady who is THE expert on fashion. It seems she is out to find a new model with a new look and her photographer (Astaire) notices a lady that Maggie completely overlooked--cute little Jo, the girl at the bookstore (Audrey Hepburn). Jo is then signed with a big contract and goes to Paris for photo shoots and to make her a mega-star. In the process, she and her photographer fall in love. But, minor complications arise and it might just mean the two will go their separate ways. First, the good. A few of the songs are very nice and the film stars Astaire and Hepburn. It also has really lovely footage of Paris. If you've been to this city (like I have), it's a wonderful walk down memory lane and the city really is that beautiful. Now the not so good. The biggest problem is that Astaire is easily old enough to be Audrey's father--and I am sure that many in the audience must have thought that. Thirty years' difference is a lot. Also, while some of the songs were nice (particularly the Gershwin ones), a few of the numbers were pretty bad--such as the Florida song and dance number. Overall, the good does outweigh the bad and I suggest you see it. It's just that both stars did far better work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now we know what the word empathy means
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dimitri44
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a motion picture where Audrey Hepburn stunningly empathizes with the audience as well, more and more, all the way through to the very end of the movie. The lighthearted story line begins with high brow Audrey Hepburn employed as manager of an intellectual type bookstore in Greenwich Village, NYC, and her dream is to go to Paris where she can then attend lectures offered by someone who is said to be a Professor of Empathy. Meanwhile, Fred Astaire, a fashion photographer, also has the opportunity to implore Audrey Hepburn to empathize with his photographic work as well, which then leads to her being provided with free passage to Paris, as she also then becomes a great fashion model in turn. Towards the end, the Professor of Empathy turns out to be quite a bit younger than thought, and with Audrey, his idea of empathy turns out to be something unexpectedly more basic than also thought. Thus, Fred and Audrey certainly empathize with each other in a most dignified way in the end. Yes, in 1957, movies were generally quite a bit more dignified as well. Postscript: I recently bought the Paramount Home Entertainment (UK) DVD version of this movie, and I watched it carefully more than once. I now believe this is the best motion picture that Audrey Hepburn made. It's almost even as though George and Ira Gershwin, even from the hereafter, were waiting for Audrey Hepburn, and then she came.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Astaire makes this musical semi-watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dani-marie
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One would assume that combining the talents of director Stanley Donen, Fred Astaire, and Audrey Hepburn would produce one knockout of a film. The turnout is anything but. From the get go the film left me both disinterested and unimpressed, even as an avid fan of musicals. The only savior of the film was Fred Astaire, who makes the most of each lackluster song and dance. He also holds the only slightly intriguing character and dialogue, standing out from the remaining wreckage of the film, which is mostly fluff without entertainment. The film begins with "Think Pink", an off the wall number which holds zero place in the plot. Donen effectively demonstrates the coldness of Quality magazine and the fashion industry itself through Kay Thompson's character, while the mostly sarcastic and charming dialogue of Astaire's character contribute to the message. The wit in Astaire's dialogue is the writers' only vehicle to humor. Once Hepburn is introduced, her soft face is the only saving grace of her character. The writers have managed to create a leading lady without charm. In short: the writers create a stereotypical facade of an intellectual woman, further cheapening the plot. Hepburn's other musical roles feature her voice dubbed, which might have been the proper choice for this film. Not once does she seem fully immersed in the character or film. However, what could she have done with less than adequate material and a flat character to work with? Chemistry between Audrey and Fred would have helped tons. Despite thoughts in another reviews, age differences do not factor into any type of chemistry. Check out Gene Kelly and Leslie Caron in An American in Paris or Audrey and Cary Grant in Charade in which large age gaps do not get in the way of emotion between the actors. The production design and cinematography are small beauties, but do little to improve the soppy, one dimensional plot. As the plot progresses, our two leads inevitably fall in love (it is not evident of course) and one forgettable song after another only left me waiting for the film to improve. Instead of being amazed by the performers, I only wanted the song to end. Again, Astaire is the only performer that delivers, even through drab choreography. He is the only actor that infuses some form of charm and enthusiasm into both the songs and dances. By the end of the film, all you are left with is Paris eye candy and a flat, uninteresting script. And maybe a little Astaire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fred Snaps! Audrey Crackles! Kay Pops!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This original musical comedy is not based upon the 1927 Broadway Gershwin musical that starred Fred and Adele Astaire on the stage. It has been updated to the 1950's Greenwich Village where photographer Astaire and his merry models take over Audrey Hepburn's book store (long before some computer devise ran most bookstores out of business), leaving her with a huge mess to clean up. Realizing his error, Astaire helps her, and realizes, he too can make her a model. This is sort of a "My Fair Lady"/"Pygmallion" of the modeling industry, with Astaire playing Henry Higgins to Audrey's pre-"My Fair Lady" Eliza. Along with magazine editor Kay Thompson, the trio goes to Paris where Astaire and Rogers fall in love, she checks out the Latin Quarter, and the duo literally skate off into the sunset on a lily pad meant for two. Some people question the pairing of Astaire and Hepburn, citing their almost 30 year age difference as a major problem. I concur that Astaire was way too young for Leslie Caron in the entertaining but overlong "Daddy Long Legs", but his style fits much better with Audrey. Yes, the age difference is quite noticeable, but I don't get that creepy feeling here that I did with the waif-like Caron. Unlike "My Fair Lady", you get to hear Audrey sing here, and her voice fits her character. When she sings "How Long Has This Been Going On?", you really feel for her. Ironically, when Ms. Hepburn passed away, it was this song that helped me celebrate her life, not "Moon River" (which she also sings in "Breakfast at Tiffany's") or her dubbed songs in "My Fair Lady". Seeing this years ago on a double bill at the Castro Theatre with "Breakfast at Tiffany's", I was amused by the audience's reaction to various un-"P.C." remarks, particularly Astaire's rather sexist remark that in a relationship, it is the man who makes the decisions. But irregardless of that, this is still one of the loveliest musicals of the 1950's, and try not to think "music video" when Kay Thompson (all in beige) pops up with her models to sing "Think Pink", which by the way, she wouldn't be caught dead in. Then, in a dark room, Astaire sings the title song to Hepburn, appropriately lit for the song. In Paris, the trio sings (separately) the lively "Bonjour Paris!" which has many great visuals of the city of lights. This is an example of real art deco in movies way past the age of Paramount's classy romantic comedies and musicals. Astaire and Thompson get to become "hip" in an opium den when they break into "Clap Yo' Hands", one of the liveliest 1920's songs still being sung 90 years later. Acting wise, Thompson steals the show, playing a character that "Boosom Buddies"/"Two & a Half Men" supporting player Holland Taylor cut her teeth on. Stanley Donen, a veteran dancer and musical film director, turns a rather ordinary May/December romance into something special that remains as fresh today as it was 55 years ago.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Paris mis-match
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Colourful Stanley Donen movie featuring wonderful Parisian locations and the superb music of the Gershwin brothers...and that's about it. I believe this may have been Fred Astaire's last movie as the romantic lead and on the evidence here, it's easy to see why. His performance is utterly devoid of any passion or even discernible attraction to the young Audrey Hepburn, plus for once his solo dance routines seem just that, routine and while still danced consummately, somehow lacking in dynamism or invention. Hepburn gets a dream ticket herself, decked out in a succession of high-fashion costumes and even getting to sing and dance with the great man, without ever convincing the viewer that she's a natural in either discipline. Otherwise, she gets to mope and loon by turn, pretty much the two main attributes of her acting ability. Her dancing is passable at best, while her solo routine improvising to modern jazz in a smoky West Bank bar is toe-curlingly embarrassing. And we all know, I'm sure that neither of them could be considered outstanding singers and hearing Audrey's not-so-dulcet tones, one can easily see why she was overdubbed (against her wishes) in "My Fair Lady". The story has less substance than the fog over the Seine and hits a lowpoint near the end when an unlikely fellow-suitor emerges to contest Audrey's fair hand, her hero-philosopher who's much better-looking, not to mention much cleverer than old Fred. Yes it's the old why-would-she-fall-for-him conundrum that not unnaturally bedevilled the ageing Astaire's later films, but it's exaggerated even more here when contrasted with the ever-youthful looking Hepburn. The plot seeks to cash in and poke fun at Paris's post-war reputation for fashion and philosophy and certainly the settings, particularly the exteriors are luminously warm, but the humour is forced at best and lacking finesse. Director Donen employs some tricksy cinematography to mixed effect as he strains for modernity, but in the final analysis, like the pairing of the old Astaire with the young Hepburn, the marriage of traditional Hollywood musical characteristics with modern film-making ideas just clashes and doesn't come off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sumptuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-406-125589
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps the most exquisitely art-directed musical of them all, "Funny Face" is sheer delight. Forget the story (for the most part) and enjoy the remarkable Astaire-Hepburn-Thompson magic, the glorious Avedon titles and stills and the breathtaking cinematography. "Think Pink," "Bonjour Paris," "He Loves and She Loves" and many of the other numbers will transport you. It's very much a time capsule -- attitudes toward women are wince-worthy, the sneering at existentialism can be tiresome. The sophistication of the music -- a blend of Gershwin classics with three new songs by Roger Edens -- the dancing, the performances and, most of all, the physical production, more than compensate. Btw, the Edens songs provide some of the films best moments -- "Bonjour Paris, On How to Be Lovely" and the sly, stunning "Think Pink."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Audrey is able to turn it, if not into gold, at least into silver
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James Hitchcock
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a stage musical entitled "Funny Face", written by&nbsp;George&nbsp;and&nbsp;Ira Gershwin in 1927, but it has a totally different plot to that of the film, although several of its songs are included. Jo Stockton, an assistant in a Greenwich Village&nbsp;bookshop, is discovered as a fashion model by Maggie Prescott, the editor of a prestigious fashion magazine, and&nbsp;Dick Avery, a famous fashion photographer. Jo, however, is something of an amateur intellectual, has a low opinion of the fashion industry and only goes along with Maggie and Dick's plans because they offer her an assignment in Paris, a city she has always wanted to visit because her greatest ambition is to meet the great philosopher&nbsp;Professor Emile Flostre, founder of the doctrine of empathicalism. (Flostre was clearly based upon Jean-Paul Sartre and his doctrine of existentialism). A romance grows up between Jo and Dick in Paris, but Dick finds he has a rival for her affections in the form of the professor, younger and better-looking than his real-life counterpart but no less lecherous. The film was a box-office flop when first released in 1957; it only made a profit when it was re-released seven years later following the huge success of&nbsp;Audrey Hepburn's only other musical, "My Fair Lady". It upset the film critic of "The Times" (aka The Thunderer) who thundered, "There is that in the film's attitude towards the "intellectual", whether in Greenwich Village or Paris, which offends. It is not amiable parody and it is not telling satire; it has its roots in the ill-based instinct to jeer, and its jeers are offensive." When we consider that these words were directed towards a light, frothy musical comedy, this looks like is a particularly po-faced example of a critic taking himself too seriously (although criticisms of the film's supposed "anti-intellectualism" still surface). The film's main target was not intellectuals but hypocrites (although it also sends up some of the inanities of the fashion industry). The point about Flostre is that he does not practise what he preaches; "empathicalism" is supposed to be all about putting oneself in the other person's shoes, but in his dealings with Jo he is only capable of thinking about himself. For all her book-learning, Jo's initial attitude towards Flostre is one of uncritical idol-worship and she still has to learn the important lesson that idols can have feet of clay. The "funny face" of the title is Jo herself, and the implication of the words of the title song is that, although she is not very attractive, Dick still loves her because she has got so much character and personality. So why, then, was, the Divine Audrey, the most luminously beautiful actress of her generation, cast in the role? Was this simply a piece of miscasting? The answer to that question is an emphatic "no". There are a few things wrong with the film, but Audrey is not one of them. The main mistake is the miscasting of the fifty-eight year-old Fred Astaire as the male lead. Although he shows that his advancing years have done little to diminish his dancing skills, away from the dance-floor he looks embarrassingly out-of-place as the lover of the twenty-eight year-old Audrey. Sometimes the teaming of Audrey with an older man paid off, as with Bogart in "Sabrina", but this is one case where it didn't. For all his faults I was rooting for Jo to end up with Flostre rather than Dick. The music is tuneful but not particularly memorable, apart from two songs, "'S Wonderful" and the title song, and the plot is a&nbsp;fairly banal one. There is, however, a good performance from Kay Thompson as the&nbsp;autocratic Maggie. (I wonder if this was the inspiration for Meryl Streep's portrayal of a similar character in "The Devil Wears Prada"). This was Thompson's only film appearance; she was best known in her day as a singer and musician and is best remembered today as a children's author. The dance numbers are well choreographed and the visual look of the film is an attractive one. The film's biggest plus, however, is the presence of Audrey Hepburn. She was one of those rare actresses with true star quality, by which I mean the ability to take any film and make it quite different from what it would have been with anyone else in the leading role. Few will be surprised that Audrey was a great dancer- she did, after all, train as a ballerina- but those who know the story of how she was not allowed to do her own singing in "My Fair Lady" will be surprised by&nbsp;what a melodious voice she had. (Certainly better than Astaire's). Her main contribution here, however, is neither her singing nor her dancing but simply the force of her personality. "Funny Face" is not a great film; it is in nothing like the same class as "My Fair Lady" or its director Stanley Donen's masterpiece "Singin' in the Rain". (Mind you, Donen seemed to spend most of the rest of his career trying to repeat the success of that great film without ever really pulling it off). It could have been a pretty dull musical, but Audrey transforms it into something memorable. Unlike King Midas she couldn't quite manage to turn everything she touched into gold. "Paris When It Sizzles" and "Two for the Road", for example, obstinately remain base metal despite her presence. "Funny Face" might not be pure gold, however, but at least Audrey is able to turn it into silver. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad, but I have seen so much better.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FUNNY FACE It was OK... but I was expecting more. I quite like musicals and when I heard that this one had Audrey Hepburn and Fred Astaire in it I thought it would be really good. The story is OK... it is about a fashion magazine photographer who finds a new model in the form of a book shop assistant. She doesn't want to be a model, but has always wanted to go to Paris to meet a philosopher. When she finds out that to be a model she has to go to Paris, she accepts. Then the photographer falls in love with her. The acting is not very good... but like I have mentioned in previous reviews, the acting is not very good in most musicals... but I like that. It makes the films more fun. Audrey and Fred both do good jobs though... they are both really good at singing and dancing which is what is needed for a musical. The film also stars Kay Thomson. I didn't feel like the songs were very good in this film. The thing I like about musicals is the songs need to be catchy and fun... Not one of the songs in this stuck in my head. I didn't feel like tapping my foot to any of them, but there was some very interesting dancing... especially from Audrey when she starts dancing in a pub. I don't know if I can call that dancing. haha. I will give this film 5 out of 10. It was quite good, but I was slightly disappointed. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Think Pink? Not in the Eisenhower-Nixon Years.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dglink
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Splashy colors, Paris locations, Fred Astaire's dancing, Audrey Hepburn's pixie-ish charm, Stanley Donen's direction, and George Gershwin's music should have melded into an enduring musical classic in 1957's "Funny Face." However, the talented individuals involved produced a dated, clumsy film with but a few bright moments. Poor tweedy philosophizing shop girl is transformed into an elegant stylish fashion model, a "My Fair Lady" wannabe. While Audrey Hepburn is never convincing as a mousy clerk garbed in shades of drab, she comes alive in designer clothes, and, quicker than you can say "Givenchy," the character swaps her principles for a haircut and makeover, a walk down the runway, and a trip to Paris. Hepburn was often paired with older men in her films; however, Cary Grant, William Holden, and Gary Cooper had enough masculine sex appeal to be convincing love interest for a young woman. Fred Astaire, however, was never romantic material, even for those of his own age. In "Funny Face," Astaire in his late 50's is about 20 years older than Hepburn and looks it; oddly, neither the age difference nor Astaire's reason for advanced bachelorhood is ever remarked upon or mentioned in the script. Leonard Gershe's screenplay for "Funny Face" is planted firmly in the Eisenhower 1950's. Astaire's chauvinistic attitude, "the man asks the woman to dance," is archaic and would have been poison to a free-thinking young woman like Hepburn's Jo Stockton. Kay Thompson's magazine editor is a post-World War II stereotype of the working woman: unmarried, hard, bossy, mannish, and abrasive. Only in mid-20th-century America would a harem of lemming-like "yes-women" blindly follow Thompson and mindlessly praise her every mundane uttering. Further undermining the film's credibility, the supposed pictorial output of Dick Avery, a successful fashion photographer, and Maggie Prescott, editor of "Quality" magazine, is limp at best; Avery's photos are mediocre, and Prescott's earth-shattering idea is "think pink." As always, Fred Astaire's dancing is worth watching, and, although her singing is more flat than melodic and her dancing mixed, Hepburn is always a winning charmer. However, under Donen's direction, the film does not soar, but rather lumbers from clumsy number to embarrassing parody; bearded beatniks, soul-searching laments, Parisian dives, empathetic philosophers, and even fashion magazines seem so last century. "Funny Face" may be worth a view as a mid-20th-century curiosity piece, but otherwise the film is most suitable as source material to excerpt scenes for documentaries on Astaire and Hepburn. Most viewers will have to think pink to plod through "Funny Face."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some great ideas that get cobbled together with uneven direction...but the best is the best!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Funny Face (1957) I was prepared to love this movie and it let me down even though it has two fabulous leads, the classic musical dance man Fred Astaire and the new star Audrey Hepburn. It even has its photography based on the work of Richard Avedon, and Astaire's character is based on him in his fashion work. I enjoyed it, but it depends too much on common formulas, which I normally don't mind, and it lacks cohesion, flow, and what you might just call magic. That it's partly shot in New York and then Paris (a famously rainy Paris during the shoot) you would think you could hardly go wrong. And in a way it doesn't go wrong overall. But the plot lacks energy, the romantic chemistry is missing (the two are really more like father and daughter), and the series of dance numbers is choppy and uneven. Because of all this, each song goes on too long and you itch for the next scene, and then that scene merely takes us back to the weak plot. If you focus on these weaknesses the movie starts to look almost terrible. Hepburn's transformation from a tweedy intellectual in a bookshop in Manhattan to the premiere runway in Paris sounds like dream come true stuff, but it isn't really convincing (or surprising, of course). The French counter-culture intellectual scene is fun idea but it doesn't push it very far, and the leading voice is played by an actor with no presence at all. Hepburn's interactions in this whole world are forced. Even the opening twenty minutes, which sets the tone, is rough sledding before out two leading actors appear. But focus on the strengths and there are some great moments. Like the series of photo shoots, one after another quickly spreading across the highlights of the city, is fun and stylish. A few of the dance numbers, though short of classic, are great fun, like the modern one in the French smokey bar and the one in the darkroom with the safelights on. In both of these, again, director Stanley Donen (a consummate pro at this stuff) let things drag on just a minute too long, which is a long time in a fast moving movie like this. Then there is Fred Astaire, at ease and warm and really wonderful. He doesn't get a chance to quite blow the doors off any of the dances, but he's still a joy to watch, dancing or just being his warm self. (He was initially a reluctant actor at this point in his life, but was still very active. For a sense of his truer self, perhaps, behind the scenes, see "On the Beach" two years later.) Then there is Audrey Hepburn, by now a stellar and unique star trying to spread her wings into musicals (this was her first). She, as usual in her career, rose above her part and like Astaire was "herself" with such charm she keeps even weaker scenes going. When she's in them, which luckily she is in most of them by the second half. Hepburn also comes across as a superb model (appropriately thin, but not especially tall), and Avedon's photographs of her taken in conjunction with filming are iconic. They get incorporated into the movie directly, both in the scenes where Astaire creates some photos in his role, and in some of the cinematography which imitates Avedon's style (white backdrops, modern styling). In the end it's a great seeming movie with such huge flaws it's just another musical. But that's not fair, quite, so think of it as an up and down ride with some very very fine high points which make it worth watching.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable in spire of its flaws
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Funny Face" is a far from perfect film. But, considering that it stars Fred Astaire, it's still well worth watching. Anything with Astaire is worth watching! The film begins with an odd montage in which the audience is introduced to Maggie Prescott (Kay Thompson)--a wonderfully annoying lady who is THE expert on fashion. It seems she is out to find a new model with a new look and her photographer (Astaire) notices a lady that Maggie completely overlooked--cute little Jo, the girl at the bookstore (Audrey Hepburn). Jo is then signed with a big contract and goes to Paris for photo shoots and to make her a mega-star. In the process, she and her photographer fall in love. But, minor complications arise and it might just mean the two will go their separate ways. First, the good. A few of the songs are very nice and the film stars Astaire and Hepburn. It also has really lovely footage of Paris. If you've been to this city (like I have), it's a wonderful walk down memory lane and the city really is that beautiful. Now the not so good. The biggest problem is that Astaire is easily old enough to be Audrey's father--and I am sure that many in the audience must have thought that. Thirty years' difference is a lot. Also, while some of the songs were nice (particularly the Gershwin ones), a few of the numbers were pretty bad--such as the Florida song and dance number. Overall, the good does outweigh the bad and I suggest you see it. It's just that both stars did far better work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Now we know what the word empathy means
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dimitri44
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a motion picture where Audrey Hepburn stunningly empathizes with the audience as well, more and more, all the way through to the very end of the movie. The lighthearted story line begins with high brow Audrey Hepburn employed as manager of an intellectual type bookstore in Greenwich Village, NYC, and her dream is to go to Paris where she can then attend lectures offered by someone who is said to be a Professor of Empathy. Meanwhile, Fred Astaire, a fashion photographer, also has the opportunity to implore Audrey Hepburn to empathize with his photographic work as well, which then leads to her being provided with free passage to Paris, as she also then becomes a great fashion model in turn. Towards the end, the Professor of Empathy turns out to be quite a bit younger than thought, and with Audrey, his idea of empathy turns out to be something unexpectedly more basic than also thought. Thus, Fred and Audrey certainly empathize with each other in a most dignified way in the end. Yes, in 1957, movies were generally quite a bit more dignified as well. Postscript: I recently bought the Paramount Home Entertainment (UK) DVD version of this movie, and I watched it carefully more than once. I now believe this is the best motion picture that Audrey Hepburn made. It's almost even as though George and Ira Gershwin, even from the hereafter, were waiting for Audrey Hepburn, and then she came.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Astaire makes this musical semi-watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dani-marie
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One would assume that combining the talents of director Stanley Donen, Fred Astaire, and Audrey Hepburn would produce one knockout of a film. The turnout is anything but. From the get go the film left me both disinterested and unimpressed, even as an avid fan of musicals. The only savior of the film was Fred Astaire, who makes the most of each lackluster song and dance. He also holds the only slightly intriguing character and dialogue, standing out from the remaining wreckage of the film, which is mostly fluff without entertainment. The film begins with "Think Pink", an off the wall number which holds zero place in the plot. Donen effectively demonstrates the coldness of Quality magazine and the fashion industry itself through Kay Thompson's character, while the mostly sarcastic and charming dialogue of Astaire's character contribute to the message. The wit in Astaire's dialogue is the writers' only vehicle to humor. Once Hepburn is introduced, her soft face is the only saving grace of her character. The writers have managed to create a leading lady without charm. In short: the writers create a stereotypical facade of an intellectual woman, further cheapening the plot. Hepburn's other musical roles feature her voice dubbed, which might have been the proper choice for this film. Not once does she seem fully immersed in the character or film. However, what could she have done with less than adequate material and a flat character to work with? Chemistry between Audrey and Fred would have helped tons. Despite thoughts in another reviews, age differences do not factor into any type of chemistry. Check out Gene Kelly and Leslie Caron in An American in Paris or Audrey and Cary Grant in Charade in which large age gaps do not get in the way of emotion between the actors. The production design and cinematography are small beauties, but do little to improve the soppy, one dimensional plot. As the plot progresses, our two leads inevitably fall in love (it is not evident of course) and one forgettable song after another only left me waiting for the film to improve. Instead of being amazed by the performers, I only wanted the song to end. Again, Astaire is the only performer that delivers, even through drab choreography. He is the only actor that infuses some form of charm and enthusiasm into both the songs and dances. By the end of the film, all you are left with is Paris eye candy and a flat, uninteresting script. And maybe a little Astaire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fred Snaps! Audrey Crackles! Kay Pops!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This original musical comedy is not based upon the 1927 Broadway Gershwin musical that starred Fred and Adele Astaire on the stage. It has been updated to the 1950's Greenwich Village where photographer Astaire and his merry models take over Audrey Hepburn's book store (long before some computer devise ran most bookstores out of business), leaving her with a huge mess to clean up. Realizing his error, Astaire helps her, and realizes, he too can make her a model. This is sort of a "My Fair Lady"/"Pygmallion" of the modeling industry, with Astaire playing Henry Higgins to Audrey's pre-"My Fair Lady" Eliza. Along with magazine editor Kay Thompson, the trio goes to Paris where Astaire and Rogers fall in love, she checks out the Latin Quarter, and the duo literally skate off into the sunset on a lily pad meant for two. Some people question the pairing of Astaire and Hepburn, citing their almost 30 year age difference as a major problem. I concur that Astaire was way too young for Leslie Caron in the entertaining but overlong "Daddy Long Legs", but his style fits much better with Audrey. Yes, the age difference is quite noticeable, but I don't get that creepy feeling here that I did with the waif-like Caron. Unlike "My Fair Lady", you get to hear Audrey sing here, and her voice fits her character. When she sings "How Long Has This Been Going On?", you really feel for her. Ironically, when Ms. Hepburn passed away, it was this song that helped me celebrate her life, not "Moon River" (which she also sings in "Breakfast at Tiffany's") or her dubbed songs in "My Fair Lady". Seeing this years ago on a double bill at the Castro Theatre with "Breakfast at Tiffany's", I was amused by the audience's reaction to various un-"P.C." remarks, particularly Astaire's rather sexist remark that in a relationship, it is the man who makes the decisions. But irregardless of that, this is still one of the loveliest musicals of the 1950's, and try not to think "music video" when Kay Thompson (all in beige) pops up with her models to sing "Think Pink", which by the way, she wouldn't be caught dead in. Then, in a dark room, Astaire sings the title song to Hepburn, appropriately lit for the song. In Paris, the trio sings (separately) the lively "Bonjour Paris!" which has many great visuals of the city of lights. This is an example of real art deco in movies way past the age of Paramount's classy romantic comedies and musicals. Astaire and Thompson get to become "hip" in an opium den when they break into "Clap Yo' Hands", one of the liveliest 1920's songs still being sung 90 years later. Acting wise, Thompson steals the show, playing a character that "Boosom Buddies"/"Two & a Half Men" supporting player Holland Taylor cut her teeth on. Stanley Donen, a veteran dancer and musical film director, turns a rather ordinary May/December romance into something special that remains as fresh today as it was 55 years ago.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Paris mis-match
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Colourful Stanley Donen movie featuring wonderful Parisian locations and the superb music of the Gershwin brothers...and that's about it. I believe this may have been Fred Astaire's last movie as the romantic lead and on the evidence here, it's easy to see why. His performance is utterly devoid of any passion or even discernible attraction to the young Audrey Hepburn, plus for once his solo dance routines seem just that, routine and while still danced consummately, somehow lacking in dynamism or invention. Hepburn gets a dream ticket herself, decked out in a succession of high-fashion costumes and even getting to sing and dance with the great man, without ever convincing the viewer that she's a natural in either discipline. Otherwise, she gets to mope and loon by turn, pretty much the two main attributes of her acting ability. Her dancing is passable at best, while her solo routine improvising to modern jazz in a smoky West Bank bar is toe-curlingly embarrassing. And we all know, I'm sure that neither of them could be considered outstanding singers and hearing Audrey's not-so-dulcet tones, one can easily see why she was overdubbed (against her wishes) in "My Fair Lady". The story has less substance than the fog over the Seine and hits a lowpoint near the end when an unlikely fellow-suitor emerges to contest Audrey's fair hand, her hero-philosopher who's much better-looking, not to mention much cleverer than old Fred. Yes it's the old why-would-she-fall-for-him conundrum that not unnaturally bedevilled the ageing Astaire's later films, but it's exaggerated even more here when contrasted with the ever-youthful looking Hepburn. The plot seeks to cash in and poke fun at Paris's post-war reputation for fashion and philosophy and certainly the settings, particularly the exteriors are luminously warm, but the humour is forced at best and lacking finesse. Director Donen employs some tricksy cinematography to mixed effect as he strains for modernity, but in the final analysis, like the pairing of the old Astaire with the young Hepburn, the marriage of traditional Hollywood musical characteristics with modern film-making ideas just clashes and doesn't come off.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sumptuous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stuart-406-125589
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps the most exquisitely art-directed musical of them all, "Funny Face" is sheer delight. Forget the story (for the most part) and enjoy the remarkable Astaire-Hepburn-Thompson magic, the glorious Avedon titles and stills and the breathtaking cinematography. "Think Pink," "Bonjour Paris," "He Loves and She Loves" and many of the other numbers will transport you. It's very much a time capsule -- attitudes toward women are wince-worthy, the sneering at existentialism can be tiresome. The sophistication of the music -- a blend of Gershwin classics with three new songs by Roger Edens -- the dancing, the performances and, most of all, the physical production, more than compensate. Btw, the Edens songs provide some of the films best moments -- "Bonjour Paris, On How to Be Lovely" and the sly, stunning "Think Pink."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
