<filme>
 <id>
  968
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0041509
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1949
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Inspetor Geral
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An illiterate stooge in a traveling medicine show wanders into a strange town and is picked up on a vagrancy charge. The town's corrupt officials mistake him for the inspector general whom ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  An illiterate stooge in a traveling medicine show wanders into a strange town and is picked up on a vagrancy charge. The town's corrupt officials mistake him for the inspector general whom they think is traveling in disguise. Fearing he will discover they've been pocketing tax money, they make several bungled attempts to kill him.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Musical
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   medicine show
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   corruption
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   snake oil
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bribery
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   screwball
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Henry Koster
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Philip Rapp
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Harry Kurnitz
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Danny Kaye
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Walter Slezak
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Barbara Bates
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Happy Times with this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Danny Kaye got one of his most enduring and funniest parts in this adaption of Gogol's The Inspector General. Kaye suited the part very well and Warner Brothers provided him with a generous cast of familiar character players. Kaye brings a lot of laughs as well as pathos to the part of the poor illiterate schnook who is a stooge for Walter Slezak, an itinerant peddler of snake oil known as Yakov's Elixir. After they get thrown out of one town due to Kaye's bumbling, Slezak cuts him adrift. But our Danny falls into a gold mine in the next town as he arrives there poor and hungry. It seems as though the city fathers have gotten word that The Inspector General, personal emissary of the Emperor is coming to town and he's been known to go places incognito and then reveal himself and all the fraud he uncovers. The paranoid city fathers of Brodny who include such people as Gene Lockhart, Alan Hale, Byron Foulger all start fawning all over Kaye who decides to just go with the flow. That policy is encouraged by Slezak who arrives in Brodny and sees the great possibilities here. The Inspector General is one of my favorite films with Danny Kaye, he's so right for the part. This was his first film away from Sam Goldwyn and Warner Brothers managed to give this film the same kind of production values you would find in a Goldwyn production. Mrs. Kaye, aka Sylvia Fine wrote the score for The Inspector General and gave her husband one of his best film songs, Happy Times which he sings to Barbara Bates who plays a serving girl at the local inn. Kaye also has to fend off the amorous advances of Elsa Lanchester who is Lockhart's wife and who is no slouch at getting a few laughs herself. The Inspector General is a timeless classic, taken from a classic and is one of the best showcases for the many talents of Danny Kaye.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whether you like it all depends on how much you like Kaye's routine....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Danny Kaye's musical comedy isn't something that has aged all that well. Back in the 40s and 50s, he was VERY popular and his films packed the theaters. However, I really believe that his style is something that will have a very mixed reaction today. Some, of course, probably still love Kaye and adore his antics and musical routines. And, others, like myself, will find him tedious. When he sings and makes his silly grimaces, it pains me--which is a shame, as the plot itself of "The Inspector General" is actually pretty good. Danny plays Georgi--a poor and slightly crooked man. He assists in a patent medicine show run by a seriously crooked guy (Walter Slezak). When he loses this job, he's very hungry and manages to get arrested--but not a meal. However, when the townspeople mistakenly believe that he's the Inspector General in disguise, suddenly they begin lavishing him with praise and gifts. But, the mayor and his officers know that they must do something else--they must kill the Inspector General to keep their thieving ways a secret. This isn't a problem for Kaye, as he's about to run out of town as soon as humanly possible--but he can't when his old boss shows up and insists that Kaye stay and milk the town for all it's worth. If the film was a bit more subtle, I would have loved it. It did have a lot of clever moments--but it also had Kaye hamming it up something awful at times as well. Overall, a mixed bag--worth seeing but lacking at the same time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh, I have no wife. None of my family had wives. My father didn't like wives. I mean, my mother didn't like my father's wives.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Danny Kaye was a wonderful performer, he would sing, dance, tell jokes, turn his face into rubber and just generally come off as a quality humanitarian. The Inspector General showcases all of those talents. Directed by Henry Koster, The Inspector General is loosely adapted from Nikolai Gogol's classic Russian story, and it finds Kaye as a stooge of Walter Slezak's iffy tonic peddler who is mistaken by iffy officials of a small Russian town for the much feared and respected Inspector General. Cue mistaken identity mayhem as the music numbers, gags, visual contortions and all round slapstick ensues. Along for the ride are Elsa Lanchester, Alan Hale, Barbara Bates and Gene Lockhart. It's more a safe and solid Kaye movie for the family to enjoy, rather than a high end classic like The Court Jester, but sometimes the high energy jinks of Kaye is all you need to lift the blues away. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterpiece of play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artioannidis
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a great movie ...A good old movie , the way the movies tried to entertain people as were meant to be played in theaters , with the free style actors based on their talent and instict.. The best man for this role would have been Danny Kaye at its best , talent of musical , fun , singing.. The plot is very very interesting and the cast of characters so humorous .. I have watched this movie more than 20 times and every time i m excited even more .. The part of Be arrogant , be elegant , be smart and the gypsy drinking song are so nice .. To sum up , a very good set up movie with a phenomenal unique talented Danny Kaye .. Everyone should watch
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ready, set, Gogol
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I understand it, Henry Koster's movie version of "The Inspector General" is only a loose adaptation of Nikolai Gogol's play. But even so, it's a really fun movie. Danny Kaye provides a lot of fun as a illiterate drifter who gets mistaken for a government inspector in a town overrun with corruption in Napoleon-era France. There are a couple of scenes in the movie that truly elicit a lot of humor, and the songs -- which Kaye's wife Sylvia wrote -- just go to show what one can do with a language. There are a few slow scenes, but mostly it's a really entertaining piece of work. I'm going to have to see if I can find a production of Gogol's original play (called "Revizor" in Russian, often called "The Government Inspector" in English). Also starring Walter Slezak (the Clock King on the 1960s "Batman" show), Gene Lockhart, Barbara Bates, Elsa Lanchester (the Bride of Frankenstein), Alan Hale Sr. (yes, the Skipper's father) and Rhys Williams. PS: Another one of Nikolai Gogol's notable stories is the horror short story "Viy", which Mario Bava filmed as "Black Sunday" starring Barbara Steele.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Danny Kaye with a mistaken identity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Georgi is member of a wandering band of Gypsies led by Yakov.Our illiterate hero escapes after he innocently lets slip that the elixir they're selling is a fraud.He finds a town named Brodny and gets arrested as a vagrant.He's sentenced to be hanged the next day.The town is most corrupted, and there is a rumor the inspector general is coming, and he'd be wearing a disguise.Then they realize Georgi must be the inspector, which he's obviously isn't.In the town there's a sweet girl named Leza, and they're both attracted to each other.The Inspector General is a musical comedy from 1949 directed by Henry Koster.It's loosely based on Nikolai Gogol's play, which I read last year.Johnny Green won a Golden Globe for Best Motion Picture Score.Kaye's wife Sylvia Fine wrote the original songs "The Inspector General" and Happy Times".Danny Kaye is really something as Georgi.Walter Slezak does excellent work as Yakov.Barbara Bates, who met a tragic end by her own hands, is wonderful as Leza.Elsa Lanchester is glorious as Maria.Gene Lockhart is great as The Mayor.Alan Hale is terrific as Kovatch.Walter Catlett does a great job as Colonel Castine.Rhys Williams is very good as Inspector General.Lew and Sam Hearn are funny as Izzick and Gizzick.I bought this movie on a DVD some time ago, and watched it a few days ago.I really enjoyed it.Danny Kaye was a really gifted comedian, and knew how to make people laugh.He followed the traditions of the early clowns but had his own unique style.A scene that makes you laugh is the eating scene, where he finds it very difficult to get anything in his mouth.It's a very funny scene where people keep coming to his room and he keeps hiding them.It's most hilarious how he sings "Gypsy Drinking Song" holding the glass filled with poison in his hand.For every Danny Kaye fan this film is a treat that can't be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warner Bros. Rolls Out the Technicolor Carpet for Danny Kaye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Danny Kaye stars in this musical comedy about a case of mistaken identity and the poor fool caught in the middle of it. Georgi (Kaye) is an illiterate member of a traveling medicine show who is mistaken by a small Russian village as the Inspector General, a royal official with vast powers. While the local government officials plot to bribe or kill him, Georgi ingrains himself into the public's favor all the while trying to find a way out of his situation," according to the DVD sleeve description. Mr. Kaye's films usually fall into one of two categories - they can either be enjoyed by almost everyone in the average film-going public, or they mainly appeal to those already inclined to admire Kaye. The latter films will sometimes show the strains of a story "showcase" vehicle, while the more universally appealing films feature Kaye using his skills to more naturally essay a character. "The Inspector General" is a good example of the latter. Many of the gags fall flat, and the plot is laboriously adapted from the satirical Russian classic. Look for impressive Ida Moore in a great bit as the old "mother" Kaye wards off his potion. ***** The Inspector General (12/30/49) Henry Koster ~ Danny Kaye, Walter Slezak, Elsa Lanchester, Gene Lockhart
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as Silly as Some Might Think.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a little difficult to grasp the notion of Danny Kaye, one of his era's premier farceurs, being the lead in a story from the 1840s by a Russian dramatist. We all know those Russian plays had more clouds of gray than any song by George Gershwin could guarantee. But, though I haven't read Gogol's story, he was one of those gloomy Russkies who happened to have a sense of humor, sarcastic and cynical though it might have been. It's the Napoleonic era in Middle Europe. Every town in the regime is corrupt in varying degrees and Napoleon has sent an Inspector General to clean things up. The Inspector General has Napoleon's power of attorney. He generally enters a town in some humble disguise -- a tinker, a salesman, an utter nobody -- then snoops around until he uncovers the miscreants, who he then promptly hangs. Nobody knows what he looks like. Kaye is a shill for a snake oil salesman, Walter Slezak in the most outrageously villainous bad-guy make up since Mack Swain, Chaplin's gorilla. When Kaye tries to stop an old lady from spending all her money on Slezak's cure-all to save her dying husband -- it's really furniture polish -- Slezak overhears the conversation and kicks Kaye out. Kaye then turns into a starving tramp. He wanders from town to town, trying to steal bits of food from dogs. But in the village of Brodny, misleading evidence comes to light that he is the Inspector General in disguise. So instead of being hanged for a thief, he's feted by the terrified corrupt town officials. He spends most of the movie strutting around in resplendent garb, trying to imitate a self-possessed pal of Napoleon or, alternatively, trying desperately to have his real identity hidden from the public. This spoiled identity becomes especially problematic after Slezak shows up, recognizes him for the buffoon he is, and manipulates him to extort bribes from the officials. Kaye handles the role pretty well, actually, as unlikely as it sounds. Well, why not? So it's a farce. I doubt that Gogol's original play had the fake Inspector General singing gibberish songs, but somehow it fits. Kaye's usual cowardly and neurotic persona is imposed on what I imagine to have been an amusing but relatively grounded story. If W. C. Fields could play Mr. Micawber in Charles Dickens' "David Copperfield", why not Kaye as a jiggling and stuttering Inspector General? The plot is too logical to allow for many of Kaye's set pieces. The gibberish songs (by his then-wife, Sylvia Fine) aren't as funny as some of his earlier ones. The gags, though muted, are imposed on a narrative that is funny in itself and this makes up, to some extent, for our watching a Danny Kaye who is in harness to the plot. There isn't as much mindless sentiment as there were in some of Kaye's lesser vehicles -- no sick children or any of that crap. Barbara Bates as the housemaid is Kaye's love interest, such as it is. Bates, an exquisite young woman of modest talent, was the underhanded high-school girl Phoebe who shows up at the end of "All About Eve." Here, in period wardrobe, she's just another pretty face, but it doesn't matter because her part isn't particularly important. Anyway, I kind of enjoyed it. Kaye does a lot of jumping around and shuffling of objects and there are some laughs in it, desperately needed in these too-laughless times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dated humor style, timeless subject matter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CEdWright
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Danny Kaye appealed most to our parents'/grandparents' generation, with their better appreciation of the often inane humor that entertainers like Danny Kaye provided: Overplayed, with sight or sound gags milked for all they're worth and then some. It was an easier, simpler time for entertainers, when slapstick was king and The Three Stooges and Abbott & Costello were the gold standard, with the later rise & fall of the Smothers Brothers marking the end of that era. But there were also the sort of more subtle gag lines and themes that still appeal to our more developed, sophisticated senses of humor. A fine example of this, "alone worth the price of admission" to this film, is where one of those corrupt officials, noted in other comments above, at first repeats about Georgi, "Less and less I like this Yakobovich...!" but as time goes on, and Georgi wins hearts & minds, his tune changes to repeating, "More and more I like this Yakobovich!" Gogol's original play was a bitter satire about corruption in Tsarist Russia, a theme and storyline that would likely puzzle Western audiences. Perhaps the greater familiarity of Napoleon as "the Emperor" in place of the Tsar -- also an emperor -- inspired the screenplay author to change the setting from Russia to some vague 'Eastern European' town, retaining the Russian names & even pseudo-accent, that may have fallen into Napoleon's empire for a while; making this film less about the Russian (pre-Soviet-Communist-during-the-Cold-War) Bear than about the rampant silliness of pervasive small-town petty and not-so-petty corruption even as still practiced today in many small towns in America. A fine farce based on real life in Russia originally, in mythical small towns in Europe then, and in our very real home towns today: Over centuries and across millions of miles, only the names on the doors have changed; from big city graft to small town vice, the only real difference is in the size of the numbers. Some say this movie is merely a vehicle for Danny Kaye; actually, only Danny Kaye could make us laugh at all the routine petty criminality encompassed in the saying, "You can't fight City Hall." All you need to do to ENJOY this wonderful timeless parody of malodorous malingering municipal malapropism & malfeasances is to willingly suspend any modern expectation of & insistence upon sophisticated authenticity & realism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The inspector General
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tombancroft2
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a fan of Danny Kaye, but I have to say that this is one of his poorest films. Too many silly songs which don't do justice to his fine voice and a weak plot line. "The Court Jester" and "Walter Mitty" are far superior. However, the finest Danny Kaye film in my humble view is "Hans Christian Anderson". The stories of Anderson are timeless and the songs in the film were big hits at the time and have since become classics (Inch Worm, Ugly Duckling, Thumbellina, I'm Hans Christian Anderson, etc.). Danny Kaye was a crooner almost in the Crosby class and his talents are wasted in the "Inspector General". The odd silly song is o.k, but there are too many in this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Happy Times with this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Danny Kaye got one of his most enduring and funniest parts in this adaption of Gogol's The Inspector General. Kaye suited the part very well and Warner Brothers provided him with a generous cast of familiar character players. Kaye brings a lot of laughs as well as pathos to the part of the poor illiterate schnook who is a stooge for Walter Slezak, an itinerant peddler of snake oil known as Yakov's Elixir. After they get thrown out of one town due to Kaye's bumbling, Slezak cuts him adrift. But our Danny falls into a gold mine in the next town as he arrives there poor and hungry. It seems as though the city fathers have gotten word that The Inspector General, personal emissary of the Emperor is coming to town and he's been known to go places incognito and then reveal himself and all the fraud he uncovers. The paranoid city fathers of Brodny who include such people as Gene Lockhart, Alan Hale, Byron Foulger all start fawning all over Kaye who decides to just go with the flow. That policy is encouraged by Slezak who arrives in Brodny and sees the great possibilities here. The Inspector General is one of my favorite films with Danny Kaye, he's so right for the part. This was his first film away from Sam Goldwyn and Warner Brothers managed to give this film the same kind of production values you would find in a Goldwyn production. Mrs. Kaye, aka Sylvia Fine wrote the score for The Inspector General and gave her husband one of his best film songs, Happy Times which he sings to Barbara Bates who plays a serving girl at the local inn. Kaye also has to fend off the amorous advances of Elsa Lanchester who is Lockhart's wife and who is no slouch at getting a few laughs herself. The Inspector General is a timeless classic, taken from a classic and is one of the best showcases for the many talents of Danny Kaye.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whether you like it all depends on how much you like Kaye's routine....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Danny Kaye's musical comedy isn't something that has aged all that well. Back in the 40s and 50s, he was VERY popular and his films packed the theaters. However, I really believe that his style is something that will have a very mixed reaction today. Some, of course, probably still love Kaye and adore his antics and musical routines. And, others, like myself, will find him tedious. When he sings and makes his silly grimaces, it pains me--which is a shame, as the plot itself of "The Inspector General" is actually pretty good. Danny plays Georgi--a poor and slightly crooked man. He assists in a patent medicine show run by a seriously crooked guy (Walter Slezak). When he loses this job, he's very hungry and manages to get arrested--but not a meal. However, when the townspeople mistakenly believe that he's the Inspector General in disguise, suddenly they begin lavishing him with praise and gifts. But, the mayor and his officers know that they must do something else--they must kill the Inspector General to keep their thieving ways a secret. This isn't a problem for Kaye, as he's about to run out of town as soon as humanly possible--but he can't when his old boss shows up and insists that Kaye stay and milk the town for all it's worth. If the film was a bit more subtle, I would have loved it. It did have a lot of clever moments--but it also had Kaye hamming it up something awful at times as well. Overall, a mixed bag--worth seeing but lacking at the same time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh, I have no wife. None of my family had wives. My father didn't like wives. I mean, my mother didn't like my father's wives.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Danny Kaye was a wonderful performer, he would sing, dance, tell jokes, turn his face into rubber and just generally come off as a quality humanitarian. The Inspector General showcases all of those talents. Directed by Henry Koster, The Inspector General is loosely adapted from Nikolai Gogol's classic Russian story, and it finds Kaye as a stooge of Walter Slezak's iffy tonic peddler who is mistaken by iffy officials of a small Russian town for the much feared and respected Inspector General. Cue mistaken identity mayhem as the music numbers, gags, visual contortions and all round slapstick ensues. Along for the ride are Elsa Lanchester, Alan Hale, Barbara Bates and Gene Lockhart. It's more a safe and solid Kaye movie for the family to enjoy, rather than a high end classic like The Court Jester, but sometimes the high energy jinks of Kaye is all you need to lift the blues away. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterpiece of play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artioannidis
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a great movie ...A good old movie , the way the movies tried to entertain people as were meant to be played in theaters , with the free style actors based on their talent and instict.. The best man for this role would have been Danny Kaye at its best , talent of musical , fun , singing.. The plot is very very interesting and the cast of characters so humorous .. I have watched this movie more than 20 times and every time i m excited even more .. The part of Be arrogant , be elegant , be smart and the gypsy drinking song are so nice .. To sum up , a very good set up movie with a phenomenal unique talented Danny Kaye .. Everyone should watch
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ready, set, Gogol
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I understand it, Henry Koster's movie version of "The Inspector General" is only a loose adaptation of Nikolai Gogol's play. But even so, it's a really fun movie. Danny Kaye provides a lot of fun as a illiterate drifter who gets mistaken for a government inspector in a town overrun with corruption in Napoleon-era France. There are a couple of scenes in the movie that truly elicit a lot of humor, and the songs -- which Kaye's wife Sylvia wrote -- just go to show what one can do with a language. There are a few slow scenes, but mostly it's a really entertaining piece of work. I'm going to have to see if I can find a production of Gogol's original play (called "Revizor" in Russian, often called "The Government Inspector" in English). Also starring Walter Slezak (the Clock King on the 1960s "Batman" show), Gene Lockhart, Barbara Bates, Elsa Lanchester (the Bride of Frankenstein), Alan Hale Sr. (yes, the Skipper's father) and Rhys Williams. PS: Another one of Nikolai Gogol's notable stories is the horror short story "Viy", which Mario Bava filmed as "Black Sunday" starring Barbara Steele.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Danny Kaye with a mistaken identity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Georgi is member of a wandering band of Gypsies led by Yakov.Our illiterate hero escapes after he innocently lets slip that the elixir they're selling is a fraud.He finds a town named Brodny and gets arrested as a vagrant.He's sentenced to be hanged the next day.The town is most corrupted, and there is a rumor the inspector general is coming, and he'd be wearing a disguise.Then they realize Georgi must be the inspector, which he's obviously isn't.In the town there's a sweet girl named Leza, and they're both attracted to each other.The Inspector General is a musical comedy from 1949 directed by Henry Koster.It's loosely based on Nikolai Gogol's play, which I read last year.Johnny Green won a Golden Globe for Best Motion Picture Score.Kaye's wife Sylvia Fine wrote the original songs "The Inspector General" and Happy Times".Danny Kaye is really something as Georgi.Walter Slezak does excellent work as Yakov.Barbara Bates, who met a tragic end by her own hands, is wonderful as Leza.Elsa Lanchester is glorious as Maria.Gene Lockhart is great as The Mayor.Alan Hale is terrific as Kovatch.Walter Catlett does a great job as Colonel Castine.Rhys Williams is very good as Inspector General.Lew and Sam Hearn are funny as Izzick and Gizzick.I bought this movie on a DVD some time ago, and watched it a few days ago.I really enjoyed it.Danny Kaye was a really gifted comedian, and knew how to make people laugh.He followed the traditions of the early clowns but had his own unique style.A scene that makes you laugh is the eating scene, where he finds it very difficult to get anything in his mouth.It's a very funny scene where people keep coming to his room and he keeps hiding them.It's most hilarious how he sings "Gypsy Drinking Song" holding the glass filled with poison in his hand.For every Danny Kaye fan this film is a treat that can't be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warner Bros. Rolls Out the Technicolor Carpet for Danny Kaye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Danny Kaye stars in this musical comedy about a case of mistaken identity and the poor fool caught in the middle of it. Georgi (Kaye) is an illiterate member of a traveling medicine show who is mistaken by a small Russian village as the Inspector General, a royal official with vast powers. While the local government officials plot to bribe or kill him, Georgi ingrains himself into the public's favor all the while trying to find a way out of his situation," according to the DVD sleeve description. Mr. Kaye's films usually fall into one of two categories - they can either be enjoyed by almost everyone in the average film-going public, or they mainly appeal to those already inclined to admire Kaye. The latter films will sometimes show the strains of a story "showcase" vehicle, while the more universally appealing films feature Kaye using his skills to more naturally essay a character. "The Inspector General" is a good example of the latter. Many of the gags fall flat, and the plot is laboriously adapted from the satirical Russian classic. Look for impressive Ida Moore in a great bit as the old "mother" Kaye wards off his potion. ***** The Inspector General (12/30/49) Henry Koster ~ Danny Kaye, Walter Slezak, Elsa Lanchester, Gene Lockhart
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as Silly as Some Might Think.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a little difficult to grasp the notion of Danny Kaye, one of his era's premier farceurs, being the lead in a story from the 1840s by a Russian dramatist. We all know those Russian plays had more clouds of gray than any song by George Gershwin could guarantee. But, though I haven't read Gogol's story, he was one of those gloomy Russkies who happened to have a sense of humor, sarcastic and cynical though it might have been. It's the Napoleonic era in Middle Europe. Every town in the regime is corrupt in varying degrees and Napoleon has sent an Inspector General to clean things up. The Inspector General has Napoleon's power of attorney. He generally enters a town in some humble disguise -- a tinker, a salesman, an utter nobody -- then snoops around until he uncovers the miscreants, who he then promptly hangs. Nobody knows what he looks like. Kaye is a shill for a snake oil salesman, Walter Slezak in the most outrageously villainous bad-guy make up since Mack Swain, Chaplin's gorilla. When Kaye tries to stop an old lady from spending all her money on Slezak's cure-all to save her dying husband -- it's really furniture polish -- Slezak overhears the conversation and kicks Kaye out. Kaye then turns into a starving tramp. He wanders from town to town, trying to steal bits of food from dogs. But in the village of Brodny, misleading evidence comes to light that he is the Inspector General in disguise. So instead of being hanged for a thief, he's feted by the terrified corrupt town officials. He spends most of the movie strutting around in resplendent garb, trying to imitate a self-possessed pal of Napoleon or, alternatively, trying desperately to have his real identity hidden from the public. This spoiled identity becomes especially problematic after Slezak shows up, recognizes him for the buffoon he is, and manipulates him to extort bribes from the officials. Kaye handles the role pretty well, actually, as unlikely as it sounds. Well, why not? So it's a farce. I doubt that Gogol's original play had the fake Inspector General singing gibberish songs, but somehow it fits. Kaye's usual cowardly and neurotic persona is imposed on what I imagine to have been an amusing but relatively grounded story. If W. C. Fields could play Mr. Micawber in Charles Dickens' "David Copperfield", why not Kaye as a jiggling and stuttering Inspector General? The plot is too logical to allow for many of Kaye's set pieces. The gibberish songs (by his then-wife, Sylvia Fine) aren't as funny as some of his earlier ones. The gags, though muted, are imposed on a narrative that is funny in itself and this makes up, to some extent, for our watching a Danny Kaye who is in harness to the plot. There isn't as much mindless sentiment as there were in some of Kaye's lesser vehicles -- no sick children or any of that crap. Barbara Bates as the housemaid is Kaye's love interest, such as it is. Bates, an exquisite young woman of modest talent, was the underhanded high-school girl Phoebe who shows up at the end of "All About Eve." Here, in period wardrobe, she's just another pretty face, but it doesn't matter because her part isn't particularly important. Anyway, I kind of enjoyed it. Kaye does a lot of jumping around and shuffling of objects and there are some laughs in it, desperately needed in these too-laughless times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dated humor style, timeless subject matter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CEdWright
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Danny Kaye appealed most to our parents'/grandparents' generation, with their better appreciation of the often inane humor that entertainers like Danny Kaye provided: Overplayed, with sight or sound gags milked for all they're worth and then some. It was an easier, simpler time for entertainers, when slapstick was king and The Three Stooges and Abbott & Costello were the gold standard, with the later rise & fall of the Smothers Brothers marking the end of that era. But there were also the sort of more subtle gag lines and themes that still appeal to our more developed, sophisticated senses of humor. A fine example of this, "alone worth the price of admission" to this film, is where one of those corrupt officials, noted in other comments above, at first repeats about Georgi, "Less and less I like this Yakobovich...!" but as time goes on, and Georgi wins hearts & minds, his tune changes to repeating, "More and more I like this Yakobovich!" Gogol's original play was a bitter satire about corruption in Tsarist Russia, a theme and storyline that would likely puzzle Western audiences. Perhaps the greater familiarity of Napoleon as "the Emperor" in place of the Tsar -- also an emperor -- inspired the screenplay author to change the setting from Russia to some vague 'Eastern European' town, retaining the Russian names & even pseudo-accent, that may have fallen into Napoleon's empire for a while; making this film less about the Russian (pre-Soviet-Communist-during-the-Cold-War) Bear than about the rampant silliness of pervasive small-town petty and not-so-petty corruption even as still practiced today in many small towns in America. A fine farce based on real life in Russia originally, in mythical small towns in Europe then, and in our very real home towns today: Over centuries and across millions of miles, only the names on the doors have changed; from big city graft to small town vice, the only real difference is in the size of the numbers. Some say this movie is merely a vehicle for Danny Kaye; actually, only Danny Kaye could make us laugh at all the routine petty criminality encompassed in the saying, "You can't fight City Hall." All you need to do to ENJOY this wonderful timeless parody of malodorous malingering municipal malapropism & malfeasances is to willingly suspend any modern expectation of & insistence upon sophisticated authenticity & realism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The inspector General
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tombancroft2
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a fan of Danny Kaye, but I have to say that this is one of his poorest films. Too many silly songs which don't do justice to his fine voice and a weak plot line. "The Court Jester" and "Walter Mitty" are far superior. However, the finest Danny Kaye film in my humble view is "Hans Christian Anderson". The stories of Anderson are timeless and the songs in the film were big hits at the time and have since become classics (Inch Worm, Ugly Duckling, Thumbellina, I'm Hans Christian Anderson, etc.). Danny Kaye was a crooner almost in the Crosby class and his talents are wasted in the "Inspector General". The odd silly song is o.k, but there are too many in this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Happy Times with this film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bkoganbing
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Danny Kaye got one of his most enduring and funniest parts in this adaption of Gogol's The Inspector General. Kaye suited the part very well and Warner Brothers provided him with a generous cast of familiar character players. Kaye brings a lot of laughs as well as pathos to the part of the poor illiterate schnook who is a stooge for Walter Slezak, an itinerant peddler of snake oil known as Yakov's Elixir. After they get thrown out of one town due to Kaye's bumbling, Slezak cuts him adrift. But our Danny falls into a gold mine in the next town as he arrives there poor and hungry. It seems as though the city fathers have gotten word that The Inspector General, personal emissary of the Emperor is coming to town and he's been known to go places incognito and then reveal himself and all the fraud he uncovers. The paranoid city fathers of Brodny who include such people as Gene Lockhart, Alan Hale, Byron Foulger all start fawning all over Kaye who decides to just go with the flow. That policy is encouraged by Slezak who arrives in Brodny and sees the great possibilities here. The Inspector General is one of my favorite films with Danny Kaye, he's so right for the part. This was his first film away from Sam Goldwyn and Warner Brothers managed to give this film the same kind of production values you would find in a Goldwyn production. Mrs. Kaye, aka Sylvia Fine wrote the score for The Inspector General and gave her husband one of his best film songs, Happy Times which he sings to Barbara Bates who plays a serving girl at the local inn. Kaye also has to fend off the amorous advances of Elsa Lanchester who is Lockhart's wife and who is no slouch at getting a few laughs herself. The Inspector General is a timeless classic, taken from a classic and is one of the best showcases for the many talents of Danny Kaye.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whether you like it all depends on how much you like Kaye's routine....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Danny Kaye's musical comedy isn't something that has aged all that well. Back in the 40s and 50s, he was VERY popular and his films packed the theaters. However, I really believe that his style is something that will have a very mixed reaction today. Some, of course, probably still love Kaye and adore his antics and musical routines. And, others, like myself, will find him tedious. When he sings and makes his silly grimaces, it pains me--which is a shame, as the plot itself of "The Inspector General" is actually pretty good. Danny plays Georgi--a poor and slightly crooked man. He assists in a patent medicine show run by a seriously crooked guy (Walter Slezak). When he loses this job, he's very hungry and manages to get arrested--but not a meal. However, when the townspeople mistakenly believe that he's the Inspector General in disguise, suddenly they begin lavishing him with praise and gifts. But, the mayor and his officers know that they must do something else--they must kill the Inspector General to keep their thieving ways a secret. This isn't a problem for Kaye, as he's about to run out of town as soon as humanly possible--but he can't when his old boss shows up and insists that Kaye stay and milk the town for all it's worth. If the film was a bit more subtle, I would have loved it. It did have a lot of clever moments--but it also had Kaye hamming it up something awful at times as well. Overall, a mixed bag--worth seeing but lacking at the same time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh, I have no wife. None of my family had wives. My father didn't like wives. I mean, my mother didn't like my father's wives.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Danny Kaye was a wonderful performer, he would sing, dance, tell jokes, turn his face into rubber and just generally come off as a quality humanitarian. The Inspector General showcases all of those talents. Directed by Henry Koster, The Inspector General is loosely adapted from Nikolai Gogol's classic Russian story, and it finds Kaye as a stooge of Walter Slezak's iffy tonic peddler who is mistaken by iffy officials of a small Russian town for the much feared and respected Inspector General. Cue mistaken identity mayhem as the music numbers, gags, visual contortions and all round slapstick ensues. Along for the ride are Elsa Lanchester, Alan Hale, Barbara Bates and Gene Lockhart. It's more a safe and solid Kaye movie for the family to enjoy, rather than a high end classic like The Court Jester, but sometimes the high energy jinks of Kaye is all you need to lift the blues away. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterpiece of play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artioannidis
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a great movie ...A good old movie , the way the movies tried to entertain people as were meant to be played in theaters , with the free style actors based on their talent and instict.. The best man for this role would have been Danny Kaye at its best , talent of musical , fun , singing.. The plot is very very interesting and the cast of characters so humorous .. I have watched this movie more than 20 times and every time i m excited even more .. The part of Be arrogant , be elegant , be smart and the gypsy drinking song are so nice .. To sum up , a very good set up movie with a phenomenal unique talented Danny Kaye .. Everyone should watch
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ready, set, Gogol
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I understand it, Henry Koster's movie version of "The Inspector General" is only a loose adaptation of Nikolai Gogol's play. But even so, it's a really fun movie. Danny Kaye provides a lot of fun as a illiterate drifter who gets mistaken for a government inspector in a town overrun with corruption in Napoleon-era France. There are a couple of scenes in the movie that truly elicit a lot of humor, and the songs -- which Kaye's wife Sylvia wrote -- just go to show what one can do with a language. There are a few slow scenes, but mostly it's a really entertaining piece of work. I'm going to have to see if I can find a production of Gogol's original play (called "Revizor" in Russian, often called "The Government Inspector" in English). Also starring Walter Slezak (the Clock King on the 1960s "Batman" show), Gene Lockhart, Barbara Bates, Elsa Lanchester (the Bride of Frankenstein), Alan Hale Sr. (yes, the Skipper's father) and Rhys Williams. PS: Another one of Nikolai Gogol's notable stories is the horror short story "Viy", which Mario Bava filmed as "Black Sunday" starring Barbara Steele.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Danny Kaye with a mistaken identity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Petri Pelkonen (petri_pelkonen@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Georgi is member of a wandering band of Gypsies led by Yakov.Our illiterate hero escapes after he innocently lets slip that the elixir they're selling is a fraud.He finds a town named Brodny and gets arrested as a vagrant.He's sentenced to be hanged the next day.The town is most corrupted, and there is a rumor the inspector general is coming, and he'd be wearing a disguise.Then they realize Georgi must be the inspector, which he's obviously isn't.In the town there's a sweet girl named Leza, and they're both attracted to each other.The Inspector General is a musical comedy from 1949 directed by Henry Koster.It's loosely based on Nikolai Gogol's play, which I read last year.Johnny Green won a Golden Globe for Best Motion Picture Score.Kaye's wife Sylvia Fine wrote the original songs "The Inspector General" and Happy Times".Danny Kaye is really something as Georgi.Walter Slezak does excellent work as Yakov.Barbara Bates, who met a tragic end by her own hands, is wonderful as Leza.Elsa Lanchester is glorious as Maria.Gene Lockhart is great as The Mayor.Alan Hale is terrific as Kovatch.Walter Catlett does a great job as Colonel Castine.Rhys Williams is very good as Inspector General.Lew and Sam Hearn are funny as Izzick and Gizzick.I bought this movie on a DVD some time ago, and watched it a few days ago.I really enjoyed it.Danny Kaye was a really gifted comedian, and knew how to make people laugh.He followed the traditions of the early clowns but had his own unique style.A scene that makes you laugh is the eating scene, where he finds it very difficult to get anything in his mouth.It's a very funny scene where people keep coming to his room and he keeps hiding them.It's most hilarious how he sings "Gypsy Drinking Song" holding the glass filled with poison in his hand.For every Danny Kaye fan this film is a treat that can't be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warner Bros. Rolls Out the Technicolor Carpet for Danny Kaye
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Danny Kaye stars in this musical comedy about a case of mistaken identity and the poor fool caught in the middle of it. Georgi (Kaye) is an illiterate member of a traveling medicine show who is mistaken by a small Russian village as the Inspector General, a royal official with vast powers. While the local government officials plot to bribe or kill him, Georgi ingrains himself into the public's favor all the while trying to find a way out of his situation," according to the DVD sleeve description. Mr. Kaye's films usually fall into one of two categories - they can either be enjoyed by almost everyone in the average film-going public, or they mainly appeal to those already inclined to admire Kaye. The latter films will sometimes show the strains of a story "showcase" vehicle, while the more universally appealing films feature Kaye using his skills to more naturally essay a character. "The Inspector General" is a good example of the latter. Many of the gags fall flat, and the plot is laboriously adapted from the satirical Russian classic. Look for impressive Ida Moore in a great bit as the old "mother" Kaye wards off his potion. ***** The Inspector General (12/30/49) Henry Koster ~ Danny Kaye, Walter Slezak, Elsa Lanchester, Gene Lockhart
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not as Silly as Some Might Think.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a little difficult to grasp the notion of Danny Kaye, one of his era's premier farceurs, being the lead in a story from the 1840s by a Russian dramatist. We all know those Russian plays had more clouds of gray than any song by George Gershwin could guarantee. But, though I haven't read Gogol's story, he was one of those gloomy Russkies who happened to have a sense of humor, sarcastic and cynical though it might have been. It's the Napoleonic era in Middle Europe. Every town in the regime is corrupt in varying degrees and Napoleon has sent an Inspector General to clean things up. The Inspector General has Napoleon's power of attorney. He generally enters a town in some humble disguise -- a tinker, a salesman, an utter nobody -- then snoops around until he uncovers the miscreants, who he then promptly hangs. Nobody knows what he looks like. Kaye is a shill for a snake oil salesman, Walter Slezak in the most outrageously villainous bad-guy make up since Mack Swain, Chaplin's gorilla. When Kaye tries to stop an old lady from spending all her money on Slezak's cure-all to save her dying husband -- it's really furniture polish -- Slezak overhears the conversation and kicks Kaye out. Kaye then turns into a starving tramp. He wanders from town to town, trying to steal bits of food from dogs. But in the village of Brodny, misleading evidence comes to light that he is the Inspector General in disguise. So instead of being hanged for a thief, he's feted by the terrified corrupt town officials. He spends most of the movie strutting around in resplendent garb, trying to imitate a self-possessed pal of Napoleon or, alternatively, trying desperately to have his real identity hidden from the public. This spoiled identity becomes especially problematic after Slezak shows up, recognizes him for the buffoon he is, and manipulates him to extort bribes from the officials. Kaye handles the role pretty well, actually, as unlikely as it sounds. Well, why not? So it's a farce. I doubt that Gogol's original play had the fake Inspector General singing gibberish songs, but somehow it fits. Kaye's usual cowardly and neurotic persona is imposed on what I imagine to have been an amusing but relatively grounded story. If W. C. Fields could play Mr. Micawber in Charles Dickens' "David Copperfield", why not Kaye as a jiggling and stuttering Inspector General? The plot is too logical to allow for many of Kaye's set pieces. The gibberish songs (by his then-wife, Sylvia Fine) aren't as funny as some of his earlier ones. The gags, though muted, are imposed on a narrative that is funny in itself and this makes up, to some extent, for our watching a Danny Kaye who is in harness to the plot. There isn't as much mindless sentiment as there were in some of Kaye's lesser vehicles -- no sick children or any of that crap. Barbara Bates as the housemaid is Kaye's love interest, such as it is. Bates, an exquisite young woman of modest talent, was the underhanded high-school girl Phoebe who shows up at the end of "All About Eve." Here, in period wardrobe, she's just another pretty face, but it doesn't matter because her part isn't particularly important. Anyway, I kind of enjoyed it. Kaye does a lot of jumping around and shuffling of objects and there are some laughs in it, desperately needed in these too-laughless times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dated humor style, timeless subject matter
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CEdWright
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Danny Kaye appealed most to our parents'/grandparents' generation, with their better appreciation of the often inane humor that entertainers like Danny Kaye provided: Overplayed, with sight or sound gags milked for all they're worth and then some. It was an easier, simpler time for entertainers, when slapstick was king and The Three Stooges and Abbott & Costello were the gold standard, with the later rise & fall of the Smothers Brothers marking the end of that era. But there were also the sort of more subtle gag lines and themes that still appeal to our more developed, sophisticated senses of humor. A fine example of this, "alone worth the price of admission" to this film, is where one of those corrupt officials, noted in other comments above, at first repeats about Georgi, "Less and less I like this Yakobovich...!" but as time goes on, and Georgi wins hearts & minds, his tune changes to repeating, "More and more I like this Yakobovich!" Gogol's original play was a bitter satire about corruption in Tsarist Russia, a theme and storyline that would likely puzzle Western audiences. Perhaps the greater familiarity of Napoleon as "the Emperor" in place of the Tsar -- also an emperor -- inspired the screenplay author to change the setting from Russia to some vague 'Eastern European' town, retaining the Russian names & even pseudo-accent, that may have fallen into Napoleon's empire for a while; making this film less about the Russian (pre-Soviet-Communist-during-the-Cold-War) Bear than about the rampant silliness of pervasive small-town petty and not-so-petty corruption even as still practiced today in many small towns in America. A fine farce based on real life in Russia originally, in mythical small towns in Europe then, and in our very real home towns today: Over centuries and across millions of miles, only the names on the doors have changed; from big city graft to small town vice, the only real difference is in the size of the numbers. Some say this movie is merely a vehicle for Danny Kaye; actually, only Danny Kaye could make us laugh at all the routine petty criminality encompassed in the saying, "You can't fight City Hall." All you need to do to ENJOY this wonderful timeless parody of malodorous malingering municipal malapropism & malfeasances is to willingly suspend any modern expectation of & insistence upon sophisticated authenticity & realism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The inspector General
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tombancroft2
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a fan of Danny Kaye, but I have to say that this is one of his poorest films. Too many silly songs which don't do justice to his fine voice and a weak plot line. "The Court Jester" and "Walter Mitty" are far superior. However, the finest Danny Kaye film in my humble view is "Hans Christian Anderson". The stories of Anderson are timeless and the songs in the film were big hits at the time and have since become classics (Inch Worm, Ugly Duckling, Thumbellina, I'm Hans Christian Anderson, etc.). Danny Kaye was a crooner almost in the Crosby class and his talents are wasted in the "Inspector General". The odd silly song is o.k, but there are too many in this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
