<filme>
 <id>
  97
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0099348
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1990
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Dan&ccedil;a com Lobos
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Lt. John Dunbar, exiled to a remote western Civil War outpost, befriends wolves and Indians, making him an intolerable aberration in the military.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Lt. John Dunbar is dubbed a hero after he accidentally leads Union troops to a victory during the Civil War. He requests a position on the western frontier, but finds it deserted. He soon finds out he is not alone, but meets a wolf he dubs "Two-socks" and a curious Indian tribe. Dunbar quickly makes friends with the tribe, and discovers a white woman who was raised by the Indians. He gradually earns the respect of these native people, and sheds his white-man's ways.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Western
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   frontier
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   outpost
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hero
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wolf
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sioux tribe
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Kevin Costner
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Michael Blake
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kevin Costner
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Mary McDonnell
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Graham Greene
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyrian-shibara
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is hands down one of the best I've ever seen in reference to the American Indian. It does a fantastic job of portraying the Sioux as they really were, without bias or embellishment. The inclusion of the Pawnee in key scenes reinforces the fact that not all American Indians were the same - something that most Americans don't know or simply don't care about. It also makes a strong statement on the ignorance, cruelty, and disregard for the land that the whites showed when they settled the United States, and through the story of Dunbar, illustrates how that could have been avoided with nothing more than respect for another group as people and interest in their culture, instead of blind contempt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only one word: Harmony
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    geo-546-616925
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I beforehand knew that 'Dances with Wolves' ain't a typical western. However, I didn't know what exactly to expect. First of all, the direction is great, being Costner's first attempt. The performance of Costner, Greene and Grant added a lot to the movie, while the cinematographer wasn't awarded an Academy Award for nothing. However, the most important reason why everyone should watch and remember this film is its message; white man's madness has destroyed ancient cultures and spoiled Mother Nature. McDonnels's role wasn't bad, but she seemed to try too hard. The somewhat abrupt ending is something I didn't like, too. What is more, I believe the movie could be much more powerful in some scenes. This film is an all-time classic western and one of the best costume dramas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Born to be a hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nietzdrich Frietzsche
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunately, for some reason Kevin Costner didn't have the reputation of a talented actor. It would seem, that he has everything: he is a courageous, handsome, textured. He could play both brave daredevil and degraded debauchee-ribald. And he played, but evidently didn't convince exacting critics. Well, let so be it. All the same we love him. He nevertheless won critics' hearts by his director's talent. His epic western film &laquo;Dances with Wolves&raquo; - the confirmation of that. This is an extraordinary story about extraordinary man. Each of us makes strides along the road of life with one or another destination, leaving the tracks by acts of various kinds. Somebody sows the good seed, somebody destroys everything, somebody creates for the welfare of science and culture and somebody aimlessly goes down with the stream in expectation of opportune destiny. The character of &laquo; Dances with wolves&raquo;, First Lieutenant John Dunbar doomed to be a hero. His heroism is not the ostentatious prowess and thirst of recognize, it's his self, his way of life. His conscience, his spirit and his desperate heart lead his acts. His vital desire don't come to conquest of all possible and impossible heights, he violently persists in discover the frontier within himself. Growing roots in an uninhabited fort, stoically and thoroughly overcoming the harsh natural conditions, John Dunbar conscientiously and patiently waits for other soldiers. At first sight, he's absolutely lonely. But he realized very quickly all advantages of his loneliness: finally he was left alone with himself. Getting acquainted with Sioux, with their way of life, rituals and law, he doesn't look for personal gain. His aspiration to become closer with new neighbors, to be imbued with their traditions and, in the end, to become a part of their tribe, was dictated not by desire to relieve the lonely pastime or establish the good neighborly relations with strangers. All his acts  are heartfelt needs heart and soul. The destiny an incredible way throws John in the dizzying centrifuge of even more incredible circumstances, which frenzied rotation only strengthens his will and morale, opening him his true capabilities and personal orientations. Going over to the Sioux side and fighting against the U.S. Army, Dances with Wolves has no doubts in his right choice and actions. He doesn't compromise with his conscience, he acts jointly with it. He had found himself, the meaning of his way, and he didn't betray these acquirement. John Dunbar stepped into a heroic way from his birth and relentlessly moved on it even on unconscious level, without changing neither his route nor to himself. Ha was a hero even before accomplishment of his heroic feat. He went all his life to these and subsequent feats. John Dunbar didn't become Dances with Wolves, he became himself. And those circumstances, which thick he gets into, only push him to the frontier within himself, his genuine predestination. The staggering movie! And staggering Kevin Costner!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderfully and in details done masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luka V.
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is great about this film is that the plot itself completely fits in Costner's directing view which has easy pace and deep processed content. Furthermore, the way Costner displays such strong feelings as friendship( for example how wolf sacrifices himself for Lt. Dunbar and even how wolf hesitates to eat Dunbar's ham until it makes sure that he means well) and patriotism( in its true sense: battle for your people not country) and of course love( in a way that is not sneeze to watch, quite opposite). He dares criticize the way how American's treated Indians which sends humane message and shows how Kevin Costner's views are wide and beyond the limits( those opinions initiated the creation of the movie). Costner did the job perfectly and I'd like people not to question academy's decision to award this movie before Goodfellas for example( which is also a fantastic movie). I would recommend this movie to anyone because it will make an impression most likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Western-Drama-Romance-Action-Comedy-War masterpiece....what else can anyone ask for?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The talented and famous Kevin Costner during his great career he never received a deserved recognition for his impeccable performances. He had to sit on the director's chair and act at the same time to be finally awarded, and it wasn't for nothing. But to be able to start talking about the work of Costner and his great team, let's start talking about the wonderful story. "Dances with Wolves" begins during the American Civil War with the Lieutenant Dunbar (Kevin Costner), tired of all the war and after facing a near-death experience in the middle of a battlefield, he asks to be transferred to the unknown area of America, " The Frontier ", a vast green area with only animal and native life. Dunbar always dreamed of know and explore the frontier before she disappeared with the economic advancement of the Americans. But on this trip he is faced with the indigenous tribe, the "Sioux", and with them the great change of his life. A film that works as a Western with a vast Western environment and even moments of fantastic action in the Western style, but the film manages to go much deeper than that. From the beginning, the film manages to put ourselves on the feet of Dunbar, from the output of the world he was born into the unexplored world. The 1st hour of the film we only see Dunbar with his internal monologues and dialogs with his horse and a wild wolf that serves as their only company, but always with "Kicking Bird" (Graham Greene), a member of the Sioux tribe, watching him. Michael Blake's writing is just fantastic (who also manages to be loyal to his own work) making a fantastic job deepening Dunbar since a lonely man to a great friend of the Sioux. The film not only puts us at Dunbar's place but we get to feel the same feelings that he has regarding to the Sioux that goes from admiration to love. The Sioux can not only be an indigenous people with a great culture but nourish a huge intelligence and respect between each other, and they also have a innocent and good sense of humor (they fart; insults jokingly) making each one very realistic and human. We even feel a bit of the relationship between Dunbar and "Stand Fist" (Mary McDonnell), no big surprise, beyond beautiful she is smart and brave and also be the only white people among the tribe. Not only the writing of the film is fantastic maintaining an excellent character development but Costner's direction is just superb. Behind the camera he delivers a flawless direction putting us closely to the action scenes and makes us feel in the midst of the beautiful green desert with beautiful scenery magnificently filmed. The cast also stands out without difficulty: Kevin Costner is already superb behind the camera and in front of it would be no different with a sparkling gleam in his eye and his way of speaking the language of the Sioux without difficulty is just stunning; Mary McDonnell fantastic in every detail; Graham Greene honor his Native heritage perfectly. Kevin Costner was able to show a real talent for management and shines with a sparkling performance with a superb cast, all included in this beautiful story of a man who went out to find his place and eventually found himself. A wonderful writing and direction and an ending that made the strongest gets wet in tears, "Dances with Wolves" is a true classic masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical movie in more ways than one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Kevin Costner epic will undoubtedly never blow away with the wind, as a memorable and historical western, which for one - marks a new phase in relations with Native Americans. Most importantly "Dances with Wolves" sets a point in time, where native American culture can no longer be portrayed as savage, with incoming immigrants bringing with them technology, progress and the American dream. Now tainted, it could be said that one myth (of the civilisational conquering of the wild west) was supplanted by romanticised wigwams, but the latter for one thing is a much closer account of historical facts. Despite certain elaborated idealisation of Sioux life, this is a far cry from your mystical tree-hugging pacifists (aptly portrayed as being ruthless in warfare). However pointless this may be given the far-reaching recognisability of the movie, a short recap of the: Lt. John Dunbar (Kevin Costner) is sent out to the west to guard the frontier, while the rest of the country is in civil turmoil. The post is completely deserted apart from a stray wolf, who slowly grows an affinity to the kind-hearted man. Waiting for reinforcements to arrive, the first to contact him are his neighbours, the Sioux, with whom he soon forms a close familial relation, slowly immersing into their culture and way of life. Meanwhile chance encounters with bison hunters, cavalry troopers and loggers, have Dunbar grow increasingly disillusioned with his own kind... Rewatching the movie over twenty years after it received a multitude of Oscars (including Best Picture and Best Director), the widespread appeal of the movie has not faltered, still a touching, awe-inducing epic of stark significance to mainstream perceptions of American history. Certain aspects of the story-telling are simplistic and unrefined, often supplanting more cognitive portrayal of Sioux society with opportunities to bring in a hearty laugh. This doesn't however take away the charm of Costner's legendary feature, as comedy basically offers light-hearted respite from the inevitable downfall of the American Indians and the natural habitat in which they resided. The extended four hour cut undoubtedly has its coherence issues, as some scenes are visibly less well-rounded, often superfluous or just jarring. Nonetheless they do add to the overall scope and emotional pull of the story, hence all in all they largely feel best kept untouched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An epic dedicated to the human civilization
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huang20130418
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not an American. I have no right to judge this history and I'm not going to. The saddest thing about this movie is that we all know the end but we don't want it to come. We hope the harmony situation can last long, longer than the movie showed. But there's no way to expect that the tragedy of the Indian culture never come. Ancient civilization is bound to be replaced by modern one, though it may take blood, tears, darkness and sin to go through this. It's inevitable. As one saying (in China) goes, men are created to die. Though this analogy seems pretty sad, it's quite true. As soon as a man is born, he is moving to death every day, every hour and every second. So does human civilization. Human beings have gone through the original society, agriculture society, and now we are going through industrial society. It's impossible for us to foresee what the next society will be like after, say, 10000 years. So we can say that the industrial societies we build today are made to die, just like the original society and agriculture society. It's cruel to say this, but it does expose the cruelty that the world we live in and history we went through truly posses. This movie showed us this bloody and glory,miserable and honorable substitution process. So it's sure to be an epic. It's an epic dedicated to the human civilization. Also, being an epic requires magnificent scenes. This movie created a quite perfect one with the prairie, the sky, the buffalo and the wolf. Why do I count "wolf" in? Well, this movie spent a lot on that, didn't it? First, the name, "Dances with Wolves". Then the real wolf, there are lots of scenes about it. More importantly, this wolf, "two socks", is a symbol of Indian civilization. Outside the Indians look like cavemen, which is terrifying, this is similar to the wolf. But inside, they are kind, generous and warm-hearted, just like the development of the relationship between "two socks" and John Dunbar. So the denouement of the wolf marks the denouement of Indian culture. P.S. The music played in this movie is so wonderful and it contributed to the epic atmosphere. I think the only music which is better than this one is "My Heart Will Go On" in Titanic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful, Boring Anthem to Mr. Costner How Cool He Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I heard much about this movie - Dances was always names one of the best, decent, greatest and so on. I finally watched the complete 4-hour Director's Cut and what? It is tedious, boring, mediocre, long, slow, painfully pathetic film where we simply see every frame how cool, great, nice, heroic and grand Kevin Costner is. He made many awful movies, so far, but this one is a real under low, a real failure. Well, there are 2 great moments - the excellent scenery and animals. They are very good and sweet. The rest is very preachy, predictable, real boring and yawning all 4 long slow hours. This is what they call a heritage? Maybe, I was not impressed - Kevin made a movie about himself, for himself and with much of his beloved his self. Sorry, this does not work. This is not a Civil War movie, not a movie about nature, but a preachy-peachy saga of dullness and tediousness. Never watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best Western I've ever seen. One of its greatest strengths is its even handed portrayal of both sides of what was a gruesome bigotry ridden fight for land, opportunity, and way of life, between two very different cultures in the late 1800's. The Civil Wars' leftovers were a maliciously violent and frighteningly ignorant bunch, pit them against a culture of genuinely primitive & savage people (scalping & yelping pridefully about it  wow) and you have a perfect breeding ground for intolerance, impetuous violence, and never ending retaliatory fighting. "Dances with Wolves" provides a context for understanding both sides' humanity (for better and for worse) concerning this scar on our nation's history. Said understanding is permitted through an engaging story told on a stunning backdrop of our disappearing plains and enriched with beautifully moving music. In 2007, "Dances with Wolves" was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant." It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen. It won 7 Academy Awards, including Best Picture 1990; I'm not at all surprised and support the Library of Congress' decision.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably the best "going native" film to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film that manages to combine deep and meaningful character study with exotic locations and the feel of an adventure. Dances with Wolves is one of those rare films where time becomes transcendent and you're no longer able to perceive the usual story arcs or acts. They're there and the film has a rock-solid foundation, but you're still surprised when something new happens, because the film has managed to lull you into its world, its prolonged seasons. This is a movie that is able to portray the passage of time properly. It's a film in which events don't take place over a weekend or even a month. Rather whole years just glide by. Or perhaps just months, it's impossible to say for sure, but it feels like years, a sizable chunk of a whole life. And what a life that is and what a person living it. Lieutenant Dunbar - masterfully played by Kevin Costner - is a war hero given a dead end assignment according to his wishes, so that he can resign there to die a slow death. Thus the film starts as a macabre portrayal of a man giving up, but unable to just lay down. And it never becomes clear whether he manages to shake that initial attitude towards life. The events slowly give him more reasons to live, but Costner always plays him slightly detached, like he's always just one step away from giving up again. It's an amazing story and one that requires space to flourish. Quite many films since this one have managed to recreate the same "going native" storyline, which of course existed before this film though never quite like this, but none of them have seemed to realize that the film needs to dedicate most of its running time to the actual "going". Because that's the story, that's the attraction. The action scenes and battles have their place, but the magic is in the community, in the bonds that slowly grow between the main character and the natives. It's very hard to find any flaws in this film. Its slow pace is not for everyone, especially in the extended cut, but I personally never complained or even noticed the hours. It's a captivating film from start to finish and every minute is well spent, be it a minute of quiet landscapes rolling by or a minute of blazing battle. All has its place and every scene tells a story, reveals another layer. One of the greatest westerns ever filmed, if not one of the greatest films. In my opinion a film that everyone should watch at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyrian-shibara
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is hands down one of the best I've ever seen in reference to the American Indian. It does a fantastic job of portraying the Sioux as they really were, without bias or embellishment. The inclusion of the Pawnee in key scenes reinforces the fact that not all American Indians were the same - something that most Americans don't know or simply don't care about. It also makes a strong statement on the ignorance, cruelty, and disregard for the land that the whites showed when they settled the United States, and through the story of Dunbar, illustrates how that could have been avoided with nothing more than respect for another group as people and interest in their culture, instead of blind contempt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only one word: Harmony
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    geo-546-616925
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I beforehand knew that 'Dances with Wolves' ain't a typical western. However, I didn't know what exactly to expect. First of all, the direction is great, being Costner's first attempt. The performance of Costner, Greene and Grant added a lot to the movie, while the cinematographer wasn't awarded an Academy Award for nothing. However, the most important reason why everyone should watch and remember this film is its message; white man's madness has destroyed ancient cultures and spoiled Mother Nature. McDonnels's role wasn't bad, but she seemed to try too hard. The somewhat abrupt ending is something I didn't like, too. What is more, I believe the movie could be much more powerful in some scenes. This film is an all-time classic western and one of the best costume dramas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Born to be a hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nietzdrich Frietzsche
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunately, for some reason Kevin Costner didn't have the reputation of a talented actor. It would seem, that he has everything: he is a courageous, handsome, textured. He could play both brave daredevil and degraded debauchee-ribald. And he played, but evidently didn't convince exacting critics. Well, let so be it. All the same we love him. He nevertheless won critics' hearts by his director's talent. His epic western film &laquo;Dances with Wolves&raquo; - the confirmation of that. This is an extraordinary story about extraordinary man. Each of us makes strides along the road of life with one or another destination, leaving the tracks by acts of various kinds. Somebody sows the good seed, somebody destroys everything, somebody creates for the welfare of science and culture and somebody aimlessly goes down with the stream in expectation of opportune destiny. The character of &laquo; Dances with wolves&raquo;, First Lieutenant John Dunbar doomed to be a hero. His heroism is not the ostentatious prowess and thirst of recognize, it's his self, his way of life. His conscience, his spirit and his desperate heart lead his acts. His vital desire don't come to conquest of all possible and impossible heights, he violently persists in discover the frontier within himself. Growing roots in an uninhabited fort, stoically and thoroughly overcoming the harsh natural conditions, John Dunbar conscientiously and patiently waits for other soldiers. At first sight, he's absolutely lonely. But he realized very quickly all advantages of his loneliness: finally he was left alone with himself. Getting acquainted with Sioux, with their way of life, rituals and law, he doesn't look for personal gain. His aspiration to become closer with new neighbors, to be imbued with their traditions and, in the end, to become a part of their tribe, was dictated not by desire to relieve the lonely pastime or establish the good neighborly relations with strangers. All his acts  are heartfelt needs heart and soul. The destiny an incredible way throws John in the dizzying centrifuge of even more incredible circumstances, which frenzied rotation only strengthens his will and morale, opening him his true capabilities and personal orientations. Going over to the Sioux side and fighting against the U.S. Army, Dances with Wolves has no doubts in his right choice and actions. He doesn't compromise with his conscience, he acts jointly with it. He had found himself, the meaning of his way, and he didn't betray these acquirement. John Dunbar stepped into a heroic way from his birth and relentlessly moved on it even on unconscious level, without changing neither his route nor to himself. Ha was a hero even before accomplishment of his heroic feat. He went all his life to these and subsequent feats. John Dunbar didn't become Dances with Wolves, he became himself. And those circumstances, which thick he gets into, only push him to the frontier within himself, his genuine predestination. The staggering movie! And staggering Kevin Costner!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderfully and in details done masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luka V.
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is great about this film is that the plot itself completely fits in Costner's directing view which has easy pace and deep processed content. Furthermore, the way Costner displays such strong feelings as friendship( for example how wolf sacrifices himself for Lt. Dunbar and even how wolf hesitates to eat Dunbar's ham until it makes sure that he means well) and patriotism( in its true sense: battle for your people not country) and of course love( in a way that is not sneeze to watch, quite opposite). He dares criticize the way how American's treated Indians which sends humane message and shows how Kevin Costner's views are wide and beyond the limits( those opinions initiated the creation of the movie). Costner did the job perfectly and I'd like people not to question academy's decision to award this movie before Goodfellas for example( which is also a fantastic movie). I would recommend this movie to anyone because it will make an impression most likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Western-Drama-Romance-Action-Comedy-War masterpiece....what else can anyone ask for?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The talented and famous Kevin Costner during his great career he never received a deserved recognition for his impeccable performances. He had to sit on the director's chair and act at the same time to be finally awarded, and it wasn't for nothing. But to be able to start talking about the work of Costner and his great team, let's start talking about the wonderful story. "Dances with Wolves" begins during the American Civil War with the Lieutenant Dunbar (Kevin Costner), tired of all the war and after facing a near-death experience in the middle of a battlefield, he asks to be transferred to the unknown area of America, " The Frontier ", a vast green area with only animal and native life. Dunbar always dreamed of know and explore the frontier before she disappeared with the economic advancement of the Americans. But on this trip he is faced with the indigenous tribe, the "Sioux", and with them the great change of his life. A film that works as a Western with a vast Western environment and even moments of fantastic action in the Western style, but the film manages to go much deeper than that. From the beginning, the film manages to put ourselves on the feet of Dunbar, from the output of the world he was born into the unexplored world. The 1st hour of the film we only see Dunbar with his internal monologues and dialogs with his horse and a wild wolf that serves as their only company, but always with "Kicking Bird" (Graham Greene), a member of the Sioux tribe, watching him. Michael Blake's writing is just fantastic (who also manages to be loyal to his own work) making a fantastic job deepening Dunbar since a lonely man to a great friend of the Sioux. The film not only puts us at Dunbar's place but we get to feel the same feelings that he has regarding to the Sioux that goes from admiration to love. The Sioux can not only be an indigenous people with a great culture but nourish a huge intelligence and respect between each other, and they also have a innocent and good sense of humor (they fart; insults jokingly) making each one very realistic and human. We even feel a bit of the relationship between Dunbar and "Stand Fist" (Mary McDonnell), no big surprise, beyond beautiful she is smart and brave and also be the only white people among the tribe. Not only the writing of the film is fantastic maintaining an excellent character development but Costner's direction is just superb. Behind the camera he delivers a flawless direction putting us closely to the action scenes and makes us feel in the midst of the beautiful green desert with beautiful scenery magnificently filmed. The cast also stands out without difficulty: Kevin Costner is already superb behind the camera and in front of it would be no different with a sparkling gleam in his eye and his way of speaking the language of the Sioux without difficulty is just stunning; Mary McDonnell fantastic in every detail; Graham Greene honor his Native heritage perfectly. Kevin Costner was able to show a real talent for management and shines with a sparkling performance with a superb cast, all included in this beautiful story of a man who went out to find his place and eventually found himself. A wonderful writing and direction and an ending that made the strongest gets wet in tears, "Dances with Wolves" is a true classic masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical movie in more ways than one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Kevin Costner epic will undoubtedly never blow away with the wind, as a memorable and historical western, which for one - marks a new phase in relations with Native Americans. Most importantly "Dances with Wolves" sets a point in time, where native American culture can no longer be portrayed as savage, with incoming immigrants bringing with them technology, progress and the American dream. Now tainted, it could be said that one myth (of the civilisational conquering of the wild west) was supplanted by romanticised wigwams, but the latter for one thing is a much closer account of historical facts. Despite certain elaborated idealisation of Sioux life, this is a far cry from your mystical tree-hugging pacifists (aptly portrayed as being ruthless in warfare). However pointless this may be given the far-reaching recognisability of the movie, a short recap of the: Lt. John Dunbar (Kevin Costner) is sent out to the west to guard the frontier, while the rest of the country is in civil turmoil. The post is completely deserted apart from a stray wolf, who slowly grows an affinity to the kind-hearted man. Waiting for reinforcements to arrive, the first to contact him are his neighbours, the Sioux, with whom he soon forms a close familial relation, slowly immersing into their culture and way of life. Meanwhile chance encounters with bison hunters, cavalry troopers and loggers, have Dunbar grow increasingly disillusioned with his own kind... Rewatching the movie over twenty years after it received a multitude of Oscars (including Best Picture and Best Director), the widespread appeal of the movie has not faltered, still a touching, awe-inducing epic of stark significance to mainstream perceptions of American history. Certain aspects of the story-telling are simplistic and unrefined, often supplanting more cognitive portrayal of Sioux society with opportunities to bring in a hearty laugh. This doesn't however take away the charm of Costner's legendary feature, as comedy basically offers light-hearted respite from the inevitable downfall of the American Indians and the natural habitat in which they resided. The extended four hour cut undoubtedly has its coherence issues, as some scenes are visibly less well-rounded, often superfluous or just jarring. Nonetheless they do add to the overall scope and emotional pull of the story, hence all in all they largely feel best kept untouched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An epic dedicated to the human civilization
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huang20130418
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not an American. I have no right to judge this history and I'm not going to. The saddest thing about this movie is that we all know the end but we don't want it to come. We hope the harmony situation can last long, longer than the movie showed. But there's no way to expect that the tragedy of the Indian culture never come. Ancient civilization is bound to be replaced by modern one, though it may take blood, tears, darkness and sin to go through this. It's inevitable. As one saying (in China) goes, men are created to die. Though this analogy seems pretty sad, it's quite true. As soon as a man is born, he is moving to death every day, every hour and every second. So does human civilization. Human beings have gone through the original society, agriculture society, and now we are going through industrial society. It's impossible for us to foresee what the next society will be like after, say, 10000 years. So we can say that the industrial societies we build today are made to die, just like the original society and agriculture society. It's cruel to say this, but it does expose the cruelty that the world we live in and history we went through truly posses. This movie showed us this bloody and glory,miserable and honorable substitution process. So it's sure to be an epic. It's an epic dedicated to the human civilization. Also, being an epic requires magnificent scenes. This movie created a quite perfect one with the prairie, the sky, the buffalo and the wolf. Why do I count "wolf" in? Well, this movie spent a lot on that, didn't it? First, the name, "Dances with Wolves". Then the real wolf, there are lots of scenes about it. More importantly, this wolf, "two socks", is a symbol of Indian civilization. Outside the Indians look like cavemen, which is terrifying, this is similar to the wolf. But inside, they are kind, generous and warm-hearted, just like the development of the relationship between "two socks" and John Dunbar. So the denouement of the wolf marks the denouement of Indian culture. P.S. The music played in this movie is so wonderful and it contributed to the epic atmosphere. I think the only music which is better than this one is "My Heart Will Go On" in Titanic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful, Boring Anthem to Mr. Costner How Cool He Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I heard much about this movie - Dances was always names one of the best, decent, greatest and so on. I finally watched the complete 4-hour Director's Cut and what? It is tedious, boring, mediocre, long, slow, painfully pathetic film where we simply see every frame how cool, great, nice, heroic and grand Kevin Costner is. He made many awful movies, so far, but this one is a real under low, a real failure. Well, there are 2 great moments - the excellent scenery and animals. They are very good and sweet. The rest is very preachy, predictable, real boring and yawning all 4 long slow hours. This is what they call a heritage? Maybe, I was not impressed - Kevin made a movie about himself, for himself and with much of his beloved his self. Sorry, this does not work. This is not a Civil War movie, not a movie about nature, but a preachy-peachy saga of dullness and tediousness. Never watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best Western I've ever seen. One of its greatest strengths is its even handed portrayal of both sides of what was a gruesome bigotry ridden fight for land, opportunity, and way of life, between two very different cultures in the late 1800's. The Civil Wars' leftovers were a maliciously violent and frighteningly ignorant bunch, pit them against a culture of genuinely primitive & savage people (scalping & yelping pridefully about it  wow) and you have a perfect breeding ground for intolerance, impetuous violence, and never ending retaliatory fighting. "Dances with Wolves" provides a context for understanding both sides' humanity (for better and for worse) concerning this scar on our nation's history. Said understanding is permitted through an engaging story told on a stunning backdrop of our disappearing plains and enriched with beautifully moving music. In 2007, "Dances with Wolves" was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant." It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen. It won 7 Academy Awards, including Best Picture 1990; I'm not at all surprised and support the Library of Congress' decision.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably the best "going native" film to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film that manages to combine deep and meaningful character study with exotic locations and the feel of an adventure. Dances with Wolves is one of those rare films where time becomes transcendent and you're no longer able to perceive the usual story arcs or acts. They're there and the film has a rock-solid foundation, but you're still surprised when something new happens, because the film has managed to lull you into its world, its prolonged seasons. This is a movie that is able to portray the passage of time properly. It's a film in which events don't take place over a weekend or even a month. Rather whole years just glide by. Or perhaps just months, it's impossible to say for sure, but it feels like years, a sizable chunk of a whole life. And what a life that is and what a person living it. Lieutenant Dunbar - masterfully played by Kevin Costner - is a war hero given a dead end assignment according to his wishes, so that he can resign there to die a slow death. Thus the film starts as a macabre portrayal of a man giving up, but unable to just lay down. And it never becomes clear whether he manages to shake that initial attitude towards life. The events slowly give him more reasons to live, but Costner always plays him slightly detached, like he's always just one step away from giving up again. It's an amazing story and one that requires space to flourish. Quite many films since this one have managed to recreate the same "going native" storyline, which of course existed before this film though never quite like this, but none of them have seemed to realize that the film needs to dedicate most of its running time to the actual "going". Because that's the story, that's the attraction. The action scenes and battles have their place, but the magic is in the community, in the bonds that slowly grow between the main character and the natives. It's very hard to find any flaws in this film. Its slow pace is not for everyone, especially in the extended cut, but I personally never complained or even noticed the hours. It's a captivating film from start to finish and every minute is well spent, be it a minute of quiet landscapes rolling by or a minute of blazing battle. All has its place and every scene tells a story, reveals another layer. One of the greatest westerns ever filmed, if not one of the greatest films. In my opinion a film that everyone should watch at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyrian-shibara
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is hands down one of the best I've ever seen in reference to the American Indian. It does a fantastic job of portraying the Sioux as they really were, without bias or embellishment. The inclusion of the Pawnee in key scenes reinforces the fact that not all American Indians were the same - something that most Americans don't know or simply don't care about. It also makes a strong statement on the ignorance, cruelty, and disregard for the land that the whites showed when they settled the United States, and through the story of Dunbar, illustrates how that could have been avoided with nothing more than respect for another group as people and interest in their culture, instead of blind contempt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only one word: Harmony
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    geo-546-616925
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I beforehand knew that 'Dances with Wolves' ain't a typical western. However, I didn't know what exactly to expect. First of all, the direction is great, being Costner's first attempt. The performance of Costner, Greene and Grant added a lot to the movie, while the cinematographer wasn't awarded an Academy Award for nothing. However, the most important reason why everyone should watch and remember this film is its message; white man's madness has destroyed ancient cultures and spoiled Mother Nature. McDonnels's role wasn't bad, but she seemed to try too hard. The somewhat abrupt ending is something I didn't like, too. What is more, I believe the movie could be much more powerful in some scenes. This film is an all-time classic western and one of the best costume dramas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Born to be a hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nietzdrich Frietzsche
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunately, for some reason Kevin Costner didn't have the reputation of a talented actor. It would seem, that he has everything: he is a courageous, handsome, textured. He could play both brave daredevil and degraded debauchee-ribald. And he played, but evidently didn't convince exacting critics. Well, let so be it. All the same we love him. He nevertheless won critics' hearts by his director's talent. His epic western film &laquo;Dances with Wolves&raquo; - the confirmation of that. This is an extraordinary story about extraordinary man. Each of us makes strides along the road of life with one or another destination, leaving the tracks by acts of various kinds. Somebody sows the good seed, somebody destroys everything, somebody creates for the welfare of science and culture and somebody aimlessly goes down with the stream in expectation of opportune destiny. The character of &laquo; Dances with wolves&raquo;, First Lieutenant John Dunbar doomed to be a hero. His heroism is not the ostentatious prowess and thirst of recognize, it's his self, his way of life. His conscience, his spirit and his desperate heart lead his acts. His vital desire don't come to conquest of all possible and impossible heights, he violently persists in discover the frontier within himself. Growing roots in an uninhabited fort, stoically and thoroughly overcoming the harsh natural conditions, John Dunbar conscientiously and patiently waits for other soldiers. At first sight, he's absolutely lonely. But he realized very quickly all advantages of his loneliness: finally he was left alone with himself. Getting acquainted with Sioux, with their way of life, rituals and law, he doesn't look for personal gain. His aspiration to become closer with new neighbors, to be imbued with their traditions and, in the end, to become a part of their tribe, was dictated not by desire to relieve the lonely pastime or establish the good neighborly relations with strangers. All his acts  are heartfelt needs heart and soul. The destiny an incredible way throws John in the dizzying centrifuge of even more incredible circumstances, which frenzied rotation only strengthens his will and morale, opening him his true capabilities and personal orientations. Going over to the Sioux side and fighting against the U.S. Army, Dances with Wolves has no doubts in his right choice and actions. He doesn't compromise with his conscience, he acts jointly with it. He had found himself, the meaning of his way, and he didn't betray these acquirement. John Dunbar stepped into a heroic way from his birth and relentlessly moved on it even on unconscious level, without changing neither his route nor to himself. Ha was a hero even before accomplishment of his heroic feat. He went all his life to these and subsequent feats. John Dunbar didn't become Dances with Wolves, he became himself. And those circumstances, which thick he gets into, only push him to the frontier within himself, his genuine predestination. The staggering movie! And staggering Kevin Costner!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderfully and in details done masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luka V.
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is great about this film is that the plot itself completely fits in Costner's directing view which has easy pace and deep processed content. Furthermore, the way Costner displays such strong feelings as friendship( for example how wolf sacrifices himself for Lt. Dunbar and even how wolf hesitates to eat Dunbar's ham until it makes sure that he means well) and patriotism( in its true sense: battle for your people not country) and of course love( in a way that is not sneeze to watch, quite opposite). He dares criticize the way how American's treated Indians which sends humane message and shows how Kevin Costner's views are wide and beyond the limits( those opinions initiated the creation of the movie). Costner did the job perfectly and I'd like people not to question academy's decision to award this movie before Goodfellas for example( which is also a fantastic movie). I would recommend this movie to anyone because it will make an impression most likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Western-Drama-Romance-Action-Comedy-War masterpiece....what else can anyone ask for?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The talented and famous Kevin Costner during his great career he never received a deserved recognition for his impeccable performances. He had to sit on the director's chair and act at the same time to be finally awarded, and it wasn't for nothing. But to be able to start talking about the work of Costner and his great team, let's start talking about the wonderful story. "Dances with Wolves" begins during the American Civil War with the Lieutenant Dunbar (Kevin Costner), tired of all the war and after facing a near-death experience in the middle of a battlefield, he asks to be transferred to the unknown area of America, " The Frontier ", a vast green area with only animal and native life. Dunbar always dreamed of know and explore the frontier before she disappeared with the economic advancement of the Americans. But on this trip he is faced with the indigenous tribe, the "Sioux", and with them the great change of his life. A film that works as a Western with a vast Western environment and even moments of fantastic action in the Western style, but the film manages to go much deeper than that. From the beginning, the film manages to put ourselves on the feet of Dunbar, from the output of the world he was born into the unexplored world. The 1st hour of the film we only see Dunbar with his internal monologues and dialogs with his horse and a wild wolf that serves as their only company, but always with "Kicking Bird" (Graham Greene), a member of the Sioux tribe, watching him. Michael Blake's writing is just fantastic (who also manages to be loyal to his own work) making a fantastic job deepening Dunbar since a lonely man to a great friend of the Sioux. The film not only puts us at Dunbar's place but we get to feel the same feelings that he has regarding to the Sioux that goes from admiration to love. The Sioux can not only be an indigenous people with a great culture but nourish a huge intelligence and respect between each other, and they also have a innocent and good sense of humor (they fart; insults jokingly) making each one very realistic and human. We even feel a bit of the relationship between Dunbar and "Stand Fist" (Mary McDonnell), no big surprise, beyond beautiful she is smart and brave and also be the only white people among the tribe. Not only the writing of the film is fantastic maintaining an excellent character development but Costner's direction is just superb. Behind the camera he delivers a flawless direction putting us closely to the action scenes and makes us feel in the midst of the beautiful green desert with beautiful scenery magnificently filmed. The cast also stands out without difficulty: Kevin Costner is already superb behind the camera and in front of it would be no different with a sparkling gleam in his eye and his way of speaking the language of the Sioux without difficulty is just stunning; Mary McDonnell fantastic in every detail; Graham Greene honor his Native heritage perfectly. Kevin Costner was able to show a real talent for management and shines with a sparkling performance with a superb cast, all included in this beautiful story of a man who went out to find his place and eventually found himself. A wonderful writing and direction and an ending that made the strongest gets wet in tears, "Dances with Wolves" is a true classic masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical movie in more ways than one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Kevin Costner epic will undoubtedly never blow away with the wind, as a memorable and historical western, which for one - marks a new phase in relations with Native Americans. Most importantly "Dances with Wolves" sets a point in time, where native American culture can no longer be portrayed as savage, with incoming immigrants bringing with them technology, progress and the American dream. Now tainted, it could be said that one myth (of the civilisational conquering of the wild west) was supplanted by romanticised wigwams, but the latter for one thing is a much closer account of historical facts. Despite certain elaborated idealisation of Sioux life, this is a far cry from your mystical tree-hugging pacifists (aptly portrayed as being ruthless in warfare). However pointless this may be given the far-reaching recognisability of the movie, a short recap of the: Lt. John Dunbar (Kevin Costner) is sent out to the west to guard the frontier, while the rest of the country is in civil turmoil. The post is completely deserted apart from a stray wolf, who slowly grows an affinity to the kind-hearted man. Waiting for reinforcements to arrive, the first to contact him are his neighbours, the Sioux, with whom he soon forms a close familial relation, slowly immersing into their culture and way of life. Meanwhile chance encounters with bison hunters, cavalry troopers and loggers, have Dunbar grow increasingly disillusioned with his own kind... Rewatching the movie over twenty years after it received a multitude of Oscars (including Best Picture and Best Director), the widespread appeal of the movie has not faltered, still a touching, awe-inducing epic of stark significance to mainstream perceptions of American history. Certain aspects of the story-telling are simplistic and unrefined, often supplanting more cognitive portrayal of Sioux society with opportunities to bring in a hearty laugh. This doesn't however take away the charm of Costner's legendary feature, as comedy basically offers light-hearted respite from the inevitable downfall of the American Indians and the natural habitat in which they resided. The extended four hour cut undoubtedly has its coherence issues, as some scenes are visibly less well-rounded, often superfluous or just jarring. Nonetheless they do add to the overall scope and emotional pull of the story, hence all in all they largely feel best kept untouched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An epic dedicated to the human civilization
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huang20130418
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not an American. I have no right to judge this history and I'm not going to. The saddest thing about this movie is that we all know the end but we don't want it to come. We hope the harmony situation can last long, longer than the movie showed. But there's no way to expect that the tragedy of the Indian culture never come. Ancient civilization is bound to be replaced by modern one, though it may take blood, tears, darkness and sin to go through this. It's inevitable. As one saying (in China) goes, men are created to die. Though this analogy seems pretty sad, it's quite true. As soon as a man is born, he is moving to death every day, every hour and every second. So does human civilization. Human beings have gone through the original society, agriculture society, and now we are going through industrial society. It's impossible for us to foresee what the next society will be like after, say, 10000 years. So we can say that the industrial societies we build today are made to die, just like the original society and agriculture society. It's cruel to say this, but it does expose the cruelty that the world we live in and history we went through truly posses. This movie showed us this bloody and glory,miserable and honorable substitution process. So it's sure to be an epic. It's an epic dedicated to the human civilization. Also, being an epic requires magnificent scenes. This movie created a quite perfect one with the prairie, the sky, the buffalo and the wolf. Why do I count "wolf" in? Well, this movie spent a lot on that, didn't it? First, the name, "Dances with Wolves". Then the real wolf, there are lots of scenes about it. More importantly, this wolf, "two socks", is a symbol of Indian civilization. Outside the Indians look like cavemen, which is terrifying, this is similar to the wolf. But inside, they are kind, generous and warm-hearted, just like the development of the relationship between "two socks" and John Dunbar. So the denouement of the wolf marks the denouement of Indian culture. P.S. The music played in this movie is so wonderful and it contributed to the epic atmosphere. I think the only music which is better than this one is "My Heart Will Go On" in Titanic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful, Boring Anthem to Mr. Costner How Cool He Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I heard much about this movie - Dances was always names one of the best, decent, greatest and so on. I finally watched the complete 4-hour Director's Cut and what? It is tedious, boring, mediocre, long, slow, painfully pathetic film where we simply see every frame how cool, great, nice, heroic and grand Kevin Costner is. He made many awful movies, so far, but this one is a real under low, a real failure. Well, there are 2 great moments - the excellent scenery and animals. They are very good and sweet. The rest is very preachy, predictable, real boring and yawning all 4 long slow hours. This is what they call a heritage? Maybe, I was not impressed - Kevin made a movie about himself, for himself and with much of his beloved his self. Sorry, this does not work. This is not a Civil War movie, not a movie about nature, but a preachy-peachy saga of dullness and tediousness. Never watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best Western I've ever seen. One of its greatest strengths is its even handed portrayal of both sides of what was a gruesome bigotry ridden fight for land, opportunity, and way of life, between two very different cultures in the late 1800's. The Civil Wars' leftovers were a maliciously violent and frighteningly ignorant bunch, pit them against a culture of genuinely primitive & savage people (scalping & yelping pridefully about it  wow) and you have a perfect breeding ground for intolerance, impetuous violence, and never ending retaliatory fighting. "Dances with Wolves" provides a context for understanding both sides' humanity (for better and for worse) concerning this scar on our nation's history. Said understanding is permitted through an engaging story told on a stunning backdrop of our disappearing plains and enriched with beautifully moving music. In 2007, "Dances with Wolves" was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant." It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen. It won 7 Academy Awards, including Best Picture 1990; I'm not at all surprised and support the Library of Congress' decision.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably the best "going native" film to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film that manages to combine deep and meaningful character study with exotic locations and the feel of an adventure. Dances with Wolves is one of those rare films where time becomes transcendent and you're no longer able to perceive the usual story arcs or acts. They're there and the film has a rock-solid foundation, but you're still surprised when something new happens, because the film has managed to lull you into its world, its prolonged seasons. This is a movie that is able to portray the passage of time properly. It's a film in which events don't take place over a weekend or even a month. Rather whole years just glide by. Or perhaps just months, it's impossible to say for sure, but it feels like years, a sizable chunk of a whole life. And what a life that is and what a person living it. Lieutenant Dunbar - masterfully played by Kevin Costner - is a war hero given a dead end assignment according to his wishes, so that he can resign there to die a slow death. Thus the film starts as a macabre portrayal of a man giving up, but unable to just lay down. And it never becomes clear whether he manages to shake that initial attitude towards life. The events slowly give him more reasons to live, but Costner always plays him slightly detached, like he's always just one step away from giving up again. It's an amazing story and one that requires space to flourish. Quite many films since this one have managed to recreate the same "going native" storyline, which of course existed before this film though never quite like this, but none of them have seemed to realize that the film needs to dedicate most of its running time to the actual "going". Because that's the story, that's the attraction. The action scenes and battles have their place, but the magic is in the community, in the bonds that slowly grow between the main character and the natives. It's very hard to find any flaws in this film. Its slow pace is not for everyone, especially in the extended cut, but I personally never complained or even noticed the hours. It's a captivating film from start to finish and every minute is well spent, be it a minute of quiet landscapes rolling by or a minute of blazing battle. All has its place and every scene tells a story, reveals another layer. One of the greatest westerns ever filmed, if not one of the greatest films. In my opinion a film that everyone should watch at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyrian-shibara
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is hands down one of the best I've ever seen in reference to the American Indian. It does a fantastic job of portraying the Sioux as they really were, without bias or embellishment. The inclusion of the Pawnee in key scenes reinforces the fact that not all American Indians were the same - something that most Americans don't know or simply don't care about. It also makes a strong statement on the ignorance, cruelty, and disregard for the land that the whites showed when they settled the United States, and through the story of Dunbar, illustrates how that could have been avoided with nothing more than respect for another group as people and interest in their culture, instead of blind contempt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only one word: Harmony
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    geo-546-616925
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I beforehand knew that 'Dances with Wolves' ain't a typical western. However, I didn't know what exactly to expect. First of all, the direction is great, being Costner's first attempt. The performance of Costner, Greene and Grant added a lot to the movie, while the cinematographer wasn't awarded an Academy Award for nothing. However, the most important reason why everyone should watch and remember this film is its message; white man's madness has destroyed ancient cultures and spoiled Mother Nature. McDonnels's role wasn't bad, but she seemed to try too hard. The somewhat abrupt ending is something I didn't like, too. What is more, I believe the movie could be much more powerful in some scenes. This film is an all-time classic western and one of the best costume dramas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Born to be a hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nietzdrich Frietzsche
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunately, for some reason Kevin Costner didn't have the reputation of a talented actor. It would seem, that he has everything: he is a courageous, handsome, textured. He could play both brave daredevil and degraded debauchee-ribald. And he played, but evidently didn't convince exacting critics. Well, let so be it. All the same we love him. He nevertheless won critics' hearts by his director's talent. His epic western film &laquo;Dances with Wolves&raquo; - the confirmation of that. This is an extraordinary story about extraordinary man. Each of us makes strides along the road of life with one or another destination, leaving the tracks by acts of various kinds. Somebody sows the good seed, somebody destroys everything, somebody creates for the welfare of science and culture and somebody aimlessly goes down with the stream in expectation of opportune destiny. The character of &laquo; Dances with wolves&raquo;, First Lieutenant John Dunbar doomed to be a hero. His heroism is not the ostentatious prowess and thirst of recognize, it's his self, his way of life. His conscience, his spirit and his desperate heart lead his acts. His vital desire don't come to conquest of all possible and impossible heights, he violently persists in discover the frontier within himself. Growing roots in an uninhabited fort, stoically and thoroughly overcoming the harsh natural conditions, John Dunbar conscientiously and patiently waits for other soldiers. At first sight, he's absolutely lonely. But he realized very quickly all advantages of his loneliness: finally he was left alone with himself. Getting acquainted with Sioux, with their way of life, rituals and law, he doesn't look for personal gain. His aspiration to become closer with new neighbors, to be imbued with their traditions and, in the end, to become a part of their tribe, was dictated not by desire to relieve the lonely pastime or establish the good neighborly relations with strangers. All his acts  are heartfelt needs heart and soul. The destiny an incredible way throws John in the dizzying centrifuge of even more incredible circumstances, which frenzied rotation only strengthens his will and morale, opening him his true capabilities and personal orientations. Going over to the Sioux side and fighting against the U.S. Army, Dances with Wolves has no doubts in his right choice and actions. He doesn't compromise with his conscience, he acts jointly with it. He had found himself, the meaning of his way, and he didn't betray these acquirement. John Dunbar stepped into a heroic way from his birth and relentlessly moved on it even on unconscious level, without changing neither his route nor to himself. Ha was a hero even before accomplishment of his heroic feat. He went all his life to these and subsequent feats. John Dunbar didn't become Dances with Wolves, he became himself. And those circumstances, which thick he gets into, only push him to the frontier within himself, his genuine predestination. The staggering movie! And staggering Kevin Costner!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderfully and in details done masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luka V.
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is great about this film is that the plot itself completely fits in Costner's directing view which has easy pace and deep processed content. Furthermore, the way Costner displays such strong feelings as friendship( for example how wolf sacrifices himself for Lt. Dunbar and even how wolf hesitates to eat Dunbar's ham until it makes sure that he means well) and patriotism( in its true sense: battle for your people not country) and of course love( in a way that is not sneeze to watch, quite opposite). He dares criticize the way how American's treated Indians which sends humane message and shows how Kevin Costner's views are wide and beyond the limits( those opinions initiated the creation of the movie). Costner did the job perfectly and I'd like people not to question academy's decision to award this movie before Goodfellas for example( which is also a fantastic movie). I would recommend this movie to anyone because it will make an impression most likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Western-Drama-Romance-Action-Comedy-War masterpiece....what else can anyone ask for?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The talented and famous Kevin Costner during his great career he never received a deserved recognition for his impeccable performances. He had to sit on the director's chair and act at the same time to be finally awarded, and it wasn't for nothing. But to be able to start talking about the work of Costner and his great team, let's start talking about the wonderful story. "Dances with Wolves" begins during the American Civil War with the Lieutenant Dunbar (Kevin Costner), tired of all the war and after facing a near-death experience in the middle of a battlefield, he asks to be transferred to the unknown area of America, " The Frontier ", a vast green area with only animal and native life. Dunbar always dreamed of know and explore the frontier before she disappeared with the economic advancement of the Americans. But on this trip he is faced with the indigenous tribe, the "Sioux", and with them the great change of his life. A film that works as a Western with a vast Western environment and even moments of fantastic action in the Western style, but the film manages to go much deeper than that. From the beginning, the film manages to put ourselves on the feet of Dunbar, from the output of the world he was born into the unexplored world. The 1st hour of the film we only see Dunbar with his internal monologues and dialogs with his horse and a wild wolf that serves as their only company, but always with "Kicking Bird" (Graham Greene), a member of the Sioux tribe, watching him. Michael Blake's writing is just fantastic (who also manages to be loyal to his own work) making a fantastic job deepening Dunbar since a lonely man to a great friend of the Sioux. The film not only puts us at Dunbar's place but we get to feel the same feelings that he has regarding to the Sioux that goes from admiration to love. The Sioux can not only be an indigenous people with a great culture but nourish a huge intelligence and respect between each other, and they also have a innocent and good sense of humor (they fart; insults jokingly) making each one very realistic and human. We even feel a bit of the relationship between Dunbar and "Stand Fist" (Mary McDonnell), no big surprise, beyond beautiful she is smart and brave and also be the only white people among the tribe. Not only the writing of the film is fantastic maintaining an excellent character development but Costner's direction is just superb. Behind the camera he delivers a flawless direction putting us closely to the action scenes and makes us feel in the midst of the beautiful green desert with beautiful scenery magnificently filmed. The cast also stands out without difficulty: Kevin Costner is already superb behind the camera and in front of it would be no different with a sparkling gleam in his eye and his way of speaking the language of the Sioux without difficulty is just stunning; Mary McDonnell fantastic in every detail; Graham Greene honor his Native heritage perfectly. Kevin Costner was able to show a real talent for management and shines with a sparkling performance with a superb cast, all included in this beautiful story of a man who went out to find his place and eventually found himself. A wonderful writing and direction and an ending that made the strongest gets wet in tears, "Dances with Wolves" is a true classic masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical movie in more ways than one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Kevin Costner epic will undoubtedly never blow away with the wind, as a memorable and historical western, which for one - marks a new phase in relations with Native Americans. Most importantly "Dances with Wolves" sets a point in time, where native American culture can no longer be portrayed as savage, with incoming immigrants bringing with them technology, progress and the American dream. Now tainted, it could be said that one myth (of the civilisational conquering of the wild west) was supplanted by romanticised wigwams, but the latter for one thing is a much closer account of historical facts. Despite certain elaborated idealisation of Sioux life, this is a far cry from your mystical tree-hugging pacifists (aptly portrayed as being ruthless in warfare). However pointless this may be given the far-reaching recognisability of the movie, a short recap of the: Lt. John Dunbar (Kevin Costner) is sent out to the west to guard the frontier, while the rest of the country is in civil turmoil. The post is completely deserted apart from a stray wolf, who slowly grows an affinity to the kind-hearted man. Waiting for reinforcements to arrive, the first to contact him are his neighbours, the Sioux, with whom he soon forms a close familial relation, slowly immersing into their culture and way of life. Meanwhile chance encounters with bison hunters, cavalry troopers and loggers, have Dunbar grow increasingly disillusioned with his own kind... Rewatching the movie over twenty years after it received a multitude of Oscars (including Best Picture and Best Director), the widespread appeal of the movie has not faltered, still a touching, awe-inducing epic of stark significance to mainstream perceptions of American history. Certain aspects of the story-telling are simplistic and unrefined, often supplanting more cognitive portrayal of Sioux society with opportunities to bring in a hearty laugh. This doesn't however take away the charm of Costner's legendary feature, as comedy basically offers light-hearted respite from the inevitable downfall of the American Indians and the natural habitat in which they resided. The extended four hour cut undoubtedly has its coherence issues, as some scenes are visibly less well-rounded, often superfluous or just jarring. Nonetheless they do add to the overall scope and emotional pull of the story, hence all in all they largely feel best kept untouched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An epic dedicated to the human civilization
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huang20130418
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not an American. I have no right to judge this history and I'm not going to. The saddest thing about this movie is that we all know the end but we don't want it to come. We hope the harmony situation can last long, longer than the movie showed. But there's no way to expect that the tragedy of the Indian culture never come. Ancient civilization is bound to be replaced by modern one, though it may take blood, tears, darkness and sin to go through this. It's inevitable. As one saying (in China) goes, men are created to die. Though this analogy seems pretty sad, it's quite true. As soon as a man is born, he is moving to death every day, every hour and every second. So does human civilization. Human beings have gone through the original society, agriculture society, and now we are going through industrial society. It's impossible for us to foresee what the next society will be like after, say, 10000 years. So we can say that the industrial societies we build today are made to die, just like the original society and agriculture society. It's cruel to say this, but it does expose the cruelty that the world we live in and history we went through truly posses. This movie showed us this bloody and glory,miserable and honorable substitution process. So it's sure to be an epic. It's an epic dedicated to the human civilization. Also, being an epic requires magnificent scenes. This movie created a quite perfect one with the prairie, the sky, the buffalo and the wolf. Why do I count "wolf" in? Well, this movie spent a lot on that, didn't it? First, the name, "Dances with Wolves". Then the real wolf, there are lots of scenes about it. More importantly, this wolf, "two socks", is a symbol of Indian civilization. Outside the Indians look like cavemen, which is terrifying, this is similar to the wolf. But inside, they are kind, generous and warm-hearted, just like the development of the relationship between "two socks" and John Dunbar. So the denouement of the wolf marks the denouement of Indian culture. P.S. The music played in this movie is so wonderful and it contributed to the epic atmosphere. I think the only music which is better than this one is "My Heart Will Go On" in Titanic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful, Boring Anthem to Mr. Costner How Cool He Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I heard much about this movie - Dances was always names one of the best, decent, greatest and so on. I finally watched the complete 4-hour Director's Cut and what? It is tedious, boring, mediocre, long, slow, painfully pathetic film where we simply see every frame how cool, great, nice, heroic and grand Kevin Costner is. He made many awful movies, so far, but this one is a real under low, a real failure. Well, there are 2 great moments - the excellent scenery and animals. They are very good and sweet. The rest is very preachy, predictable, real boring and yawning all 4 long slow hours. This is what they call a heritage? Maybe, I was not impressed - Kevin made a movie about himself, for himself and with much of his beloved his self. Sorry, this does not work. This is not a Civil War movie, not a movie about nature, but a preachy-peachy saga of dullness and tediousness. Never watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best Western I've ever seen. One of its greatest strengths is its even handed portrayal of both sides of what was a gruesome bigotry ridden fight for land, opportunity, and way of life, between two very different cultures in the late 1800's. The Civil Wars' leftovers were a maliciously violent and frighteningly ignorant bunch, pit them against a culture of genuinely primitive & savage people (scalping & yelping pridefully about it  wow) and you have a perfect breeding ground for intolerance, impetuous violence, and never ending retaliatory fighting. "Dances with Wolves" provides a context for understanding both sides' humanity (for better and for worse) concerning this scar on our nation's history. Said understanding is permitted through an engaging story told on a stunning backdrop of our disappearing plains and enriched with beautifully moving music. In 2007, "Dances with Wolves" was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant." It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen. It won 7 Academy Awards, including Best Picture 1990; I'm not at all surprised and support the Library of Congress' decision.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably the best "going native" film to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film that manages to combine deep and meaningful character study with exotic locations and the feel of an adventure. Dances with Wolves is one of those rare films where time becomes transcendent and you're no longer able to perceive the usual story arcs or acts. They're there and the film has a rock-solid foundation, but you're still surprised when something new happens, because the film has managed to lull you into its world, its prolonged seasons. This is a movie that is able to portray the passage of time properly. It's a film in which events don't take place over a weekend or even a month. Rather whole years just glide by. Or perhaps just months, it's impossible to say for sure, but it feels like years, a sizable chunk of a whole life. And what a life that is and what a person living it. Lieutenant Dunbar - masterfully played by Kevin Costner - is a war hero given a dead end assignment according to his wishes, so that he can resign there to die a slow death. Thus the film starts as a macabre portrayal of a man giving up, but unable to just lay down. And it never becomes clear whether he manages to shake that initial attitude towards life. The events slowly give him more reasons to live, but Costner always plays him slightly detached, like he's always just one step away from giving up again. It's an amazing story and one that requires space to flourish. Quite many films since this one have managed to recreate the same "going native" storyline, which of course existed before this film though never quite like this, but none of them have seemed to realize that the film needs to dedicate most of its running time to the actual "going". Because that's the story, that's the attraction. The action scenes and battles have their place, but the magic is in the community, in the bonds that slowly grow between the main character and the natives. It's very hard to find any flaws in this film. Its slow pace is not for everyone, especially in the extended cut, but I personally never complained or even noticed the hours. It's a captivating film from start to finish and every minute is well spent, be it a minute of quiet landscapes rolling by or a minute of blazing battle. All has its place and every scene tells a story, reveals another layer. One of the greatest westerns ever filmed, if not one of the greatest films. In my opinion a film that everyone should watch at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyrian-shibara
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is hands down one of the best I've ever seen in reference to the American Indian. It does a fantastic job of portraying the Sioux as they really were, without bias or embellishment. The inclusion of the Pawnee in key scenes reinforces the fact that not all American Indians were the same - something that most Americans don't know or simply don't care about. It also makes a strong statement on the ignorance, cruelty, and disregard for the land that the whites showed when they settled the United States, and through the story of Dunbar, illustrates how that could have been avoided with nothing more than respect for another group as people and interest in their culture, instead of blind contempt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only one word: Harmony
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    geo-546-616925
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I beforehand knew that 'Dances with Wolves' ain't a typical western. However, I didn't know what exactly to expect. First of all, the direction is great, being Costner's first attempt. The performance of Costner, Greene and Grant added a lot to the movie, while the cinematographer wasn't awarded an Academy Award for nothing. However, the most important reason why everyone should watch and remember this film is its message; white man's madness has destroyed ancient cultures and spoiled Mother Nature. McDonnels's role wasn't bad, but she seemed to try too hard. The somewhat abrupt ending is something I didn't like, too. What is more, I believe the movie could be much more powerful in some scenes. This film is an all-time classic western and one of the best costume dramas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Born to be a hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nietzdrich Frietzsche
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunately, for some reason Kevin Costner didn't have the reputation of a talented actor. It would seem, that he has everything: he is a courageous, handsome, textured. He could play both brave daredevil and degraded debauchee-ribald. And he played, but evidently didn't convince exacting critics. Well, let so be it. All the same we love him. He nevertheless won critics' hearts by his director's talent. His epic western film &laquo;Dances with Wolves&raquo; - the confirmation of that. This is an extraordinary story about extraordinary man. Each of us makes strides along the road of life with one or another destination, leaving the tracks by acts of various kinds. Somebody sows the good seed, somebody destroys everything, somebody creates for the welfare of science and culture and somebody aimlessly goes down with the stream in expectation of opportune destiny. The character of &laquo; Dances with wolves&raquo;, First Lieutenant John Dunbar doomed to be a hero. His heroism is not the ostentatious prowess and thirst of recognize, it's his self, his way of life. His conscience, his spirit and his desperate heart lead his acts. His vital desire don't come to conquest of all possible and impossible heights, he violently persists in discover the frontier within himself. Growing roots in an uninhabited fort, stoically and thoroughly overcoming the harsh natural conditions, John Dunbar conscientiously and patiently waits for other soldiers. At first sight, he's absolutely lonely. But he realized very quickly all advantages of his loneliness: finally he was left alone with himself. Getting acquainted with Sioux, with their way of life, rituals and law, he doesn't look for personal gain. His aspiration to become closer with new neighbors, to be imbued with their traditions and, in the end, to become a part of their tribe, was dictated not by desire to relieve the lonely pastime or establish the good neighborly relations with strangers. All his acts  are heartfelt needs heart and soul. The destiny an incredible way throws John in the dizzying centrifuge of even more incredible circumstances, which frenzied rotation only strengthens his will and morale, opening him his true capabilities and personal orientations. Going over to the Sioux side and fighting against the U.S. Army, Dances with Wolves has no doubts in his right choice and actions. He doesn't compromise with his conscience, he acts jointly with it. He had found himself, the meaning of his way, and he didn't betray these acquirement. John Dunbar stepped into a heroic way from his birth and relentlessly moved on it even on unconscious level, without changing neither his route nor to himself. Ha was a hero even before accomplishment of his heroic feat. He went all his life to these and subsequent feats. John Dunbar didn't become Dances with Wolves, he became himself. And those circumstances, which thick he gets into, only push him to the frontier within himself, his genuine predestination. The staggering movie! And staggering Kevin Costner!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderfully and in details done masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luka V.
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is great about this film is that the plot itself completely fits in Costner's directing view which has easy pace and deep processed content. Furthermore, the way Costner displays such strong feelings as friendship( for example how wolf sacrifices himself for Lt. Dunbar and even how wolf hesitates to eat Dunbar's ham until it makes sure that he means well) and patriotism( in its true sense: battle for your people not country) and of course love( in a way that is not sneeze to watch, quite opposite). He dares criticize the way how American's treated Indians which sends humane message and shows how Kevin Costner's views are wide and beyond the limits( those opinions initiated the creation of the movie). Costner did the job perfectly and I'd like people not to question academy's decision to award this movie before Goodfellas for example( which is also a fantastic movie). I would recommend this movie to anyone because it will make an impression most likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Western-Drama-Romance-Action-Comedy-War masterpiece....what else can anyone ask for?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The talented and famous Kevin Costner during his great career he never received a deserved recognition for his impeccable performances. He had to sit on the director's chair and act at the same time to be finally awarded, and it wasn't for nothing. But to be able to start talking about the work of Costner and his great team, let's start talking about the wonderful story. "Dances with Wolves" begins during the American Civil War with the Lieutenant Dunbar (Kevin Costner), tired of all the war and after facing a near-death experience in the middle of a battlefield, he asks to be transferred to the unknown area of America, " The Frontier ", a vast green area with only animal and native life. Dunbar always dreamed of know and explore the frontier before she disappeared with the economic advancement of the Americans. But on this trip he is faced with the indigenous tribe, the "Sioux", and with them the great change of his life. A film that works as a Western with a vast Western environment and even moments of fantastic action in the Western style, but the film manages to go much deeper than that. From the beginning, the film manages to put ourselves on the feet of Dunbar, from the output of the world he was born into the unexplored world. The 1st hour of the film we only see Dunbar with his internal monologues and dialogs with his horse and a wild wolf that serves as their only company, but always with "Kicking Bird" (Graham Greene), a member of the Sioux tribe, watching him. Michael Blake's writing is just fantastic (who also manages to be loyal to his own work) making a fantastic job deepening Dunbar since a lonely man to a great friend of the Sioux. The film not only puts us at Dunbar's place but we get to feel the same feelings that he has regarding to the Sioux that goes from admiration to love. The Sioux can not only be an indigenous people with a great culture but nourish a huge intelligence and respect between each other, and they also have a innocent and good sense of humor (they fart; insults jokingly) making each one very realistic and human. We even feel a bit of the relationship between Dunbar and "Stand Fist" (Mary McDonnell), no big surprise, beyond beautiful she is smart and brave and also be the only white people among the tribe. Not only the writing of the film is fantastic maintaining an excellent character development but Costner's direction is just superb. Behind the camera he delivers a flawless direction putting us closely to the action scenes and makes us feel in the midst of the beautiful green desert with beautiful scenery magnificently filmed. The cast also stands out without difficulty: Kevin Costner is already superb behind the camera and in front of it would be no different with a sparkling gleam in his eye and his way of speaking the language of the Sioux without difficulty is just stunning; Mary McDonnell fantastic in every detail; Graham Greene honor his Native heritage perfectly. Kevin Costner was able to show a real talent for management and shines with a sparkling performance with a superb cast, all included in this beautiful story of a man who went out to find his place and eventually found himself. A wonderful writing and direction and an ending that made the strongest gets wet in tears, "Dances with Wolves" is a true classic masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical movie in more ways than one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Kevin Costner epic will undoubtedly never blow away with the wind, as a memorable and historical western, which for one - marks a new phase in relations with Native Americans. Most importantly "Dances with Wolves" sets a point in time, where native American culture can no longer be portrayed as savage, with incoming immigrants bringing with them technology, progress and the American dream. Now tainted, it could be said that one myth (of the civilisational conquering of the wild west) was supplanted by romanticised wigwams, but the latter for one thing is a much closer account of historical facts. Despite certain elaborated idealisation of Sioux life, this is a far cry from your mystical tree-hugging pacifists (aptly portrayed as being ruthless in warfare). However pointless this may be given the far-reaching recognisability of the movie, a short recap of the: Lt. John Dunbar (Kevin Costner) is sent out to the west to guard the frontier, while the rest of the country is in civil turmoil. The post is completely deserted apart from a stray wolf, who slowly grows an affinity to the kind-hearted man. Waiting for reinforcements to arrive, the first to contact him are his neighbours, the Sioux, with whom he soon forms a close familial relation, slowly immersing into their culture and way of life. Meanwhile chance encounters with bison hunters, cavalry troopers and loggers, have Dunbar grow increasingly disillusioned with his own kind... Rewatching the movie over twenty years after it received a multitude of Oscars (including Best Picture and Best Director), the widespread appeal of the movie has not faltered, still a touching, awe-inducing epic of stark significance to mainstream perceptions of American history. Certain aspects of the story-telling are simplistic and unrefined, often supplanting more cognitive portrayal of Sioux society with opportunities to bring in a hearty laugh. This doesn't however take away the charm of Costner's legendary feature, as comedy basically offers light-hearted respite from the inevitable downfall of the American Indians and the natural habitat in which they resided. The extended four hour cut undoubtedly has its coherence issues, as some scenes are visibly less well-rounded, often superfluous or just jarring. Nonetheless they do add to the overall scope and emotional pull of the story, hence all in all they largely feel best kept untouched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An epic dedicated to the human civilization
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huang20130418
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not an American. I have no right to judge this history and I'm not going to. The saddest thing about this movie is that we all know the end but we don't want it to come. We hope the harmony situation can last long, longer than the movie showed. But there's no way to expect that the tragedy of the Indian culture never come. Ancient civilization is bound to be replaced by modern one, though it may take blood, tears, darkness and sin to go through this. It's inevitable. As one saying (in China) goes, men are created to die. Though this analogy seems pretty sad, it's quite true. As soon as a man is born, he is moving to death every day, every hour and every second. So does human civilization. Human beings have gone through the original society, agriculture society, and now we are going through industrial society. It's impossible for us to foresee what the next society will be like after, say, 10000 years. So we can say that the industrial societies we build today are made to die, just like the original society and agriculture society. It's cruel to say this, but it does expose the cruelty that the world we live in and history we went through truly posses. This movie showed us this bloody and glory,miserable and honorable substitution process. So it's sure to be an epic. It's an epic dedicated to the human civilization. Also, being an epic requires magnificent scenes. This movie created a quite perfect one with the prairie, the sky, the buffalo and the wolf. Why do I count "wolf" in? Well, this movie spent a lot on that, didn't it? First, the name, "Dances with Wolves". Then the real wolf, there are lots of scenes about it. More importantly, this wolf, "two socks", is a symbol of Indian civilization. Outside the Indians look like cavemen, which is terrifying, this is similar to the wolf. But inside, they are kind, generous and warm-hearted, just like the development of the relationship between "two socks" and John Dunbar. So the denouement of the wolf marks the denouement of Indian culture. P.S. The music played in this movie is so wonderful and it contributed to the epic atmosphere. I think the only music which is better than this one is "My Heart Will Go On" in Titanic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful, Boring Anthem to Mr. Costner How Cool He Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I heard much about this movie - Dances was always names one of the best, decent, greatest and so on. I finally watched the complete 4-hour Director's Cut and what? It is tedious, boring, mediocre, long, slow, painfully pathetic film where we simply see every frame how cool, great, nice, heroic and grand Kevin Costner is. He made many awful movies, so far, but this one is a real under low, a real failure. Well, there are 2 great moments - the excellent scenery and animals. They are very good and sweet. The rest is very preachy, predictable, real boring and yawning all 4 long slow hours. This is what they call a heritage? Maybe, I was not impressed - Kevin made a movie about himself, for himself and with much of his beloved his self. Sorry, this does not work. This is not a Civil War movie, not a movie about nature, but a preachy-peachy saga of dullness and tediousness. Never watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best Western I've ever seen. One of its greatest strengths is its even handed portrayal of both sides of what was a gruesome bigotry ridden fight for land, opportunity, and way of life, between two very different cultures in the late 1800's. The Civil Wars' leftovers were a maliciously violent and frighteningly ignorant bunch, pit them against a culture of genuinely primitive & savage people (scalping & yelping pridefully about it  wow) and you have a perfect breeding ground for intolerance, impetuous violence, and never ending retaliatory fighting. "Dances with Wolves" provides a context for understanding both sides' humanity (for better and for worse) concerning this scar on our nation's history. Said understanding is permitted through an engaging story told on a stunning backdrop of our disappearing plains and enriched with beautifully moving music. In 2007, "Dances with Wolves" was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant." It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen. It won 7 Academy Awards, including Best Picture 1990; I'm not at all surprised and support the Library of Congress' decision.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably the best "going native" film to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film that manages to combine deep and meaningful character study with exotic locations and the feel of an adventure. Dances with Wolves is one of those rare films where time becomes transcendent and you're no longer able to perceive the usual story arcs or acts. They're there and the film has a rock-solid foundation, but you're still surprised when something new happens, because the film has managed to lull you into its world, its prolonged seasons. This is a movie that is able to portray the passage of time properly. It's a film in which events don't take place over a weekend or even a month. Rather whole years just glide by. Or perhaps just months, it's impossible to say for sure, but it feels like years, a sizable chunk of a whole life. And what a life that is and what a person living it. Lieutenant Dunbar - masterfully played by Kevin Costner - is a war hero given a dead end assignment according to his wishes, so that he can resign there to die a slow death. Thus the film starts as a macabre portrayal of a man giving up, but unable to just lay down. And it never becomes clear whether he manages to shake that initial attitude towards life. The events slowly give him more reasons to live, but Costner always plays him slightly detached, like he's always just one step away from giving up again. It's an amazing story and one that requires space to flourish. Quite many films since this one have managed to recreate the same "going native" storyline, which of course existed before this film though never quite like this, but none of them have seemed to realize that the film needs to dedicate most of its running time to the actual "going". Because that's the story, that's the attraction. The action scenes and battles have their place, but the magic is in the community, in the bonds that slowly grow between the main character and the natives. It's very hard to find any flaws in this film. Its slow pace is not for everyone, especially in the extended cut, but I personally never complained or even noticed the hours. It's a captivating film from start to finish and every minute is well spent, be it a minute of quiet landscapes rolling by or a minute of blazing battle. All has its place and every scene tells a story, reveals another layer. One of the greatest westerns ever filmed, if not one of the greatest films. In my opinion a film that everyone should watch at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyrian-shibara
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is hands down one of the best I've ever seen in reference to the American Indian. It does a fantastic job of portraying the Sioux as they really were, without bias or embellishment. The inclusion of the Pawnee in key scenes reinforces the fact that not all American Indians were the same - something that most Americans don't know or simply don't care about. It also makes a strong statement on the ignorance, cruelty, and disregard for the land that the whites showed when they settled the United States, and through the story of Dunbar, illustrates how that could have been avoided with nothing more than respect for another group as people and interest in their culture, instead of blind contempt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only one word: Harmony
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    geo-546-616925
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I beforehand knew that 'Dances with Wolves' ain't a typical western. However, I didn't know what exactly to expect. First of all, the direction is great, being Costner's first attempt. The performance of Costner, Greene and Grant added a lot to the movie, while the cinematographer wasn't awarded an Academy Award for nothing. However, the most important reason why everyone should watch and remember this film is its message; white man's madness has destroyed ancient cultures and spoiled Mother Nature. McDonnels's role wasn't bad, but she seemed to try too hard. The somewhat abrupt ending is something I didn't like, too. What is more, I believe the movie could be much more powerful in some scenes. This film is an all-time classic western and one of the best costume dramas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Born to be a hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nietzdrich Frietzsche
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunately, for some reason Kevin Costner didn't have the reputation of a talented actor. It would seem, that he has everything: he is a courageous, handsome, textured. He could play both brave daredevil and degraded debauchee-ribald. And he played, but evidently didn't convince exacting critics. Well, let so be it. All the same we love him. He nevertheless won critics' hearts by his director's talent. His epic western film &laquo;Dances with Wolves&raquo; - the confirmation of that. This is an extraordinary story about extraordinary man. Each of us makes strides along the road of life with one or another destination, leaving the tracks by acts of various kinds. Somebody sows the good seed, somebody destroys everything, somebody creates for the welfare of science and culture and somebody aimlessly goes down with the stream in expectation of opportune destiny. The character of &laquo; Dances with wolves&raquo;, First Lieutenant John Dunbar doomed to be a hero. His heroism is not the ostentatious prowess and thirst of recognize, it's his self, his way of life. His conscience, his spirit and his desperate heart lead his acts. His vital desire don't come to conquest of all possible and impossible heights, he violently persists in discover the frontier within himself. Growing roots in an uninhabited fort, stoically and thoroughly overcoming the harsh natural conditions, John Dunbar conscientiously and patiently waits for other soldiers. At first sight, he's absolutely lonely. But he realized very quickly all advantages of his loneliness: finally he was left alone with himself. Getting acquainted with Sioux, with their way of life, rituals and law, he doesn't look for personal gain. His aspiration to become closer with new neighbors, to be imbued with their traditions and, in the end, to become a part of their tribe, was dictated not by desire to relieve the lonely pastime or establish the good neighborly relations with strangers. All his acts  are heartfelt needs heart and soul. The destiny an incredible way throws John in the dizzying centrifuge of even more incredible circumstances, which frenzied rotation only strengthens his will and morale, opening him his true capabilities and personal orientations. Going over to the Sioux side and fighting against the U.S. Army, Dances with Wolves has no doubts in his right choice and actions. He doesn't compromise with his conscience, he acts jointly with it. He had found himself, the meaning of his way, and he didn't betray these acquirement. John Dunbar stepped into a heroic way from his birth and relentlessly moved on it even on unconscious level, without changing neither his route nor to himself. Ha was a hero even before accomplishment of his heroic feat. He went all his life to these and subsequent feats. John Dunbar didn't become Dances with Wolves, he became himself. And those circumstances, which thick he gets into, only push him to the frontier within himself, his genuine predestination. The staggering movie! And staggering Kevin Costner!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderfully and in details done masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luka V.
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is great about this film is that the plot itself completely fits in Costner's directing view which has easy pace and deep processed content. Furthermore, the way Costner displays such strong feelings as friendship( for example how wolf sacrifices himself for Lt. Dunbar and even how wolf hesitates to eat Dunbar's ham until it makes sure that he means well) and patriotism( in its true sense: battle for your people not country) and of course love( in a way that is not sneeze to watch, quite opposite). He dares criticize the way how American's treated Indians which sends humane message and shows how Kevin Costner's views are wide and beyond the limits( those opinions initiated the creation of the movie). Costner did the job perfectly and I'd like people not to question academy's decision to award this movie before Goodfellas for example( which is also a fantastic movie). I would recommend this movie to anyone because it will make an impression most likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Western-Drama-Romance-Action-Comedy-War masterpiece....what else can anyone ask for?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The talented and famous Kevin Costner during his great career he never received a deserved recognition for his impeccable performances. He had to sit on the director's chair and act at the same time to be finally awarded, and it wasn't for nothing. But to be able to start talking about the work of Costner and his great team, let's start talking about the wonderful story. "Dances with Wolves" begins during the American Civil War with the Lieutenant Dunbar (Kevin Costner), tired of all the war and after facing a near-death experience in the middle of a battlefield, he asks to be transferred to the unknown area of America, " The Frontier ", a vast green area with only animal and native life. Dunbar always dreamed of know and explore the frontier before she disappeared with the economic advancement of the Americans. But on this trip he is faced with the indigenous tribe, the "Sioux", and with them the great change of his life. A film that works as a Western with a vast Western environment and even moments of fantastic action in the Western style, but the film manages to go much deeper than that. From the beginning, the film manages to put ourselves on the feet of Dunbar, from the output of the world he was born into the unexplored world. The 1st hour of the film we only see Dunbar with his internal monologues and dialogs with his horse and a wild wolf that serves as their only company, but always with "Kicking Bird" (Graham Greene), a member of the Sioux tribe, watching him. Michael Blake's writing is just fantastic (who also manages to be loyal to his own work) making a fantastic job deepening Dunbar since a lonely man to a great friend of the Sioux. The film not only puts us at Dunbar's place but we get to feel the same feelings that he has regarding to the Sioux that goes from admiration to love. The Sioux can not only be an indigenous people with a great culture but nourish a huge intelligence and respect between each other, and they also have a innocent and good sense of humor (they fart; insults jokingly) making each one very realistic and human. We even feel a bit of the relationship between Dunbar and "Stand Fist" (Mary McDonnell), no big surprise, beyond beautiful she is smart and brave and also be the only white people among the tribe. Not only the writing of the film is fantastic maintaining an excellent character development but Costner's direction is just superb. Behind the camera he delivers a flawless direction putting us closely to the action scenes and makes us feel in the midst of the beautiful green desert with beautiful scenery magnificently filmed. The cast also stands out without difficulty: Kevin Costner is already superb behind the camera and in front of it would be no different with a sparkling gleam in his eye and his way of speaking the language of the Sioux without difficulty is just stunning; Mary McDonnell fantastic in every detail; Graham Greene honor his Native heritage perfectly. Kevin Costner was able to show a real talent for management and shines with a sparkling performance with a superb cast, all included in this beautiful story of a man who went out to find his place and eventually found himself. A wonderful writing and direction and an ending that made the strongest gets wet in tears, "Dances with Wolves" is a true classic masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical movie in more ways than one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Kevin Costner epic will undoubtedly never blow away with the wind, as a memorable and historical western, which for one - marks a new phase in relations with Native Americans. Most importantly "Dances with Wolves" sets a point in time, where native American culture can no longer be portrayed as savage, with incoming immigrants bringing with them technology, progress and the American dream. Now tainted, it could be said that one myth (of the civilisational conquering of the wild west) was supplanted by romanticised wigwams, but the latter for one thing is a much closer account of historical facts. Despite certain elaborated idealisation of Sioux life, this is a far cry from your mystical tree-hugging pacifists (aptly portrayed as being ruthless in warfare). However pointless this may be given the far-reaching recognisability of the movie, a short recap of the: Lt. John Dunbar (Kevin Costner) is sent out to the west to guard the frontier, while the rest of the country is in civil turmoil. The post is completely deserted apart from a stray wolf, who slowly grows an affinity to the kind-hearted man. Waiting for reinforcements to arrive, the first to contact him are his neighbours, the Sioux, with whom he soon forms a close familial relation, slowly immersing into their culture and way of life. Meanwhile chance encounters with bison hunters, cavalry troopers and loggers, have Dunbar grow increasingly disillusioned with his own kind... Rewatching the movie over twenty years after it received a multitude of Oscars (including Best Picture and Best Director), the widespread appeal of the movie has not faltered, still a touching, awe-inducing epic of stark significance to mainstream perceptions of American history. Certain aspects of the story-telling are simplistic and unrefined, often supplanting more cognitive portrayal of Sioux society with opportunities to bring in a hearty laugh. This doesn't however take away the charm of Costner's legendary feature, as comedy basically offers light-hearted respite from the inevitable downfall of the American Indians and the natural habitat in which they resided. The extended four hour cut undoubtedly has its coherence issues, as some scenes are visibly less well-rounded, often superfluous or just jarring. Nonetheless they do add to the overall scope and emotional pull of the story, hence all in all they largely feel best kept untouched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An epic dedicated to the human civilization
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huang20130418
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not an American. I have no right to judge this history and I'm not going to. The saddest thing about this movie is that we all know the end but we don't want it to come. We hope the harmony situation can last long, longer than the movie showed. But there's no way to expect that the tragedy of the Indian culture never come. Ancient civilization is bound to be replaced by modern one, though it may take blood, tears, darkness and sin to go through this. It's inevitable. As one saying (in China) goes, men are created to die. Though this analogy seems pretty sad, it's quite true. As soon as a man is born, he is moving to death every day, every hour and every second. So does human civilization. Human beings have gone through the original society, agriculture society, and now we are going through industrial society. It's impossible for us to foresee what the next society will be like after, say, 10000 years. So we can say that the industrial societies we build today are made to die, just like the original society and agriculture society. It's cruel to say this, but it does expose the cruelty that the world we live in and history we went through truly posses. This movie showed us this bloody and glory,miserable and honorable substitution process. So it's sure to be an epic. It's an epic dedicated to the human civilization. Also, being an epic requires magnificent scenes. This movie created a quite perfect one with the prairie, the sky, the buffalo and the wolf. Why do I count "wolf" in? Well, this movie spent a lot on that, didn't it? First, the name, "Dances with Wolves". Then the real wolf, there are lots of scenes about it. More importantly, this wolf, "two socks", is a symbol of Indian civilization. Outside the Indians look like cavemen, which is terrifying, this is similar to the wolf. But inside, they are kind, generous and warm-hearted, just like the development of the relationship between "two socks" and John Dunbar. So the denouement of the wolf marks the denouement of Indian culture. P.S. The music played in this movie is so wonderful and it contributed to the epic atmosphere. I think the only music which is better than this one is "My Heart Will Go On" in Titanic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful, Boring Anthem to Mr. Costner How Cool He Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I heard much about this movie - Dances was always names one of the best, decent, greatest and so on. I finally watched the complete 4-hour Director's Cut and what? It is tedious, boring, mediocre, long, slow, painfully pathetic film where we simply see every frame how cool, great, nice, heroic and grand Kevin Costner is. He made many awful movies, so far, but this one is a real under low, a real failure. Well, there are 2 great moments - the excellent scenery and animals. They are very good and sweet. The rest is very preachy, predictable, real boring and yawning all 4 long slow hours. This is what they call a heritage? Maybe, I was not impressed - Kevin made a movie about himself, for himself and with much of his beloved his self. Sorry, this does not work. This is not a Civil War movie, not a movie about nature, but a preachy-peachy saga of dullness and tediousness. Never watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best Western I've ever seen. One of its greatest strengths is its even handed portrayal of both sides of what was a gruesome bigotry ridden fight for land, opportunity, and way of life, between two very different cultures in the late 1800's. The Civil Wars' leftovers were a maliciously violent and frighteningly ignorant bunch, pit them against a culture of genuinely primitive & savage people (scalping & yelping pridefully about it  wow) and you have a perfect breeding ground for intolerance, impetuous violence, and never ending retaliatory fighting. "Dances with Wolves" provides a context for understanding both sides' humanity (for better and for worse) concerning this scar on our nation's history. Said understanding is permitted through an engaging story told on a stunning backdrop of our disappearing plains and enriched with beautifully moving music. In 2007, "Dances with Wolves" was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant." It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen. It won 7 Academy Awards, including Best Picture 1990; I'm not at all surprised and support the Library of Congress' decision.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably the best "going native" film to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film that manages to combine deep and meaningful character study with exotic locations and the feel of an adventure. Dances with Wolves is one of those rare films where time becomes transcendent and you're no longer able to perceive the usual story arcs or acts. They're there and the film has a rock-solid foundation, but you're still surprised when something new happens, because the film has managed to lull you into its world, its prolonged seasons. This is a movie that is able to portray the passage of time properly. It's a film in which events don't take place over a weekend or even a month. Rather whole years just glide by. Or perhaps just months, it's impossible to say for sure, but it feels like years, a sizable chunk of a whole life. And what a life that is and what a person living it. Lieutenant Dunbar - masterfully played by Kevin Costner - is a war hero given a dead end assignment according to his wishes, so that he can resign there to die a slow death. Thus the film starts as a macabre portrayal of a man giving up, but unable to just lay down. And it never becomes clear whether he manages to shake that initial attitude towards life. The events slowly give him more reasons to live, but Costner always plays him slightly detached, like he's always just one step away from giving up again. It's an amazing story and one that requires space to flourish. Quite many films since this one have managed to recreate the same "going native" storyline, which of course existed before this film though never quite like this, but none of them have seemed to realize that the film needs to dedicate most of its running time to the actual "going". Because that's the story, that's the attraction. The action scenes and battles have their place, but the magic is in the community, in the bonds that slowly grow between the main character and the natives. It's very hard to find any flaws in this film. Its slow pace is not for everyone, especially in the extended cut, but I personally never complained or even noticed the hours. It's a captivating film from start to finish and every minute is well spent, be it a minute of quiet landscapes rolling by or a minute of blazing battle. All has its place and every scene tells a story, reveals another layer. One of the greatest westerns ever filmed, if not one of the greatest films. In my opinion a film that everyone should watch at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyrian-shibara
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is hands down one of the best I've ever seen in reference to the American Indian. It does a fantastic job of portraying the Sioux as they really were, without bias or embellishment. The inclusion of the Pawnee in key scenes reinforces the fact that not all American Indians were the same - something that most Americans don't know or simply don't care about. It also makes a strong statement on the ignorance, cruelty, and disregard for the land that the whites showed when they settled the United States, and through the story of Dunbar, illustrates how that could have been avoided with nothing more than respect for another group as people and interest in their culture, instead of blind contempt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only one word: Harmony
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    geo-546-616925
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I beforehand knew that 'Dances with Wolves' ain't a typical western. However, I didn't know what exactly to expect. First of all, the direction is great, being Costner's first attempt. The performance of Costner, Greene and Grant added a lot to the movie, while the cinematographer wasn't awarded an Academy Award for nothing. However, the most important reason why everyone should watch and remember this film is its message; white man's madness has destroyed ancient cultures and spoiled Mother Nature. McDonnels's role wasn't bad, but she seemed to try too hard. The somewhat abrupt ending is something I didn't like, too. What is more, I believe the movie could be much more powerful in some scenes. This film is an all-time classic western and one of the best costume dramas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Born to be a hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nietzdrich Frietzsche
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunately, for some reason Kevin Costner didn't have the reputation of a talented actor. It would seem, that he has everything: he is a courageous, handsome, textured. He could play both brave daredevil and degraded debauchee-ribald. And he played, but evidently didn't convince exacting critics. Well, let so be it. All the same we love him. He nevertheless won critics' hearts by his director's talent. His epic western film &laquo;Dances with Wolves&raquo; - the confirmation of that. This is an extraordinary story about extraordinary man. Each of us makes strides along the road of life with one or another destination, leaving the tracks by acts of various kinds. Somebody sows the good seed, somebody destroys everything, somebody creates for the welfare of science and culture and somebody aimlessly goes down with the stream in expectation of opportune destiny. The character of &laquo; Dances with wolves&raquo;, First Lieutenant John Dunbar doomed to be a hero. His heroism is not the ostentatious prowess and thirst of recognize, it's his self, his way of life. His conscience, his spirit and his desperate heart lead his acts. His vital desire don't come to conquest of all possible and impossible heights, he violently persists in discover the frontier within himself. Growing roots in an uninhabited fort, stoically and thoroughly overcoming the harsh natural conditions, John Dunbar conscientiously and patiently waits for other soldiers. At first sight, he's absolutely lonely. But he realized very quickly all advantages of his loneliness: finally he was left alone with himself. Getting acquainted with Sioux, with their way of life, rituals and law, he doesn't look for personal gain. His aspiration to become closer with new neighbors, to be imbued with their traditions and, in the end, to become a part of their tribe, was dictated not by desire to relieve the lonely pastime or establish the good neighborly relations with strangers. All his acts  are heartfelt needs heart and soul. The destiny an incredible way throws John in the dizzying centrifuge of even more incredible circumstances, which frenzied rotation only strengthens his will and morale, opening him his true capabilities and personal orientations. Going over to the Sioux side and fighting against the U.S. Army, Dances with Wolves has no doubts in his right choice and actions. He doesn't compromise with his conscience, he acts jointly with it. He had found himself, the meaning of his way, and he didn't betray these acquirement. John Dunbar stepped into a heroic way from his birth and relentlessly moved on it even on unconscious level, without changing neither his route nor to himself. Ha was a hero even before accomplishment of his heroic feat. He went all his life to these and subsequent feats. John Dunbar didn't become Dances with Wolves, he became himself. And those circumstances, which thick he gets into, only push him to the frontier within himself, his genuine predestination. The staggering movie! And staggering Kevin Costner!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderfully and in details done masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luka V.
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is great about this film is that the plot itself completely fits in Costner's directing view which has easy pace and deep processed content. Furthermore, the way Costner displays such strong feelings as friendship( for example how wolf sacrifices himself for Lt. Dunbar and even how wolf hesitates to eat Dunbar's ham until it makes sure that he means well) and patriotism( in its true sense: battle for your people not country) and of course love( in a way that is not sneeze to watch, quite opposite). He dares criticize the way how American's treated Indians which sends humane message and shows how Kevin Costner's views are wide and beyond the limits( those opinions initiated the creation of the movie). Costner did the job perfectly and I'd like people not to question academy's decision to award this movie before Goodfellas for example( which is also a fantastic movie). I would recommend this movie to anyone because it will make an impression most likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Western-Drama-Romance-Action-Comedy-War masterpiece....what else can anyone ask for?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The talented and famous Kevin Costner during his great career he never received a deserved recognition for his impeccable performances. He had to sit on the director's chair and act at the same time to be finally awarded, and it wasn't for nothing. But to be able to start talking about the work of Costner and his great team, let's start talking about the wonderful story. "Dances with Wolves" begins during the American Civil War with the Lieutenant Dunbar (Kevin Costner), tired of all the war and after facing a near-death experience in the middle of a battlefield, he asks to be transferred to the unknown area of America, " The Frontier ", a vast green area with only animal and native life. Dunbar always dreamed of know and explore the frontier before she disappeared with the economic advancement of the Americans. But on this trip he is faced with the indigenous tribe, the "Sioux", and with them the great change of his life. A film that works as a Western with a vast Western environment and even moments of fantastic action in the Western style, but the film manages to go much deeper than that. From the beginning, the film manages to put ourselves on the feet of Dunbar, from the output of the world he was born into the unexplored world. The 1st hour of the film we only see Dunbar with his internal monologues and dialogs with his horse and a wild wolf that serves as their only company, but always with "Kicking Bird" (Graham Greene), a member of the Sioux tribe, watching him. Michael Blake's writing is just fantastic (who also manages to be loyal to his own work) making a fantastic job deepening Dunbar since a lonely man to a great friend of the Sioux. The film not only puts us at Dunbar's place but we get to feel the same feelings that he has regarding to the Sioux that goes from admiration to love. The Sioux can not only be an indigenous people with a great culture but nourish a huge intelligence and respect between each other, and they also have a innocent and good sense of humor (they fart; insults jokingly) making each one very realistic and human. We even feel a bit of the relationship between Dunbar and "Stand Fist" (Mary McDonnell), no big surprise, beyond beautiful she is smart and brave and also be the only white people among the tribe. Not only the writing of the film is fantastic maintaining an excellent character development but Costner's direction is just superb. Behind the camera he delivers a flawless direction putting us closely to the action scenes and makes us feel in the midst of the beautiful green desert with beautiful scenery magnificently filmed. The cast also stands out without difficulty: Kevin Costner is already superb behind the camera and in front of it would be no different with a sparkling gleam in his eye and his way of speaking the language of the Sioux without difficulty is just stunning; Mary McDonnell fantastic in every detail; Graham Greene honor his Native heritage perfectly. Kevin Costner was able to show a real talent for management and shines with a sparkling performance with a superb cast, all included in this beautiful story of a man who went out to find his place and eventually found himself. A wonderful writing and direction and an ending that made the strongest gets wet in tears, "Dances with Wolves" is a true classic masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical movie in more ways than one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Kevin Costner epic will undoubtedly never blow away with the wind, as a memorable and historical western, which for one - marks a new phase in relations with Native Americans. Most importantly "Dances with Wolves" sets a point in time, where native American culture can no longer be portrayed as savage, with incoming immigrants bringing with them technology, progress and the American dream. Now tainted, it could be said that one myth (of the civilisational conquering of the wild west) was supplanted by romanticised wigwams, but the latter for one thing is a much closer account of historical facts. Despite certain elaborated idealisation of Sioux life, this is a far cry from your mystical tree-hugging pacifists (aptly portrayed as being ruthless in warfare). However pointless this may be given the far-reaching recognisability of the movie, a short recap of the: Lt. John Dunbar (Kevin Costner) is sent out to the west to guard the frontier, while the rest of the country is in civil turmoil. The post is completely deserted apart from a stray wolf, who slowly grows an affinity to the kind-hearted man. Waiting for reinforcements to arrive, the first to contact him are his neighbours, the Sioux, with whom he soon forms a close familial relation, slowly immersing into their culture and way of life. Meanwhile chance encounters with bison hunters, cavalry troopers and loggers, have Dunbar grow increasingly disillusioned with his own kind... Rewatching the movie over twenty years after it received a multitude of Oscars (including Best Picture and Best Director), the widespread appeal of the movie has not faltered, still a touching, awe-inducing epic of stark significance to mainstream perceptions of American history. Certain aspects of the story-telling are simplistic and unrefined, often supplanting more cognitive portrayal of Sioux society with opportunities to bring in a hearty laugh. This doesn't however take away the charm of Costner's legendary feature, as comedy basically offers light-hearted respite from the inevitable downfall of the American Indians and the natural habitat in which they resided. The extended four hour cut undoubtedly has its coherence issues, as some scenes are visibly less well-rounded, often superfluous or just jarring. Nonetheless they do add to the overall scope and emotional pull of the story, hence all in all they largely feel best kept untouched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An epic dedicated to the human civilization
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huang20130418
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not an American. I have no right to judge this history and I'm not going to. The saddest thing about this movie is that we all know the end but we don't want it to come. We hope the harmony situation can last long, longer than the movie showed. But there's no way to expect that the tragedy of the Indian culture never come. Ancient civilization is bound to be replaced by modern one, though it may take blood, tears, darkness and sin to go through this. It's inevitable. As one saying (in China) goes, men are created to die. Though this analogy seems pretty sad, it's quite true. As soon as a man is born, he is moving to death every day, every hour and every second. So does human civilization. Human beings have gone through the original society, agriculture society, and now we are going through industrial society. It's impossible for us to foresee what the next society will be like after, say, 10000 years. So we can say that the industrial societies we build today are made to die, just like the original society and agriculture society. It's cruel to say this, but it does expose the cruelty that the world we live in and history we went through truly posses. This movie showed us this bloody and glory,miserable and honorable substitution process. So it's sure to be an epic. It's an epic dedicated to the human civilization. Also, being an epic requires magnificent scenes. This movie created a quite perfect one with the prairie, the sky, the buffalo and the wolf. Why do I count "wolf" in? Well, this movie spent a lot on that, didn't it? First, the name, "Dances with Wolves". Then the real wolf, there are lots of scenes about it. More importantly, this wolf, "two socks", is a symbol of Indian civilization. Outside the Indians look like cavemen, which is terrifying, this is similar to the wolf. But inside, they are kind, generous and warm-hearted, just like the development of the relationship between "two socks" and John Dunbar. So the denouement of the wolf marks the denouement of Indian culture. P.S. The music played in this movie is so wonderful and it contributed to the epic atmosphere. I think the only music which is better than this one is "My Heart Will Go On" in Titanic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful, Boring Anthem to Mr. Costner How Cool He Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I heard much about this movie - Dances was always names one of the best, decent, greatest and so on. I finally watched the complete 4-hour Director's Cut and what? It is tedious, boring, mediocre, long, slow, painfully pathetic film where we simply see every frame how cool, great, nice, heroic and grand Kevin Costner is. He made many awful movies, so far, but this one is a real under low, a real failure. Well, there are 2 great moments - the excellent scenery and animals. They are very good and sweet. The rest is very preachy, predictable, real boring and yawning all 4 long slow hours. This is what they call a heritage? Maybe, I was not impressed - Kevin made a movie about himself, for himself and with much of his beloved his self. Sorry, this does not work. This is not a Civil War movie, not a movie about nature, but a preachy-peachy saga of dullness and tediousness. Never watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best Western I've ever seen. One of its greatest strengths is its even handed portrayal of both sides of what was a gruesome bigotry ridden fight for land, opportunity, and way of life, between two very different cultures in the late 1800's. The Civil Wars' leftovers were a maliciously violent and frighteningly ignorant bunch, pit them against a culture of genuinely primitive & savage people (scalping & yelping pridefully about it  wow) and you have a perfect breeding ground for intolerance, impetuous violence, and never ending retaliatory fighting. "Dances with Wolves" provides a context for understanding both sides' humanity (for better and for worse) concerning this scar on our nation's history. Said understanding is permitted through an engaging story told on a stunning backdrop of our disappearing plains and enriched with beautifully moving music. In 2007, "Dances with Wolves" was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant." It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen. It won 7 Academy Awards, including Best Picture 1990; I'm not at all surprised and support the Library of Congress' decision.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably the best "going native" film to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film that manages to combine deep and meaningful character study with exotic locations and the feel of an adventure. Dances with Wolves is one of those rare films where time becomes transcendent and you're no longer able to perceive the usual story arcs or acts. They're there and the film has a rock-solid foundation, but you're still surprised when something new happens, because the film has managed to lull you into its world, its prolonged seasons. This is a movie that is able to portray the passage of time properly. It's a film in which events don't take place over a weekend or even a month. Rather whole years just glide by. Or perhaps just months, it's impossible to say for sure, but it feels like years, a sizable chunk of a whole life. And what a life that is and what a person living it. Lieutenant Dunbar - masterfully played by Kevin Costner - is a war hero given a dead end assignment according to his wishes, so that he can resign there to die a slow death. Thus the film starts as a macabre portrayal of a man giving up, but unable to just lay down. And it never becomes clear whether he manages to shake that initial attitude towards life. The events slowly give him more reasons to live, but Costner always plays him slightly detached, like he's always just one step away from giving up again. It's an amazing story and one that requires space to flourish. Quite many films since this one have managed to recreate the same "going native" storyline, which of course existed before this film though never quite like this, but none of them have seemed to realize that the film needs to dedicate most of its running time to the actual "going". Because that's the story, that's the attraction. The action scenes and battles have their place, but the magic is in the community, in the bonds that slowly grow between the main character and the natives. It's very hard to find any flaws in this film. Its slow pace is not for everyone, especially in the extended cut, but I personally never complained or even noticed the hours. It's a captivating film from start to finish and every minute is well spent, be it a minute of quiet landscapes rolling by or a minute of blazing battle. All has its place and every scene tells a story, reveals another layer. One of the greatest westerns ever filmed, if not one of the greatest films. In my opinion a film that everyone should watch at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyrian-shibara
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is hands down one of the best I've ever seen in reference to the American Indian. It does a fantastic job of portraying the Sioux as they really were, without bias or embellishment. The inclusion of the Pawnee in key scenes reinforces the fact that not all American Indians were the same - something that most Americans don't know or simply don't care about. It also makes a strong statement on the ignorance, cruelty, and disregard for the land that the whites showed when they settled the United States, and through the story of Dunbar, illustrates how that could have been avoided with nothing more than respect for another group as people and interest in their culture, instead of blind contempt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only one word: Harmony
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    geo-546-616925
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I beforehand knew that 'Dances with Wolves' ain't a typical western. However, I didn't know what exactly to expect. First of all, the direction is great, being Costner's first attempt. The performance of Costner, Greene and Grant added a lot to the movie, while the cinematographer wasn't awarded an Academy Award for nothing. However, the most important reason why everyone should watch and remember this film is its message; white man's madness has destroyed ancient cultures and spoiled Mother Nature. McDonnels's role wasn't bad, but she seemed to try too hard. The somewhat abrupt ending is something I didn't like, too. What is more, I believe the movie could be much more powerful in some scenes. This film is an all-time classic western and one of the best costume dramas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Born to be a hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nietzdrich Frietzsche
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunately, for some reason Kevin Costner didn't have the reputation of a talented actor. It would seem, that he has everything: he is a courageous, handsome, textured. He could play both brave daredevil and degraded debauchee-ribald. And he played, but evidently didn't convince exacting critics. Well, let so be it. All the same we love him. He nevertheless won critics' hearts by his director's talent. His epic western film &laquo;Dances with Wolves&raquo; - the confirmation of that. This is an extraordinary story about extraordinary man. Each of us makes strides along the road of life with one or another destination, leaving the tracks by acts of various kinds. Somebody sows the good seed, somebody destroys everything, somebody creates for the welfare of science and culture and somebody aimlessly goes down with the stream in expectation of opportune destiny. The character of &laquo; Dances with wolves&raquo;, First Lieutenant John Dunbar doomed to be a hero. His heroism is not the ostentatious prowess and thirst of recognize, it's his self, his way of life. His conscience, his spirit and his desperate heart lead his acts. His vital desire don't come to conquest of all possible and impossible heights, he violently persists in discover the frontier within himself. Growing roots in an uninhabited fort, stoically and thoroughly overcoming the harsh natural conditions, John Dunbar conscientiously and patiently waits for other soldiers. At first sight, he's absolutely lonely. But he realized very quickly all advantages of his loneliness: finally he was left alone with himself. Getting acquainted with Sioux, with their way of life, rituals and law, he doesn't look for personal gain. His aspiration to become closer with new neighbors, to be imbued with their traditions and, in the end, to become a part of their tribe, was dictated not by desire to relieve the lonely pastime or establish the good neighborly relations with strangers. All his acts  are heartfelt needs heart and soul. The destiny an incredible way throws John in the dizzying centrifuge of even more incredible circumstances, which frenzied rotation only strengthens his will and morale, opening him his true capabilities and personal orientations. Going over to the Sioux side and fighting against the U.S. Army, Dances with Wolves has no doubts in his right choice and actions. He doesn't compromise with his conscience, he acts jointly with it. He had found himself, the meaning of his way, and he didn't betray these acquirement. John Dunbar stepped into a heroic way from his birth and relentlessly moved on it even on unconscious level, without changing neither his route nor to himself. Ha was a hero even before accomplishment of his heroic feat. He went all his life to these and subsequent feats. John Dunbar didn't become Dances with Wolves, he became himself. And those circumstances, which thick he gets into, only push him to the frontier within himself, his genuine predestination. The staggering movie! And staggering Kevin Costner!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderfully and in details done masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luka V.
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is great about this film is that the plot itself completely fits in Costner's directing view which has easy pace and deep processed content. Furthermore, the way Costner displays such strong feelings as friendship( for example how wolf sacrifices himself for Lt. Dunbar and even how wolf hesitates to eat Dunbar's ham until it makes sure that he means well) and patriotism( in its true sense: battle for your people not country) and of course love( in a way that is not sneeze to watch, quite opposite). He dares criticize the way how American's treated Indians which sends humane message and shows how Kevin Costner's views are wide and beyond the limits( those opinions initiated the creation of the movie). Costner did the job perfectly and I'd like people not to question academy's decision to award this movie before Goodfellas for example( which is also a fantastic movie). I would recommend this movie to anyone because it will make an impression most likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Western-Drama-Romance-Action-Comedy-War masterpiece....what else can anyone ask for?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The talented and famous Kevin Costner during his great career he never received a deserved recognition for his impeccable performances. He had to sit on the director's chair and act at the same time to be finally awarded, and it wasn't for nothing. But to be able to start talking about the work of Costner and his great team, let's start talking about the wonderful story. "Dances with Wolves" begins during the American Civil War with the Lieutenant Dunbar (Kevin Costner), tired of all the war and after facing a near-death experience in the middle of a battlefield, he asks to be transferred to the unknown area of America, " The Frontier ", a vast green area with only animal and native life. Dunbar always dreamed of know and explore the frontier before she disappeared with the economic advancement of the Americans. But on this trip he is faced with the indigenous tribe, the "Sioux", and with them the great change of his life. A film that works as a Western with a vast Western environment and even moments of fantastic action in the Western style, but the film manages to go much deeper than that. From the beginning, the film manages to put ourselves on the feet of Dunbar, from the output of the world he was born into the unexplored world. The 1st hour of the film we only see Dunbar with his internal monologues and dialogs with his horse and a wild wolf that serves as their only company, but always with "Kicking Bird" (Graham Greene), a member of the Sioux tribe, watching him. Michael Blake's writing is just fantastic (who also manages to be loyal to his own work) making a fantastic job deepening Dunbar since a lonely man to a great friend of the Sioux. The film not only puts us at Dunbar's place but we get to feel the same feelings that he has regarding to the Sioux that goes from admiration to love. The Sioux can not only be an indigenous people with a great culture but nourish a huge intelligence and respect between each other, and they also have a innocent and good sense of humor (they fart; insults jokingly) making each one very realistic and human. We even feel a bit of the relationship between Dunbar and "Stand Fist" (Mary McDonnell), no big surprise, beyond beautiful she is smart and brave and also be the only white people among the tribe. Not only the writing of the film is fantastic maintaining an excellent character development but Costner's direction is just superb. Behind the camera he delivers a flawless direction putting us closely to the action scenes and makes us feel in the midst of the beautiful green desert with beautiful scenery magnificently filmed. The cast also stands out without difficulty: Kevin Costner is already superb behind the camera and in front of it would be no different with a sparkling gleam in his eye and his way of speaking the language of the Sioux without difficulty is just stunning; Mary McDonnell fantastic in every detail; Graham Greene honor his Native heritage perfectly. Kevin Costner was able to show a real talent for management and shines with a sparkling performance with a superb cast, all included in this beautiful story of a man who went out to find his place and eventually found himself. A wonderful writing and direction and an ending that made the strongest gets wet in tears, "Dances with Wolves" is a true classic masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical movie in more ways than one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Kevin Costner epic will undoubtedly never blow away with the wind, as a memorable and historical western, which for one - marks a new phase in relations with Native Americans. Most importantly "Dances with Wolves" sets a point in time, where native American culture can no longer be portrayed as savage, with incoming immigrants bringing with them technology, progress and the American dream. Now tainted, it could be said that one myth (of the civilisational conquering of the wild west) was supplanted by romanticised wigwams, but the latter for one thing is a much closer account of historical facts. Despite certain elaborated idealisation of Sioux life, this is a far cry from your mystical tree-hugging pacifists (aptly portrayed as being ruthless in warfare). However pointless this may be given the far-reaching recognisability of the movie, a short recap of the: Lt. John Dunbar (Kevin Costner) is sent out to the west to guard the frontier, while the rest of the country is in civil turmoil. The post is completely deserted apart from a stray wolf, who slowly grows an affinity to the kind-hearted man. Waiting for reinforcements to arrive, the first to contact him are his neighbours, the Sioux, with whom he soon forms a close familial relation, slowly immersing into their culture and way of life. Meanwhile chance encounters with bison hunters, cavalry troopers and loggers, have Dunbar grow increasingly disillusioned with his own kind... Rewatching the movie over twenty years after it received a multitude of Oscars (including Best Picture and Best Director), the widespread appeal of the movie has not faltered, still a touching, awe-inducing epic of stark significance to mainstream perceptions of American history. Certain aspects of the story-telling are simplistic and unrefined, often supplanting more cognitive portrayal of Sioux society with opportunities to bring in a hearty laugh. This doesn't however take away the charm of Costner's legendary feature, as comedy basically offers light-hearted respite from the inevitable downfall of the American Indians and the natural habitat in which they resided. The extended four hour cut undoubtedly has its coherence issues, as some scenes are visibly less well-rounded, often superfluous or just jarring. Nonetheless they do add to the overall scope and emotional pull of the story, hence all in all they largely feel best kept untouched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An epic dedicated to the human civilization
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huang20130418
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not an American. I have no right to judge this history and I'm not going to. The saddest thing about this movie is that we all know the end but we don't want it to come. We hope the harmony situation can last long, longer than the movie showed. But there's no way to expect that the tragedy of the Indian culture never come. Ancient civilization is bound to be replaced by modern one, though it may take blood, tears, darkness and sin to go through this. It's inevitable. As one saying (in China) goes, men are created to die. Though this analogy seems pretty sad, it's quite true. As soon as a man is born, he is moving to death every day, every hour and every second. So does human civilization. Human beings have gone through the original society, agriculture society, and now we are going through industrial society. It's impossible for us to foresee what the next society will be like after, say, 10000 years. So we can say that the industrial societies we build today are made to die, just like the original society and agriculture society. It's cruel to say this, but it does expose the cruelty that the world we live in and history we went through truly posses. This movie showed us this bloody and glory,miserable and honorable substitution process. So it's sure to be an epic. It's an epic dedicated to the human civilization. Also, being an epic requires magnificent scenes. This movie created a quite perfect one with the prairie, the sky, the buffalo and the wolf. Why do I count "wolf" in? Well, this movie spent a lot on that, didn't it? First, the name, "Dances with Wolves". Then the real wolf, there are lots of scenes about it. More importantly, this wolf, "two socks", is a symbol of Indian civilization. Outside the Indians look like cavemen, which is terrifying, this is similar to the wolf. But inside, they are kind, generous and warm-hearted, just like the development of the relationship between "two socks" and John Dunbar. So the denouement of the wolf marks the denouement of Indian culture. P.S. The music played in this movie is so wonderful and it contributed to the epic atmosphere. I think the only music which is better than this one is "My Heart Will Go On" in Titanic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful, Boring Anthem to Mr. Costner How Cool He Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I heard much about this movie - Dances was always names one of the best, decent, greatest and so on. I finally watched the complete 4-hour Director's Cut and what? It is tedious, boring, mediocre, long, slow, painfully pathetic film where we simply see every frame how cool, great, nice, heroic and grand Kevin Costner is. He made many awful movies, so far, but this one is a real under low, a real failure. Well, there are 2 great moments - the excellent scenery and animals. They are very good and sweet. The rest is very preachy, predictable, real boring and yawning all 4 long slow hours. This is what they call a heritage? Maybe, I was not impressed - Kevin made a movie about himself, for himself and with much of his beloved his self. Sorry, this does not work. This is not a Civil War movie, not a movie about nature, but a preachy-peachy saga of dullness and tediousness. Never watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best Western I've ever seen. One of its greatest strengths is its even handed portrayal of both sides of what was a gruesome bigotry ridden fight for land, opportunity, and way of life, between two very different cultures in the late 1800's. The Civil Wars' leftovers were a maliciously violent and frighteningly ignorant bunch, pit them against a culture of genuinely primitive & savage people (scalping & yelping pridefully about it  wow) and you have a perfect breeding ground for intolerance, impetuous violence, and never ending retaliatory fighting. "Dances with Wolves" provides a context for understanding both sides' humanity (for better and for worse) concerning this scar on our nation's history. Said understanding is permitted through an engaging story told on a stunning backdrop of our disappearing plains and enriched with beautifully moving music. In 2007, "Dances with Wolves" was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant." It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen. It won 7 Academy Awards, including Best Picture 1990; I'm not at all surprised and support the Library of Congress' decision.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably the best "going native" film to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film that manages to combine deep and meaningful character study with exotic locations and the feel of an adventure. Dances with Wolves is one of those rare films where time becomes transcendent and you're no longer able to perceive the usual story arcs or acts. They're there and the film has a rock-solid foundation, but you're still surprised when something new happens, because the film has managed to lull you into its world, its prolonged seasons. This is a movie that is able to portray the passage of time properly. It's a film in which events don't take place over a weekend or even a month. Rather whole years just glide by. Or perhaps just months, it's impossible to say for sure, but it feels like years, a sizable chunk of a whole life. And what a life that is and what a person living it. Lieutenant Dunbar - masterfully played by Kevin Costner - is a war hero given a dead end assignment according to his wishes, so that he can resign there to die a slow death. Thus the film starts as a macabre portrayal of a man giving up, but unable to just lay down. And it never becomes clear whether he manages to shake that initial attitude towards life. The events slowly give him more reasons to live, but Costner always plays him slightly detached, like he's always just one step away from giving up again. It's an amazing story and one that requires space to flourish. Quite many films since this one have managed to recreate the same "going native" storyline, which of course existed before this film though never quite like this, but none of them have seemed to realize that the film needs to dedicate most of its running time to the actual "going". Because that's the story, that's the attraction. The action scenes and battles have their place, but the magic is in the community, in the bonds that slowly grow between the main character and the natives. It's very hard to find any flaws in this film. Its slow pace is not for everyone, especially in the extended cut, but I personally never complained or even noticed the hours. It's a captivating film from start to finish and every minute is well spent, be it a minute of quiet landscapes rolling by or a minute of blazing battle. All has its place and every scene tells a story, reveals another layer. One of the greatest westerns ever filmed, if not one of the greatest films. In my opinion a film that everyone should watch at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyrian-shibara
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is hands down one of the best I've ever seen in reference to the American Indian. It does a fantastic job of portraying the Sioux as they really were, without bias or embellishment. The inclusion of the Pawnee in key scenes reinforces the fact that not all American Indians were the same - something that most Americans don't know or simply don't care about. It also makes a strong statement on the ignorance, cruelty, and disregard for the land that the whites showed when they settled the United States, and through the story of Dunbar, illustrates how that could have been avoided with nothing more than respect for another group as people and interest in their culture, instead of blind contempt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only one word: Harmony
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    geo-546-616925
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I beforehand knew that 'Dances with Wolves' ain't a typical western. However, I didn't know what exactly to expect. First of all, the direction is great, being Costner's first attempt. The performance of Costner, Greene and Grant added a lot to the movie, while the cinematographer wasn't awarded an Academy Award for nothing. However, the most important reason why everyone should watch and remember this film is its message; white man's madness has destroyed ancient cultures and spoiled Mother Nature. McDonnels's role wasn't bad, but she seemed to try too hard. The somewhat abrupt ending is something I didn't like, too. What is more, I believe the movie could be much more powerful in some scenes. This film is an all-time classic western and one of the best costume dramas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Born to be a hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nietzdrich Frietzsche
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunately, for some reason Kevin Costner didn't have the reputation of a talented actor. It would seem, that he has everything: he is a courageous, handsome, textured. He could play both brave daredevil and degraded debauchee-ribald. And he played, but evidently didn't convince exacting critics. Well, let so be it. All the same we love him. He nevertheless won critics' hearts by his director's talent. His epic western film &laquo;Dances with Wolves&raquo; - the confirmation of that. This is an extraordinary story about extraordinary man. Each of us makes strides along the road of life with one or another destination, leaving the tracks by acts of various kinds. Somebody sows the good seed, somebody destroys everything, somebody creates for the welfare of science and culture and somebody aimlessly goes down with the stream in expectation of opportune destiny. The character of &laquo; Dances with wolves&raquo;, First Lieutenant John Dunbar doomed to be a hero. His heroism is not the ostentatious prowess and thirst of recognize, it's his self, his way of life. His conscience, his spirit and his desperate heart lead his acts. His vital desire don't come to conquest of all possible and impossible heights, he violently persists in discover the frontier within himself. Growing roots in an uninhabited fort, stoically and thoroughly overcoming the harsh natural conditions, John Dunbar conscientiously and patiently waits for other soldiers. At first sight, he's absolutely lonely. But he realized very quickly all advantages of his loneliness: finally he was left alone with himself. Getting acquainted with Sioux, with their way of life, rituals and law, he doesn't look for personal gain. His aspiration to become closer with new neighbors, to be imbued with their traditions and, in the end, to become a part of their tribe, was dictated not by desire to relieve the lonely pastime or establish the good neighborly relations with strangers. All his acts  are heartfelt needs heart and soul. The destiny an incredible way throws John in the dizzying centrifuge of even more incredible circumstances, which frenzied rotation only strengthens his will and morale, opening him his true capabilities and personal orientations. Going over to the Sioux side and fighting against the U.S. Army, Dances with Wolves has no doubts in his right choice and actions. He doesn't compromise with his conscience, he acts jointly with it. He had found himself, the meaning of his way, and he didn't betray these acquirement. John Dunbar stepped into a heroic way from his birth and relentlessly moved on it even on unconscious level, without changing neither his route nor to himself. Ha was a hero even before accomplishment of his heroic feat. He went all his life to these and subsequent feats. John Dunbar didn't become Dances with Wolves, he became himself. And those circumstances, which thick he gets into, only push him to the frontier within himself, his genuine predestination. The staggering movie! And staggering Kevin Costner!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderfully and in details done masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luka V.
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is great about this film is that the plot itself completely fits in Costner's directing view which has easy pace and deep processed content. Furthermore, the way Costner displays such strong feelings as friendship( for example how wolf sacrifices himself for Lt. Dunbar and even how wolf hesitates to eat Dunbar's ham until it makes sure that he means well) and patriotism( in its true sense: battle for your people not country) and of course love( in a way that is not sneeze to watch, quite opposite). He dares criticize the way how American's treated Indians which sends humane message and shows how Kevin Costner's views are wide and beyond the limits( those opinions initiated the creation of the movie). Costner did the job perfectly and I'd like people not to question academy's decision to award this movie before Goodfellas for example( which is also a fantastic movie). I would recommend this movie to anyone because it will make an impression most likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Western-Drama-Romance-Action-Comedy-War masterpiece....what else can anyone ask for?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The talented and famous Kevin Costner during his great career he never received a deserved recognition for his impeccable performances. He had to sit on the director's chair and act at the same time to be finally awarded, and it wasn't for nothing. But to be able to start talking about the work of Costner and his great team, let's start talking about the wonderful story. "Dances with Wolves" begins during the American Civil War with the Lieutenant Dunbar (Kevin Costner), tired of all the war and after facing a near-death experience in the middle of a battlefield, he asks to be transferred to the unknown area of America, " The Frontier ", a vast green area with only animal and native life. Dunbar always dreamed of know and explore the frontier before she disappeared with the economic advancement of the Americans. But on this trip he is faced with the indigenous tribe, the "Sioux", and with them the great change of his life. A film that works as a Western with a vast Western environment and even moments of fantastic action in the Western style, but the film manages to go much deeper than that. From the beginning, the film manages to put ourselves on the feet of Dunbar, from the output of the world he was born into the unexplored world. The 1st hour of the film we only see Dunbar with his internal monologues and dialogs with his horse and a wild wolf that serves as their only company, but always with "Kicking Bird" (Graham Greene), a member of the Sioux tribe, watching him. Michael Blake's writing is just fantastic (who also manages to be loyal to his own work) making a fantastic job deepening Dunbar since a lonely man to a great friend of the Sioux. The film not only puts us at Dunbar's place but we get to feel the same feelings that he has regarding to the Sioux that goes from admiration to love. The Sioux can not only be an indigenous people with a great culture but nourish a huge intelligence and respect between each other, and they also have a innocent and good sense of humor (they fart; insults jokingly) making each one very realistic and human. We even feel a bit of the relationship between Dunbar and "Stand Fist" (Mary McDonnell), no big surprise, beyond beautiful she is smart and brave and also be the only white people among the tribe. Not only the writing of the film is fantastic maintaining an excellent character development but Costner's direction is just superb. Behind the camera he delivers a flawless direction putting us closely to the action scenes and makes us feel in the midst of the beautiful green desert with beautiful scenery magnificently filmed. The cast also stands out without difficulty: Kevin Costner is already superb behind the camera and in front of it would be no different with a sparkling gleam in his eye and his way of speaking the language of the Sioux without difficulty is just stunning; Mary McDonnell fantastic in every detail; Graham Greene honor his Native heritage perfectly. Kevin Costner was able to show a real talent for management and shines with a sparkling performance with a superb cast, all included in this beautiful story of a man who went out to find his place and eventually found himself. A wonderful writing and direction and an ending that made the strongest gets wet in tears, "Dances with Wolves" is a true classic masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical movie in more ways than one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Kevin Costner epic will undoubtedly never blow away with the wind, as a memorable and historical western, which for one - marks a new phase in relations with Native Americans. Most importantly "Dances with Wolves" sets a point in time, where native American culture can no longer be portrayed as savage, with incoming immigrants bringing with them technology, progress and the American dream. Now tainted, it could be said that one myth (of the civilisational conquering of the wild west) was supplanted by romanticised wigwams, but the latter for one thing is a much closer account of historical facts. Despite certain elaborated idealisation of Sioux life, this is a far cry from your mystical tree-hugging pacifists (aptly portrayed as being ruthless in warfare). However pointless this may be given the far-reaching recognisability of the movie, a short recap of the: Lt. John Dunbar (Kevin Costner) is sent out to the west to guard the frontier, while the rest of the country is in civil turmoil. The post is completely deserted apart from a stray wolf, who slowly grows an affinity to the kind-hearted man. Waiting for reinforcements to arrive, the first to contact him are his neighbours, the Sioux, with whom he soon forms a close familial relation, slowly immersing into their culture and way of life. Meanwhile chance encounters with bison hunters, cavalry troopers and loggers, have Dunbar grow increasingly disillusioned with his own kind... Rewatching the movie over twenty years after it received a multitude of Oscars (including Best Picture and Best Director), the widespread appeal of the movie has not faltered, still a touching, awe-inducing epic of stark significance to mainstream perceptions of American history. Certain aspects of the story-telling are simplistic and unrefined, often supplanting more cognitive portrayal of Sioux society with opportunities to bring in a hearty laugh. This doesn't however take away the charm of Costner's legendary feature, as comedy basically offers light-hearted respite from the inevitable downfall of the American Indians and the natural habitat in which they resided. The extended four hour cut undoubtedly has its coherence issues, as some scenes are visibly less well-rounded, often superfluous or just jarring. Nonetheless they do add to the overall scope and emotional pull of the story, hence all in all they largely feel best kept untouched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An epic dedicated to the human civilization
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huang20130418
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not an American. I have no right to judge this history and I'm not going to. The saddest thing about this movie is that we all know the end but we don't want it to come. We hope the harmony situation can last long, longer than the movie showed. But there's no way to expect that the tragedy of the Indian culture never come. Ancient civilization is bound to be replaced by modern one, though it may take blood, tears, darkness and sin to go through this. It's inevitable. As one saying (in China) goes, men are created to die. Though this analogy seems pretty sad, it's quite true. As soon as a man is born, he is moving to death every day, every hour and every second. So does human civilization. Human beings have gone through the original society, agriculture society, and now we are going through industrial society. It's impossible for us to foresee what the next society will be like after, say, 10000 years. So we can say that the industrial societies we build today are made to die, just like the original society and agriculture society. It's cruel to say this, but it does expose the cruelty that the world we live in and history we went through truly posses. This movie showed us this bloody and glory,miserable and honorable substitution process. So it's sure to be an epic. It's an epic dedicated to the human civilization. Also, being an epic requires magnificent scenes. This movie created a quite perfect one with the prairie, the sky, the buffalo and the wolf. Why do I count "wolf" in? Well, this movie spent a lot on that, didn't it? First, the name, "Dances with Wolves". Then the real wolf, there are lots of scenes about it. More importantly, this wolf, "two socks", is a symbol of Indian civilization. Outside the Indians look like cavemen, which is terrifying, this is similar to the wolf. But inside, they are kind, generous and warm-hearted, just like the development of the relationship between "two socks" and John Dunbar. So the denouement of the wolf marks the denouement of Indian culture. P.S. The music played in this movie is so wonderful and it contributed to the epic atmosphere. I think the only music which is better than this one is "My Heart Will Go On" in Titanic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful, Boring Anthem to Mr. Costner How Cool He Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I heard much about this movie - Dances was always names one of the best, decent, greatest and so on. I finally watched the complete 4-hour Director's Cut and what? It is tedious, boring, mediocre, long, slow, painfully pathetic film where we simply see every frame how cool, great, nice, heroic and grand Kevin Costner is. He made many awful movies, so far, but this one is a real under low, a real failure. Well, there are 2 great moments - the excellent scenery and animals. They are very good and sweet. The rest is very preachy, predictable, real boring and yawning all 4 long slow hours. This is what they call a heritage? Maybe, I was not impressed - Kevin made a movie about himself, for himself and with much of his beloved his self. Sorry, this does not work. This is not a Civil War movie, not a movie about nature, but a preachy-peachy saga of dullness and tediousness. Never watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best Western I've ever seen. One of its greatest strengths is its even handed portrayal of both sides of what was a gruesome bigotry ridden fight for land, opportunity, and way of life, between two very different cultures in the late 1800's. The Civil Wars' leftovers were a maliciously violent and frighteningly ignorant bunch, pit them against a culture of genuinely primitive & savage people (scalping & yelping pridefully about it  wow) and you have a perfect breeding ground for intolerance, impetuous violence, and never ending retaliatory fighting. "Dances with Wolves" provides a context for understanding both sides' humanity (for better and for worse) concerning this scar on our nation's history. Said understanding is permitted through an engaging story told on a stunning backdrop of our disappearing plains and enriched with beautifully moving music. In 2007, "Dances with Wolves" was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant." It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen. It won 7 Academy Awards, including Best Picture 1990; I'm not at all surprised and support the Library of Congress' decision.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably the best "going native" film to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film that manages to combine deep and meaningful character study with exotic locations and the feel of an adventure. Dances with Wolves is one of those rare films where time becomes transcendent and you're no longer able to perceive the usual story arcs or acts. They're there and the film has a rock-solid foundation, but you're still surprised when something new happens, because the film has managed to lull you into its world, its prolonged seasons. This is a movie that is able to portray the passage of time properly. It's a film in which events don't take place over a weekend or even a month. Rather whole years just glide by. Or perhaps just months, it's impossible to say for sure, but it feels like years, a sizable chunk of a whole life. And what a life that is and what a person living it. Lieutenant Dunbar - masterfully played by Kevin Costner - is a war hero given a dead end assignment according to his wishes, so that he can resign there to die a slow death. Thus the film starts as a macabre portrayal of a man giving up, but unable to just lay down. And it never becomes clear whether he manages to shake that initial attitude towards life. The events slowly give him more reasons to live, but Costner always plays him slightly detached, like he's always just one step away from giving up again. It's an amazing story and one that requires space to flourish. Quite many films since this one have managed to recreate the same "going native" storyline, which of course existed before this film though never quite like this, but none of them have seemed to realize that the film needs to dedicate most of its running time to the actual "going". Because that's the story, that's the attraction. The action scenes and battles have their place, but the magic is in the community, in the bonds that slowly grow between the main character and the natives. It's very hard to find any flaws in this film. Its slow pace is not for everyone, especially in the extended cut, but I personally never complained or even noticed the hours. It's a captivating film from start to finish and every minute is well spent, be it a minute of quiet landscapes rolling by or a minute of blazing battle. All has its place and every scene tells a story, reveals another layer. One of the greatest westerns ever filmed, if not one of the greatest films. In my opinion a film that everyone should watch at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greats
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kyrian-shibara
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is hands down one of the best I've ever seen in reference to the American Indian. It does a fantastic job of portraying the Sioux as they really were, without bias or embellishment. The inclusion of the Pawnee in key scenes reinforces the fact that not all American Indians were the same - something that most Americans don't know or simply don't care about. It also makes a strong statement on the ignorance, cruelty, and disregard for the land that the whites showed when they settled the United States, and through the story of Dunbar, illustrates how that could have been avoided with nothing more than respect for another group as people and interest in their culture, instead of blind contempt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only one word: Harmony
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    geo-546-616925
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I beforehand knew that 'Dances with Wolves' ain't a typical western. However, I didn't know what exactly to expect. First of all, the direction is great, being Costner's first attempt. The performance of Costner, Greene and Grant added a lot to the movie, while the cinematographer wasn't awarded an Academy Award for nothing. However, the most important reason why everyone should watch and remember this film is its message; white man's madness has destroyed ancient cultures and spoiled Mother Nature. McDonnels's role wasn't bad, but she seemed to try too hard. The somewhat abrupt ending is something I didn't like, too. What is more, I believe the movie could be much more powerful in some scenes. This film is an all-time classic western and one of the best costume dramas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Born to be a hero
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nietzdrich Frietzsche
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unfortunately, for some reason Kevin Costner didn't have the reputation of a talented actor. It would seem, that he has everything: he is a courageous, handsome, textured. He could play both brave daredevil and degraded debauchee-ribald. And he played, but evidently didn't convince exacting critics. Well, let so be it. All the same we love him. He nevertheless won critics' hearts by his director's talent. His epic western film &laquo;Dances with Wolves&raquo; - the confirmation of that. This is an extraordinary story about extraordinary man. Each of us makes strides along the road of life with one or another destination, leaving the tracks by acts of various kinds. Somebody sows the good seed, somebody destroys everything, somebody creates for the welfare of science and culture and somebody aimlessly goes down with the stream in expectation of opportune destiny. The character of &laquo; Dances with wolves&raquo;, First Lieutenant John Dunbar doomed to be a hero. His heroism is not the ostentatious prowess and thirst of recognize, it's his self, his way of life. His conscience, his spirit and his desperate heart lead his acts. His vital desire don't come to conquest of all possible and impossible heights, he violently persists in discover the frontier within himself. Growing roots in an uninhabited fort, stoically and thoroughly overcoming the harsh natural conditions, John Dunbar conscientiously and patiently waits for other soldiers. At first sight, he's absolutely lonely. But he realized very quickly all advantages of his loneliness: finally he was left alone with himself. Getting acquainted with Sioux, with their way of life, rituals and law, he doesn't look for personal gain. His aspiration to become closer with new neighbors, to be imbued with their traditions and, in the end, to become a part of their tribe, was dictated not by desire to relieve the lonely pastime or establish the good neighborly relations with strangers. All his acts  are heartfelt needs heart and soul. The destiny an incredible way throws John in the dizzying centrifuge of even more incredible circumstances, which frenzied rotation only strengthens his will and morale, opening him his true capabilities and personal orientations. Going over to the Sioux side and fighting against the U.S. Army, Dances with Wolves has no doubts in his right choice and actions. He doesn't compromise with his conscience, he acts jointly with it. He had found himself, the meaning of his way, and he didn't betray these acquirement. John Dunbar stepped into a heroic way from his birth and relentlessly moved on it even on unconscious level, without changing neither his route nor to himself. Ha was a hero even before accomplishment of his heroic feat. He went all his life to these and subsequent feats. John Dunbar didn't become Dances with Wolves, he became himself. And those circumstances, which thick he gets into, only push him to the frontier within himself, his genuine predestination. The staggering movie! And staggering Kevin Costner!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderfully and in details done masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luka V.
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What is great about this film is that the plot itself completely fits in Costner's directing view which has easy pace and deep processed content. Furthermore, the way Costner displays such strong feelings as friendship( for example how wolf sacrifices himself for Lt. Dunbar and even how wolf hesitates to eat Dunbar's ham until it makes sure that he means well) and patriotism( in its true sense: battle for your people not country) and of course love( in a way that is not sneeze to watch, quite opposite). He dares criticize the way how American's treated Indians which sends humane message and shows how Kevin Costner's views are wide and beyond the limits( those opinions initiated the creation of the movie). Costner did the job perfectly and I'd like people not to question academy's decision to award this movie before Goodfellas for example( which is also a fantastic movie). I would recommend this movie to anyone because it will make an impression most likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Western-Drama-Romance-Action-Comedy-War masterpiece....what else can anyone ask for?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raphaklopper
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The talented and famous Kevin Costner during his great career he never received a deserved recognition for his impeccable performances. He had to sit on the director's chair and act at the same time to be finally awarded, and it wasn't for nothing. But to be able to start talking about the work of Costner and his great team, let's start talking about the wonderful story. "Dances with Wolves" begins during the American Civil War with the Lieutenant Dunbar (Kevin Costner), tired of all the war and after facing a near-death experience in the middle of a battlefield, he asks to be transferred to the unknown area of America, " The Frontier ", a vast green area with only animal and native life. Dunbar always dreamed of know and explore the frontier before she disappeared with the economic advancement of the Americans. But on this trip he is faced with the indigenous tribe, the "Sioux", and with them the great change of his life. A film that works as a Western with a vast Western environment and even moments of fantastic action in the Western style, but the film manages to go much deeper than that. From the beginning, the film manages to put ourselves on the feet of Dunbar, from the output of the world he was born into the unexplored world. The 1st hour of the film we only see Dunbar with his internal monologues and dialogs with his horse and a wild wolf that serves as their only company, but always with "Kicking Bird" (Graham Greene), a member of the Sioux tribe, watching him. Michael Blake's writing is just fantastic (who also manages to be loyal to his own work) making a fantastic job deepening Dunbar since a lonely man to a great friend of the Sioux. The film not only puts us at Dunbar's place but we get to feel the same feelings that he has regarding to the Sioux that goes from admiration to love. The Sioux can not only be an indigenous people with a great culture but nourish a huge intelligence and respect between each other, and they also have a innocent and good sense of humor (they fart; insults jokingly) making each one very realistic and human. We even feel a bit of the relationship between Dunbar and "Stand Fist" (Mary McDonnell), no big surprise, beyond beautiful she is smart and brave and also be the only white people among the tribe. Not only the writing of the film is fantastic maintaining an excellent character development but Costner's direction is just superb. Behind the camera he delivers a flawless direction putting us closely to the action scenes and makes us feel in the midst of the beautiful green desert with beautiful scenery magnificently filmed. The cast also stands out without difficulty: Kevin Costner is already superb behind the camera and in front of it would be no different with a sparkling gleam in his eye and his way of speaking the language of the Sioux without difficulty is just stunning; Mary McDonnell fantastic in every detail; Graham Greene honor his Native heritage perfectly. Kevin Costner was able to show a real talent for management and shines with a sparkling performance with a superb cast, all included in this beautiful story of a man who went out to find his place and eventually found himself. A wonderful writing and direction and an ending that made the strongest gets wet in tears, "Dances with Wolves" is a true classic masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical movie in more ways than one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This Kevin Costner epic will undoubtedly never blow away with the wind, as a memorable and historical western, which for one - marks a new phase in relations with Native Americans. Most importantly "Dances with Wolves" sets a point in time, where native American culture can no longer be portrayed as savage, with incoming immigrants bringing with them technology, progress and the American dream. Now tainted, it could be said that one myth (of the civilisational conquering of the wild west) was supplanted by romanticised wigwams, but the latter for one thing is a much closer account of historical facts. Despite certain elaborated idealisation of Sioux life, this is a far cry from your mystical tree-hugging pacifists (aptly portrayed as being ruthless in warfare). However pointless this may be given the far-reaching recognisability of the movie, a short recap of the: Lt. John Dunbar (Kevin Costner) is sent out to the west to guard the frontier, while the rest of the country is in civil turmoil. The post is completely deserted apart from a stray wolf, who slowly grows an affinity to the kind-hearted man. Waiting for reinforcements to arrive, the first to contact him are his neighbours, the Sioux, with whom he soon forms a close familial relation, slowly immersing into their culture and way of life. Meanwhile chance encounters with bison hunters, cavalry troopers and loggers, have Dunbar grow increasingly disillusioned with his own kind... Rewatching the movie over twenty years after it received a multitude of Oscars (including Best Picture and Best Director), the widespread appeal of the movie has not faltered, still a touching, awe-inducing epic of stark significance to mainstream perceptions of American history. Certain aspects of the story-telling are simplistic and unrefined, often supplanting more cognitive portrayal of Sioux society with opportunities to bring in a hearty laugh. This doesn't however take away the charm of Costner's legendary feature, as comedy basically offers light-hearted respite from the inevitable downfall of the American Indians and the natural habitat in which they resided. The extended four hour cut undoubtedly has its coherence issues, as some scenes are visibly less well-rounded, often superfluous or just jarring. Nonetheless they do add to the overall scope and emotional pull of the story, hence all in all they largely feel best kept untouched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An epic dedicated to the human civilization
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    huang20130418
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not an American. I have no right to judge this history and I'm not going to. The saddest thing about this movie is that we all know the end but we don't want it to come. We hope the harmony situation can last long, longer than the movie showed. But there's no way to expect that the tragedy of the Indian culture never come. Ancient civilization is bound to be replaced by modern one, though it may take blood, tears, darkness and sin to go through this. It's inevitable. As one saying (in China) goes, men are created to die. Though this analogy seems pretty sad, it's quite true. As soon as a man is born, he is moving to death every day, every hour and every second. So does human civilization. Human beings have gone through the original society, agriculture society, and now we are going through industrial society. It's impossible for us to foresee what the next society will be like after, say, 10000 years. So we can say that the industrial societies we build today are made to die, just like the original society and agriculture society. It's cruel to say this, but it does expose the cruelty that the world we live in and history we went through truly posses. This movie showed us this bloody and glory,miserable and honorable substitution process. So it's sure to be an epic. It's an epic dedicated to the human civilization. Also, being an epic requires magnificent scenes. This movie created a quite perfect one with the prairie, the sky, the buffalo and the wolf. Why do I count "wolf" in? Well, this movie spent a lot on that, didn't it? First, the name, "Dances with Wolves". Then the real wolf, there are lots of scenes about it. More importantly, this wolf, "two socks", is a symbol of Indian civilization. Outside the Indians look like cavemen, which is terrifying, this is similar to the wolf. But inside, they are kind, generous and warm-hearted, just like the development of the relationship between "two socks" and John Dunbar. So the denouement of the wolf marks the denouement of Indian culture. P.S. The music played in this movie is so wonderful and it contributed to the epic atmosphere. I think the only music which is better than this one is "My Heart Will Go On" in Titanic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful, Boring Anthem to Mr. Costner How Cool He Is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I heard much about this movie - Dances was always names one of the best, decent, greatest and so on. I finally watched the complete 4-hour Director's Cut and what? It is tedious, boring, mediocre, long, slow, painfully pathetic film where we simply see every frame how cool, great, nice, heroic and grand Kevin Costner is. He made many awful movies, so far, but this one is a real under low, a real failure. Well, there are 2 great moments - the excellent scenery and animals. They are very good and sweet. The rest is very preachy, predictable, real boring and yawning all 4 long slow hours. This is what they call a heritage? Maybe, I was not impressed - Kevin made a movie about himself, for himself and with much of his beloved his self. Sorry, this does not work. This is not a Civil War movie, not a movie about nature, but a preachy-peachy saga of dullness and tediousness. Never watch it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Whitney
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best Western I've ever seen. One of its greatest strengths is its even handed portrayal of both sides of what was a gruesome bigotry ridden fight for land, opportunity, and way of life, between two very different cultures in the late 1800's. The Civil Wars' leftovers were a maliciously violent and frighteningly ignorant bunch, pit them against a culture of genuinely primitive & savage people (scalping & yelping pridefully about it  wow) and you have a perfect breeding ground for intolerance, impetuous violence, and never ending retaliatory fighting. "Dances with Wolves" provides a context for understanding both sides' humanity (for better and for worse) concerning this scar on our nation's history. Said understanding is permitted through an engaging story told on a stunning backdrop of our disappearing plains and enriched with beautifully moving music. In 2007, "Dances with Wolves" was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant." It may drive home the meaning of being human more than any other film I've ever seen. It won 7 Academy Awards, including Best Picture 1990; I'm not at all surprised and support the Library of Congress' decision.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Probably the best "going native" film to date
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pihlaja
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A film that manages to combine deep and meaningful character study with exotic locations and the feel of an adventure. Dances with Wolves is one of those rare films where time becomes transcendent and you're no longer able to perceive the usual story arcs or acts. They're there and the film has a rock-solid foundation, but you're still surprised when something new happens, because the film has managed to lull you into its world, its prolonged seasons. This is a movie that is able to portray the passage of time properly. It's a film in which events don't take place over a weekend or even a month. Rather whole years just glide by. Or perhaps just months, it's impossible to say for sure, but it feels like years, a sizable chunk of a whole life. And what a life that is and what a person living it. Lieutenant Dunbar - masterfully played by Kevin Costner - is a war hero given a dead end assignment according to his wishes, so that he can resign there to die a slow death. Thus the film starts as a macabre portrayal of a man giving up, but unable to just lay down. And it never becomes clear whether he manages to shake that initial attitude towards life. The events slowly give him more reasons to live, but Costner always plays him slightly detached, like he's always just one step away from giving up again. It's an amazing story and one that requires space to flourish. Quite many films since this one have managed to recreate the same "going native" storyline, which of course existed before this film though never quite like this, but none of them have seemed to realize that the film needs to dedicate most of its running time to the actual "going". Because that's the story, that's the attraction. The action scenes and battles have their place, but the magic is in the community, in the bonds that slowly grow between the main character and the natives. It's very hard to find any flaws in this film. Its slow pace is not for everyone, especially in the extended cut, but I personally never complained or even noticed the hours. It's a captivating film from start to finish and every minute is well spent, be it a minute of quiet landscapes rolling by or a minute of blazing battle. All has its place and every scene tells a story, reveals another layer. One of the greatest westerns ever filmed, if not one of the greatest films. In my opinion a film that everyone should watch at least once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
