<filme>
 <id>
  970
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0102014
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1991
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Escute Minha Can&ccedil;&atilde;o
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The film is based loosely on the life of the Irish Tenor, Josef Locke (1917-1999), played by Ned Beatty... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The film is based loosely on the life of the Irish Tenor, Josef Locke (1917-1999), played by Ned Beatty... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   expatriate
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   orchestra
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jaguar car
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   on the road
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sex
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Peter Chelsom
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Peter Chelsom
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Adrian Dunbar
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Ned Beatty
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Adrian Dunbar
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Brian Flanagan
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You see those girls, Mickey. Would you like to be responsible for their dreams?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have been watching Waking the Dead, and thought I would explore other works done by it's stars. I'm starting with Eve (Tara Fitzgerald). This is a great one for Ms. Fitzgerald, as we see all she has to offer as she jumps out of bed with Adrian Dunbar, after he fails to say he loves her. Unfortunately, her role is little more than that, as Dunbar is the star. When you mention Irish tenors, people immediately think of Finbar Wright, Anthony Kearns, and Ronan Tynan. But long before, there was Joseph McLaughlin, better known as Josef Locke. This film is loosely based upon his life. It really gets funny as Micky O'Neill (Dunbar) goes broke trying to fake everyone out with Franc Cinatra, and then with a Mister X, who pretends to be Locke, and goes chasing around Ireland to find the real Josef Locke and bring him back to England. Locke is played by Ned Beatty. He manages to come to the realization that he really loves Nancy (Fitzgerald), and gets Locke to return. What an ending!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It weaves some kind of spell...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Howlett
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoiler warning! A superb low-budget fantasy film about a down-at-heel club that just clings on by booking cheap, crummy look-a-like acts. When manager Mickey O' Neill (Dunbar) looks like losing his girl, he decides to impress her by booking the legendary tax-dodger Josef Locke and hopes to save his club into the bargain. What he ends up with is not what he imagined, and the search begins... We've watched this film a couple of times since it was first shown on TV and it gets better with every viewing. The characters are great and the almost magical atmosphere conjured up in some scenes is incredible. *Spoiler alert again* Locke's triumphant performance is the climax, and I admit to getting very touched by 'Count your Blessings', delivered in that wonderful tenor voice (supplied by Vernon Midgeley). What a film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an unexpected pleasure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The owner of a low rent English music hall finds himself in hot water after booking a legendary (but fraudulent) Irish tenor, prompting a desperate visit to the Emerald Isle in search of the genuine article, not an easy assignment since no one has seen the man in 25 years. Maybe it makes a difference that the film was made on the far side of the Atlantic Ocean, but it succeeds as a genuinely charming and disarming romantic comedy without the expected formula plotting or trendy visual hype, and (perhaps not surprisingly) without the box office benefit of brand name stars. The climax is somewhat overwrought, but by then director Peter Chelsum is working from a surplus of good-natured blarney and local brogue, with some gorgeous Irish scenery added almost as an afterthought. And where else can you expect to see a movie hero declare his love to a girl while clutching a whippet?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes quiet, sometimes laugh out loud comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donofthedial
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jolly fun as we get to see and hear Franc Sinatra, plus the potential of seeing Bing Krosby "with a "K"" as a disgruntled Franc Sinatra concert goer calls out from their seat. A...ummm....'crafty' young music promoter must keep his girlfriend happy by finding the reclusive and out of country tenor Josef Locke who had romanced her mother (voted "Miss Dairy Goodness of 1952") back in the day and wishes to see him again. The promoter heads for Ireland to find Locke and convince him to do just one more performance in England. Problem is Locke cant come back to England because of a huge tax debt and a very eager and waiting tax collector. Result = much fun and quite a bit of excitement. Fine performances by all. I saw this film once or twice about a decade ago, so please forgive and small diversions from the actual plot due to memory.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Desperately seeking Josef.....................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ianlouisiana
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I listened to the wireless in the 1940s and 50s Mr Locke was a regular on the Light Programme,constantly appearing as a guest of such luminaries as Henry Hall or Vic Oliver on their radio shows.He topped the bill at Variety Theatres all over the country for years then disappeared off the radar - "Got some girl in trouble I'll be bound",was my father's comment which went a bit above my head at the age of 13.So clearly his reputation had reached even the leafy lanes of Surrey by that time,if not the real reason for his vanishing.My mother was inconsolable until she discovered Mario Lanza who was Italian and much more exciting. "Hear my song" tells of the search by a cut- price impresario for the elusive Irish tenor.Like "The Commitments" it presents the Irish as they really are rather than how the Americans choose to portray them - as refugees from a John Ford movie. Ned Beatty is splendid as the reluctant recluse, a man still capable of charming the birds out of the trees.He has the voice of an angel - so he does.My personal favourite Miss Shirley Anne Field makes a very welcome appearance,and the circle is closed by Mr Harold Behrens in a small role rounding off the connection to post - war BBC radio where he was a regular on "Ignorance is Bliss". Appearing unheralded on the horizon out of nowhere - as it were - "Hear my Song" is a beautifully crafted little film,a masterpiece in miniature and anyone whose love for movies is more than skin deep will adore it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Bit of Irish Whimsy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Angilly (staffba3)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hear My Song (1991) is a bit of Irish whimsy about a fast talking London theatrical promoter, (Adrian Dunbar) who books legendary Irish tenor Joseph Locke When the tenor is revealed as an impostor, and Dunbar loses both his theater and his fianc&eacute;e (Tara Fitzgerald). He then sets forth on an odyssey to Ireland to find the real Joseph Locke, bring him back to London, save the theater, and win back the girl. Of course, the whole point of every epic quest from Homer on down is for the hero to finally realize why he left in the first place (this realization occurs while Dunbar is dangled off the side of a very high cliff). The cast is amazing, especially David McCallum as a police inspector obsessed with capturing Locke, and Ned Beatty gives a very credible and warmhearted performance as Joseph Locke (although the singing is dubbed). The Irish countryside is breathtaking--as is Tara Fitzgerald--and the story is great fun in the tradition of Local Hero and Eat the Peach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zorro2a
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unlike Larcher-2 who also has a comment on this film, l did see Josef Locke, l can remember my mother took me to see him when l was a young boy and was drawn to his type of sining. It is well known that Mr Locke was a ladies man, but that did not detract from his voice, and Ned Beatty does a remarkable job of playing Josef Locke, dubbed in Mr Lockes own voice. This is a great film, Adrian Dunbar plays his role as a seedy agent well and David McCallum as the policeman always trying to get Mr Locke is a gem... The "tooth" scene is a great laugh....Please watch this film, if you know nothing of Mr Locke try to find out about him first then you will enjoy it better, and understand the title... I give this film 8 out of 10...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chelsom's Song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Edgar Sober&oacute;n Torchia (estorchia@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't think Peter Chelsom's appreciation will grow much today, with audiences and critics more inclined to pyrotechnics, flamboyant styles and cynic approach to mankind's troubles. Chelsom is a skilled filmmaker, but for today's tastes his cinema seems too close to the audience's soft hearts, and that is probably his less attractive trait. I like a few of his movies: "The Mighty", "Serendipity" as predictable as it is, and my favorites "Funny Bones" and "Hear My Song" which he also wrote. Both deal with a search and possess a frenetic and funny approach to human foibles, and in this case an enthusiastic leading character, as played by Adrian Dunbar who also co-wrote. He is a nightclub administrator who keeps cheating on his patrons, bringing mediocre artists to perform. When he brings a fake tenor who humiliates his future mother-in-law (Shirley-Ann Field, who had an affair with the real tenor), he embarks on the almost impossible: finding the real singer, who cannot step on Irish soil due to tax evasion. Ned Beatty gives the performance of his life (and that's a lot to say) as the singer, leading the story to a moving conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never boils over, just a heart warming hug for your soul.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kumasan
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    More than a bit of blarney brings a sham of a singer to do a good deed bringing a smile to any heart. Hear My Song as a tune, is sure to haunt most listeners for a long time, even if they can not remember anything past the first line. Great rainy day fare, perfect when served with Irish Breakfast Tea and just a drop or two of Irish Whiskey. John Patrick
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A True Delight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hausrathman
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shady liverpool concert promoter, Adrian Dunbar, goes to Ireland to find and bring back an elusive tenor, Ned Beatty, who is wanted by the law for tax evasion, in order to restore his reputation and win back his girl. This romantic comedy is so charming I am surprised anyone could dislike it. Director Peter Chelson does an wonderful job. He displays a real feel for the characters, and the small details which give the film its sense of authenticity. The leading actors are excellent, particularly Ned Beatty, who gives the performance of his career, but they have to compete with a host of colorful minor characters. Give it a look. You shant be disappointed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You see those girls, Mickey. Would you like to be responsible for their dreams?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have been watching Waking the Dead, and thought I would explore other works done by it's stars. I'm starting with Eve (Tara Fitzgerald). This is a great one for Ms. Fitzgerald, as we see all she has to offer as she jumps out of bed with Adrian Dunbar, after he fails to say he loves her. Unfortunately, her role is little more than that, as Dunbar is the star. When you mention Irish tenors, people immediately think of Finbar Wright, Anthony Kearns, and Ronan Tynan. But long before, there was Joseph McLaughlin, better known as Josef Locke. This film is loosely based upon his life. It really gets funny as Micky O'Neill (Dunbar) goes broke trying to fake everyone out with Franc Cinatra, and then with a Mister X, who pretends to be Locke, and goes chasing around Ireland to find the real Josef Locke and bring him back to England. Locke is played by Ned Beatty. He manages to come to the realization that he really loves Nancy (Fitzgerald), and gets Locke to return. What an ending!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It weaves some kind of spell...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Howlett
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoiler warning! A superb low-budget fantasy film about a down-at-heel club that just clings on by booking cheap, crummy look-a-like acts. When manager Mickey O' Neill (Dunbar) looks like losing his girl, he decides to impress her by booking the legendary tax-dodger Josef Locke and hopes to save his club into the bargain. What he ends up with is not what he imagined, and the search begins... We've watched this film a couple of times since it was first shown on TV and it gets better with every viewing. The characters are great and the almost magical atmosphere conjured up in some scenes is incredible. *Spoiler alert again* Locke's triumphant performance is the climax, and I admit to getting very touched by 'Count your Blessings', delivered in that wonderful tenor voice (supplied by Vernon Midgeley). What a film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an unexpected pleasure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The owner of a low rent English music hall finds himself in hot water after booking a legendary (but fraudulent) Irish tenor, prompting a desperate visit to the Emerald Isle in search of the genuine article, not an easy assignment since no one has seen the man in 25 years. Maybe it makes a difference that the film was made on the far side of the Atlantic Ocean, but it succeeds as a genuinely charming and disarming romantic comedy without the expected formula plotting or trendy visual hype, and (perhaps not surprisingly) without the box office benefit of brand name stars. The climax is somewhat overwrought, but by then director Peter Chelsum is working from a surplus of good-natured blarney and local brogue, with some gorgeous Irish scenery added almost as an afterthought. And where else can you expect to see a movie hero declare his love to a girl while clutching a whippet?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes quiet, sometimes laugh out loud comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donofthedial
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jolly fun as we get to see and hear Franc Sinatra, plus the potential of seeing Bing Krosby "with a "K"" as a disgruntled Franc Sinatra concert goer calls out from their seat. A...ummm....'crafty' young music promoter must keep his girlfriend happy by finding the reclusive and out of country tenor Josef Locke who had romanced her mother (voted "Miss Dairy Goodness of 1952") back in the day and wishes to see him again. The promoter heads for Ireland to find Locke and convince him to do just one more performance in England. Problem is Locke cant come back to England because of a huge tax debt and a very eager and waiting tax collector. Result = much fun and quite a bit of excitement. Fine performances by all. I saw this film once or twice about a decade ago, so please forgive and small diversions from the actual plot due to memory.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Desperately seeking Josef.....................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ianlouisiana
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I listened to the wireless in the 1940s and 50s Mr Locke was a regular on the Light Programme,constantly appearing as a guest of such luminaries as Henry Hall or Vic Oliver on their radio shows.He topped the bill at Variety Theatres all over the country for years then disappeared off the radar - "Got some girl in trouble I'll be bound",was my father's comment which went a bit above my head at the age of 13.So clearly his reputation had reached even the leafy lanes of Surrey by that time,if not the real reason for his vanishing.My mother was inconsolable until she discovered Mario Lanza who was Italian and much more exciting. "Hear my song" tells of the search by a cut- price impresario for the elusive Irish tenor.Like "The Commitments" it presents the Irish as they really are rather than how the Americans choose to portray them - as refugees from a John Ford movie. Ned Beatty is splendid as the reluctant recluse, a man still capable of charming the birds out of the trees.He has the voice of an angel - so he does.My personal favourite Miss Shirley Anne Field makes a very welcome appearance,and the circle is closed by Mr Harold Behrens in a small role rounding off the connection to post - war BBC radio where he was a regular on "Ignorance is Bliss". Appearing unheralded on the horizon out of nowhere - as it were - "Hear my Song" is a beautifully crafted little film,a masterpiece in miniature and anyone whose love for movies is more than skin deep will adore it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Bit of Irish Whimsy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Angilly (staffba3)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hear My Song (1991) is a bit of Irish whimsy about a fast talking London theatrical promoter, (Adrian Dunbar) who books legendary Irish tenor Joseph Locke When the tenor is revealed as an impostor, and Dunbar loses both his theater and his fianc&eacute;e (Tara Fitzgerald). He then sets forth on an odyssey to Ireland to find the real Joseph Locke, bring him back to London, save the theater, and win back the girl. Of course, the whole point of every epic quest from Homer on down is for the hero to finally realize why he left in the first place (this realization occurs while Dunbar is dangled off the side of a very high cliff). The cast is amazing, especially David McCallum as a police inspector obsessed with capturing Locke, and Ned Beatty gives a very credible and warmhearted performance as Joseph Locke (although the singing is dubbed). The Irish countryside is breathtaking--as is Tara Fitzgerald--and the story is great fun in the tradition of Local Hero and Eat the Peach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zorro2a
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unlike Larcher-2 who also has a comment on this film, l did see Josef Locke, l can remember my mother took me to see him when l was a young boy and was drawn to his type of sining. It is well known that Mr Locke was a ladies man, but that did not detract from his voice, and Ned Beatty does a remarkable job of playing Josef Locke, dubbed in Mr Lockes own voice. This is a great film, Adrian Dunbar plays his role as a seedy agent well and David McCallum as the policeman always trying to get Mr Locke is a gem... The "tooth" scene is a great laugh....Please watch this film, if you know nothing of Mr Locke try to find out about him first then you will enjoy it better, and understand the title... I give this film 8 out of 10...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chelsom's Song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Edgar Sober&oacute;n Torchia (estorchia@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't think Peter Chelsom's appreciation will grow much today, with audiences and critics more inclined to pyrotechnics, flamboyant styles and cynic approach to mankind's troubles. Chelsom is a skilled filmmaker, but for today's tastes his cinema seems too close to the audience's soft hearts, and that is probably his less attractive trait. I like a few of his movies: "The Mighty", "Serendipity" as predictable as it is, and my favorites "Funny Bones" and "Hear My Song" which he also wrote. Both deal with a search and possess a frenetic and funny approach to human foibles, and in this case an enthusiastic leading character, as played by Adrian Dunbar who also co-wrote. He is a nightclub administrator who keeps cheating on his patrons, bringing mediocre artists to perform. When he brings a fake tenor who humiliates his future mother-in-law (Shirley-Ann Field, who had an affair with the real tenor), he embarks on the almost impossible: finding the real singer, who cannot step on Irish soil due to tax evasion. Ned Beatty gives the performance of his life (and that's a lot to say) as the singer, leading the story to a moving conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never boils over, just a heart warming hug for your soul.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kumasan
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    More than a bit of blarney brings a sham of a singer to do a good deed bringing a smile to any heart. Hear My Song as a tune, is sure to haunt most listeners for a long time, even if they can not remember anything past the first line. Great rainy day fare, perfect when served with Irish Breakfast Tea and just a drop or two of Irish Whiskey. John Patrick
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A True Delight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hausrathman
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shady liverpool concert promoter, Adrian Dunbar, goes to Ireland to find and bring back an elusive tenor, Ned Beatty, who is wanted by the law for tax evasion, in order to restore his reputation and win back his girl. This romantic comedy is so charming I am surprised anyone could dislike it. Director Peter Chelson does an wonderful job. He displays a real feel for the characters, and the small details which give the film its sense of authenticity. The leading actors are excellent, particularly Ned Beatty, who gives the performance of his career, but they have to compete with a host of colorful minor characters. Give it a look. You shant be disappointed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You see those girls, Mickey. Would you like to be responsible for their dreams?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have been watching Waking the Dead, and thought I would explore other works done by it's stars. I'm starting with Eve (Tara Fitzgerald). This is a great one for Ms. Fitzgerald, as we see all she has to offer as she jumps out of bed with Adrian Dunbar, after he fails to say he loves her. Unfortunately, her role is little more than that, as Dunbar is the star. When you mention Irish tenors, people immediately think of Finbar Wright, Anthony Kearns, and Ronan Tynan. But long before, there was Joseph McLaughlin, better known as Josef Locke. This film is loosely based upon his life. It really gets funny as Micky O'Neill (Dunbar) goes broke trying to fake everyone out with Franc Cinatra, and then with a Mister X, who pretends to be Locke, and goes chasing around Ireland to find the real Josef Locke and bring him back to England. Locke is played by Ned Beatty. He manages to come to the realization that he really loves Nancy (Fitzgerald), and gets Locke to return. What an ending!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It weaves some kind of spell...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy Howlett
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoiler warning! A superb low-budget fantasy film about a down-at-heel club that just clings on by booking cheap, crummy look-a-like acts. When manager Mickey O' Neill (Dunbar) looks like losing his girl, he decides to impress her by booking the legendary tax-dodger Josef Locke and hopes to save his club into the bargain. What he ends up with is not what he imagined, and the search begins... We've watched this film a couple of times since it was first shown on TV and it gets better with every viewing. The characters are great and the almost magical atmosphere conjured up in some scenes is incredible. *Spoiler alert again* Locke's triumphant performance is the climax, and I admit to getting very touched by 'Count your Blessings', delivered in that wonderful tenor voice (supplied by Vernon Midgeley). What a film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    an unexpected pleasure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Neumann
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The owner of a low rent English music hall finds himself in hot water after booking a legendary (but fraudulent) Irish tenor, prompting a desperate visit to the Emerald Isle in search of the genuine article, not an easy assignment since no one has seen the man in 25 years. Maybe it makes a difference that the film was made on the far side of the Atlantic Ocean, but it succeeds as a genuinely charming and disarming romantic comedy without the expected formula plotting or trendy visual hype, and (perhaps not surprisingly) without the box office benefit of brand name stars. The climax is somewhat overwrought, but by then director Peter Chelsum is working from a surplus of good-natured blarney and local brogue, with some gorgeous Irish scenery added almost as an afterthought. And where else can you expect to see a movie hero declare his love to a girl while clutching a whippet?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sometimes quiet, sometimes laugh out loud comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donofthedial
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jolly fun as we get to see and hear Franc Sinatra, plus the potential of seeing Bing Krosby "with a "K"" as a disgruntled Franc Sinatra concert goer calls out from their seat. A...ummm....'crafty' young music promoter must keep his girlfriend happy by finding the reclusive and out of country tenor Josef Locke who had romanced her mother (voted "Miss Dairy Goodness of 1952") back in the day and wishes to see him again. The promoter heads for Ireland to find Locke and convince him to do just one more performance in England. Problem is Locke cant come back to England because of a huge tax debt and a very eager and waiting tax collector. Result = much fun and quite a bit of excitement. Fine performances by all. I saw this film once or twice about a decade ago, so please forgive and small diversions from the actual plot due to memory.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Desperately seeking Josef.....................
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ianlouisiana
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I listened to the wireless in the 1940s and 50s Mr Locke was a regular on the Light Programme,constantly appearing as a guest of such luminaries as Henry Hall or Vic Oliver on their radio shows.He topped the bill at Variety Theatres all over the country for years then disappeared off the radar - "Got some girl in trouble I'll be bound",was my father's comment which went a bit above my head at the age of 13.So clearly his reputation had reached even the leafy lanes of Surrey by that time,if not the real reason for his vanishing.My mother was inconsolable until she discovered Mario Lanza who was Italian and much more exciting. "Hear my song" tells of the search by a cut- price impresario for the elusive Irish tenor.Like "The Commitments" it presents the Irish as they really are rather than how the Americans choose to portray them - as refugees from a John Ford movie. Ned Beatty is splendid as the reluctant recluse, a man still capable of charming the birds out of the trees.He has the voice of an angel - so he does.My personal favourite Miss Shirley Anne Field makes a very welcome appearance,and the circle is closed by Mr Harold Behrens in a small role rounding off the connection to post - war BBC radio where he was a regular on "Ignorance is Bliss". Appearing unheralded on the horizon out of nowhere - as it were - "Hear my Song" is a beautifully crafted little film,a masterpiece in miniature and anyone whose love for movies is more than skin deep will adore it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Bit of Irish Whimsy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Angilly (staffba3)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Hear My Song (1991) is a bit of Irish whimsy about a fast talking London theatrical promoter, (Adrian Dunbar) who books legendary Irish tenor Joseph Locke When the tenor is revealed as an impostor, and Dunbar loses both his theater and his fianc&eacute;e (Tara Fitzgerald). He then sets forth on an odyssey to Ireland to find the real Joseph Locke, bring him back to London, save the theater, and win back the girl. Of course, the whole point of every epic quest from Homer on down is for the hero to finally realize why he left in the first place (this realization occurs while Dunbar is dangled off the side of a very high cliff). The cast is amazing, especially David McCallum as a police inspector obsessed with capturing Locke, and Ned Beatty gives a very credible and warmhearted performance as Joseph Locke (although the singing is dubbed). The Irish countryside is breathtaking--as is Tara Fitzgerald--and the story is great fun in the tradition of Local Hero and Eat the Peach.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zorro2a
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Unlike Larcher-2 who also has a comment on this film, l did see Josef Locke, l can remember my mother took me to see him when l was a young boy and was drawn to his type of sining. It is well known that Mr Locke was a ladies man, but that did not detract from his voice, and Ned Beatty does a remarkable job of playing Josef Locke, dubbed in Mr Lockes own voice. This is a great film, Adrian Dunbar plays his role as a seedy agent well and David McCallum as the policeman always trying to get Mr Locke is a gem... The "tooth" scene is a great laugh....Please watch this film, if you know nothing of Mr Locke try to find out about him first then you will enjoy it better, and understand the title... I give this film 8 out of 10...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chelsom's Song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Edgar Sober&oacute;n Torchia (estorchia@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't think Peter Chelsom's appreciation will grow much today, with audiences and critics more inclined to pyrotechnics, flamboyant styles and cynic approach to mankind's troubles. Chelsom is a skilled filmmaker, but for today's tastes his cinema seems too close to the audience's soft hearts, and that is probably his less attractive trait. I like a few of his movies: "The Mighty", "Serendipity" as predictable as it is, and my favorites "Funny Bones" and "Hear My Song" which he also wrote. Both deal with a search and possess a frenetic and funny approach to human foibles, and in this case an enthusiastic leading character, as played by Adrian Dunbar who also co-wrote. He is a nightclub administrator who keeps cheating on his patrons, bringing mediocre artists to perform. When he brings a fake tenor who humiliates his future mother-in-law (Shirley-Ann Field, who had an affair with the real tenor), he embarks on the almost impossible: finding the real singer, who cannot step on Irish soil due to tax evasion. Ned Beatty gives the performance of his life (and that's a lot to say) as the singer, leading the story to a moving conclusion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never boils over, just a heart warming hug for your soul.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kumasan
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/11/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    More than a bit of blarney brings a sham of a singer to do a good deed bringing a smile to any heart. Hear My Song as a tune, is sure to haunt most listeners for a long time, even if they can not remember anything past the first line. Great rainy day fare, perfect when served with Irish Breakfast Tea and just a drop or two of Irish Whiskey. John Patrick
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A True Delight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hausrathman
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shady liverpool concert promoter, Adrian Dunbar, goes to Ireland to find and bring back an elusive tenor, Ned Beatty, who is wanted by the law for tax evasion, in order to restore his reputation and win back his girl. This romantic comedy is so charming I am surprised anyone could dislike it. Director Peter Chelson does an wonderful job. He displays a real feel for the characters, and the small details which give the film its sense of authenticity. The leading actors are excellent, particularly Ned Beatty, who gives the performance of his career, but they have to compete with a host of colorful minor characters. Give it a look. You shant be disappointed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
