<filme>
 <id>
  974
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116260
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Olho Por Olho
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  After her daughter Julie is brutally raped and murdered, Karen McCann is turned down by the LAPD after she requests they keep suspect Robert Doob in jail for good instead of paroling him. ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  After her daughter Julie is brutally raped and murdered, Karen McCann is turned down by the LAPD after she requests they keep suspect Robert Doob in jail for good instead of paroling him. Nevertheless, the LAPD and the courts do decide to parole him and Karen turns to a group of hit man trainers for help. They teach her how to manage a gun, etc. Eventually, Karen's husband, Mack, finds out and tries to stop her. Karen backs off. Robert Doob tracks Karen down at the McCaan home and breaks in, hoping to kill her.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   rape
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   support group
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murderer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   california
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Schlesinger
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Erika Holzer
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Amanda Silver
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Sally Field
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kiefer Sutherland
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ed Harris
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kiefer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought Kiefer Sutherland did a wonderful job with the movie first off, his acting skills are hard to match by anyone,, how many actors today can bounce back and forth between movies and TV just like that.. Sally Field.. wow what happened to her since Coal Miner's Daughter. she did very good to in the role of the mother trying to get vengeance on her daughter being raped,, in the initial opening scene,, the teenage daughter is on the phone with mom,, and she get's raped and mom hear's the entire rape,start to finish, due to a technicality our rapist is set free, and free to rape and kill again. he starts stalking different prey this time, while our raging mother is trying to find our rapist and bring him to either justice or death.. these kind of movies have been overdone and watered down in the past 30 years. but this one seems to me to have a little more staying power.. I think that will be because of Kiefer's high profile,, 24,, and an amazing performance by Sally Field,, the Coal Miner's Daughter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Revenge Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sally Fields does a good job with this movie as a revenge seeking mother of a teenage daughter who's been raped and murdered. I suppose to make this worth watching, she has to do a good job with this. The story itself has been done over and over: seeking revenge after a violent crime because the justice system has failed. That's a pretty clich&eacute; type of situation and story, so there's not really a great deal to recommend this as far as originality is concerned. But Fields is good, and Kiefer Sutherland is appropriately creepy and threatening as the rapist/murderer. The portrayal of the rape of Karen's daughter was terrifying, but (thankfully) not especially graphic.) The same could be said for the later rape committed by Sutherland's Doob. The movie, in my opinion, also makes a fair point about the justice system leaning too far on the side of defending the rights of obviously guilty criminals at the expense of actually dispensing justice for their victims. I understand the need to protect the rights of the accused, but there does have to be a balance, and that balance is sometimes lost in the system that we have. I was kind of put off by the "group" the McCann's attended for people who had lost loved ones to violence. To each his or her own, I suppose, but I can't imagine that sitting around night after night talking about the same thing over and over and over again is really going to help anyone move on, and I wasn't convinced by the "vigilante organization" aspect of this. I have to say, though, that I did like the ending. What I was finding distasteful up to this point was that Karen was going to turn vigilante, and by so doing she'd be be risking losing her other daughter as well by ending up in prison, which might have satisfied her own desire for revenge but would have been very selfish toward the younger daughter. So, the way she played things, she made sure that (a) she'd get her revenge, but (b) that she wouldn't lose anything more by doing it. So, the ending worked for me. Overall, I found this a pretty good watch. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Exactly a Shining Endorsement of Men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In many ways, Eye for an Eye is a fairly bland thriller, indistinguishable from other vigilante-style movies. In fact, it plays at times like one of those cheaply made TV movies, and yet it contains a couple of attacks on women which are quite shocking in their intensity and completely at odds with the rest of the film. Sally Field plays a typically upper-middle class working mother whose teenage daughter is brutally raped and murdered by ultra-sleazy deliveryman Kiefer Sutherland. When the American justice system lets him free on a technicality, Field resolves to take the law into her own hands. The film's basically just a variation on Death Wish, with the added frisson that the vigilante is physically the weaker party and therefore just as likely to become a victim of her target as the other way around. Field is pretty good in the role, as is Sutherland as her nemesis, even though he is portrayed as pure evil with no redeeming  or human  qualities to speak of. The guy can't even sit down without pouring his coffee over a passing dog. Given that, away from his battle with Field, Sutherland isn't given much to play with beyond a couple of scenes which provide no insight into his character  in one he's threatened by frustrated cop Joe Mantegna, and in the other he plays frenetic drums on his legs as he watches a video in his grubby hotel room  he makes quite an impression, proving he's as adept at playing irredeemable bad guys as he is clean cut heroes of the Jack Bauer variety. Ed Harris plays Field's understanding but long-suffering husband, and he's about as emasculated as a man can be in a movie. Never really knowing what's going on, regularly catching on a couple of scenes too late, he's effortlessly sent trotting off to the mountains by Field when she wants him out of the way so that she can put her revenge plan into action. I'm not sure I'd have been as understanding as him in that final scene, and it kind of makes you wonder what Harris saw in the role
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tolerable revenge thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Considering the calibre of the cast and director, Eye For An Eye is a rather low key affair. It tells a familiar story - rapist/murderer goes free through legal loophole, bereaved parent pursues vengeance/justice - and does so reasonably well. Some might think Keifer Sutherland's villain is one dimensional and overstated - I suspect not. Some might think the reactions of Sally Field and Ed Harris as parents of the murdered girl are unrealistic - the answer here must be whether they are credible, and I think they are credible possible reactions. No two people will react the same way, and none of us knows what we would do unless it happens to us (and I profoundly hope it does not happen to anyone reading this). Ultimately, though, despite decent performances and a satisfactory (though somewhat perfunctory) conclusion, the emotional intensity of the opening is not really sustained, and the film peters out in a welter of obviousness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A decent revenge film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cppguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's more interesting to review the reviews than review the movie. There's nothing technically wrong with this movie. Production values are fine. The acting is fine. Anyone rating this a 1 is an incompetent reviewer. 1-star reviews so far rant that Ed Harris ruined the movie and at the same time wonder why Super Ed was saddled with such a horrible supporting cast. Maybe reviewers should be allowed to vote 4-6 until they prove competency. Back to the movie. So far, I have yet to see a movie with Sally Field where she doesn't shine. While her movies may not be perfect, she's a superb actress. Like Tom Hanks, she generally picks winners to be in (funny they starred in at least 2 movies together). I'm also developing a liking for Joe Montegna. I see him in a lot of films and he brings a nice competency to supporting roles. Same for Ed Harris. I like Kiefer Sutherland in his various movies and he does a fine job (even if slightly over the top here) of being creepy. So let's talk film content. Revenge films are intriguing in many ways. To an extent, that concept is an easy way to develop conflict for the viewer. However, it's much harder to come up with a reason for the vengeance. "The Sting" took revenge to high art. "Eye for an Eye" is not high art, so no 10 from me for the film. A 7 will have to do. Others have compared this to the better known "Death Wish," but I think this was better produced and had better flow. Aspects of the movie are predictable, but I've seen many a good movie that was predictable. Summary: if you're scanning Netflix or Blockbuster for an unseen movie with decent action and dialog that moves at a good pace, "Eye for an Eye" isn't revenge on the level of "M," "The Sting," or "Gran Torino" but it's a decent watch... especially if you like the acting talents of Field, Sutherland, Harris and Montegna. If you like action/revenge films, pop some popcorn, curl up with someone special and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An engaging drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a mother who goes to seek justice for the brutal murder of her teenage daughter. "Eye for an Eye" is an intense drama that tells a family's grief in losing a teenage girl in the family. They all react in different ways; the father seems casual and detached on the surface, but actually has intense anger inside. The younger daughter blames herself, while the mother becomes obsessed with getting justice. The plot is good, it is engaging and well told. However, I think the title gives the whole film away, so things will happen in a certain way in order for the film to be called "Eye for an Eye".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ed harris is awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gs20
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing that spoiled the story for me and just made the whole thing implausible was ed harris and ed harris alone........i cannot imagine a father whose daughter is violently raped and murdered acting in such a blaze' or indifferent and completely detached manner.........he was absolutely blank about it and acted pretty much as if nothing unusual happened in his life.........as opposed, say, to sean penn in mystic river reacting to the same situation (outstanding believability) i have never thought much of harris' quirky and bizarre acting style until i realized he is just a terrible actor, that there is no real style to think about and this is a good example of that blankness and absence of emotion..........they would have gotten a better performance out of someone who just happened by the set. Harris' performance here, as in many of his performances was without substance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Controversial topic must drive home a point
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Says nothing, and does nothing. John Schlesinger's "Eye For an Eye" takes a very controversial topic and has nothing to say about it. The entire film appears to have no point. Films of this type cannot be effective just by telling a story. Sadly, this was a complete waste of Sally Field's enormous talent, which was on show again in this movie. The two time Oscar winner almost saved this film. The rest of the cast, including the villainous Kiefer Sutherland and Ed Harris, do little with their roles. Based upon Erica Holzer's novel. Friday, September 3, 1999 - T.V.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too manipulative and heavy handed, even for aspiring vigilantes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to start with this movie? Well, first of all I don't blame the actors in this movie for its failings. The cast is a talented bunch that I've admired elsewhere, and it's clear they are doing what the screenplay and direction tell them to do. On second thought, maybe part of the cast can be blamed - there is a brief appearance by martial arts actress Cynthia Rothrock, and if you know her, you know that any (American) movie she stars in turns out to be a turkey. I'll get serious now. The direction and screen writing of this movie, as I indicated in my summary line, are way below par. There's hardly any time with the protagonist before tragedy strikes, so we don't see how she's changed and scarred. The villain of the movie is so BAD, so EVIL, that he becomes a cartoon character instead of someone realistic that we the audience could really fear and feel genuine hatred. The second half of the movie, where Field becomes an aspiring vigilante, is sometimes laughable in showing how far she'll go. On that note, I'll leave my final thought. With the movie's heavy hand and sometimes laughable plot turns, I have to wonder if this would have worked better as a spoof of vigilante movies. Even if it had failed, I'm sure the end results would be more interesting than how the movie is now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dreadful excuse for a drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lilith Hexus
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into this film with no expectations poor or positive. I am, however, a person who does not believe Sally Field deserves her acclaim and finds her to be a good deal overrated. Is she a bad actress? Over the top, maybe, but I would not use the term 'bad'. At least not until I saw this. The film is about a woman who calls her teenage daughter from a traffic jam and, as they are talking, she hears her daughter being attacked. The girl is raped and killed. This already brings me to the first issue with the film, as well as with Sally Field's acting. For starters, there may have been an issue with hanging up the phone due to the daughter not hitting 'end' back then, I am not up to date on how cell phones worked in the mid-90's. However, why did she never attempt to hang up and call 911 on the phone in her hand? Comfort does not mean as much as life, and every second counts. There is also the fact that, other than two brief scenes, I never once felt like Sally's character cared a thing for her daughter. She never acts sad or distraught over her daughter's death, and only comes off as either indifferent or offended, as if someone had stolen property from her and given her a reason to be defensive over herself. I understand denial and hysterics, but at a certain point the family members of victims of such crimes do end up breaking down and, in nearly every case, lose track of life and shut down partially. There is even a moment when a woman tells Sally she needs to stay strong for her youngest daughter, despite the fact that she is the least upset person at the entire memorial. She seems to use her daughter's death as an excuse to be illogical, hysterical, and hateful but never once gave me a reason to feel bad for her, when I should normally be able to without much expression at all. The film's villain is also abysmal. He behaves like an overly cartoon-like fiend who lives for no reason other than to do mischief (it is bad when I can use this word accurately about a rapist/murderer in a serious drama). I was honestly waiting for him to get hold of Sally Field and tie her to the railroad tracks by the third time he laughed deviously and did another random, senseless act of naughtiness. The man rapes and kills two people for certain, as well as pours hot coffee on a dog and urinates through a woman's fence, and somehow managed to not only make none of this seem overly malicious or cruel, but almost like a child trying to get attention. Every character is unbelievable and ridiculous, except for perhaps the two victims who are seen so briefly each. The police officer defies logic at every turn and when he actually does decide to do something, it is not only at the wrong time but in a way that in most cases he would have been fired for his actions. He assaults a man who has been legally dismissed of all charges, simply on suspicion. This includes holding a gun to his head. Plenty of witnesses saw and heard the assault, and one word from any of them and he would be turning in his badge and completely useless to anyone. This may have been his true goal, though, as without such a useless officer on the force they may actually get something done. Now just to deal with the idiots handling the evidence. The finale of the film is absurd, not due to the plot but simply because of how it is delivered. At one point Sally Field has the killer at gunpoint, easily six feet away minimum, and has plenty of opportunity and logical reason, as well as every intent, to shoot and kill him. This was her plan, to kill the man while under legal conditions. Instead, she waits around for literally no reason and somehow allows him to ram his entire body into her before she can do so much as to pull the trigger once. She is then knocked down the stairs and lands on her back at the bottom, and though the gun is lying only a few inches away from her in plain sight to both of them, this for some reason did not seem threatening to the killer who idly strolls down the stairs taunting her. No shock to anyone, she grabs the gun and fires repeatedly into his torso, not missing a single time. Strangely, he seems bewildered by these events and does not understand how the woman lying only a few inches away from a loaded gun shot him while he taunted her and slowly moved in for the kill. I will not even discuss the "Vigilante Group", that is simply something you will have to see yourself, or be glad you are not aware of. Plain and simple, this film is entirely unbelievable, every attempt at inducing any sort of emotion is a miserable failure, and it will make you wish you had two hours of your life back. How so many people seemed to have liked this disturbs me. I would recommend this to only an enemy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kiefer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought Kiefer Sutherland did a wonderful job with the movie first off, his acting skills are hard to match by anyone,, how many actors today can bounce back and forth between movies and TV just like that.. Sally Field.. wow what happened to her since Coal Miner's Daughter. she did very good to in the role of the mother trying to get vengeance on her daughter being raped,, in the initial opening scene,, the teenage daughter is on the phone with mom,, and she get's raped and mom hear's the entire rape,start to finish, due to a technicality our rapist is set free, and free to rape and kill again. he starts stalking different prey this time, while our raging mother is trying to find our rapist and bring him to either justice or death.. these kind of movies have been overdone and watered down in the past 30 years. but this one seems to me to have a little more staying power.. I think that will be because of Kiefer's high profile,, 24,, and an amazing performance by Sally Field,, the Coal Miner's Daughter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Revenge Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sally Fields does a good job with this movie as a revenge seeking mother of a teenage daughter who's been raped and murdered. I suppose to make this worth watching, she has to do a good job with this. The story itself has been done over and over: seeking revenge after a violent crime because the justice system has failed. That's a pretty clich&eacute; type of situation and story, so there's not really a great deal to recommend this as far as originality is concerned. But Fields is good, and Kiefer Sutherland is appropriately creepy and threatening as the rapist/murderer. The portrayal of the rape of Karen's daughter was terrifying, but (thankfully) not especially graphic.) The same could be said for the later rape committed by Sutherland's Doob. The movie, in my opinion, also makes a fair point about the justice system leaning too far on the side of defending the rights of obviously guilty criminals at the expense of actually dispensing justice for their victims. I understand the need to protect the rights of the accused, but there does have to be a balance, and that balance is sometimes lost in the system that we have. I was kind of put off by the "group" the McCann's attended for people who had lost loved ones to violence. To each his or her own, I suppose, but I can't imagine that sitting around night after night talking about the same thing over and over and over again is really going to help anyone move on, and I wasn't convinced by the "vigilante organization" aspect of this. I have to say, though, that I did like the ending. What I was finding distasteful up to this point was that Karen was going to turn vigilante, and by so doing she'd be be risking losing her other daughter as well by ending up in prison, which might have satisfied her own desire for revenge but would have been very selfish toward the younger daughter. So, the way she played things, she made sure that (a) she'd get her revenge, but (b) that she wouldn't lose anything more by doing it. So, the ending worked for me. Overall, I found this a pretty good watch. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Exactly a Shining Endorsement of Men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In many ways, Eye for an Eye is a fairly bland thriller, indistinguishable from other vigilante-style movies. In fact, it plays at times like one of those cheaply made TV movies, and yet it contains a couple of attacks on women which are quite shocking in their intensity and completely at odds with the rest of the film. Sally Field plays a typically upper-middle class working mother whose teenage daughter is brutally raped and murdered by ultra-sleazy deliveryman Kiefer Sutherland. When the American justice system lets him free on a technicality, Field resolves to take the law into her own hands. The film's basically just a variation on Death Wish, with the added frisson that the vigilante is physically the weaker party and therefore just as likely to become a victim of her target as the other way around. Field is pretty good in the role, as is Sutherland as her nemesis, even though he is portrayed as pure evil with no redeeming  or human  qualities to speak of. The guy can't even sit down without pouring his coffee over a passing dog. Given that, away from his battle with Field, Sutherland isn't given much to play with beyond a couple of scenes which provide no insight into his character  in one he's threatened by frustrated cop Joe Mantegna, and in the other he plays frenetic drums on his legs as he watches a video in his grubby hotel room  he makes quite an impression, proving he's as adept at playing irredeemable bad guys as he is clean cut heroes of the Jack Bauer variety. Ed Harris plays Field's understanding but long-suffering husband, and he's about as emasculated as a man can be in a movie. Never really knowing what's going on, regularly catching on a couple of scenes too late, he's effortlessly sent trotting off to the mountains by Field when she wants him out of the way so that she can put her revenge plan into action. I'm not sure I'd have been as understanding as him in that final scene, and it kind of makes you wonder what Harris saw in the role
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tolerable revenge thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Considering the calibre of the cast and director, Eye For An Eye is a rather low key affair. It tells a familiar story - rapist/murderer goes free through legal loophole, bereaved parent pursues vengeance/justice - and does so reasonably well. Some might think Keifer Sutherland's villain is one dimensional and overstated - I suspect not. Some might think the reactions of Sally Field and Ed Harris as parents of the murdered girl are unrealistic - the answer here must be whether they are credible, and I think they are credible possible reactions. No two people will react the same way, and none of us knows what we would do unless it happens to us (and I profoundly hope it does not happen to anyone reading this). Ultimately, though, despite decent performances and a satisfactory (though somewhat perfunctory) conclusion, the emotional intensity of the opening is not really sustained, and the film peters out in a welter of obviousness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A decent revenge film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cppguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's more interesting to review the reviews than review the movie. There's nothing technically wrong with this movie. Production values are fine. The acting is fine. Anyone rating this a 1 is an incompetent reviewer. 1-star reviews so far rant that Ed Harris ruined the movie and at the same time wonder why Super Ed was saddled with such a horrible supporting cast. Maybe reviewers should be allowed to vote 4-6 until they prove competency. Back to the movie. So far, I have yet to see a movie with Sally Field where she doesn't shine. While her movies may not be perfect, she's a superb actress. Like Tom Hanks, she generally picks winners to be in (funny they starred in at least 2 movies together). I'm also developing a liking for Joe Montegna. I see him in a lot of films and he brings a nice competency to supporting roles. Same for Ed Harris. I like Kiefer Sutherland in his various movies and he does a fine job (even if slightly over the top here) of being creepy. So let's talk film content. Revenge films are intriguing in many ways. To an extent, that concept is an easy way to develop conflict for the viewer. However, it's much harder to come up with a reason for the vengeance. "The Sting" took revenge to high art. "Eye for an Eye" is not high art, so no 10 from me for the film. A 7 will have to do. Others have compared this to the better known "Death Wish," but I think this was better produced and had better flow. Aspects of the movie are predictable, but I've seen many a good movie that was predictable. Summary: if you're scanning Netflix or Blockbuster for an unseen movie with decent action and dialog that moves at a good pace, "Eye for an Eye" isn't revenge on the level of "M," "The Sting," or "Gran Torino" but it's a decent watch... especially if you like the acting talents of Field, Sutherland, Harris and Montegna. If you like action/revenge films, pop some popcorn, curl up with someone special and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An engaging drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a mother who goes to seek justice for the brutal murder of her teenage daughter. "Eye for an Eye" is an intense drama that tells a family's grief in losing a teenage girl in the family. They all react in different ways; the father seems casual and detached on the surface, but actually has intense anger inside. The younger daughter blames herself, while the mother becomes obsessed with getting justice. The plot is good, it is engaging and well told. However, I think the title gives the whole film away, so things will happen in a certain way in order for the film to be called "Eye for an Eye".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ed harris is awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gs20
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing that spoiled the story for me and just made the whole thing implausible was ed harris and ed harris alone........i cannot imagine a father whose daughter is violently raped and murdered acting in such a blaze' or indifferent and completely detached manner.........he was absolutely blank about it and acted pretty much as if nothing unusual happened in his life.........as opposed, say, to sean penn in mystic river reacting to the same situation (outstanding believability) i have never thought much of harris' quirky and bizarre acting style until i realized he is just a terrible actor, that there is no real style to think about and this is a good example of that blankness and absence of emotion..........they would have gotten a better performance out of someone who just happened by the set. Harris' performance here, as in many of his performances was without substance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Controversial topic must drive home a point
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Says nothing, and does nothing. John Schlesinger's "Eye For an Eye" takes a very controversial topic and has nothing to say about it. The entire film appears to have no point. Films of this type cannot be effective just by telling a story. Sadly, this was a complete waste of Sally Field's enormous talent, which was on show again in this movie. The two time Oscar winner almost saved this film. The rest of the cast, including the villainous Kiefer Sutherland and Ed Harris, do little with their roles. Based upon Erica Holzer's novel. Friday, September 3, 1999 - T.V.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too manipulative and heavy handed, even for aspiring vigilantes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to start with this movie? Well, first of all I don't blame the actors in this movie for its failings. The cast is a talented bunch that I've admired elsewhere, and it's clear they are doing what the screenplay and direction tell them to do. On second thought, maybe part of the cast can be blamed - there is a brief appearance by martial arts actress Cynthia Rothrock, and if you know her, you know that any (American) movie she stars in turns out to be a turkey. I'll get serious now. The direction and screen writing of this movie, as I indicated in my summary line, are way below par. There's hardly any time with the protagonist before tragedy strikes, so we don't see how she's changed and scarred. The villain of the movie is so BAD, so EVIL, that he becomes a cartoon character instead of someone realistic that we the audience could really fear and feel genuine hatred. The second half of the movie, where Field becomes an aspiring vigilante, is sometimes laughable in showing how far she'll go. On that note, I'll leave my final thought. With the movie's heavy hand and sometimes laughable plot turns, I have to wonder if this would have worked better as a spoof of vigilante movies. Even if it had failed, I'm sure the end results would be more interesting than how the movie is now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dreadful excuse for a drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lilith Hexus
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into this film with no expectations poor or positive. I am, however, a person who does not believe Sally Field deserves her acclaim and finds her to be a good deal overrated. Is she a bad actress? Over the top, maybe, but I would not use the term 'bad'. At least not until I saw this. The film is about a woman who calls her teenage daughter from a traffic jam and, as they are talking, she hears her daughter being attacked. The girl is raped and killed. This already brings me to the first issue with the film, as well as with Sally Field's acting. For starters, there may have been an issue with hanging up the phone due to the daughter not hitting 'end' back then, I am not up to date on how cell phones worked in the mid-90's. However, why did she never attempt to hang up and call 911 on the phone in her hand? Comfort does not mean as much as life, and every second counts. There is also the fact that, other than two brief scenes, I never once felt like Sally's character cared a thing for her daughter. She never acts sad or distraught over her daughter's death, and only comes off as either indifferent or offended, as if someone had stolen property from her and given her a reason to be defensive over herself. I understand denial and hysterics, but at a certain point the family members of victims of such crimes do end up breaking down and, in nearly every case, lose track of life and shut down partially. There is even a moment when a woman tells Sally she needs to stay strong for her youngest daughter, despite the fact that she is the least upset person at the entire memorial. She seems to use her daughter's death as an excuse to be illogical, hysterical, and hateful but never once gave me a reason to feel bad for her, when I should normally be able to without much expression at all. The film's villain is also abysmal. He behaves like an overly cartoon-like fiend who lives for no reason other than to do mischief (it is bad when I can use this word accurately about a rapist/murderer in a serious drama). I was honestly waiting for him to get hold of Sally Field and tie her to the railroad tracks by the third time he laughed deviously and did another random, senseless act of naughtiness. The man rapes and kills two people for certain, as well as pours hot coffee on a dog and urinates through a woman's fence, and somehow managed to not only make none of this seem overly malicious or cruel, but almost like a child trying to get attention. Every character is unbelievable and ridiculous, except for perhaps the two victims who are seen so briefly each. The police officer defies logic at every turn and when he actually does decide to do something, it is not only at the wrong time but in a way that in most cases he would have been fired for his actions. He assaults a man who has been legally dismissed of all charges, simply on suspicion. This includes holding a gun to his head. Plenty of witnesses saw and heard the assault, and one word from any of them and he would be turning in his badge and completely useless to anyone. This may have been his true goal, though, as without such a useless officer on the force they may actually get something done. Now just to deal with the idiots handling the evidence. The finale of the film is absurd, not due to the plot but simply because of how it is delivered. At one point Sally Field has the killer at gunpoint, easily six feet away minimum, and has plenty of opportunity and logical reason, as well as every intent, to shoot and kill him. This was her plan, to kill the man while under legal conditions. Instead, she waits around for literally no reason and somehow allows him to ram his entire body into her before she can do so much as to pull the trigger once. She is then knocked down the stairs and lands on her back at the bottom, and though the gun is lying only a few inches away from her in plain sight to both of them, this for some reason did not seem threatening to the killer who idly strolls down the stairs taunting her. No shock to anyone, she grabs the gun and fires repeatedly into his torso, not missing a single time. Strangely, he seems bewildered by these events and does not understand how the woman lying only a few inches away from a loaded gun shot him while he taunted her and slowly moved in for the kill. I will not even discuss the "Vigilante Group", that is simply something you will have to see yourself, or be glad you are not aware of. Plain and simple, this film is entirely unbelievable, every attempt at inducing any sort of emotion is a miserable failure, and it will make you wish you had two hours of your life back. How so many people seemed to have liked this disturbs me. I would recommend this to only an enemy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kiefer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought Kiefer Sutherland did a wonderful job with the movie first off, his acting skills are hard to match by anyone,, how many actors today can bounce back and forth between movies and TV just like that.. Sally Field.. wow what happened to her since Coal Miner's Daughter. she did very good to in the role of the mother trying to get vengeance on her daughter being raped,, in the initial opening scene,, the teenage daughter is on the phone with mom,, and she get's raped and mom hear's the entire rape,start to finish, due to a technicality our rapist is set free, and free to rape and kill again. he starts stalking different prey this time, while our raging mother is trying to find our rapist and bring him to either justice or death.. these kind of movies have been overdone and watered down in the past 30 years. but this one seems to me to have a little more staying power.. I think that will be because of Kiefer's high profile,, 24,, and an amazing performance by Sally Field,, the Coal Miner's Daughter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Revenge Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sally Fields does a good job with this movie as a revenge seeking mother of a teenage daughter who's been raped and murdered. I suppose to make this worth watching, she has to do a good job with this. The story itself has been done over and over: seeking revenge after a violent crime because the justice system has failed. That's a pretty clich&eacute; type of situation and story, so there's not really a great deal to recommend this as far as originality is concerned. But Fields is good, and Kiefer Sutherland is appropriately creepy and threatening as the rapist/murderer. The portrayal of the rape of Karen's daughter was terrifying, but (thankfully) not especially graphic.) The same could be said for the later rape committed by Sutherland's Doob. The movie, in my opinion, also makes a fair point about the justice system leaning too far on the side of defending the rights of obviously guilty criminals at the expense of actually dispensing justice for their victims. I understand the need to protect the rights of the accused, but there does have to be a balance, and that balance is sometimes lost in the system that we have. I was kind of put off by the "group" the McCann's attended for people who had lost loved ones to violence. To each his or her own, I suppose, but I can't imagine that sitting around night after night talking about the same thing over and over and over again is really going to help anyone move on, and I wasn't convinced by the "vigilante organization" aspect of this. I have to say, though, that I did like the ending. What I was finding distasteful up to this point was that Karen was going to turn vigilante, and by so doing she'd be be risking losing her other daughter as well by ending up in prison, which might have satisfied her own desire for revenge but would have been very selfish toward the younger daughter. So, the way she played things, she made sure that (a) she'd get her revenge, but (b) that she wouldn't lose anything more by doing it. So, the ending worked for me. Overall, I found this a pretty good watch. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Exactly a Shining Endorsement of Men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In many ways, Eye for an Eye is a fairly bland thriller, indistinguishable from other vigilante-style movies. In fact, it plays at times like one of those cheaply made TV movies, and yet it contains a couple of attacks on women which are quite shocking in their intensity and completely at odds with the rest of the film. Sally Field plays a typically upper-middle class working mother whose teenage daughter is brutally raped and murdered by ultra-sleazy deliveryman Kiefer Sutherland. When the American justice system lets him free on a technicality, Field resolves to take the law into her own hands. The film's basically just a variation on Death Wish, with the added frisson that the vigilante is physically the weaker party and therefore just as likely to become a victim of her target as the other way around. Field is pretty good in the role, as is Sutherland as her nemesis, even though he is portrayed as pure evil with no redeeming  or human  qualities to speak of. The guy can't even sit down without pouring his coffee over a passing dog. Given that, away from his battle with Field, Sutherland isn't given much to play with beyond a couple of scenes which provide no insight into his character  in one he's threatened by frustrated cop Joe Mantegna, and in the other he plays frenetic drums on his legs as he watches a video in his grubby hotel room  he makes quite an impression, proving he's as adept at playing irredeemable bad guys as he is clean cut heroes of the Jack Bauer variety. Ed Harris plays Field's understanding but long-suffering husband, and he's about as emasculated as a man can be in a movie. Never really knowing what's going on, regularly catching on a couple of scenes too late, he's effortlessly sent trotting off to the mountains by Field when she wants him out of the way so that she can put her revenge plan into action. I'm not sure I'd have been as understanding as him in that final scene, and it kind of makes you wonder what Harris saw in the role
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tolerable revenge thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Considering the calibre of the cast and director, Eye For An Eye is a rather low key affair. It tells a familiar story - rapist/murderer goes free through legal loophole, bereaved parent pursues vengeance/justice - and does so reasonably well. Some might think Keifer Sutherland's villain is one dimensional and overstated - I suspect not. Some might think the reactions of Sally Field and Ed Harris as parents of the murdered girl are unrealistic - the answer here must be whether they are credible, and I think they are credible possible reactions. No two people will react the same way, and none of us knows what we would do unless it happens to us (and I profoundly hope it does not happen to anyone reading this). Ultimately, though, despite decent performances and a satisfactory (though somewhat perfunctory) conclusion, the emotional intensity of the opening is not really sustained, and the film peters out in a welter of obviousness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A decent revenge film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cppguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's more interesting to review the reviews than review the movie. There's nothing technically wrong with this movie. Production values are fine. The acting is fine. Anyone rating this a 1 is an incompetent reviewer. 1-star reviews so far rant that Ed Harris ruined the movie and at the same time wonder why Super Ed was saddled with such a horrible supporting cast. Maybe reviewers should be allowed to vote 4-6 until they prove competency. Back to the movie. So far, I have yet to see a movie with Sally Field where she doesn't shine. While her movies may not be perfect, she's a superb actress. Like Tom Hanks, she generally picks winners to be in (funny they starred in at least 2 movies together). I'm also developing a liking for Joe Montegna. I see him in a lot of films and he brings a nice competency to supporting roles. Same for Ed Harris. I like Kiefer Sutherland in his various movies and he does a fine job (even if slightly over the top here) of being creepy. So let's talk film content. Revenge films are intriguing in many ways. To an extent, that concept is an easy way to develop conflict for the viewer. However, it's much harder to come up with a reason for the vengeance. "The Sting" took revenge to high art. "Eye for an Eye" is not high art, so no 10 from me for the film. A 7 will have to do. Others have compared this to the better known "Death Wish," but I think this was better produced and had better flow. Aspects of the movie are predictable, but I've seen many a good movie that was predictable. Summary: if you're scanning Netflix or Blockbuster for an unseen movie with decent action and dialog that moves at a good pace, "Eye for an Eye" isn't revenge on the level of "M," "The Sting," or "Gran Torino" but it's a decent watch... especially if you like the acting talents of Field, Sutherland, Harris and Montegna. If you like action/revenge films, pop some popcorn, curl up with someone special and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An engaging drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a mother who goes to seek justice for the brutal murder of her teenage daughter. "Eye for an Eye" is an intense drama that tells a family's grief in losing a teenage girl in the family. They all react in different ways; the father seems casual and detached on the surface, but actually has intense anger inside. The younger daughter blames herself, while the mother becomes obsessed with getting justice. The plot is good, it is engaging and well told. However, I think the title gives the whole film away, so things will happen in a certain way in order for the film to be called "Eye for an Eye".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ed harris is awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gs20
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing that spoiled the story for me and just made the whole thing implausible was ed harris and ed harris alone........i cannot imagine a father whose daughter is violently raped and murdered acting in such a blaze' or indifferent and completely detached manner.........he was absolutely blank about it and acted pretty much as if nothing unusual happened in his life.........as opposed, say, to sean penn in mystic river reacting to the same situation (outstanding believability) i have never thought much of harris' quirky and bizarre acting style until i realized he is just a terrible actor, that there is no real style to think about and this is a good example of that blankness and absence of emotion..........they would have gotten a better performance out of someone who just happened by the set. Harris' performance here, as in many of his performances was without substance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Controversial topic must drive home a point
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Says nothing, and does nothing. John Schlesinger's "Eye For an Eye" takes a very controversial topic and has nothing to say about it. The entire film appears to have no point. Films of this type cannot be effective just by telling a story. Sadly, this was a complete waste of Sally Field's enormous talent, which was on show again in this movie. The two time Oscar winner almost saved this film. The rest of the cast, including the villainous Kiefer Sutherland and Ed Harris, do little with their roles. Based upon Erica Holzer's novel. Friday, September 3, 1999 - T.V.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too manipulative and heavy handed, even for aspiring vigilantes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to start with this movie? Well, first of all I don't blame the actors in this movie for its failings. The cast is a talented bunch that I've admired elsewhere, and it's clear they are doing what the screenplay and direction tell them to do. On second thought, maybe part of the cast can be blamed - there is a brief appearance by martial arts actress Cynthia Rothrock, and if you know her, you know that any (American) movie she stars in turns out to be a turkey. I'll get serious now. The direction and screen writing of this movie, as I indicated in my summary line, are way below par. There's hardly any time with the protagonist before tragedy strikes, so we don't see how she's changed and scarred. The villain of the movie is so BAD, so EVIL, that he becomes a cartoon character instead of someone realistic that we the audience could really fear and feel genuine hatred. The second half of the movie, where Field becomes an aspiring vigilante, is sometimes laughable in showing how far she'll go. On that note, I'll leave my final thought. With the movie's heavy hand and sometimes laughable plot turns, I have to wonder if this would have worked better as a spoof of vigilante movies. Even if it had failed, I'm sure the end results would be more interesting than how the movie is now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dreadful excuse for a drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lilith Hexus
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into this film with no expectations poor or positive. I am, however, a person who does not believe Sally Field deserves her acclaim and finds her to be a good deal overrated. Is she a bad actress? Over the top, maybe, but I would not use the term 'bad'. At least not until I saw this. The film is about a woman who calls her teenage daughter from a traffic jam and, as they are talking, she hears her daughter being attacked. The girl is raped and killed. This already brings me to the first issue with the film, as well as with Sally Field's acting. For starters, there may have been an issue with hanging up the phone due to the daughter not hitting 'end' back then, I am not up to date on how cell phones worked in the mid-90's. However, why did she never attempt to hang up and call 911 on the phone in her hand? Comfort does not mean as much as life, and every second counts. There is also the fact that, other than two brief scenes, I never once felt like Sally's character cared a thing for her daughter. She never acts sad or distraught over her daughter's death, and only comes off as either indifferent or offended, as if someone had stolen property from her and given her a reason to be defensive over herself. I understand denial and hysterics, but at a certain point the family members of victims of such crimes do end up breaking down and, in nearly every case, lose track of life and shut down partially. There is even a moment when a woman tells Sally she needs to stay strong for her youngest daughter, despite the fact that she is the least upset person at the entire memorial. She seems to use her daughter's death as an excuse to be illogical, hysterical, and hateful but never once gave me a reason to feel bad for her, when I should normally be able to without much expression at all. The film's villain is also abysmal. He behaves like an overly cartoon-like fiend who lives for no reason other than to do mischief (it is bad when I can use this word accurately about a rapist/murderer in a serious drama). I was honestly waiting for him to get hold of Sally Field and tie her to the railroad tracks by the third time he laughed deviously and did another random, senseless act of naughtiness. The man rapes and kills two people for certain, as well as pours hot coffee on a dog and urinates through a woman's fence, and somehow managed to not only make none of this seem overly malicious or cruel, but almost like a child trying to get attention. Every character is unbelievable and ridiculous, except for perhaps the two victims who are seen so briefly each. The police officer defies logic at every turn and when he actually does decide to do something, it is not only at the wrong time but in a way that in most cases he would have been fired for his actions. He assaults a man who has been legally dismissed of all charges, simply on suspicion. This includes holding a gun to his head. Plenty of witnesses saw and heard the assault, and one word from any of them and he would be turning in his badge and completely useless to anyone. This may have been his true goal, though, as without such a useless officer on the force they may actually get something done. Now just to deal with the idiots handling the evidence. The finale of the film is absurd, not due to the plot but simply because of how it is delivered. At one point Sally Field has the killer at gunpoint, easily six feet away minimum, and has plenty of opportunity and logical reason, as well as every intent, to shoot and kill him. This was her plan, to kill the man while under legal conditions. Instead, she waits around for literally no reason and somehow allows him to ram his entire body into her before she can do so much as to pull the trigger once. She is then knocked down the stairs and lands on her back at the bottom, and though the gun is lying only a few inches away from her in plain sight to both of them, this for some reason did not seem threatening to the killer who idly strolls down the stairs taunting her. No shock to anyone, she grabs the gun and fires repeatedly into his torso, not missing a single time. Strangely, he seems bewildered by these events and does not understand how the woman lying only a few inches away from a loaded gun shot him while he taunted her and slowly moved in for the kill. I will not even discuss the "Vigilante Group", that is simply something you will have to see yourself, or be glad you are not aware of. Plain and simple, this film is entirely unbelievable, every attempt at inducing any sort of emotion is a miserable failure, and it will make you wish you had two hours of your life back. How so many people seemed to have liked this disturbs me. I would recommend this to only an enemy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kiefer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought Kiefer Sutherland did a wonderful job with the movie first off, his acting skills are hard to match by anyone,, how many actors today can bounce back and forth between movies and TV just like that.. Sally Field.. wow what happened to her since Coal Miner's Daughter. she did very good to in the role of the mother trying to get vengeance on her daughter being raped,, in the initial opening scene,, the teenage daughter is on the phone with mom,, and she get's raped and mom hear's the entire rape,start to finish, due to a technicality our rapist is set free, and free to rape and kill again. he starts stalking different prey this time, while our raging mother is trying to find our rapist and bring him to either justice or death.. these kind of movies have been overdone and watered down in the past 30 years. but this one seems to me to have a little more staying power.. I think that will be because of Kiefer's high profile,, 24,, and an amazing performance by Sally Field,, the Coal Miner's Daughter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Revenge Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sally Fields does a good job with this movie as a revenge seeking mother of a teenage daughter who's been raped and murdered. I suppose to make this worth watching, she has to do a good job with this. The story itself has been done over and over: seeking revenge after a violent crime because the justice system has failed. That's a pretty clich&eacute; type of situation and story, so there's not really a great deal to recommend this as far as originality is concerned. But Fields is good, and Kiefer Sutherland is appropriately creepy and threatening as the rapist/murderer. The portrayal of the rape of Karen's daughter was terrifying, but (thankfully) not especially graphic.) The same could be said for the later rape committed by Sutherland's Doob. The movie, in my opinion, also makes a fair point about the justice system leaning too far on the side of defending the rights of obviously guilty criminals at the expense of actually dispensing justice for their victims. I understand the need to protect the rights of the accused, but there does have to be a balance, and that balance is sometimes lost in the system that we have. I was kind of put off by the "group" the McCann's attended for people who had lost loved ones to violence. To each his or her own, I suppose, but I can't imagine that sitting around night after night talking about the same thing over and over and over again is really going to help anyone move on, and I wasn't convinced by the "vigilante organization" aspect of this. I have to say, though, that I did like the ending. What I was finding distasteful up to this point was that Karen was going to turn vigilante, and by so doing she'd be be risking losing her other daughter as well by ending up in prison, which might have satisfied her own desire for revenge but would have been very selfish toward the younger daughter. So, the way she played things, she made sure that (a) she'd get her revenge, but (b) that she wouldn't lose anything more by doing it. So, the ending worked for me. Overall, I found this a pretty good watch. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Exactly a Shining Endorsement of Men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In many ways, Eye for an Eye is a fairly bland thriller, indistinguishable from other vigilante-style movies. In fact, it plays at times like one of those cheaply made TV movies, and yet it contains a couple of attacks on women which are quite shocking in their intensity and completely at odds with the rest of the film. Sally Field plays a typically upper-middle class working mother whose teenage daughter is brutally raped and murdered by ultra-sleazy deliveryman Kiefer Sutherland. When the American justice system lets him free on a technicality, Field resolves to take the law into her own hands. The film's basically just a variation on Death Wish, with the added frisson that the vigilante is physically the weaker party and therefore just as likely to become a victim of her target as the other way around. Field is pretty good in the role, as is Sutherland as her nemesis, even though he is portrayed as pure evil with no redeeming  or human  qualities to speak of. The guy can't even sit down without pouring his coffee over a passing dog. Given that, away from his battle with Field, Sutherland isn't given much to play with beyond a couple of scenes which provide no insight into his character  in one he's threatened by frustrated cop Joe Mantegna, and in the other he plays frenetic drums on his legs as he watches a video in his grubby hotel room  he makes quite an impression, proving he's as adept at playing irredeemable bad guys as he is clean cut heroes of the Jack Bauer variety. Ed Harris plays Field's understanding but long-suffering husband, and he's about as emasculated as a man can be in a movie. Never really knowing what's going on, regularly catching on a couple of scenes too late, he's effortlessly sent trotting off to the mountains by Field when she wants him out of the way so that she can put her revenge plan into action. I'm not sure I'd have been as understanding as him in that final scene, and it kind of makes you wonder what Harris saw in the role
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tolerable revenge thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Considering the calibre of the cast and director, Eye For An Eye is a rather low key affair. It tells a familiar story - rapist/murderer goes free through legal loophole, bereaved parent pursues vengeance/justice - and does so reasonably well. Some might think Keifer Sutherland's villain is one dimensional and overstated - I suspect not. Some might think the reactions of Sally Field and Ed Harris as parents of the murdered girl are unrealistic - the answer here must be whether they are credible, and I think they are credible possible reactions. No two people will react the same way, and none of us knows what we would do unless it happens to us (and I profoundly hope it does not happen to anyone reading this). Ultimately, though, despite decent performances and a satisfactory (though somewhat perfunctory) conclusion, the emotional intensity of the opening is not really sustained, and the film peters out in a welter of obviousness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A decent revenge film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cppguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's more interesting to review the reviews than review the movie. There's nothing technically wrong with this movie. Production values are fine. The acting is fine. Anyone rating this a 1 is an incompetent reviewer. 1-star reviews so far rant that Ed Harris ruined the movie and at the same time wonder why Super Ed was saddled with such a horrible supporting cast. Maybe reviewers should be allowed to vote 4-6 until they prove competency. Back to the movie. So far, I have yet to see a movie with Sally Field where she doesn't shine. While her movies may not be perfect, she's a superb actress. Like Tom Hanks, she generally picks winners to be in (funny they starred in at least 2 movies together). I'm also developing a liking for Joe Montegna. I see him in a lot of films and he brings a nice competency to supporting roles. Same for Ed Harris. I like Kiefer Sutherland in his various movies and he does a fine job (even if slightly over the top here) of being creepy. So let's talk film content. Revenge films are intriguing in many ways. To an extent, that concept is an easy way to develop conflict for the viewer. However, it's much harder to come up with a reason for the vengeance. "The Sting" took revenge to high art. "Eye for an Eye" is not high art, so no 10 from me for the film. A 7 will have to do. Others have compared this to the better known "Death Wish," but I think this was better produced and had better flow. Aspects of the movie are predictable, but I've seen many a good movie that was predictable. Summary: if you're scanning Netflix or Blockbuster for an unseen movie with decent action and dialog that moves at a good pace, "Eye for an Eye" isn't revenge on the level of "M," "The Sting," or "Gran Torino" but it's a decent watch... especially if you like the acting talents of Field, Sutherland, Harris and Montegna. If you like action/revenge films, pop some popcorn, curl up with someone special and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An engaging drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a mother who goes to seek justice for the brutal murder of her teenage daughter. "Eye for an Eye" is an intense drama that tells a family's grief in losing a teenage girl in the family. They all react in different ways; the father seems casual and detached on the surface, but actually has intense anger inside. The younger daughter blames herself, while the mother becomes obsessed with getting justice. The plot is good, it is engaging and well told. However, I think the title gives the whole film away, so things will happen in a certain way in order for the film to be called "Eye for an Eye".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ed harris is awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gs20
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing that spoiled the story for me and just made the whole thing implausible was ed harris and ed harris alone........i cannot imagine a father whose daughter is violently raped and murdered acting in such a blaze' or indifferent and completely detached manner.........he was absolutely blank about it and acted pretty much as if nothing unusual happened in his life.........as opposed, say, to sean penn in mystic river reacting to the same situation (outstanding believability) i have never thought much of harris' quirky and bizarre acting style until i realized he is just a terrible actor, that there is no real style to think about and this is a good example of that blankness and absence of emotion..........they would have gotten a better performance out of someone who just happened by the set. Harris' performance here, as in many of his performances was without substance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Controversial topic must drive home a point
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Says nothing, and does nothing. John Schlesinger's "Eye For an Eye" takes a very controversial topic and has nothing to say about it. The entire film appears to have no point. Films of this type cannot be effective just by telling a story. Sadly, this was a complete waste of Sally Field's enormous talent, which was on show again in this movie. The two time Oscar winner almost saved this film. The rest of the cast, including the villainous Kiefer Sutherland and Ed Harris, do little with their roles. Based upon Erica Holzer's novel. Friday, September 3, 1999 - T.V.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too manipulative and heavy handed, even for aspiring vigilantes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to start with this movie? Well, first of all I don't blame the actors in this movie for its failings. The cast is a talented bunch that I've admired elsewhere, and it's clear they are doing what the screenplay and direction tell them to do. On second thought, maybe part of the cast can be blamed - there is a brief appearance by martial arts actress Cynthia Rothrock, and if you know her, you know that any (American) movie she stars in turns out to be a turkey. I'll get serious now. The direction and screen writing of this movie, as I indicated in my summary line, are way below par. There's hardly any time with the protagonist before tragedy strikes, so we don't see how she's changed and scarred. The villain of the movie is so BAD, so EVIL, that he becomes a cartoon character instead of someone realistic that we the audience could really fear and feel genuine hatred. The second half of the movie, where Field becomes an aspiring vigilante, is sometimes laughable in showing how far she'll go. On that note, I'll leave my final thought. With the movie's heavy hand and sometimes laughable plot turns, I have to wonder if this would have worked better as a spoof of vigilante movies. Even if it had failed, I'm sure the end results would be more interesting than how the movie is now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dreadful excuse for a drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lilith Hexus
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into this film with no expectations poor or positive. I am, however, a person who does not believe Sally Field deserves her acclaim and finds her to be a good deal overrated. Is she a bad actress? Over the top, maybe, but I would not use the term 'bad'. At least not until I saw this. The film is about a woman who calls her teenage daughter from a traffic jam and, as they are talking, she hears her daughter being attacked. The girl is raped and killed. This already brings me to the first issue with the film, as well as with Sally Field's acting. For starters, there may have been an issue with hanging up the phone due to the daughter not hitting 'end' back then, I am not up to date on how cell phones worked in the mid-90's. However, why did she never attempt to hang up and call 911 on the phone in her hand? Comfort does not mean as much as life, and every second counts. There is also the fact that, other than two brief scenes, I never once felt like Sally's character cared a thing for her daughter. She never acts sad or distraught over her daughter's death, and only comes off as either indifferent or offended, as if someone had stolen property from her and given her a reason to be defensive over herself. I understand denial and hysterics, but at a certain point the family members of victims of such crimes do end up breaking down and, in nearly every case, lose track of life and shut down partially. There is even a moment when a woman tells Sally she needs to stay strong for her youngest daughter, despite the fact that she is the least upset person at the entire memorial. She seems to use her daughter's death as an excuse to be illogical, hysterical, and hateful but never once gave me a reason to feel bad for her, when I should normally be able to without much expression at all. The film's villain is also abysmal. He behaves like an overly cartoon-like fiend who lives for no reason other than to do mischief (it is bad when I can use this word accurately about a rapist/murderer in a serious drama). I was honestly waiting for him to get hold of Sally Field and tie her to the railroad tracks by the third time he laughed deviously and did another random, senseless act of naughtiness. The man rapes and kills two people for certain, as well as pours hot coffee on a dog and urinates through a woman's fence, and somehow managed to not only make none of this seem overly malicious or cruel, but almost like a child trying to get attention. Every character is unbelievable and ridiculous, except for perhaps the two victims who are seen so briefly each. The police officer defies logic at every turn and when he actually does decide to do something, it is not only at the wrong time but in a way that in most cases he would have been fired for his actions. He assaults a man who has been legally dismissed of all charges, simply on suspicion. This includes holding a gun to his head. Plenty of witnesses saw and heard the assault, and one word from any of them and he would be turning in his badge and completely useless to anyone. This may have been his true goal, though, as without such a useless officer on the force they may actually get something done. Now just to deal with the idiots handling the evidence. The finale of the film is absurd, not due to the plot but simply because of how it is delivered. At one point Sally Field has the killer at gunpoint, easily six feet away minimum, and has plenty of opportunity and logical reason, as well as every intent, to shoot and kill him. This was her plan, to kill the man while under legal conditions. Instead, she waits around for literally no reason and somehow allows him to ram his entire body into her before she can do so much as to pull the trigger once. She is then knocked down the stairs and lands on her back at the bottom, and though the gun is lying only a few inches away from her in plain sight to both of them, this for some reason did not seem threatening to the killer who idly strolls down the stairs taunting her. No shock to anyone, she grabs the gun and fires repeatedly into his torso, not missing a single time. Strangely, he seems bewildered by these events and does not understand how the woman lying only a few inches away from a loaded gun shot him while he taunted her and slowly moved in for the kill. I will not even discuss the "Vigilante Group", that is simply something you will have to see yourself, or be glad you are not aware of. Plain and simple, this film is entirely unbelievable, every attempt at inducing any sort of emotion is a miserable failure, and it will make you wish you had two hours of your life back. How so many people seemed to have liked this disturbs me. I would recommend this to only an enemy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kiefer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought Kiefer Sutherland did a wonderful job with the movie first off, his acting skills are hard to match by anyone,, how many actors today can bounce back and forth between movies and TV just like that.. Sally Field.. wow what happened to her since Coal Miner's Daughter. she did very good to in the role of the mother trying to get vengeance on her daughter being raped,, in the initial opening scene,, the teenage daughter is on the phone with mom,, and she get's raped and mom hear's the entire rape,start to finish, due to a technicality our rapist is set free, and free to rape and kill again. he starts stalking different prey this time, while our raging mother is trying to find our rapist and bring him to either justice or death.. these kind of movies have been overdone and watered down in the past 30 years. but this one seems to me to have a little more staying power.. I think that will be because of Kiefer's high profile,, 24,, and an amazing performance by Sally Field,, the Coal Miner's Daughter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Revenge Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sally Fields does a good job with this movie as a revenge seeking mother of a teenage daughter who's been raped and murdered. I suppose to make this worth watching, she has to do a good job with this. The story itself has been done over and over: seeking revenge after a violent crime because the justice system has failed. That's a pretty clich&eacute; type of situation and story, so there's not really a great deal to recommend this as far as originality is concerned. But Fields is good, and Kiefer Sutherland is appropriately creepy and threatening as the rapist/murderer. The portrayal of the rape of Karen's daughter was terrifying, but (thankfully) not especially graphic.) The same could be said for the later rape committed by Sutherland's Doob. The movie, in my opinion, also makes a fair point about the justice system leaning too far on the side of defending the rights of obviously guilty criminals at the expense of actually dispensing justice for their victims. I understand the need to protect the rights of the accused, but there does have to be a balance, and that balance is sometimes lost in the system that we have. I was kind of put off by the "group" the McCann's attended for people who had lost loved ones to violence. To each his or her own, I suppose, but I can't imagine that sitting around night after night talking about the same thing over and over and over again is really going to help anyone move on, and I wasn't convinced by the "vigilante organization" aspect of this. I have to say, though, that I did like the ending. What I was finding distasteful up to this point was that Karen was going to turn vigilante, and by so doing she'd be be risking losing her other daughter as well by ending up in prison, which might have satisfied her own desire for revenge but would have been very selfish toward the younger daughter. So, the way she played things, she made sure that (a) she'd get her revenge, but (b) that she wouldn't lose anything more by doing it. So, the ending worked for me. Overall, I found this a pretty good watch. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Exactly a Shining Endorsement of Men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In many ways, Eye for an Eye is a fairly bland thriller, indistinguishable from other vigilante-style movies. In fact, it plays at times like one of those cheaply made TV movies, and yet it contains a couple of attacks on women which are quite shocking in their intensity and completely at odds with the rest of the film. Sally Field plays a typically upper-middle class working mother whose teenage daughter is brutally raped and murdered by ultra-sleazy deliveryman Kiefer Sutherland. When the American justice system lets him free on a technicality, Field resolves to take the law into her own hands. The film's basically just a variation on Death Wish, with the added frisson that the vigilante is physically the weaker party and therefore just as likely to become a victim of her target as the other way around. Field is pretty good in the role, as is Sutherland as her nemesis, even though he is portrayed as pure evil with no redeeming  or human  qualities to speak of. The guy can't even sit down without pouring his coffee over a passing dog. Given that, away from his battle with Field, Sutherland isn't given much to play with beyond a couple of scenes which provide no insight into his character  in one he's threatened by frustrated cop Joe Mantegna, and in the other he plays frenetic drums on his legs as he watches a video in his grubby hotel room  he makes quite an impression, proving he's as adept at playing irredeemable bad guys as he is clean cut heroes of the Jack Bauer variety. Ed Harris plays Field's understanding but long-suffering husband, and he's about as emasculated as a man can be in a movie. Never really knowing what's going on, regularly catching on a couple of scenes too late, he's effortlessly sent trotting off to the mountains by Field when she wants him out of the way so that she can put her revenge plan into action. I'm not sure I'd have been as understanding as him in that final scene, and it kind of makes you wonder what Harris saw in the role
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tolerable revenge thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Considering the calibre of the cast and director, Eye For An Eye is a rather low key affair. It tells a familiar story - rapist/murderer goes free through legal loophole, bereaved parent pursues vengeance/justice - and does so reasonably well. Some might think Keifer Sutherland's villain is one dimensional and overstated - I suspect not. Some might think the reactions of Sally Field and Ed Harris as parents of the murdered girl are unrealistic - the answer here must be whether they are credible, and I think they are credible possible reactions. No two people will react the same way, and none of us knows what we would do unless it happens to us (and I profoundly hope it does not happen to anyone reading this). Ultimately, though, despite decent performances and a satisfactory (though somewhat perfunctory) conclusion, the emotional intensity of the opening is not really sustained, and the film peters out in a welter of obviousness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A decent revenge film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cppguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's more interesting to review the reviews than review the movie. There's nothing technically wrong with this movie. Production values are fine. The acting is fine. Anyone rating this a 1 is an incompetent reviewer. 1-star reviews so far rant that Ed Harris ruined the movie and at the same time wonder why Super Ed was saddled with such a horrible supporting cast. Maybe reviewers should be allowed to vote 4-6 until they prove competency. Back to the movie. So far, I have yet to see a movie with Sally Field where she doesn't shine. While her movies may not be perfect, she's a superb actress. Like Tom Hanks, she generally picks winners to be in (funny they starred in at least 2 movies together). I'm also developing a liking for Joe Montegna. I see him in a lot of films and he brings a nice competency to supporting roles. Same for Ed Harris. I like Kiefer Sutherland in his various movies and he does a fine job (even if slightly over the top here) of being creepy. So let's talk film content. Revenge films are intriguing in many ways. To an extent, that concept is an easy way to develop conflict for the viewer. However, it's much harder to come up with a reason for the vengeance. "The Sting" took revenge to high art. "Eye for an Eye" is not high art, so no 10 from me for the film. A 7 will have to do. Others have compared this to the better known "Death Wish," but I think this was better produced and had better flow. Aspects of the movie are predictable, but I've seen many a good movie that was predictable. Summary: if you're scanning Netflix or Blockbuster for an unseen movie with decent action and dialog that moves at a good pace, "Eye for an Eye" isn't revenge on the level of "M," "The Sting," or "Gran Torino" but it's a decent watch... especially if you like the acting talents of Field, Sutherland, Harris and Montegna. If you like action/revenge films, pop some popcorn, curl up with someone special and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An engaging drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a mother who goes to seek justice for the brutal murder of her teenage daughter. "Eye for an Eye" is an intense drama that tells a family's grief in losing a teenage girl in the family. They all react in different ways; the father seems casual and detached on the surface, but actually has intense anger inside. The younger daughter blames herself, while the mother becomes obsessed with getting justice. The plot is good, it is engaging and well told. However, I think the title gives the whole film away, so things will happen in a certain way in order for the film to be called "Eye for an Eye".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ed harris is awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gs20
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing that spoiled the story for me and just made the whole thing implausible was ed harris and ed harris alone........i cannot imagine a father whose daughter is violently raped and murdered acting in such a blaze' or indifferent and completely detached manner.........he was absolutely blank about it and acted pretty much as if nothing unusual happened in his life.........as opposed, say, to sean penn in mystic river reacting to the same situation (outstanding believability) i have never thought much of harris' quirky and bizarre acting style until i realized he is just a terrible actor, that there is no real style to think about and this is a good example of that blankness and absence of emotion..........they would have gotten a better performance out of someone who just happened by the set. Harris' performance here, as in many of his performances was without substance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Controversial topic must drive home a point
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Says nothing, and does nothing. John Schlesinger's "Eye For an Eye" takes a very controversial topic and has nothing to say about it. The entire film appears to have no point. Films of this type cannot be effective just by telling a story. Sadly, this was a complete waste of Sally Field's enormous talent, which was on show again in this movie. The two time Oscar winner almost saved this film. The rest of the cast, including the villainous Kiefer Sutherland and Ed Harris, do little with their roles. Based upon Erica Holzer's novel. Friday, September 3, 1999 - T.V.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too manipulative and heavy handed, even for aspiring vigilantes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to start with this movie? Well, first of all I don't blame the actors in this movie for its failings. The cast is a talented bunch that I've admired elsewhere, and it's clear they are doing what the screenplay and direction tell them to do. On second thought, maybe part of the cast can be blamed - there is a brief appearance by martial arts actress Cynthia Rothrock, and if you know her, you know that any (American) movie she stars in turns out to be a turkey. I'll get serious now. The direction and screen writing of this movie, as I indicated in my summary line, are way below par. There's hardly any time with the protagonist before tragedy strikes, so we don't see how she's changed and scarred. The villain of the movie is so BAD, so EVIL, that he becomes a cartoon character instead of someone realistic that we the audience could really fear and feel genuine hatred. The second half of the movie, where Field becomes an aspiring vigilante, is sometimes laughable in showing how far she'll go. On that note, I'll leave my final thought. With the movie's heavy hand and sometimes laughable plot turns, I have to wonder if this would have worked better as a spoof of vigilante movies. Even if it had failed, I'm sure the end results would be more interesting than how the movie is now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dreadful excuse for a drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lilith Hexus
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into this film with no expectations poor or positive. I am, however, a person who does not believe Sally Field deserves her acclaim and finds her to be a good deal overrated. Is she a bad actress? Over the top, maybe, but I would not use the term 'bad'. At least not until I saw this. The film is about a woman who calls her teenage daughter from a traffic jam and, as they are talking, she hears her daughter being attacked. The girl is raped and killed. This already brings me to the first issue with the film, as well as with Sally Field's acting. For starters, there may have been an issue with hanging up the phone due to the daughter not hitting 'end' back then, I am not up to date on how cell phones worked in the mid-90's. However, why did she never attempt to hang up and call 911 on the phone in her hand? Comfort does not mean as much as life, and every second counts. There is also the fact that, other than two brief scenes, I never once felt like Sally's character cared a thing for her daughter. She never acts sad or distraught over her daughter's death, and only comes off as either indifferent or offended, as if someone had stolen property from her and given her a reason to be defensive over herself. I understand denial and hysterics, but at a certain point the family members of victims of such crimes do end up breaking down and, in nearly every case, lose track of life and shut down partially. There is even a moment when a woman tells Sally she needs to stay strong for her youngest daughter, despite the fact that she is the least upset person at the entire memorial. She seems to use her daughter's death as an excuse to be illogical, hysterical, and hateful but never once gave me a reason to feel bad for her, when I should normally be able to without much expression at all. The film's villain is also abysmal. He behaves like an overly cartoon-like fiend who lives for no reason other than to do mischief (it is bad when I can use this word accurately about a rapist/murderer in a serious drama). I was honestly waiting for him to get hold of Sally Field and tie her to the railroad tracks by the third time he laughed deviously and did another random, senseless act of naughtiness. The man rapes and kills two people for certain, as well as pours hot coffee on a dog and urinates through a woman's fence, and somehow managed to not only make none of this seem overly malicious or cruel, but almost like a child trying to get attention. Every character is unbelievable and ridiculous, except for perhaps the two victims who are seen so briefly each. The police officer defies logic at every turn and when he actually does decide to do something, it is not only at the wrong time but in a way that in most cases he would have been fired for his actions. He assaults a man who has been legally dismissed of all charges, simply on suspicion. This includes holding a gun to his head. Plenty of witnesses saw and heard the assault, and one word from any of them and he would be turning in his badge and completely useless to anyone. This may have been his true goal, though, as without such a useless officer on the force they may actually get something done. Now just to deal with the idiots handling the evidence. The finale of the film is absurd, not due to the plot but simply because of how it is delivered. At one point Sally Field has the killer at gunpoint, easily six feet away minimum, and has plenty of opportunity and logical reason, as well as every intent, to shoot and kill him. This was her plan, to kill the man while under legal conditions. Instead, she waits around for literally no reason and somehow allows him to ram his entire body into her before she can do so much as to pull the trigger once. She is then knocked down the stairs and lands on her back at the bottom, and though the gun is lying only a few inches away from her in plain sight to both of them, this for some reason did not seem threatening to the killer who idly strolls down the stairs taunting her. No shock to anyone, she grabs the gun and fires repeatedly into his torso, not missing a single time. Strangely, he seems bewildered by these events and does not understand how the woman lying only a few inches away from a loaded gun shot him while he taunted her and slowly moved in for the kill. I will not even discuss the "Vigilante Group", that is simply something you will have to see yourself, or be glad you are not aware of. Plain and simple, this film is entirely unbelievable, every attempt at inducing any sort of emotion is a miserable failure, and it will make you wish you had two hours of your life back. How so many people seemed to have liked this disturbs me. I would recommend this to only an enemy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kiefer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought Kiefer Sutherland did a wonderful job with the movie first off, his acting skills are hard to match by anyone,, how many actors today can bounce back and forth between movies and TV just like that.. Sally Field.. wow what happened to her since Coal Miner's Daughter. she did very good to in the role of the mother trying to get vengeance on her daughter being raped,, in the initial opening scene,, the teenage daughter is on the phone with mom,, and she get's raped and mom hear's the entire rape,start to finish, due to a technicality our rapist is set free, and free to rape and kill again. he starts stalking different prey this time, while our raging mother is trying to find our rapist and bring him to either justice or death.. these kind of movies have been overdone and watered down in the past 30 years. but this one seems to me to have a little more staying power.. I think that will be because of Kiefer's high profile,, 24,, and an amazing performance by Sally Field,, the Coal Miner's Daughter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Revenge Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sally Fields does a good job with this movie as a revenge seeking mother of a teenage daughter who's been raped and murdered. I suppose to make this worth watching, she has to do a good job with this. The story itself has been done over and over: seeking revenge after a violent crime because the justice system has failed. That's a pretty clich&eacute; type of situation and story, so there's not really a great deal to recommend this as far as originality is concerned. But Fields is good, and Kiefer Sutherland is appropriately creepy and threatening as the rapist/murderer. The portrayal of the rape of Karen's daughter was terrifying, but (thankfully) not especially graphic.) The same could be said for the later rape committed by Sutherland's Doob. The movie, in my opinion, also makes a fair point about the justice system leaning too far on the side of defending the rights of obviously guilty criminals at the expense of actually dispensing justice for their victims. I understand the need to protect the rights of the accused, but there does have to be a balance, and that balance is sometimes lost in the system that we have. I was kind of put off by the "group" the McCann's attended for people who had lost loved ones to violence. To each his or her own, I suppose, but I can't imagine that sitting around night after night talking about the same thing over and over and over again is really going to help anyone move on, and I wasn't convinced by the "vigilante organization" aspect of this. I have to say, though, that I did like the ending. What I was finding distasteful up to this point was that Karen was going to turn vigilante, and by so doing she'd be be risking losing her other daughter as well by ending up in prison, which might have satisfied her own desire for revenge but would have been very selfish toward the younger daughter. So, the way she played things, she made sure that (a) she'd get her revenge, but (b) that she wouldn't lose anything more by doing it. So, the ending worked for me. Overall, I found this a pretty good watch. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Exactly a Shining Endorsement of Men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In many ways, Eye for an Eye is a fairly bland thriller, indistinguishable from other vigilante-style movies. In fact, it plays at times like one of those cheaply made TV movies, and yet it contains a couple of attacks on women which are quite shocking in their intensity and completely at odds with the rest of the film. Sally Field plays a typically upper-middle class working mother whose teenage daughter is brutally raped and murdered by ultra-sleazy deliveryman Kiefer Sutherland. When the American justice system lets him free on a technicality, Field resolves to take the law into her own hands. The film's basically just a variation on Death Wish, with the added frisson that the vigilante is physically the weaker party and therefore just as likely to become a victim of her target as the other way around. Field is pretty good in the role, as is Sutherland as her nemesis, even though he is portrayed as pure evil with no redeeming  or human  qualities to speak of. The guy can't even sit down without pouring his coffee over a passing dog. Given that, away from his battle with Field, Sutherland isn't given much to play with beyond a couple of scenes which provide no insight into his character  in one he's threatened by frustrated cop Joe Mantegna, and in the other he plays frenetic drums on his legs as he watches a video in his grubby hotel room  he makes quite an impression, proving he's as adept at playing irredeemable bad guys as he is clean cut heroes of the Jack Bauer variety. Ed Harris plays Field's understanding but long-suffering husband, and he's about as emasculated as a man can be in a movie. Never really knowing what's going on, regularly catching on a couple of scenes too late, he's effortlessly sent trotting off to the mountains by Field when she wants him out of the way so that she can put her revenge plan into action. I'm not sure I'd have been as understanding as him in that final scene, and it kind of makes you wonder what Harris saw in the role
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tolerable revenge thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Considering the calibre of the cast and director, Eye For An Eye is a rather low key affair. It tells a familiar story - rapist/murderer goes free through legal loophole, bereaved parent pursues vengeance/justice - and does so reasonably well. Some might think Keifer Sutherland's villain is one dimensional and overstated - I suspect not. Some might think the reactions of Sally Field and Ed Harris as parents of the murdered girl are unrealistic - the answer here must be whether they are credible, and I think they are credible possible reactions. No two people will react the same way, and none of us knows what we would do unless it happens to us (and I profoundly hope it does not happen to anyone reading this). Ultimately, though, despite decent performances and a satisfactory (though somewhat perfunctory) conclusion, the emotional intensity of the opening is not really sustained, and the film peters out in a welter of obviousness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A decent revenge film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cppguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's more interesting to review the reviews than review the movie. There's nothing technically wrong with this movie. Production values are fine. The acting is fine. Anyone rating this a 1 is an incompetent reviewer. 1-star reviews so far rant that Ed Harris ruined the movie and at the same time wonder why Super Ed was saddled with such a horrible supporting cast. Maybe reviewers should be allowed to vote 4-6 until they prove competency. Back to the movie. So far, I have yet to see a movie with Sally Field where she doesn't shine. While her movies may not be perfect, she's a superb actress. Like Tom Hanks, she generally picks winners to be in (funny they starred in at least 2 movies together). I'm also developing a liking for Joe Montegna. I see him in a lot of films and he brings a nice competency to supporting roles. Same for Ed Harris. I like Kiefer Sutherland in his various movies and he does a fine job (even if slightly over the top here) of being creepy. So let's talk film content. Revenge films are intriguing in many ways. To an extent, that concept is an easy way to develop conflict for the viewer. However, it's much harder to come up with a reason for the vengeance. "The Sting" took revenge to high art. "Eye for an Eye" is not high art, so no 10 from me for the film. A 7 will have to do. Others have compared this to the better known "Death Wish," but I think this was better produced and had better flow. Aspects of the movie are predictable, but I've seen many a good movie that was predictable. Summary: if you're scanning Netflix or Blockbuster for an unseen movie with decent action and dialog that moves at a good pace, "Eye for an Eye" isn't revenge on the level of "M," "The Sting," or "Gran Torino" but it's a decent watch... especially if you like the acting talents of Field, Sutherland, Harris and Montegna. If you like action/revenge films, pop some popcorn, curl up with someone special and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An engaging drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a mother who goes to seek justice for the brutal murder of her teenage daughter. "Eye for an Eye" is an intense drama that tells a family's grief in losing a teenage girl in the family. They all react in different ways; the father seems casual and detached on the surface, but actually has intense anger inside. The younger daughter blames herself, while the mother becomes obsessed with getting justice. The plot is good, it is engaging and well told. However, I think the title gives the whole film away, so things will happen in a certain way in order for the film to be called "Eye for an Eye".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ed harris is awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gs20
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing that spoiled the story for me and just made the whole thing implausible was ed harris and ed harris alone........i cannot imagine a father whose daughter is violently raped and murdered acting in such a blaze' or indifferent and completely detached manner.........he was absolutely blank about it and acted pretty much as if nothing unusual happened in his life.........as opposed, say, to sean penn in mystic river reacting to the same situation (outstanding believability) i have never thought much of harris' quirky and bizarre acting style until i realized he is just a terrible actor, that there is no real style to think about and this is a good example of that blankness and absence of emotion..........they would have gotten a better performance out of someone who just happened by the set. Harris' performance here, as in many of his performances was without substance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Controversial topic must drive home a point
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Says nothing, and does nothing. John Schlesinger's "Eye For an Eye" takes a very controversial topic and has nothing to say about it. The entire film appears to have no point. Films of this type cannot be effective just by telling a story. Sadly, this was a complete waste of Sally Field's enormous talent, which was on show again in this movie. The two time Oscar winner almost saved this film. The rest of the cast, including the villainous Kiefer Sutherland and Ed Harris, do little with their roles. Based upon Erica Holzer's novel. Friday, September 3, 1999 - T.V.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too manipulative and heavy handed, even for aspiring vigilantes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to start with this movie? Well, first of all I don't blame the actors in this movie for its failings. The cast is a talented bunch that I've admired elsewhere, and it's clear they are doing what the screenplay and direction tell them to do. On second thought, maybe part of the cast can be blamed - there is a brief appearance by martial arts actress Cynthia Rothrock, and if you know her, you know that any (American) movie she stars in turns out to be a turkey. I'll get serious now. The direction and screen writing of this movie, as I indicated in my summary line, are way below par. There's hardly any time with the protagonist before tragedy strikes, so we don't see how she's changed and scarred. The villain of the movie is so BAD, so EVIL, that he becomes a cartoon character instead of someone realistic that we the audience could really fear and feel genuine hatred. The second half of the movie, where Field becomes an aspiring vigilante, is sometimes laughable in showing how far she'll go. On that note, I'll leave my final thought. With the movie's heavy hand and sometimes laughable plot turns, I have to wonder if this would have worked better as a spoof of vigilante movies. Even if it had failed, I'm sure the end results would be more interesting than how the movie is now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dreadful excuse for a drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lilith Hexus
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into this film with no expectations poor or positive. I am, however, a person who does not believe Sally Field deserves her acclaim and finds her to be a good deal overrated. Is she a bad actress? Over the top, maybe, but I would not use the term 'bad'. At least not until I saw this. The film is about a woman who calls her teenage daughter from a traffic jam and, as they are talking, she hears her daughter being attacked. The girl is raped and killed. This already brings me to the first issue with the film, as well as with Sally Field's acting. For starters, there may have been an issue with hanging up the phone due to the daughter not hitting 'end' back then, I am not up to date on how cell phones worked in the mid-90's. However, why did she never attempt to hang up and call 911 on the phone in her hand? Comfort does not mean as much as life, and every second counts. There is also the fact that, other than two brief scenes, I never once felt like Sally's character cared a thing for her daughter. She never acts sad or distraught over her daughter's death, and only comes off as either indifferent or offended, as if someone had stolen property from her and given her a reason to be defensive over herself. I understand denial and hysterics, but at a certain point the family members of victims of such crimes do end up breaking down and, in nearly every case, lose track of life and shut down partially. There is even a moment when a woman tells Sally she needs to stay strong for her youngest daughter, despite the fact that she is the least upset person at the entire memorial. She seems to use her daughter's death as an excuse to be illogical, hysterical, and hateful but never once gave me a reason to feel bad for her, when I should normally be able to without much expression at all. The film's villain is also abysmal. He behaves like an overly cartoon-like fiend who lives for no reason other than to do mischief (it is bad when I can use this word accurately about a rapist/murderer in a serious drama). I was honestly waiting for him to get hold of Sally Field and tie her to the railroad tracks by the third time he laughed deviously and did another random, senseless act of naughtiness. The man rapes and kills two people for certain, as well as pours hot coffee on a dog and urinates through a woman's fence, and somehow managed to not only make none of this seem overly malicious or cruel, but almost like a child trying to get attention. Every character is unbelievable and ridiculous, except for perhaps the two victims who are seen so briefly each. The police officer defies logic at every turn and when he actually does decide to do something, it is not only at the wrong time but in a way that in most cases he would have been fired for his actions. He assaults a man who has been legally dismissed of all charges, simply on suspicion. This includes holding a gun to his head. Plenty of witnesses saw and heard the assault, and one word from any of them and he would be turning in his badge and completely useless to anyone. This may have been his true goal, though, as without such a useless officer on the force they may actually get something done. Now just to deal with the idiots handling the evidence. The finale of the film is absurd, not due to the plot but simply because of how it is delivered. At one point Sally Field has the killer at gunpoint, easily six feet away minimum, and has plenty of opportunity and logical reason, as well as every intent, to shoot and kill him. This was her plan, to kill the man while under legal conditions. Instead, she waits around for literally no reason and somehow allows him to ram his entire body into her before she can do so much as to pull the trigger once. She is then knocked down the stairs and lands on her back at the bottom, and though the gun is lying only a few inches away from her in plain sight to both of them, this for some reason did not seem threatening to the killer who idly strolls down the stairs taunting her. No shock to anyone, she grabs the gun and fires repeatedly into his torso, not missing a single time. Strangely, he seems bewildered by these events and does not understand how the woman lying only a few inches away from a loaded gun shot him while he taunted her and slowly moved in for the kill. I will not even discuss the "Vigilante Group", that is simply something you will have to see yourself, or be glad you are not aware of. Plain and simple, this film is entirely unbelievable, every attempt at inducing any sort of emotion is a miserable failure, and it will make you wish you had two hours of your life back. How so many people seemed to have liked this disturbs me. I would recommend this to only an enemy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kiefer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought Kiefer Sutherland did a wonderful job with the movie first off, his acting skills are hard to match by anyone,, how many actors today can bounce back and forth between movies and TV just like that.. Sally Field.. wow what happened to her since Coal Miner's Daughter. she did very good to in the role of the mother trying to get vengeance on her daughter being raped,, in the initial opening scene,, the teenage daughter is on the phone with mom,, and she get's raped and mom hear's the entire rape,start to finish, due to a technicality our rapist is set free, and free to rape and kill again. he starts stalking different prey this time, while our raging mother is trying to find our rapist and bring him to either justice or death.. these kind of movies have been overdone and watered down in the past 30 years. but this one seems to me to have a little more staying power.. I think that will be because of Kiefer's high profile,, 24,, and an amazing performance by Sally Field,, the Coal Miner's Daughter.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Revenge Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sally Fields does a good job with this movie as a revenge seeking mother of a teenage daughter who's been raped and murdered. I suppose to make this worth watching, she has to do a good job with this. The story itself has been done over and over: seeking revenge after a violent crime because the justice system has failed. That's a pretty clich&eacute; type of situation and story, so there's not really a great deal to recommend this as far as originality is concerned. But Fields is good, and Kiefer Sutherland is appropriately creepy and threatening as the rapist/murderer. The portrayal of the rape of Karen's daughter was terrifying, but (thankfully) not especially graphic.) The same could be said for the later rape committed by Sutherland's Doob. The movie, in my opinion, also makes a fair point about the justice system leaning too far on the side of defending the rights of obviously guilty criminals at the expense of actually dispensing justice for their victims. I understand the need to protect the rights of the accused, but there does have to be a balance, and that balance is sometimes lost in the system that we have. I was kind of put off by the "group" the McCann's attended for people who had lost loved ones to violence. To each his or her own, I suppose, but I can't imagine that sitting around night after night talking about the same thing over and over and over again is really going to help anyone move on, and I wasn't convinced by the "vigilante organization" aspect of this. I have to say, though, that I did like the ending. What I was finding distasteful up to this point was that Karen was going to turn vigilante, and by so doing she'd be be risking losing her other daughter as well by ending up in prison, which might have satisfied her own desire for revenge but would have been very selfish toward the younger daughter. So, the way she played things, she made sure that (a) she'd get her revenge, but (b) that she wouldn't lose anything more by doing it. So, the ending worked for me. Overall, I found this a pretty good watch. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Exactly a Shining Endorsement of Men
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In many ways, Eye for an Eye is a fairly bland thriller, indistinguishable from other vigilante-style movies. In fact, it plays at times like one of those cheaply made TV movies, and yet it contains a couple of attacks on women which are quite shocking in their intensity and completely at odds with the rest of the film. Sally Field plays a typically upper-middle class working mother whose teenage daughter is brutally raped and murdered by ultra-sleazy deliveryman Kiefer Sutherland. When the American justice system lets him free on a technicality, Field resolves to take the law into her own hands. The film's basically just a variation on Death Wish, with the added frisson that the vigilante is physically the weaker party and therefore just as likely to become a victim of her target as the other way around. Field is pretty good in the role, as is Sutherland as her nemesis, even though he is portrayed as pure evil with no redeeming  or human  qualities to speak of. The guy can't even sit down without pouring his coffee over a passing dog. Given that, away from his battle with Field, Sutherland isn't given much to play with beyond a couple of scenes which provide no insight into his character  in one he's threatened by frustrated cop Joe Mantegna, and in the other he plays frenetic drums on his legs as he watches a video in his grubby hotel room  he makes quite an impression, proving he's as adept at playing irredeemable bad guys as he is clean cut heroes of the Jack Bauer variety. Ed Harris plays Field's understanding but long-suffering husband, and he's about as emasculated as a man can be in a movie. Never really knowing what's going on, regularly catching on a couple of scenes too late, he's effortlessly sent trotting off to the mountains by Field when she wants him out of the way so that she can put her revenge plan into action. I'm not sure I'd have been as understanding as him in that final scene, and it kind of makes you wonder what Harris saw in the role
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tolerable revenge thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Considering the calibre of the cast and director, Eye For An Eye is a rather low key affair. It tells a familiar story - rapist/murderer goes free through legal loophole, bereaved parent pursues vengeance/justice - and does so reasonably well. Some might think Keifer Sutherland's villain is one dimensional and overstated - I suspect not. Some might think the reactions of Sally Field and Ed Harris as parents of the murdered girl are unrealistic - the answer here must be whether they are credible, and I think they are credible possible reactions. No two people will react the same way, and none of us knows what we would do unless it happens to us (and I profoundly hope it does not happen to anyone reading this). Ultimately, though, despite decent performances and a satisfactory (though somewhat perfunctory) conclusion, the emotional intensity of the opening is not really sustained, and the film peters out in a welter of obviousness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A decent revenge film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cppguy
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes it's more interesting to review the reviews than review the movie. There's nothing technically wrong with this movie. Production values are fine. The acting is fine. Anyone rating this a 1 is an incompetent reviewer. 1-star reviews so far rant that Ed Harris ruined the movie and at the same time wonder why Super Ed was saddled with such a horrible supporting cast. Maybe reviewers should be allowed to vote 4-6 until they prove competency. Back to the movie. So far, I have yet to see a movie with Sally Field where she doesn't shine. While her movies may not be perfect, she's a superb actress. Like Tom Hanks, she generally picks winners to be in (funny they starred in at least 2 movies together). I'm also developing a liking for Joe Montegna. I see him in a lot of films and he brings a nice competency to supporting roles. Same for Ed Harris. I like Kiefer Sutherland in his various movies and he does a fine job (even if slightly over the top here) of being creepy. So let's talk film content. Revenge films are intriguing in many ways. To an extent, that concept is an easy way to develop conflict for the viewer. However, it's much harder to come up with a reason for the vengeance. "The Sting" took revenge to high art. "Eye for an Eye" is not high art, so no 10 from me for the film. A 7 will have to do. Others have compared this to the better known "Death Wish," but I think this was better produced and had better flow. Aspects of the movie are predictable, but I've seen many a good movie that was predictable. Summary: if you're scanning Netflix or Blockbuster for an unseen movie with decent action and dialog that moves at a good pace, "Eye for an Eye" isn't revenge on the level of "M," "The Sting," or "Gran Torino" but it's a decent watch... especially if you like the acting talents of Field, Sutherland, Harris and Montegna. If you like action/revenge films, pop some popcorn, curl up with someone special and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An engaging drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about a mother who goes to seek justice for the brutal murder of her teenage daughter. "Eye for an Eye" is an intense drama that tells a family's grief in losing a teenage girl in the family. They all react in different ways; the father seems casual and detached on the surface, but actually has intense anger inside. The younger daughter blames herself, while the mother becomes obsessed with getting justice. The plot is good, it is engaging and well told. However, I think the title gives the whole film away, so things will happen in a certain way in order for the film to be called "Eye for an Eye".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ed harris is awful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gs20
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The thing that spoiled the story for me and just made the whole thing implausible was ed harris and ed harris alone........i cannot imagine a father whose daughter is violently raped and murdered acting in such a blaze' or indifferent and completely detached manner.........he was absolutely blank about it and acted pretty much as if nothing unusual happened in his life.........as opposed, say, to sean penn in mystic river reacting to the same situation (outstanding believability) i have never thought much of harris' quirky and bizarre acting style until i realized he is just a terrible actor, that there is no real style to think about and this is a good example of that blankness and absence of emotion..........they would have gotten a better performance out of someone who just happened by the set. Harris' performance here, as in many of his performances was without substance.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Controversial topic must drive home a point
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Says nothing, and does nothing. John Schlesinger's "Eye For an Eye" takes a very controversial topic and has nothing to say about it. The entire film appears to have no point. Films of this type cannot be effective just by telling a story. Sadly, this was a complete waste of Sally Field's enormous talent, which was on show again in this movie. The two time Oscar winner almost saved this film. The rest of the cast, including the villainous Kiefer Sutherland and Ed Harris, do little with their roles. Based upon Erica Holzer's novel. Friday, September 3, 1999 - T.V.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Too manipulative and heavy handed, even for aspiring vigilantes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wizard-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where to start with this movie? Well, first of all I don't blame the actors in this movie for its failings. The cast is a talented bunch that I've admired elsewhere, and it's clear they are doing what the screenplay and direction tell them to do. On second thought, maybe part of the cast can be blamed - there is a brief appearance by martial arts actress Cynthia Rothrock, and if you know her, you know that any (American) movie she stars in turns out to be a turkey. I'll get serious now. The direction and screen writing of this movie, as I indicated in my summary line, are way below par. There's hardly any time with the protagonist before tragedy strikes, so we don't see how she's changed and scarred. The villain of the movie is so BAD, so EVIL, that he becomes a cartoon character instead of someone realistic that we the audience could really fear and feel genuine hatred. The second half of the movie, where Field becomes an aspiring vigilante, is sometimes laughable in showing how far she'll go. On that note, I'll leave my final thought. With the movie's heavy hand and sometimes laughable plot turns, I have to wonder if this would have worked better as a spoof of vigilante movies. Even if it had failed, I'm sure the end results would be more interesting than how the movie is now.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dreadful excuse for a drama
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lilith Hexus
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into this film with no expectations poor or positive. I am, however, a person who does not believe Sally Field deserves her acclaim and finds her to be a good deal overrated. Is she a bad actress? Over the top, maybe, but I would not use the term 'bad'. At least not until I saw this. The film is about a woman who calls her teenage daughter from a traffic jam and, as they are talking, she hears her daughter being attacked. The girl is raped and killed. This already brings me to the first issue with the film, as well as with Sally Field's acting. For starters, there may have been an issue with hanging up the phone due to the daughter not hitting 'end' back then, I am not up to date on how cell phones worked in the mid-90's. However, why did she never attempt to hang up and call 911 on the phone in her hand? Comfort does not mean as much as life, and every second counts. There is also the fact that, other than two brief scenes, I never once felt like Sally's character cared a thing for her daughter. She never acts sad or distraught over her daughter's death, and only comes off as either indifferent or offended, as if someone had stolen property from her and given her a reason to be defensive over herself. I understand denial and hysterics, but at a certain point the family members of victims of such crimes do end up breaking down and, in nearly every case, lose track of life and shut down partially. There is even a moment when a woman tells Sally she needs to stay strong for her youngest daughter, despite the fact that she is the least upset person at the entire memorial. She seems to use her daughter's death as an excuse to be illogical, hysterical, and hateful but never once gave me a reason to feel bad for her, when I should normally be able to without much expression at all. The film's villain is also abysmal. He behaves like an overly cartoon-like fiend who lives for no reason other than to do mischief (it is bad when I can use this word accurately about a rapist/murderer in a serious drama). I was honestly waiting for him to get hold of Sally Field and tie her to the railroad tracks by the third time he laughed deviously and did another random, senseless act of naughtiness. The man rapes and kills two people for certain, as well as pours hot coffee on a dog and urinates through a woman's fence, and somehow managed to not only make none of this seem overly malicious or cruel, but almost like a child trying to get attention. Every character is unbelievable and ridiculous, except for perhaps the two victims who are seen so briefly each. The police officer defies logic at every turn and when he actually does decide to do something, it is not only at the wrong time but in a way that in most cases he would have been fired for his actions. He assaults a man who has been legally dismissed of all charges, simply on suspicion. This includes holding a gun to his head. Plenty of witnesses saw and heard the assault, and one word from any of them and he would be turning in his badge and completely useless to anyone. This may have been his true goal, though, as without such a useless officer on the force they may actually get something done. Now just to deal with the idiots handling the evidence. The finale of the film is absurd, not due to the plot but simply because of how it is delivered. At one point Sally Field has the killer at gunpoint, easily six feet away minimum, and has plenty of opportunity and logical reason, as well as every intent, to shoot and kill him. This was her plan, to kill the man while under legal conditions. Instead, she waits around for literally no reason and somehow allows him to ram his entire body into her before she can do so much as to pull the trigger once. She is then knocked down the stairs and lands on her back at the bottom, and though the gun is lying only a few inches away from her in plain sight to both of them, this for some reason did not seem threatening to the killer who idly strolls down the stairs taunting her. No shock to anyone, she grabs the gun and fires repeatedly into his torso, not missing a single time. Strangely, he seems bewildered by these events and does not understand how the woman lying only a few inches away from a loaded gun shot him while he taunted her and slowly moved in for the kill. I will not even discuss the "Vigilante Group", that is simply something you will have to see yourself, or be glad you are not aware of. Plain and simple, this film is entirely unbelievable, every attempt at inducing any sort of emotion is a miserable failure, and it will make you wish you had two hours of your life back. How so many people seemed to have liked this disturbs me. I would recommend this to only an enemy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
