<filme>
 <id>
  98
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0102926
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1991
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Sil&ecirc;ncio dos Inocentes
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A young F.B.I. cadet must confide in an incarcerated and manipulative killer to receive his help on catching another serial killer who skins his victims.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Young FBI agent Clarice Starling is assigned to help find a missing woman to save her from a psychopathic serial killer who skins his victims. Clarice attempts to gain a better insight into the twisted mind of the killer by talking to another psychopath Hannibal Lecter, who used to be a respected psychiatrist. FBI agent Jack Crawford believes that Lecter, who is also a very powerful and clever mind manipulator, has the answers to their questions and can help locate the killer. However, Clarice must first gain Lecter's confidence before the inmate will give away any information.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   fbi
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   serial killer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   psychiatrist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   agent
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   psychopath
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jonathan Demme
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Thomas Harris
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Ted Tally
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jodie Foster
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Anthony Hopkins
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lawrence A. Bonney
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Acting In This One!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Thomas Harris novel, film follows the efforts of FBI cadet Clarice Starling(Jodie Foster, in an Academy Award winning performance) to catch a serial killer known as Buffalo Bill, who kidnaps and murders his victims. She contacts incarcerated(and legendary) serial killer Hannibal Lecter(Anthony Hopkins, in an unforgettable, brilliant Academy Award winning performance) who taunts Clarice, yet finds himself impressed by her determination and mysterious background, which he intends to take full advantage of, leading to a dramatic(and lethal) escape... Supremely well acted and well crafted horror tale is quite suspenseful and compelling as well, though is a bit over the top at times, this is still excellent. Also won Academy Awards for Best Picture and director(Jonathan Demme).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silence of the lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gabriellerawrr
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this multiple Oscar-winning thriller, Jodie Foster stars as Clarice Starling, a top student at the FBI's training academy whose shrewd analyses of serial killers lands her a special assignment: the FBI is investigating a vicious murderer nicknamed Buffalo Bill, who kills young women and then removes the skin from their bodies. Jack Crawford (Scott Glenn) wants Clarice to interview Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins), a brilliant psychiatrist who is also a violent psychopath, serving life behind bars for various acts of murder and cannibalism. Crawford believes that Lecter may have insight into this case and that Starling, as an attractive young woman, may be just the bait to draw him out. Lecter does indeed know something of Buffalo Bill, but his information comes with a price: in exchange for telling what he knows, he wants to be housed in a more comfortable facility. More important, he wants to speak with Clarice about her past. He skillfully digs into her psyche, forcing her to reveal her innermost traumas and putting her in a position of vulnerability when she can least afford to be weak. The film mingles the horrors of criminal acts with the psychological horrors of Lecter's slow-motion interrogation of Clarice and of her memories that emerge from it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST Horror movie that will stay a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joanna Hernandez
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The whole movie is about an innocent female character that steps into the world of men and into the world of terror.This movie has the perfect amount of everything every movie needs but some don't have.They have the frightening scenes,they have the sad part behind the life of the strongest bravest character,they have the right amount of suspense they definitely knew what they were doing.It all ties together the way it should. This movie keeps you drawn in during the full 118 min.There is never a moment where you will want to get up to refill your popcorn bowl or even go to use the bathroom.Every horror movie has those scenes that get too horrific but with this movie the horror is what makes want to keep watching.This is definitely the best of the best.I would definitely recommend this movie to everyone because this is the perfect movie for anyone any night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wolfkilla14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest thing about lambs is that something new is discovered each time you view it. As with all psychological films, it takes multiple views to absorb the full plot and ingest the actual meaning behind the film. The dynamic between Clarice and Hannibal is possibly one of the best acting duos in history, and if you pay attention you can pick up things between the two of them that you miss during the first viewing. Each character has layers and layers to them, they are complex and difficult to understand, which is what makes this movie so incredible. A director wants his movie to be viewed over and over, and if you can;t do that with a film its too simple to be watched. Lams executes this perfectly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The collision between first impression and true identity in Silence of the Lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    livstrongeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Finally the time came and I decided to watch all of the Hannibal movies (because after the end of Hannibal's season 1 I was left with a void that only Hannibal Lecter could fill up). So I started with the famous Silence of the Lamb. If you are familiar with this movie, you probably know the plot: FBI agent Clarise Starling plaeyd by Jodie Foster needs the help of an incarcerated prisoner Hannibal Lecter played by Anthony Hopkins to catch a serial killer on the loose. So what was most interesting for me is that people aren't what they seem from the first impression. Yes, we see Clarise training but that is because she is the character with whom we are growing together, the main character. She is running through the forest what might be a metaphor that she is trying to defeat evil as forest always was a gloomy and scary place where monsters were hiding. But that is not how she is viewed by others. There are various scenes where she is the only woman in male company and everybody is looking at her as if she is not capable of anything, but she proves them wrong. On the other hand we see Hannibal as a calm person standing in his cell. You could not tell that this person is a heartless murderer who eats his victims. But that's what everybody knows about him. And that is why he is in the cell. Later we see his change when he attacks the guards, but I think more important is his entrance scene. It is just radiating with innocence, but you still have this feeling that something is wrong. Maybe it's not the cell, but most probably it's how he looks, how he smiles. But that you notice just a bit later. So that's what I saw in this movie  the difference between first impression and true people's nature. It's a bit scary how wrong can we sometimes be. Maybe next time we will regard the innocent looking person with more care.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hannibal will always be Hannibal...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie in which a young FBI agent Clarice Starling (Jodie Foster) tries to get some information from Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins) who is a psychopath and used to be a respected psychiatrist, for a psychopathic serial killer who skins his victims. To get these information Clarice Starling has to gain the respect and the trust of Dr.Hannibal Lecter. When I saw this movie I thought that Anthony Hopkins is really not OK in his minds for real and that's because of his perfect interpretation. I also think that Jodie Foster made an also perfect interpretation. Τhese were seen and in the Academy Awards where Anthony Hopkins and Jodie Foster won the Oscars for Best Actor in a Leading Role and for Best Actress in a Leading Role respectively. Jonathan Demme's work in the direction of this film did not go unnoticed and he also won the Oscar for Best Director. "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie that you have to see it, it's a really good Thriller and Crime movie with many good scenes and an exceptional screenplay.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    silence of the lambs : movie gold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mastersahk
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film will always be known as one of the greats in the horror/thriller genre for its dramatic posture when presenting such a risky film. Anthony Hopkins performance was magnificent every word and every turn he made. Jodie foster's character brought a real sense of belief with her acting and also brought a real sense of fear towards the films story. this movie was pure movie genius capturing pure technique towards the story and the acting. Jodie and Anthony should be praised for their wonderful performances as these two characters and also by the way that they express the characters emotions towards the films story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest Movies ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to think that this film was just sick. But now I've watched it, I can appreciate how thrilling and brilliant this movie is. If it wasn't for Anthony Hopkins performance as Dr. Hannibal Lector I would have rated this movie 7/10. What a stunning performance, I was amazed by how the role of the psychopathic Hannibal Lector was filled perfectly by Anthony and it couldn't have been done ant better. It is a great storyline based on the novel by Thomas Harris, and I haven't mentioned Jodie Foster's Oscar winning performance as rookie FBI agent Clarice Starling, but let's face it, Jodie Foster's performance is good but it was overwhelmed by Anthony's performance. But still two good Oscar winning performances and good acting from the rest of the cast especially Ted Levine's role as Jame Gump (Buffalo Bill). This legendary movie swept the main five Oscar's which were: Best Picture, Best Actor, Best Actress, Best Director and Best Screenplay. The soundtrack of this movie also made the movie what it is. The soundtrack made it more dramatic and dark. As in many scenes the music increased the darkness and pure horror of this legendary thriller. Overall the Silence is one of my all time favorite's, deserved it's five Oscars, amazing acting and of course the best performance I've ever seen by Anthony Hopkins and deserves to be #23 in the top 250. A must watch but I must warn you that it is one of the most thrilling movies ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unremarkable. Why the Oscars?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lawrence Archibald von Austerlitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always wanted to see Silence of the Lambs and finally got to today. I thought that Hannibal Lector sounded like a really cool character and of course I anticipated excellent film-making with the sort of praise it has received. I saw it, and I would say that as far as movies like this go, it is excellent. But for cinema in general, Silence is unremarkable and, really, given the hype and awards, ultimately disappointing. Jodie Foster was good, but she is haunted by the slaughter of a lamb from her childhood? Ridiculous. Anthony Hopkins was great. I think he deserved his award, though his performance is overrated. Not exactly a very complex or hard to portray character... The story was not particularly exciting. It was fairly clumsy and failed to capture my attention. I was repelled by Buffalo Bill but not interested in his character whatsoever. I watched the movie for the rare encounters with Hannibal Lector, and the search for Buffalo Bill was an uninteresting but necessary backdrop. Also, how on Earth would the FBI bring a SWAT team to a house that is a false tip, that is hundreds of miles away from the killings...? It makes no sense - they completely ignored the evidence and conclusions they had already made. And so, when the so-called thrilling doorbell scene took place, I was not surprised. Of course he's not in Chicago. Ridiculous. I can honestly say I enjoyed Lector's escape. It was clever and suspenseful (if a bit illogical) and to some degree makes the movie. And is this movie scary, as has been said? No. Definitely not. The serial killer is creepy, not terrifying. Hannibal is intriguing, but not too scary. I've heard of people not sleeping for days, others having horrific nightmares... I don't understand it. This movie is worth watching if you like thrillers/serial killer/ kind of movies, but if you go into this film expecting a great piece of cinema, some groundbreaking technique or idea, or a thrilling scene or two as I did, you will be disappointed. A good movie, yes. 23rd on IMDb Top 250? Absolutely not. An 8.7 on IMDb? No.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Acting In This One!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Thomas Harris novel, film follows the efforts of FBI cadet Clarice Starling(Jodie Foster, in an Academy Award winning performance) to catch a serial killer known as Buffalo Bill, who kidnaps and murders his victims. She contacts incarcerated(and legendary) serial killer Hannibal Lecter(Anthony Hopkins, in an unforgettable, brilliant Academy Award winning performance) who taunts Clarice, yet finds himself impressed by her determination and mysterious background, which he intends to take full advantage of, leading to a dramatic(and lethal) escape... Supremely well acted and well crafted horror tale is quite suspenseful and compelling as well, though is a bit over the top at times, this is still excellent. Also won Academy Awards for Best Picture and director(Jonathan Demme).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silence of the lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gabriellerawrr
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this multiple Oscar-winning thriller, Jodie Foster stars as Clarice Starling, a top student at the FBI's training academy whose shrewd analyses of serial killers lands her a special assignment: the FBI is investigating a vicious murderer nicknamed Buffalo Bill, who kills young women and then removes the skin from their bodies. Jack Crawford (Scott Glenn) wants Clarice to interview Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins), a brilliant psychiatrist who is also a violent psychopath, serving life behind bars for various acts of murder and cannibalism. Crawford believes that Lecter may have insight into this case and that Starling, as an attractive young woman, may be just the bait to draw him out. Lecter does indeed know something of Buffalo Bill, but his information comes with a price: in exchange for telling what he knows, he wants to be housed in a more comfortable facility. More important, he wants to speak with Clarice about her past. He skillfully digs into her psyche, forcing her to reveal her innermost traumas and putting her in a position of vulnerability when she can least afford to be weak. The film mingles the horrors of criminal acts with the psychological horrors of Lecter's slow-motion interrogation of Clarice and of her memories that emerge from it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST Horror movie that will stay a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joanna Hernandez
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The whole movie is about an innocent female character that steps into the world of men and into the world of terror.This movie has the perfect amount of everything every movie needs but some don't have.They have the frightening scenes,they have the sad part behind the life of the strongest bravest character,they have the right amount of suspense they definitely knew what they were doing.It all ties together the way it should. This movie keeps you drawn in during the full 118 min.There is never a moment where you will want to get up to refill your popcorn bowl or even go to use the bathroom.Every horror movie has those scenes that get too horrific but with this movie the horror is what makes want to keep watching.This is definitely the best of the best.I would definitely recommend this movie to everyone because this is the perfect movie for anyone any night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wolfkilla14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest thing about lambs is that something new is discovered each time you view it. As with all psychological films, it takes multiple views to absorb the full plot and ingest the actual meaning behind the film. The dynamic between Clarice and Hannibal is possibly one of the best acting duos in history, and if you pay attention you can pick up things between the two of them that you miss during the first viewing. Each character has layers and layers to them, they are complex and difficult to understand, which is what makes this movie so incredible. A director wants his movie to be viewed over and over, and if you can;t do that with a film its too simple to be watched. Lams executes this perfectly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The collision between first impression and true identity in Silence of the Lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    livstrongeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Finally the time came and I decided to watch all of the Hannibal movies (because after the end of Hannibal's season 1 I was left with a void that only Hannibal Lecter could fill up). So I started with the famous Silence of the Lamb. If you are familiar with this movie, you probably know the plot: FBI agent Clarise Starling plaeyd by Jodie Foster needs the help of an incarcerated prisoner Hannibal Lecter played by Anthony Hopkins to catch a serial killer on the loose. So what was most interesting for me is that people aren't what they seem from the first impression. Yes, we see Clarise training but that is because she is the character with whom we are growing together, the main character. She is running through the forest what might be a metaphor that she is trying to defeat evil as forest always was a gloomy and scary place where monsters were hiding. But that is not how she is viewed by others. There are various scenes where she is the only woman in male company and everybody is looking at her as if she is not capable of anything, but she proves them wrong. On the other hand we see Hannibal as a calm person standing in his cell. You could not tell that this person is a heartless murderer who eats his victims. But that's what everybody knows about him. And that is why he is in the cell. Later we see his change when he attacks the guards, but I think more important is his entrance scene. It is just radiating with innocence, but you still have this feeling that something is wrong. Maybe it's not the cell, but most probably it's how he looks, how he smiles. But that you notice just a bit later. So that's what I saw in this movie  the difference between first impression and true people's nature. It's a bit scary how wrong can we sometimes be. Maybe next time we will regard the innocent looking person with more care.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hannibal will always be Hannibal...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie in which a young FBI agent Clarice Starling (Jodie Foster) tries to get some information from Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins) who is a psychopath and used to be a respected psychiatrist, for a psychopathic serial killer who skins his victims. To get these information Clarice Starling has to gain the respect and the trust of Dr.Hannibal Lecter. When I saw this movie I thought that Anthony Hopkins is really not OK in his minds for real and that's because of his perfect interpretation. I also think that Jodie Foster made an also perfect interpretation. Τhese were seen and in the Academy Awards where Anthony Hopkins and Jodie Foster won the Oscars for Best Actor in a Leading Role and for Best Actress in a Leading Role respectively. Jonathan Demme's work in the direction of this film did not go unnoticed and he also won the Oscar for Best Director. "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie that you have to see it, it's a really good Thriller and Crime movie with many good scenes and an exceptional screenplay.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    silence of the lambs : movie gold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mastersahk
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film will always be known as one of the greats in the horror/thriller genre for its dramatic posture when presenting such a risky film. Anthony Hopkins performance was magnificent every word and every turn he made. Jodie foster's character brought a real sense of belief with her acting and also brought a real sense of fear towards the films story. this movie was pure movie genius capturing pure technique towards the story and the acting. Jodie and Anthony should be praised for their wonderful performances as these two characters and also by the way that they express the characters emotions towards the films story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest Movies ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to think that this film was just sick. But now I've watched it, I can appreciate how thrilling and brilliant this movie is. If it wasn't for Anthony Hopkins performance as Dr. Hannibal Lector I would have rated this movie 7/10. What a stunning performance, I was amazed by how the role of the psychopathic Hannibal Lector was filled perfectly by Anthony and it couldn't have been done ant better. It is a great storyline based on the novel by Thomas Harris, and I haven't mentioned Jodie Foster's Oscar winning performance as rookie FBI agent Clarice Starling, but let's face it, Jodie Foster's performance is good but it was overwhelmed by Anthony's performance. But still two good Oscar winning performances and good acting from the rest of the cast especially Ted Levine's role as Jame Gump (Buffalo Bill). This legendary movie swept the main five Oscar's which were: Best Picture, Best Actor, Best Actress, Best Director and Best Screenplay. The soundtrack of this movie also made the movie what it is. The soundtrack made it more dramatic and dark. As in many scenes the music increased the darkness and pure horror of this legendary thriller. Overall the Silence is one of my all time favorite's, deserved it's five Oscars, amazing acting and of course the best performance I've ever seen by Anthony Hopkins and deserves to be #23 in the top 250. A must watch but I must warn you that it is one of the most thrilling movies ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unremarkable. Why the Oscars?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lawrence Archibald von Austerlitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always wanted to see Silence of the Lambs and finally got to today. I thought that Hannibal Lector sounded like a really cool character and of course I anticipated excellent film-making with the sort of praise it has received. I saw it, and I would say that as far as movies like this go, it is excellent. But for cinema in general, Silence is unremarkable and, really, given the hype and awards, ultimately disappointing. Jodie Foster was good, but she is haunted by the slaughter of a lamb from her childhood? Ridiculous. Anthony Hopkins was great. I think he deserved his award, though his performance is overrated. Not exactly a very complex or hard to portray character... The story was not particularly exciting. It was fairly clumsy and failed to capture my attention. I was repelled by Buffalo Bill but not interested in his character whatsoever. I watched the movie for the rare encounters with Hannibal Lector, and the search for Buffalo Bill was an uninteresting but necessary backdrop. Also, how on Earth would the FBI bring a SWAT team to a house that is a false tip, that is hundreds of miles away from the killings...? It makes no sense - they completely ignored the evidence and conclusions they had already made. And so, when the so-called thrilling doorbell scene took place, I was not surprised. Of course he's not in Chicago. Ridiculous. I can honestly say I enjoyed Lector's escape. It was clever and suspenseful (if a bit illogical) and to some degree makes the movie. And is this movie scary, as has been said? No. Definitely not. The serial killer is creepy, not terrifying. Hannibal is intriguing, but not too scary. I've heard of people not sleeping for days, others having horrific nightmares... I don't understand it. This movie is worth watching if you like thrillers/serial killer/ kind of movies, but if you go into this film expecting a great piece of cinema, some groundbreaking technique or idea, or a thrilling scene or two as I did, you will be disappointed. A good movie, yes. 23rd on IMDb Top 250? Absolutely not. An 8.7 on IMDb? No.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Acting In This One!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Thomas Harris novel, film follows the efforts of FBI cadet Clarice Starling(Jodie Foster, in an Academy Award winning performance) to catch a serial killer known as Buffalo Bill, who kidnaps and murders his victims. She contacts incarcerated(and legendary) serial killer Hannibal Lecter(Anthony Hopkins, in an unforgettable, brilliant Academy Award winning performance) who taunts Clarice, yet finds himself impressed by her determination and mysterious background, which he intends to take full advantage of, leading to a dramatic(and lethal) escape... Supremely well acted and well crafted horror tale is quite suspenseful and compelling as well, though is a bit over the top at times, this is still excellent. Also won Academy Awards for Best Picture and director(Jonathan Demme).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silence of the lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gabriellerawrr
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this multiple Oscar-winning thriller, Jodie Foster stars as Clarice Starling, a top student at the FBI's training academy whose shrewd analyses of serial killers lands her a special assignment: the FBI is investigating a vicious murderer nicknamed Buffalo Bill, who kills young women and then removes the skin from their bodies. Jack Crawford (Scott Glenn) wants Clarice to interview Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins), a brilliant psychiatrist who is also a violent psychopath, serving life behind bars for various acts of murder and cannibalism. Crawford believes that Lecter may have insight into this case and that Starling, as an attractive young woman, may be just the bait to draw him out. Lecter does indeed know something of Buffalo Bill, but his information comes with a price: in exchange for telling what he knows, he wants to be housed in a more comfortable facility. More important, he wants to speak with Clarice about her past. He skillfully digs into her psyche, forcing her to reveal her innermost traumas and putting her in a position of vulnerability when she can least afford to be weak. The film mingles the horrors of criminal acts with the psychological horrors of Lecter's slow-motion interrogation of Clarice and of her memories that emerge from it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST Horror movie that will stay a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joanna Hernandez
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The whole movie is about an innocent female character that steps into the world of men and into the world of terror.This movie has the perfect amount of everything every movie needs but some don't have.They have the frightening scenes,they have the sad part behind the life of the strongest bravest character,they have the right amount of suspense they definitely knew what they were doing.It all ties together the way it should. This movie keeps you drawn in during the full 118 min.There is never a moment where you will want to get up to refill your popcorn bowl or even go to use the bathroom.Every horror movie has those scenes that get too horrific but with this movie the horror is what makes want to keep watching.This is definitely the best of the best.I would definitely recommend this movie to everyone because this is the perfect movie for anyone any night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wolfkilla14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest thing about lambs is that something new is discovered each time you view it. As with all psychological films, it takes multiple views to absorb the full plot and ingest the actual meaning behind the film. The dynamic between Clarice and Hannibal is possibly one of the best acting duos in history, and if you pay attention you can pick up things between the two of them that you miss during the first viewing. Each character has layers and layers to them, they are complex and difficult to understand, which is what makes this movie so incredible. A director wants his movie to be viewed over and over, and if you can;t do that with a film its too simple to be watched. Lams executes this perfectly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The collision between first impression and true identity in Silence of the Lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    livstrongeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Finally the time came and I decided to watch all of the Hannibal movies (because after the end of Hannibal's season 1 I was left with a void that only Hannibal Lecter could fill up). So I started with the famous Silence of the Lamb. If you are familiar with this movie, you probably know the plot: FBI agent Clarise Starling plaeyd by Jodie Foster needs the help of an incarcerated prisoner Hannibal Lecter played by Anthony Hopkins to catch a serial killer on the loose. So what was most interesting for me is that people aren't what they seem from the first impression. Yes, we see Clarise training but that is because she is the character with whom we are growing together, the main character. She is running through the forest what might be a metaphor that she is trying to defeat evil as forest always was a gloomy and scary place where monsters were hiding. But that is not how she is viewed by others. There are various scenes where she is the only woman in male company and everybody is looking at her as if she is not capable of anything, but she proves them wrong. On the other hand we see Hannibal as a calm person standing in his cell. You could not tell that this person is a heartless murderer who eats his victims. But that's what everybody knows about him. And that is why he is in the cell. Later we see his change when he attacks the guards, but I think more important is his entrance scene. It is just radiating with innocence, but you still have this feeling that something is wrong. Maybe it's not the cell, but most probably it's how he looks, how he smiles. But that you notice just a bit later. So that's what I saw in this movie  the difference between first impression and true people's nature. It's a bit scary how wrong can we sometimes be. Maybe next time we will regard the innocent looking person with more care.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hannibal will always be Hannibal...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie in which a young FBI agent Clarice Starling (Jodie Foster) tries to get some information from Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins) who is a psychopath and used to be a respected psychiatrist, for a psychopathic serial killer who skins his victims. To get these information Clarice Starling has to gain the respect and the trust of Dr.Hannibal Lecter. When I saw this movie I thought that Anthony Hopkins is really not OK in his minds for real and that's because of his perfect interpretation. I also think that Jodie Foster made an also perfect interpretation. Τhese were seen and in the Academy Awards where Anthony Hopkins and Jodie Foster won the Oscars for Best Actor in a Leading Role and for Best Actress in a Leading Role respectively. Jonathan Demme's work in the direction of this film did not go unnoticed and he also won the Oscar for Best Director. "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie that you have to see it, it's a really good Thriller and Crime movie with many good scenes and an exceptional screenplay.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    silence of the lambs : movie gold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mastersahk
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film will always be known as one of the greats in the horror/thriller genre for its dramatic posture when presenting such a risky film. Anthony Hopkins performance was magnificent every word and every turn he made. Jodie foster's character brought a real sense of belief with her acting and also brought a real sense of fear towards the films story. this movie was pure movie genius capturing pure technique towards the story and the acting. Jodie and Anthony should be praised for their wonderful performances as these two characters and also by the way that they express the characters emotions towards the films story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest Movies ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to think that this film was just sick. But now I've watched it, I can appreciate how thrilling and brilliant this movie is. If it wasn't for Anthony Hopkins performance as Dr. Hannibal Lector I would have rated this movie 7/10. What a stunning performance, I was amazed by how the role of the psychopathic Hannibal Lector was filled perfectly by Anthony and it couldn't have been done ant better. It is a great storyline based on the novel by Thomas Harris, and I haven't mentioned Jodie Foster's Oscar winning performance as rookie FBI agent Clarice Starling, but let's face it, Jodie Foster's performance is good but it was overwhelmed by Anthony's performance. But still two good Oscar winning performances and good acting from the rest of the cast especially Ted Levine's role as Jame Gump (Buffalo Bill). This legendary movie swept the main five Oscar's which were: Best Picture, Best Actor, Best Actress, Best Director and Best Screenplay. The soundtrack of this movie also made the movie what it is. The soundtrack made it more dramatic and dark. As in many scenes the music increased the darkness and pure horror of this legendary thriller. Overall the Silence is one of my all time favorite's, deserved it's five Oscars, amazing acting and of course the best performance I've ever seen by Anthony Hopkins and deserves to be #23 in the top 250. A must watch but I must warn you that it is one of the most thrilling movies ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unremarkable. Why the Oscars?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lawrence Archibald von Austerlitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always wanted to see Silence of the Lambs and finally got to today. I thought that Hannibal Lector sounded like a really cool character and of course I anticipated excellent film-making with the sort of praise it has received. I saw it, and I would say that as far as movies like this go, it is excellent. But for cinema in general, Silence is unremarkable and, really, given the hype and awards, ultimately disappointing. Jodie Foster was good, but she is haunted by the slaughter of a lamb from her childhood? Ridiculous. Anthony Hopkins was great. I think he deserved his award, though his performance is overrated. Not exactly a very complex or hard to portray character... The story was not particularly exciting. It was fairly clumsy and failed to capture my attention. I was repelled by Buffalo Bill but not interested in his character whatsoever. I watched the movie for the rare encounters with Hannibal Lector, and the search for Buffalo Bill was an uninteresting but necessary backdrop. Also, how on Earth would the FBI bring a SWAT team to a house that is a false tip, that is hundreds of miles away from the killings...? It makes no sense - they completely ignored the evidence and conclusions they had already made. And so, when the so-called thrilling doorbell scene took place, I was not surprised. Of course he's not in Chicago. Ridiculous. I can honestly say I enjoyed Lector's escape. It was clever and suspenseful (if a bit illogical) and to some degree makes the movie. And is this movie scary, as has been said? No. Definitely not. The serial killer is creepy, not terrifying. Hannibal is intriguing, but not too scary. I've heard of people not sleeping for days, others having horrific nightmares... I don't understand it. This movie is worth watching if you like thrillers/serial killer/ kind of movies, but if you go into this film expecting a great piece of cinema, some groundbreaking technique or idea, or a thrilling scene or two as I did, you will be disappointed. A good movie, yes. 23rd on IMDb Top 250? Absolutely not. An 8.7 on IMDb? No.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Acting In This One!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Thomas Harris novel, film follows the efforts of FBI cadet Clarice Starling(Jodie Foster, in an Academy Award winning performance) to catch a serial killer known as Buffalo Bill, who kidnaps and murders his victims. She contacts incarcerated(and legendary) serial killer Hannibal Lecter(Anthony Hopkins, in an unforgettable, brilliant Academy Award winning performance) who taunts Clarice, yet finds himself impressed by her determination and mysterious background, which he intends to take full advantage of, leading to a dramatic(and lethal) escape... Supremely well acted and well crafted horror tale is quite suspenseful and compelling as well, though is a bit over the top at times, this is still excellent. Also won Academy Awards for Best Picture and director(Jonathan Demme).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silence of the lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gabriellerawrr
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this multiple Oscar-winning thriller, Jodie Foster stars as Clarice Starling, a top student at the FBI's training academy whose shrewd analyses of serial killers lands her a special assignment: the FBI is investigating a vicious murderer nicknamed Buffalo Bill, who kills young women and then removes the skin from their bodies. Jack Crawford (Scott Glenn) wants Clarice to interview Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins), a brilliant psychiatrist who is also a violent psychopath, serving life behind bars for various acts of murder and cannibalism. Crawford believes that Lecter may have insight into this case and that Starling, as an attractive young woman, may be just the bait to draw him out. Lecter does indeed know something of Buffalo Bill, but his information comes with a price: in exchange for telling what he knows, he wants to be housed in a more comfortable facility. More important, he wants to speak with Clarice about her past. He skillfully digs into her psyche, forcing her to reveal her innermost traumas and putting her in a position of vulnerability when she can least afford to be weak. The film mingles the horrors of criminal acts with the psychological horrors of Lecter's slow-motion interrogation of Clarice and of her memories that emerge from it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST Horror movie that will stay a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joanna Hernandez
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The whole movie is about an innocent female character that steps into the world of men and into the world of terror.This movie has the perfect amount of everything every movie needs but some don't have.They have the frightening scenes,they have the sad part behind the life of the strongest bravest character,they have the right amount of suspense they definitely knew what they were doing.It all ties together the way it should. This movie keeps you drawn in during the full 118 min.There is never a moment where you will want to get up to refill your popcorn bowl or even go to use the bathroom.Every horror movie has those scenes that get too horrific but with this movie the horror is what makes want to keep watching.This is definitely the best of the best.I would definitely recommend this movie to everyone because this is the perfect movie for anyone any night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wolfkilla14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest thing about lambs is that something new is discovered each time you view it. As with all psychological films, it takes multiple views to absorb the full plot and ingest the actual meaning behind the film. The dynamic between Clarice and Hannibal is possibly one of the best acting duos in history, and if you pay attention you can pick up things between the two of them that you miss during the first viewing. Each character has layers and layers to them, they are complex and difficult to understand, which is what makes this movie so incredible. A director wants his movie to be viewed over and over, and if you can;t do that with a film its too simple to be watched. Lams executes this perfectly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The collision between first impression and true identity in Silence of the Lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    livstrongeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Finally the time came and I decided to watch all of the Hannibal movies (because after the end of Hannibal's season 1 I was left with a void that only Hannibal Lecter could fill up). So I started with the famous Silence of the Lamb. If you are familiar with this movie, you probably know the plot: FBI agent Clarise Starling plaeyd by Jodie Foster needs the help of an incarcerated prisoner Hannibal Lecter played by Anthony Hopkins to catch a serial killer on the loose. So what was most interesting for me is that people aren't what they seem from the first impression. Yes, we see Clarise training but that is because she is the character with whom we are growing together, the main character. She is running through the forest what might be a metaphor that she is trying to defeat evil as forest always was a gloomy and scary place where monsters were hiding. But that is not how she is viewed by others. There are various scenes where she is the only woman in male company and everybody is looking at her as if she is not capable of anything, but she proves them wrong. On the other hand we see Hannibal as a calm person standing in his cell. You could not tell that this person is a heartless murderer who eats his victims. But that's what everybody knows about him. And that is why he is in the cell. Later we see his change when he attacks the guards, but I think more important is his entrance scene. It is just radiating with innocence, but you still have this feeling that something is wrong. Maybe it's not the cell, but most probably it's how he looks, how he smiles. But that you notice just a bit later. So that's what I saw in this movie  the difference between first impression and true people's nature. It's a bit scary how wrong can we sometimes be. Maybe next time we will regard the innocent looking person with more care.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hannibal will always be Hannibal...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie in which a young FBI agent Clarice Starling (Jodie Foster) tries to get some information from Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins) who is a psychopath and used to be a respected psychiatrist, for a psychopathic serial killer who skins his victims. To get these information Clarice Starling has to gain the respect and the trust of Dr.Hannibal Lecter. When I saw this movie I thought that Anthony Hopkins is really not OK in his minds for real and that's because of his perfect interpretation. I also think that Jodie Foster made an also perfect interpretation. Τhese were seen and in the Academy Awards where Anthony Hopkins and Jodie Foster won the Oscars for Best Actor in a Leading Role and for Best Actress in a Leading Role respectively. Jonathan Demme's work in the direction of this film did not go unnoticed and he also won the Oscar for Best Director. "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie that you have to see it, it's a really good Thriller and Crime movie with many good scenes and an exceptional screenplay.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    silence of the lambs : movie gold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mastersahk
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film will always be known as one of the greats in the horror/thriller genre for its dramatic posture when presenting such a risky film. Anthony Hopkins performance was magnificent every word and every turn he made. Jodie foster's character brought a real sense of belief with her acting and also brought a real sense of fear towards the films story. this movie was pure movie genius capturing pure technique towards the story and the acting. Jodie and Anthony should be praised for their wonderful performances as these two characters and also by the way that they express the characters emotions towards the films story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest Movies ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to think that this film was just sick. But now I've watched it, I can appreciate how thrilling and brilliant this movie is. If it wasn't for Anthony Hopkins performance as Dr. Hannibal Lector I would have rated this movie 7/10. What a stunning performance, I was amazed by how the role of the psychopathic Hannibal Lector was filled perfectly by Anthony and it couldn't have been done ant better. It is a great storyline based on the novel by Thomas Harris, and I haven't mentioned Jodie Foster's Oscar winning performance as rookie FBI agent Clarice Starling, but let's face it, Jodie Foster's performance is good but it was overwhelmed by Anthony's performance. But still two good Oscar winning performances and good acting from the rest of the cast especially Ted Levine's role as Jame Gump (Buffalo Bill). This legendary movie swept the main five Oscar's which were: Best Picture, Best Actor, Best Actress, Best Director and Best Screenplay. The soundtrack of this movie also made the movie what it is. The soundtrack made it more dramatic and dark. As in many scenes the music increased the darkness and pure horror of this legendary thriller. Overall the Silence is one of my all time favorite's, deserved it's five Oscars, amazing acting and of course the best performance I've ever seen by Anthony Hopkins and deserves to be #23 in the top 250. A must watch but I must warn you that it is one of the most thrilling movies ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unremarkable. Why the Oscars?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lawrence Archibald von Austerlitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always wanted to see Silence of the Lambs and finally got to today. I thought that Hannibal Lector sounded like a really cool character and of course I anticipated excellent film-making with the sort of praise it has received. I saw it, and I would say that as far as movies like this go, it is excellent. But for cinema in general, Silence is unremarkable and, really, given the hype and awards, ultimately disappointing. Jodie Foster was good, but she is haunted by the slaughter of a lamb from her childhood? Ridiculous. Anthony Hopkins was great. I think he deserved his award, though his performance is overrated. Not exactly a very complex or hard to portray character... The story was not particularly exciting. It was fairly clumsy and failed to capture my attention. I was repelled by Buffalo Bill but not interested in his character whatsoever. I watched the movie for the rare encounters with Hannibal Lector, and the search for Buffalo Bill was an uninteresting but necessary backdrop. Also, how on Earth would the FBI bring a SWAT team to a house that is a false tip, that is hundreds of miles away from the killings...? It makes no sense - they completely ignored the evidence and conclusions they had already made. And so, when the so-called thrilling doorbell scene took place, I was not surprised. Of course he's not in Chicago. Ridiculous. I can honestly say I enjoyed Lector's escape. It was clever and suspenseful (if a bit illogical) and to some degree makes the movie. And is this movie scary, as has been said? No. Definitely not. The serial killer is creepy, not terrifying. Hannibal is intriguing, but not too scary. I've heard of people not sleeping for days, others having horrific nightmares... I don't understand it. This movie is worth watching if you like thrillers/serial killer/ kind of movies, but if you go into this film expecting a great piece of cinema, some groundbreaking technique or idea, or a thrilling scene or two as I did, you will be disappointed. A good movie, yes. 23rd on IMDb Top 250? Absolutely not. An 8.7 on IMDb? No.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Acting In This One!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Thomas Harris novel, film follows the efforts of FBI cadet Clarice Starling(Jodie Foster, in an Academy Award winning performance) to catch a serial killer known as Buffalo Bill, who kidnaps and murders his victims. She contacts incarcerated(and legendary) serial killer Hannibal Lecter(Anthony Hopkins, in an unforgettable, brilliant Academy Award winning performance) who taunts Clarice, yet finds himself impressed by her determination and mysterious background, which he intends to take full advantage of, leading to a dramatic(and lethal) escape... Supremely well acted and well crafted horror tale is quite suspenseful and compelling as well, though is a bit over the top at times, this is still excellent. Also won Academy Awards for Best Picture and director(Jonathan Demme).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silence of the lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gabriellerawrr
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this multiple Oscar-winning thriller, Jodie Foster stars as Clarice Starling, a top student at the FBI's training academy whose shrewd analyses of serial killers lands her a special assignment: the FBI is investigating a vicious murderer nicknamed Buffalo Bill, who kills young women and then removes the skin from their bodies. Jack Crawford (Scott Glenn) wants Clarice to interview Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins), a brilliant psychiatrist who is also a violent psychopath, serving life behind bars for various acts of murder and cannibalism. Crawford believes that Lecter may have insight into this case and that Starling, as an attractive young woman, may be just the bait to draw him out. Lecter does indeed know something of Buffalo Bill, but his information comes with a price: in exchange for telling what he knows, he wants to be housed in a more comfortable facility. More important, he wants to speak with Clarice about her past. He skillfully digs into her psyche, forcing her to reveal her innermost traumas and putting her in a position of vulnerability when she can least afford to be weak. The film mingles the horrors of criminal acts with the psychological horrors of Lecter's slow-motion interrogation of Clarice and of her memories that emerge from it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST Horror movie that will stay a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joanna Hernandez
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The whole movie is about an innocent female character that steps into the world of men and into the world of terror.This movie has the perfect amount of everything every movie needs but some don't have.They have the frightening scenes,they have the sad part behind the life of the strongest bravest character,they have the right amount of suspense they definitely knew what they were doing.It all ties together the way it should. This movie keeps you drawn in during the full 118 min.There is never a moment where you will want to get up to refill your popcorn bowl or even go to use the bathroom.Every horror movie has those scenes that get too horrific but with this movie the horror is what makes want to keep watching.This is definitely the best of the best.I would definitely recommend this movie to everyone because this is the perfect movie for anyone any night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wolfkilla14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest thing about lambs is that something new is discovered each time you view it. As with all psychological films, it takes multiple views to absorb the full plot and ingest the actual meaning behind the film. The dynamic between Clarice and Hannibal is possibly one of the best acting duos in history, and if you pay attention you can pick up things between the two of them that you miss during the first viewing. Each character has layers and layers to them, they are complex and difficult to understand, which is what makes this movie so incredible. A director wants his movie to be viewed over and over, and if you can;t do that with a film its too simple to be watched. Lams executes this perfectly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The collision between first impression and true identity in Silence of the Lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    livstrongeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Finally the time came and I decided to watch all of the Hannibal movies (because after the end of Hannibal's season 1 I was left with a void that only Hannibal Lecter could fill up). So I started with the famous Silence of the Lamb. If you are familiar with this movie, you probably know the plot: FBI agent Clarise Starling plaeyd by Jodie Foster needs the help of an incarcerated prisoner Hannibal Lecter played by Anthony Hopkins to catch a serial killer on the loose. So what was most interesting for me is that people aren't what they seem from the first impression. Yes, we see Clarise training but that is because she is the character with whom we are growing together, the main character. She is running through the forest what might be a metaphor that she is trying to defeat evil as forest always was a gloomy and scary place where monsters were hiding. But that is not how she is viewed by others. There are various scenes where she is the only woman in male company and everybody is looking at her as if she is not capable of anything, but she proves them wrong. On the other hand we see Hannibal as a calm person standing in his cell. You could not tell that this person is a heartless murderer who eats his victims. But that's what everybody knows about him. And that is why he is in the cell. Later we see his change when he attacks the guards, but I think more important is his entrance scene. It is just radiating with innocence, but you still have this feeling that something is wrong. Maybe it's not the cell, but most probably it's how he looks, how he smiles. But that you notice just a bit later. So that's what I saw in this movie  the difference between first impression and true people's nature. It's a bit scary how wrong can we sometimes be. Maybe next time we will regard the innocent looking person with more care.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hannibal will always be Hannibal...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie in which a young FBI agent Clarice Starling (Jodie Foster) tries to get some information from Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins) who is a psychopath and used to be a respected psychiatrist, for a psychopathic serial killer who skins his victims. To get these information Clarice Starling has to gain the respect and the trust of Dr.Hannibal Lecter. When I saw this movie I thought that Anthony Hopkins is really not OK in his minds for real and that's because of his perfect interpretation. I also think that Jodie Foster made an also perfect interpretation. Τhese were seen and in the Academy Awards where Anthony Hopkins and Jodie Foster won the Oscars for Best Actor in a Leading Role and for Best Actress in a Leading Role respectively. Jonathan Demme's work in the direction of this film did not go unnoticed and he also won the Oscar for Best Director. "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie that you have to see it, it's a really good Thriller and Crime movie with many good scenes and an exceptional screenplay.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    silence of the lambs : movie gold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mastersahk
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film will always be known as one of the greats in the horror/thriller genre for its dramatic posture when presenting such a risky film. Anthony Hopkins performance was magnificent every word and every turn he made. Jodie foster's character brought a real sense of belief with her acting and also brought a real sense of fear towards the films story. this movie was pure movie genius capturing pure technique towards the story and the acting. Jodie and Anthony should be praised for their wonderful performances as these two characters and also by the way that they express the characters emotions towards the films story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest Movies ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to think that this film was just sick. But now I've watched it, I can appreciate how thrilling and brilliant this movie is. If it wasn't for Anthony Hopkins performance as Dr. Hannibal Lector I would have rated this movie 7/10. What a stunning performance, I was amazed by how the role of the psychopathic Hannibal Lector was filled perfectly by Anthony and it couldn't have been done ant better. It is a great storyline based on the novel by Thomas Harris, and I haven't mentioned Jodie Foster's Oscar winning performance as rookie FBI agent Clarice Starling, but let's face it, Jodie Foster's performance is good but it was overwhelmed by Anthony's performance. But still two good Oscar winning performances and good acting from the rest of the cast especially Ted Levine's role as Jame Gump (Buffalo Bill). This legendary movie swept the main five Oscar's which were: Best Picture, Best Actor, Best Actress, Best Director and Best Screenplay. The soundtrack of this movie also made the movie what it is. The soundtrack made it more dramatic and dark. As in many scenes the music increased the darkness and pure horror of this legendary thriller. Overall the Silence is one of my all time favorite's, deserved it's five Oscars, amazing acting and of course the best performance I've ever seen by Anthony Hopkins and deserves to be #23 in the top 250. A must watch but I must warn you that it is one of the most thrilling movies ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unremarkable. Why the Oscars?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lawrence Archibald von Austerlitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always wanted to see Silence of the Lambs and finally got to today. I thought that Hannibal Lector sounded like a really cool character and of course I anticipated excellent film-making with the sort of praise it has received. I saw it, and I would say that as far as movies like this go, it is excellent. But for cinema in general, Silence is unremarkable and, really, given the hype and awards, ultimately disappointing. Jodie Foster was good, but she is haunted by the slaughter of a lamb from her childhood? Ridiculous. Anthony Hopkins was great. I think he deserved his award, though his performance is overrated. Not exactly a very complex or hard to portray character... The story was not particularly exciting. It was fairly clumsy and failed to capture my attention. I was repelled by Buffalo Bill but not interested in his character whatsoever. I watched the movie for the rare encounters with Hannibal Lector, and the search for Buffalo Bill was an uninteresting but necessary backdrop. Also, how on Earth would the FBI bring a SWAT team to a house that is a false tip, that is hundreds of miles away from the killings...? It makes no sense - they completely ignored the evidence and conclusions they had already made. And so, when the so-called thrilling doorbell scene took place, I was not surprised. Of course he's not in Chicago. Ridiculous. I can honestly say I enjoyed Lector's escape. It was clever and suspenseful (if a bit illogical) and to some degree makes the movie. And is this movie scary, as has been said? No. Definitely not. The serial killer is creepy, not terrifying. Hannibal is intriguing, but not too scary. I've heard of people not sleeping for days, others having horrific nightmares... I don't understand it. This movie is worth watching if you like thrillers/serial killer/ kind of movies, but if you go into this film expecting a great piece of cinema, some groundbreaking technique or idea, or a thrilling scene or two as I did, you will be disappointed. A good movie, yes. 23rd on IMDb Top 250? Absolutely not. An 8.7 on IMDb? No.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Acting In This One!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Thomas Harris novel, film follows the efforts of FBI cadet Clarice Starling(Jodie Foster, in an Academy Award winning performance) to catch a serial killer known as Buffalo Bill, who kidnaps and murders his victims. She contacts incarcerated(and legendary) serial killer Hannibal Lecter(Anthony Hopkins, in an unforgettable, brilliant Academy Award winning performance) who taunts Clarice, yet finds himself impressed by her determination and mysterious background, which he intends to take full advantage of, leading to a dramatic(and lethal) escape... Supremely well acted and well crafted horror tale is quite suspenseful and compelling as well, though is a bit over the top at times, this is still excellent. Also won Academy Awards for Best Picture and director(Jonathan Demme).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silence of the lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gabriellerawrr
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this multiple Oscar-winning thriller, Jodie Foster stars as Clarice Starling, a top student at the FBI's training academy whose shrewd analyses of serial killers lands her a special assignment: the FBI is investigating a vicious murderer nicknamed Buffalo Bill, who kills young women and then removes the skin from their bodies. Jack Crawford (Scott Glenn) wants Clarice to interview Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins), a brilliant psychiatrist who is also a violent psychopath, serving life behind bars for various acts of murder and cannibalism. Crawford believes that Lecter may have insight into this case and that Starling, as an attractive young woman, may be just the bait to draw him out. Lecter does indeed know something of Buffalo Bill, but his information comes with a price: in exchange for telling what he knows, he wants to be housed in a more comfortable facility. More important, he wants to speak with Clarice about her past. He skillfully digs into her psyche, forcing her to reveal her innermost traumas and putting her in a position of vulnerability when she can least afford to be weak. The film mingles the horrors of criminal acts with the psychological horrors of Lecter's slow-motion interrogation of Clarice and of her memories that emerge from it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST Horror movie that will stay a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joanna Hernandez
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The whole movie is about an innocent female character that steps into the world of men and into the world of terror.This movie has the perfect amount of everything every movie needs but some don't have.They have the frightening scenes,they have the sad part behind the life of the strongest bravest character,they have the right amount of suspense they definitely knew what they were doing.It all ties together the way it should. This movie keeps you drawn in during the full 118 min.There is never a moment where you will want to get up to refill your popcorn bowl or even go to use the bathroom.Every horror movie has those scenes that get too horrific but with this movie the horror is what makes want to keep watching.This is definitely the best of the best.I would definitely recommend this movie to everyone because this is the perfect movie for anyone any night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wolfkilla14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest thing about lambs is that something new is discovered each time you view it. As with all psychological films, it takes multiple views to absorb the full plot and ingest the actual meaning behind the film. The dynamic between Clarice and Hannibal is possibly one of the best acting duos in history, and if you pay attention you can pick up things between the two of them that you miss during the first viewing. Each character has layers and layers to them, they are complex and difficult to understand, which is what makes this movie so incredible. A director wants his movie to be viewed over and over, and if you can;t do that with a film its too simple to be watched. Lams executes this perfectly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The collision between first impression and true identity in Silence of the Lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    livstrongeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Finally the time came and I decided to watch all of the Hannibal movies (because after the end of Hannibal's season 1 I was left with a void that only Hannibal Lecter could fill up). So I started with the famous Silence of the Lamb. If you are familiar with this movie, you probably know the plot: FBI agent Clarise Starling plaeyd by Jodie Foster needs the help of an incarcerated prisoner Hannibal Lecter played by Anthony Hopkins to catch a serial killer on the loose. So what was most interesting for me is that people aren't what they seem from the first impression. Yes, we see Clarise training but that is because she is the character with whom we are growing together, the main character. She is running through the forest what might be a metaphor that she is trying to defeat evil as forest always was a gloomy and scary place where monsters were hiding. But that is not how she is viewed by others. There are various scenes where she is the only woman in male company and everybody is looking at her as if she is not capable of anything, but she proves them wrong. On the other hand we see Hannibal as a calm person standing in his cell. You could not tell that this person is a heartless murderer who eats his victims. But that's what everybody knows about him. And that is why he is in the cell. Later we see his change when he attacks the guards, but I think more important is his entrance scene. It is just radiating with innocence, but you still have this feeling that something is wrong. Maybe it's not the cell, but most probably it's how he looks, how he smiles. But that you notice just a bit later. So that's what I saw in this movie  the difference between first impression and true people's nature. It's a bit scary how wrong can we sometimes be. Maybe next time we will regard the innocent looking person with more care.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hannibal will always be Hannibal...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie in which a young FBI agent Clarice Starling (Jodie Foster) tries to get some information from Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins) who is a psychopath and used to be a respected psychiatrist, for a psychopathic serial killer who skins his victims. To get these information Clarice Starling has to gain the respect and the trust of Dr.Hannibal Lecter. When I saw this movie I thought that Anthony Hopkins is really not OK in his minds for real and that's because of his perfect interpretation. I also think that Jodie Foster made an also perfect interpretation. Τhese were seen and in the Academy Awards where Anthony Hopkins and Jodie Foster won the Oscars for Best Actor in a Leading Role and for Best Actress in a Leading Role respectively. Jonathan Demme's work in the direction of this film did not go unnoticed and he also won the Oscar for Best Director. "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie that you have to see it, it's a really good Thriller and Crime movie with many good scenes and an exceptional screenplay.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    silence of the lambs : movie gold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mastersahk
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film will always be known as one of the greats in the horror/thriller genre for its dramatic posture when presenting such a risky film. Anthony Hopkins performance was magnificent every word and every turn he made. Jodie foster's character brought a real sense of belief with her acting and also brought a real sense of fear towards the films story. this movie was pure movie genius capturing pure technique towards the story and the acting. Jodie and Anthony should be praised for their wonderful performances as these two characters and also by the way that they express the characters emotions towards the films story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest Movies ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to think that this film was just sick. But now I've watched it, I can appreciate how thrilling and brilliant this movie is. If it wasn't for Anthony Hopkins performance as Dr. Hannibal Lector I would have rated this movie 7/10. What a stunning performance, I was amazed by how the role of the psychopathic Hannibal Lector was filled perfectly by Anthony and it couldn't have been done ant better. It is a great storyline based on the novel by Thomas Harris, and I haven't mentioned Jodie Foster's Oscar winning performance as rookie FBI agent Clarice Starling, but let's face it, Jodie Foster's performance is good but it was overwhelmed by Anthony's performance. But still two good Oscar winning performances and good acting from the rest of the cast especially Ted Levine's role as Jame Gump (Buffalo Bill). This legendary movie swept the main five Oscar's which were: Best Picture, Best Actor, Best Actress, Best Director and Best Screenplay. The soundtrack of this movie also made the movie what it is. The soundtrack made it more dramatic and dark. As in many scenes the music increased the darkness and pure horror of this legendary thriller. Overall the Silence is one of my all time favorite's, deserved it's five Oscars, amazing acting and of course the best performance I've ever seen by Anthony Hopkins and deserves to be #23 in the top 250. A must watch but I must warn you that it is one of the most thrilling movies ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unremarkable. Why the Oscars?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lawrence Archibald von Austerlitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always wanted to see Silence of the Lambs and finally got to today. I thought that Hannibal Lector sounded like a really cool character and of course I anticipated excellent film-making with the sort of praise it has received. I saw it, and I would say that as far as movies like this go, it is excellent. But for cinema in general, Silence is unremarkable and, really, given the hype and awards, ultimately disappointing. Jodie Foster was good, but she is haunted by the slaughter of a lamb from her childhood? Ridiculous. Anthony Hopkins was great. I think he deserved his award, though his performance is overrated. Not exactly a very complex or hard to portray character... The story was not particularly exciting. It was fairly clumsy and failed to capture my attention. I was repelled by Buffalo Bill but not interested in his character whatsoever. I watched the movie for the rare encounters with Hannibal Lector, and the search for Buffalo Bill was an uninteresting but necessary backdrop. Also, how on Earth would the FBI bring a SWAT team to a house that is a false tip, that is hundreds of miles away from the killings...? It makes no sense - they completely ignored the evidence and conclusions they had already made. And so, when the so-called thrilling doorbell scene took place, I was not surprised. Of course he's not in Chicago. Ridiculous. I can honestly say I enjoyed Lector's escape. It was clever and suspenseful (if a bit illogical) and to some degree makes the movie. And is this movie scary, as has been said? No. Definitely not. The serial killer is creepy, not terrifying. Hannibal is intriguing, but not too scary. I've heard of people not sleeping for days, others having horrific nightmares... I don't understand it. This movie is worth watching if you like thrillers/serial killer/ kind of movies, but if you go into this film expecting a great piece of cinema, some groundbreaking technique or idea, or a thrilling scene or two as I did, you will be disappointed. A good movie, yes. 23rd on IMDb Top 250? Absolutely not. An 8.7 on IMDb? No.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Acting In This One!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Thomas Harris novel, film follows the efforts of FBI cadet Clarice Starling(Jodie Foster, in an Academy Award winning performance) to catch a serial killer known as Buffalo Bill, who kidnaps and murders his victims. She contacts incarcerated(and legendary) serial killer Hannibal Lecter(Anthony Hopkins, in an unforgettable, brilliant Academy Award winning performance) who taunts Clarice, yet finds himself impressed by her determination and mysterious background, which he intends to take full advantage of, leading to a dramatic(and lethal) escape... Supremely well acted and well crafted horror tale is quite suspenseful and compelling as well, though is a bit over the top at times, this is still excellent. Also won Academy Awards for Best Picture and director(Jonathan Demme).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silence of the lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gabriellerawrr
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this multiple Oscar-winning thriller, Jodie Foster stars as Clarice Starling, a top student at the FBI's training academy whose shrewd analyses of serial killers lands her a special assignment: the FBI is investigating a vicious murderer nicknamed Buffalo Bill, who kills young women and then removes the skin from their bodies. Jack Crawford (Scott Glenn) wants Clarice to interview Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins), a brilliant psychiatrist who is also a violent psychopath, serving life behind bars for various acts of murder and cannibalism. Crawford believes that Lecter may have insight into this case and that Starling, as an attractive young woman, may be just the bait to draw him out. Lecter does indeed know something of Buffalo Bill, but his information comes with a price: in exchange for telling what he knows, he wants to be housed in a more comfortable facility. More important, he wants to speak with Clarice about her past. He skillfully digs into her psyche, forcing her to reveal her innermost traumas and putting her in a position of vulnerability when she can least afford to be weak. The film mingles the horrors of criminal acts with the psychological horrors of Lecter's slow-motion interrogation of Clarice and of her memories that emerge from it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST Horror movie that will stay a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joanna Hernandez
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The whole movie is about an innocent female character that steps into the world of men and into the world of terror.This movie has the perfect amount of everything every movie needs but some don't have.They have the frightening scenes,they have the sad part behind the life of the strongest bravest character,they have the right amount of suspense they definitely knew what they were doing.It all ties together the way it should. This movie keeps you drawn in during the full 118 min.There is never a moment where you will want to get up to refill your popcorn bowl or even go to use the bathroom.Every horror movie has those scenes that get too horrific but with this movie the horror is what makes want to keep watching.This is definitely the best of the best.I would definitely recommend this movie to everyone because this is the perfect movie for anyone any night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wolfkilla14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest thing about lambs is that something new is discovered each time you view it. As with all psychological films, it takes multiple views to absorb the full plot and ingest the actual meaning behind the film. The dynamic between Clarice and Hannibal is possibly one of the best acting duos in history, and if you pay attention you can pick up things between the two of them that you miss during the first viewing. Each character has layers and layers to them, they are complex and difficult to understand, which is what makes this movie so incredible. A director wants his movie to be viewed over and over, and if you can;t do that with a film its too simple to be watched. Lams executes this perfectly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The collision between first impression and true identity in Silence of the Lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    livstrongeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Finally the time came and I decided to watch all of the Hannibal movies (because after the end of Hannibal's season 1 I was left with a void that only Hannibal Lecter could fill up). So I started with the famous Silence of the Lamb. If you are familiar with this movie, you probably know the plot: FBI agent Clarise Starling plaeyd by Jodie Foster needs the help of an incarcerated prisoner Hannibal Lecter played by Anthony Hopkins to catch a serial killer on the loose. So what was most interesting for me is that people aren't what they seem from the first impression. Yes, we see Clarise training but that is because she is the character with whom we are growing together, the main character. She is running through the forest what might be a metaphor that she is trying to defeat evil as forest always was a gloomy and scary place where monsters were hiding. But that is not how she is viewed by others. There are various scenes where she is the only woman in male company and everybody is looking at her as if she is not capable of anything, but she proves them wrong. On the other hand we see Hannibal as a calm person standing in his cell. You could not tell that this person is a heartless murderer who eats his victims. But that's what everybody knows about him. And that is why he is in the cell. Later we see his change when he attacks the guards, but I think more important is his entrance scene. It is just radiating with innocence, but you still have this feeling that something is wrong. Maybe it's not the cell, but most probably it's how he looks, how he smiles. But that you notice just a bit later. So that's what I saw in this movie  the difference between first impression and true people's nature. It's a bit scary how wrong can we sometimes be. Maybe next time we will regard the innocent looking person with more care.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hannibal will always be Hannibal...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie in which a young FBI agent Clarice Starling (Jodie Foster) tries to get some information from Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins) who is a psychopath and used to be a respected psychiatrist, for a psychopathic serial killer who skins his victims. To get these information Clarice Starling has to gain the respect and the trust of Dr.Hannibal Lecter. When I saw this movie I thought that Anthony Hopkins is really not OK in his minds for real and that's because of his perfect interpretation. I also think that Jodie Foster made an also perfect interpretation. Τhese were seen and in the Academy Awards where Anthony Hopkins and Jodie Foster won the Oscars for Best Actor in a Leading Role and for Best Actress in a Leading Role respectively. Jonathan Demme's work in the direction of this film did not go unnoticed and he also won the Oscar for Best Director. "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie that you have to see it, it's a really good Thriller and Crime movie with many good scenes and an exceptional screenplay.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    silence of the lambs : movie gold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mastersahk
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film will always be known as one of the greats in the horror/thriller genre for its dramatic posture when presenting such a risky film. Anthony Hopkins performance was magnificent every word and every turn he made. Jodie foster's character brought a real sense of belief with her acting and also brought a real sense of fear towards the films story. this movie was pure movie genius capturing pure technique towards the story and the acting. Jodie and Anthony should be praised for their wonderful performances as these two characters and also by the way that they express the characters emotions towards the films story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest Movies ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to think that this film was just sick. But now I've watched it, I can appreciate how thrilling and brilliant this movie is. If it wasn't for Anthony Hopkins performance as Dr. Hannibal Lector I would have rated this movie 7/10. What a stunning performance, I was amazed by how the role of the psychopathic Hannibal Lector was filled perfectly by Anthony and it couldn't have been done ant better. It is a great storyline based on the novel by Thomas Harris, and I haven't mentioned Jodie Foster's Oscar winning performance as rookie FBI agent Clarice Starling, but let's face it, Jodie Foster's performance is good but it was overwhelmed by Anthony's performance. But still two good Oscar winning performances and good acting from the rest of the cast especially Ted Levine's role as Jame Gump (Buffalo Bill). This legendary movie swept the main five Oscar's which were: Best Picture, Best Actor, Best Actress, Best Director and Best Screenplay. The soundtrack of this movie also made the movie what it is. The soundtrack made it more dramatic and dark. As in many scenes the music increased the darkness and pure horror of this legendary thriller. Overall the Silence is one of my all time favorite's, deserved it's five Oscars, amazing acting and of course the best performance I've ever seen by Anthony Hopkins and deserves to be #23 in the top 250. A must watch but I must warn you that it is one of the most thrilling movies ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unremarkable. Why the Oscars?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lawrence Archibald von Austerlitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always wanted to see Silence of the Lambs and finally got to today. I thought that Hannibal Lector sounded like a really cool character and of course I anticipated excellent film-making with the sort of praise it has received. I saw it, and I would say that as far as movies like this go, it is excellent. But for cinema in general, Silence is unremarkable and, really, given the hype and awards, ultimately disappointing. Jodie Foster was good, but she is haunted by the slaughter of a lamb from her childhood? Ridiculous. Anthony Hopkins was great. I think he deserved his award, though his performance is overrated. Not exactly a very complex or hard to portray character... The story was not particularly exciting. It was fairly clumsy and failed to capture my attention. I was repelled by Buffalo Bill but not interested in his character whatsoever. I watched the movie for the rare encounters with Hannibal Lector, and the search for Buffalo Bill was an uninteresting but necessary backdrop. Also, how on Earth would the FBI bring a SWAT team to a house that is a false tip, that is hundreds of miles away from the killings...? It makes no sense - they completely ignored the evidence and conclusions they had already made. And so, when the so-called thrilling doorbell scene took place, I was not surprised. Of course he's not in Chicago. Ridiculous. I can honestly say I enjoyed Lector's escape. It was clever and suspenseful (if a bit illogical) and to some degree makes the movie. And is this movie scary, as has been said? No. Definitely not. The serial killer is creepy, not terrifying. Hannibal is intriguing, but not too scary. I've heard of people not sleeping for days, others having horrific nightmares... I don't understand it. This movie is worth watching if you like thrillers/serial killer/ kind of movies, but if you go into this film expecting a great piece of cinema, some groundbreaking technique or idea, or a thrilling scene or two as I did, you will be disappointed. A good movie, yes. 23rd on IMDb Top 250? Absolutely not. An 8.7 on IMDb? No.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Acting In This One!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Thomas Harris novel, film follows the efforts of FBI cadet Clarice Starling(Jodie Foster, in an Academy Award winning performance) to catch a serial killer known as Buffalo Bill, who kidnaps and murders his victims. She contacts incarcerated(and legendary) serial killer Hannibal Lecter(Anthony Hopkins, in an unforgettable, brilliant Academy Award winning performance) who taunts Clarice, yet finds himself impressed by her determination and mysterious background, which he intends to take full advantage of, leading to a dramatic(and lethal) escape... Supremely well acted and well crafted horror tale is quite suspenseful and compelling as well, though is a bit over the top at times, this is still excellent. Also won Academy Awards for Best Picture and director(Jonathan Demme).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silence of the lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gabriellerawrr
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this multiple Oscar-winning thriller, Jodie Foster stars as Clarice Starling, a top student at the FBI's training academy whose shrewd analyses of serial killers lands her a special assignment: the FBI is investigating a vicious murderer nicknamed Buffalo Bill, who kills young women and then removes the skin from their bodies. Jack Crawford (Scott Glenn) wants Clarice to interview Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins), a brilliant psychiatrist who is also a violent psychopath, serving life behind bars for various acts of murder and cannibalism. Crawford believes that Lecter may have insight into this case and that Starling, as an attractive young woman, may be just the bait to draw him out. Lecter does indeed know something of Buffalo Bill, but his information comes with a price: in exchange for telling what he knows, he wants to be housed in a more comfortable facility. More important, he wants to speak with Clarice about her past. He skillfully digs into her psyche, forcing her to reveal her innermost traumas and putting her in a position of vulnerability when she can least afford to be weak. The film mingles the horrors of criminal acts with the psychological horrors of Lecter's slow-motion interrogation of Clarice and of her memories that emerge from it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST Horror movie that will stay a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joanna Hernandez
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The whole movie is about an innocent female character that steps into the world of men and into the world of terror.This movie has the perfect amount of everything every movie needs but some don't have.They have the frightening scenes,they have the sad part behind the life of the strongest bravest character,they have the right amount of suspense they definitely knew what they were doing.It all ties together the way it should. This movie keeps you drawn in during the full 118 min.There is never a moment where you will want to get up to refill your popcorn bowl or even go to use the bathroom.Every horror movie has those scenes that get too horrific but with this movie the horror is what makes want to keep watching.This is definitely the best of the best.I would definitely recommend this movie to everyone because this is the perfect movie for anyone any night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wolfkilla14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest thing about lambs is that something new is discovered each time you view it. As with all psychological films, it takes multiple views to absorb the full plot and ingest the actual meaning behind the film. The dynamic between Clarice and Hannibal is possibly one of the best acting duos in history, and if you pay attention you can pick up things between the two of them that you miss during the first viewing. Each character has layers and layers to them, they are complex and difficult to understand, which is what makes this movie so incredible. A director wants his movie to be viewed over and over, and if you can;t do that with a film its too simple to be watched. Lams executes this perfectly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The collision between first impression and true identity in Silence of the Lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    livstrongeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Finally the time came and I decided to watch all of the Hannibal movies (because after the end of Hannibal's season 1 I was left with a void that only Hannibal Lecter could fill up). So I started with the famous Silence of the Lamb. If you are familiar with this movie, you probably know the plot: FBI agent Clarise Starling plaeyd by Jodie Foster needs the help of an incarcerated prisoner Hannibal Lecter played by Anthony Hopkins to catch a serial killer on the loose. So what was most interesting for me is that people aren't what they seem from the first impression. Yes, we see Clarise training but that is because she is the character with whom we are growing together, the main character. She is running through the forest what might be a metaphor that she is trying to defeat evil as forest always was a gloomy and scary place where monsters were hiding. But that is not how she is viewed by others. There are various scenes where she is the only woman in male company and everybody is looking at her as if she is not capable of anything, but she proves them wrong. On the other hand we see Hannibal as a calm person standing in his cell. You could not tell that this person is a heartless murderer who eats his victims. But that's what everybody knows about him. And that is why he is in the cell. Later we see his change when he attacks the guards, but I think more important is his entrance scene. It is just radiating with innocence, but you still have this feeling that something is wrong. Maybe it's not the cell, but most probably it's how he looks, how he smiles. But that you notice just a bit later. So that's what I saw in this movie  the difference between first impression and true people's nature. It's a bit scary how wrong can we sometimes be. Maybe next time we will regard the innocent looking person with more care.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hannibal will always be Hannibal...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie in which a young FBI agent Clarice Starling (Jodie Foster) tries to get some information from Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins) who is a psychopath and used to be a respected psychiatrist, for a psychopathic serial killer who skins his victims. To get these information Clarice Starling has to gain the respect and the trust of Dr.Hannibal Lecter. When I saw this movie I thought that Anthony Hopkins is really not OK in his minds for real and that's because of his perfect interpretation. I also think that Jodie Foster made an also perfect interpretation. Τhese were seen and in the Academy Awards where Anthony Hopkins and Jodie Foster won the Oscars for Best Actor in a Leading Role and for Best Actress in a Leading Role respectively. Jonathan Demme's work in the direction of this film did not go unnoticed and he also won the Oscar for Best Director. "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie that you have to see it, it's a really good Thriller and Crime movie with many good scenes and an exceptional screenplay.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    silence of the lambs : movie gold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mastersahk
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film will always be known as one of the greats in the horror/thriller genre for its dramatic posture when presenting such a risky film. Anthony Hopkins performance was magnificent every word and every turn he made. Jodie foster's character brought a real sense of belief with her acting and also brought a real sense of fear towards the films story. this movie was pure movie genius capturing pure technique towards the story and the acting. Jodie and Anthony should be praised for their wonderful performances as these two characters and also by the way that they express the characters emotions towards the films story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest Movies ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to think that this film was just sick. But now I've watched it, I can appreciate how thrilling and brilliant this movie is. If it wasn't for Anthony Hopkins performance as Dr. Hannibal Lector I would have rated this movie 7/10. What a stunning performance, I was amazed by how the role of the psychopathic Hannibal Lector was filled perfectly by Anthony and it couldn't have been done ant better. It is a great storyline based on the novel by Thomas Harris, and I haven't mentioned Jodie Foster's Oscar winning performance as rookie FBI agent Clarice Starling, but let's face it, Jodie Foster's performance is good but it was overwhelmed by Anthony's performance. But still two good Oscar winning performances and good acting from the rest of the cast especially Ted Levine's role as Jame Gump (Buffalo Bill). This legendary movie swept the main five Oscar's which were: Best Picture, Best Actor, Best Actress, Best Director and Best Screenplay. The soundtrack of this movie also made the movie what it is. The soundtrack made it more dramatic and dark. As in many scenes the music increased the darkness and pure horror of this legendary thriller. Overall the Silence is one of my all time favorite's, deserved it's five Oscars, amazing acting and of course the best performance I've ever seen by Anthony Hopkins and deserves to be #23 in the top 250. A must watch but I must warn you that it is one of the most thrilling movies ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unremarkable. Why the Oscars?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lawrence Archibald von Austerlitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always wanted to see Silence of the Lambs and finally got to today. I thought that Hannibal Lector sounded like a really cool character and of course I anticipated excellent film-making with the sort of praise it has received. I saw it, and I would say that as far as movies like this go, it is excellent. But for cinema in general, Silence is unremarkable and, really, given the hype and awards, ultimately disappointing. Jodie Foster was good, but she is haunted by the slaughter of a lamb from her childhood? Ridiculous. Anthony Hopkins was great. I think he deserved his award, though his performance is overrated. Not exactly a very complex or hard to portray character... The story was not particularly exciting. It was fairly clumsy and failed to capture my attention. I was repelled by Buffalo Bill but not interested in his character whatsoever. I watched the movie for the rare encounters with Hannibal Lector, and the search for Buffalo Bill was an uninteresting but necessary backdrop. Also, how on Earth would the FBI bring a SWAT team to a house that is a false tip, that is hundreds of miles away from the killings...? It makes no sense - they completely ignored the evidence and conclusions they had already made. And so, when the so-called thrilling doorbell scene took place, I was not surprised. Of course he's not in Chicago. Ridiculous. I can honestly say I enjoyed Lector's escape. It was clever and suspenseful (if a bit illogical) and to some degree makes the movie. And is this movie scary, as has been said? No. Definitely not. The serial killer is creepy, not terrifying. Hannibal is intriguing, but not too scary. I've heard of people not sleeping for days, others having horrific nightmares... I don't understand it. This movie is worth watching if you like thrillers/serial killer/ kind of movies, but if you go into this film expecting a great piece of cinema, some groundbreaking technique or idea, or a thrilling scene or two as I did, you will be disappointed. A good movie, yes. 23rd on IMDb Top 250? Absolutely not. An 8.7 on IMDb? No.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Acting In This One!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Thomas Harris novel, film follows the efforts of FBI cadet Clarice Starling(Jodie Foster, in an Academy Award winning performance) to catch a serial killer known as Buffalo Bill, who kidnaps and murders his victims. She contacts incarcerated(and legendary) serial killer Hannibal Lecter(Anthony Hopkins, in an unforgettable, brilliant Academy Award winning performance) who taunts Clarice, yet finds himself impressed by her determination and mysterious background, which he intends to take full advantage of, leading to a dramatic(and lethal) escape... Supremely well acted and well crafted horror tale is quite suspenseful and compelling as well, though is a bit over the top at times, this is still excellent. Also won Academy Awards for Best Picture and director(Jonathan Demme).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silence of the lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gabriellerawrr
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this multiple Oscar-winning thriller, Jodie Foster stars as Clarice Starling, a top student at the FBI's training academy whose shrewd analyses of serial killers lands her a special assignment: the FBI is investigating a vicious murderer nicknamed Buffalo Bill, who kills young women and then removes the skin from their bodies. Jack Crawford (Scott Glenn) wants Clarice to interview Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins), a brilliant psychiatrist who is also a violent psychopath, serving life behind bars for various acts of murder and cannibalism. Crawford believes that Lecter may have insight into this case and that Starling, as an attractive young woman, may be just the bait to draw him out. Lecter does indeed know something of Buffalo Bill, but his information comes with a price: in exchange for telling what he knows, he wants to be housed in a more comfortable facility. More important, he wants to speak with Clarice about her past. He skillfully digs into her psyche, forcing her to reveal her innermost traumas and putting her in a position of vulnerability when she can least afford to be weak. The film mingles the horrors of criminal acts with the psychological horrors of Lecter's slow-motion interrogation of Clarice and of her memories that emerge from it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST Horror movie that will stay a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joanna Hernandez
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The whole movie is about an innocent female character that steps into the world of men and into the world of terror.This movie has the perfect amount of everything every movie needs but some don't have.They have the frightening scenes,they have the sad part behind the life of the strongest bravest character,they have the right amount of suspense they definitely knew what they were doing.It all ties together the way it should. This movie keeps you drawn in during the full 118 min.There is never a moment where you will want to get up to refill your popcorn bowl or even go to use the bathroom.Every horror movie has those scenes that get too horrific but with this movie the horror is what makes want to keep watching.This is definitely the best of the best.I would definitely recommend this movie to everyone because this is the perfect movie for anyone any night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wolfkilla14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest thing about lambs is that something new is discovered each time you view it. As with all psychological films, it takes multiple views to absorb the full plot and ingest the actual meaning behind the film. The dynamic between Clarice and Hannibal is possibly one of the best acting duos in history, and if you pay attention you can pick up things between the two of them that you miss during the first viewing. Each character has layers and layers to them, they are complex and difficult to understand, which is what makes this movie so incredible. A director wants his movie to be viewed over and over, and if you can;t do that with a film its too simple to be watched. Lams executes this perfectly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The collision between first impression and true identity in Silence of the Lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    livstrongeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Finally the time came and I decided to watch all of the Hannibal movies (because after the end of Hannibal's season 1 I was left with a void that only Hannibal Lecter could fill up). So I started with the famous Silence of the Lamb. If you are familiar with this movie, you probably know the plot: FBI agent Clarise Starling plaeyd by Jodie Foster needs the help of an incarcerated prisoner Hannibal Lecter played by Anthony Hopkins to catch a serial killer on the loose. So what was most interesting for me is that people aren't what they seem from the first impression. Yes, we see Clarise training but that is because she is the character with whom we are growing together, the main character. She is running through the forest what might be a metaphor that she is trying to defeat evil as forest always was a gloomy and scary place where monsters were hiding. But that is not how she is viewed by others. There are various scenes where she is the only woman in male company and everybody is looking at her as if she is not capable of anything, but she proves them wrong. On the other hand we see Hannibal as a calm person standing in his cell. You could not tell that this person is a heartless murderer who eats his victims. But that's what everybody knows about him. And that is why he is in the cell. Later we see his change when he attacks the guards, but I think more important is his entrance scene. It is just radiating with innocence, but you still have this feeling that something is wrong. Maybe it's not the cell, but most probably it's how he looks, how he smiles. But that you notice just a bit later. So that's what I saw in this movie  the difference between first impression and true people's nature. It's a bit scary how wrong can we sometimes be. Maybe next time we will regard the innocent looking person with more care.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hannibal will always be Hannibal...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie in which a young FBI agent Clarice Starling (Jodie Foster) tries to get some information from Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins) who is a psychopath and used to be a respected psychiatrist, for a psychopathic serial killer who skins his victims. To get these information Clarice Starling has to gain the respect and the trust of Dr.Hannibal Lecter. When I saw this movie I thought that Anthony Hopkins is really not OK in his minds for real and that's because of his perfect interpretation. I also think that Jodie Foster made an also perfect interpretation. Τhese were seen and in the Academy Awards where Anthony Hopkins and Jodie Foster won the Oscars for Best Actor in a Leading Role and for Best Actress in a Leading Role respectively. Jonathan Demme's work in the direction of this film did not go unnoticed and he also won the Oscar for Best Director. "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie that you have to see it, it's a really good Thriller and Crime movie with many good scenes and an exceptional screenplay.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    silence of the lambs : movie gold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mastersahk
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film will always be known as one of the greats in the horror/thriller genre for its dramatic posture when presenting such a risky film. Anthony Hopkins performance was magnificent every word and every turn he made. Jodie foster's character brought a real sense of belief with her acting and also brought a real sense of fear towards the films story. this movie was pure movie genius capturing pure technique towards the story and the acting. Jodie and Anthony should be praised for their wonderful performances as these two characters and also by the way that they express the characters emotions towards the films story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest Movies ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to think that this film was just sick. But now I've watched it, I can appreciate how thrilling and brilliant this movie is. If it wasn't for Anthony Hopkins performance as Dr. Hannibal Lector I would have rated this movie 7/10. What a stunning performance, I was amazed by how the role of the psychopathic Hannibal Lector was filled perfectly by Anthony and it couldn't have been done ant better. It is a great storyline based on the novel by Thomas Harris, and I haven't mentioned Jodie Foster's Oscar winning performance as rookie FBI agent Clarice Starling, but let's face it, Jodie Foster's performance is good but it was overwhelmed by Anthony's performance. But still two good Oscar winning performances and good acting from the rest of the cast especially Ted Levine's role as Jame Gump (Buffalo Bill). This legendary movie swept the main five Oscar's which were: Best Picture, Best Actor, Best Actress, Best Director and Best Screenplay. The soundtrack of this movie also made the movie what it is. The soundtrack made it more dramatic and dark. As in many scenes the music increased the darkness and pure horror of this legendary thriller. Overall the Silence is one of my all time favorite's, deserved it's five Oscars, amazing acting and of course the best performance I've ever seen by Anthony Hopkins and deserves to be #23 in the top 250. A must watch but I must warn you that it is one of the most thrilling movies ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unremarkable. Why the Oscars?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lawrence Archibald von Austerlitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always wanted to see Silence of the Lambs and finally got to today. I thought that Hannibal Lector sounded like a really cool character and of course I anticipated excellent film-making with the sort of praise it has received. I saw it, and I would say that as far as movies like this go, it is excellent. But for cinema in general, Silence is unremarkable and, really, given the hype and awards, ultimately disappointing. Jodie Foster was good, but she is haunted by the slaughter of a lamb from her childhood? Ridiculous. Anthony Hopkins was great. I think he deserved his award, though his performance is overrated. Not exactly a very complex or hard to portray character... The story was not particularly exciting. It was fairly clumsy and failed to capture my attention. I was repelled by Buffalo Bill but not interested in his character whatsoever. I watched the movie for the rare encounters with Hannibal Lector, and the search for Buffalo Bill was an uninteresting but necessary backdrop. Also, how on Earth would the FBI bring a SWAT team to a house that is a false tip, that is hundreds of miles away from the killings...? It makes no sense - they completely ignored the evidence and conclusions they had already made. And so, when the so-called thrilling doorbell scene took place, I was not surprised. Of course he's not in Chicago. Ridiculous. I can honestly say I enjoyed Lector's escape. It was clever and suspenseful (if a bit illogical) and to some degree makes the movie. And is this movie scary, as has been said? No. Definitely not. The serial killer is creepy, not terrifying. Hannibal is intriguing, but not too scary. I've heard of people not sleeping for days, others having horrific nightmares... I don't understand it. This movie is worth watching if you like thrillers/serial killer/ kind of movies, but if you go into this film expecting a great piece of cinema, some groundbreaking technique or idea, or a thrilling scene or two as I did, you will be disappointed. A good movie, yes. 23rd on IMDb Top 250? Absolutely not. An 8.7 on IMDb? No.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb Acting In This One!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on the Thomas Harris novel, film follows the efforts of FBI cadet Clarice Starling(Jodie Foster, in an Academy Award winning performance) to catch a serial killer known as Buffalo Bill, who kidnaps and murders his victims. She contacts incarcerated(and legendary) serial killer Hannibal Lecter(Anthony Hopkins, in an unforgettable, brilliant Academy Award winning performance) who taunts Clarice, yet finds himself impressed by her determination and mysterious background, which he intends to take full advantage of, leading to a dramatic(and lethal) escape... Supremely well acted and well crafted horror tale is quite suspenseful and compelling as well, though is a bit over the top at times, this is still excellent. Also won Academy Awards for Best Picture and director(Jonathan Demme).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silence of the lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gabriellerawrr
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this multiple Oscar-winning thriller, Jodie Foster stars as Clarice Starling, a top student at the FBI's training academy whose shrewd analyses of serial killers lands her a special assignment: the FBI is investigating a vicious murderer nicknamed Buffalo Bill, who kills young women and then removes the skin from their bodies. Jack Crawford (Scott Glenn) wants Clarice to interview Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins), a brilliant psychiatrist who is also a violent psychopath, serving life behind bars for various acts of murder and cannibalism. Crawford believes that Lecter may have insight into this case and that Starling, as an attractive young woman, may be just the bait to draw him out. Lecter does indeed know something of Buffalo Bill, but his information comes with a price: in exchange for telling what he knows, he wants to be housed in a more comfortable facility. More important, he wants to speak with Clarice about her past. He skillfully digs into her psyche, forcing her to reveal her innermost traumas and putting her in a position of vulnerability when she can least afford to be weak. The film mingles the horrors of criminal acts with the psychological horrors of Lecter's slow-motion interrogation of Clarice and of her memories that emerge from it
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The BEST Horror movie that will stay a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joanna Hernandez
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The whole movie is about an innocent female character that steps into the world of men and into the world of terror.This movie has the perfect amount of everything every movie needs but some don't have.They have the frightening scenes,they have the sad part behind the life of the strongest bravest character,they have the right amount of suspense they definitely knew what they were doing.It all ties together the way it should. This movie keeps you drawn in during the full 118 min.There is never a moment where you will want to get up to refill your popcorn bowl or even go to use the bathroom.Every horror movie has those scenes that get too horrific but with this movie the horror is what makes want to keep watching.This is definitely the best of the best.I would definitely recommend this movie to everyone because this is the perfect movie for anyone any night.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wolfkilla14
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The greatest thing about lambs is that something new is discovered each time you view it. As with all psychological films, it takes multiple views to absorb the full plot and ingest the actual meaning behind the film. The dynamic between Clarice and Hannibal is possibly one of the best acting duos in history, and if you pay attention you can pick up things between the two of them that you miss during the first viewing. Each character has layers and layers to them, they are complex and difficult to understand, which is what makes this movie so incredible. A director wants his movie to be viewed over and over, and if you can;t do that with a film its too simple to be watched. Lams executes this perfectly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The collision between first impression and true identity in Silence of the Lambs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    livstrongeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Finally the time came and I decided to watch all of the Hannibal movies (because after the end of Hannibal's season 1 I was left with a void that only Hannibal Lecter could fill up). So I started with the famous Silence of the Lamb. If you are familiar with this movie, you probably know the plot: FBI agent Clarise Starling plaeyd by Jodie Foster needs the help of an incarcerated prisoner Hannibal Lecter played by Anthony Hopkins to catch a serial killer on the loose. So what was most interesting for me is that people aren't what they seem from the first impression. Yes, we see Clarise training but that is because she is the character with whom we are growing together, the main character. She is running through the forest what might be a metaphor that she is trying to defeat evil as forest always was a gloomy and scary place where monsters were hiding. But that is not how she is viewed by others. There are various scenes where she is the only woman in male company and everybody is looking at her as if she is not capable of anything, but she proves them wrong. On the other hand we see Hannibal as a calm person standing in his cell. You could not tell that this person is a heartless murderer who eats his victims. But that's what everybody knows about him. And that is why he is in the cell. Later we see his change when he attacks the guards, but I think more important is his entrance scene. It is just radiating with innocence, but you still have this feeling that something is wrong. Maybe it's not the cell, but most probably it's how he looks, how he smiles. But that you notice just a bit later. So that's what I saw in this movie  the difference between first impression and true people's nature. It's a bit scary how wrong can we sometimes be. Maybe next time we will regard the innocent looking person with more care.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hannibal will always be Hannibal...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thanos Alfie
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie in which a young FBI agent Clarice Starling (Jodie Foster) tries to get some information from Dr. Hannibal Lecter (Anthony Hopkins) who is a psychopath and used to be a respected psychiatrist, for a psychopathic serial killer who skins his victims. To get these information Clarice Starling has to gain the respect and the trust of Dr.Hannibal Lecter. When I saw this movie I thought that Anthony Hopkins is really not OK in his minds for real and that's because of his perfect interpretation. I also think that Jodie Foster made an also perfect interpretation. Τhese were seen and in the Academy Awards where Anthony Hopkins and Jodie Foster won the Oscars for Best Actor in a Leading Role and for Best Actress in a Leading Role respectively. Jonathan Demme's work in the direction of this film did not go unnoticed and he also won the Oscar for Best Director. "The Silence of the Lambs" is a movie that you have to see it, it's a really good Thriller and Crime movie with many good scenes and an exceptional screenplay.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    silence of the lambs : movie gold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mastersahk
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film will always be known as one of the greats in the horror/thriller genre for its dramatic posture when presenting such a risky film. Anthony Hopkins performance was magnificent every word and every turn he made. Jodie foster's character brought a real sense of belief with her acting and also brought a real sense of fear towards the films story. this movie was pure movie genius capturing pure technique towards the story and the acting. Jodie and Anthony should be praised for their wonderful performances as these two characters and also by the way that they express the characters emotions towards the films story. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the Greatest Movies ever Made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    josephledbury
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to think that this film was just sick. But now I've watched it, I can appreciate how thrilling and brilliant this movie is. If it wasn't for Anthony Hopkins performance as Dr. Hannibal Lector I would have rated this movie 7/10. What a stunning performance, I was amazed by how the role of the psychopathic Hannibal Lector was filled perfectly by Anthony and it couldn't have been done ant better. It is a great storyline based on the novel by Thomas Harris, and I haven't mentioned Jodie Foster's Oscar winning performance as rookie FBI agent Clarice Starling, but let's face it, Jodie Foster's performance is good but it was overwhelmed by Anthony's performance. But still two good Oscar winning performances and good acting from the rest of the cast especially Ted Levine's role as Jame Gump (Buffalo Bill). This legendary movie swept the main five Oscar's which were: Best Picture, Best Actor, Best Actress, Best Director and Best Screenplay. The soundtrack of this movie also made the movie what it is. The soundtrack made it more dramatic and dark. As in many scenes the music increased the darkness and pure horror of this legendary thriller. Overall the Silence is one of my all time favorite's, deserved it's five Oscars, amazing acting and of course the best performance I've ever seen by Anthony Hopkins and deserves to be #23 in the top 250. A must watch but I must warn you that it is one of the most thrilling movies ever made.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unremarkable. Why the Oscars?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lawrence Archibald von Austerlitz
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've always wanted to see Silence of the Lambs and finally got to today. I thought that Hannibal Lector sounded like a really cool character and of course I anticipated excellent film-making with the sort of praise it has received. I saw it, and I would say that as far as movies like this go, it is excellent. But for cinema in general, Silence is unremarkable and, really, given the hype and awards, ultimately disappointing. Jodie Foster was good, but she is haunted by the slaughter of a lamb from her childhood? Ridiculous. Anthony Hopkins was great. I think he deserved his award, though his performance is overrated. Not exactly a very complex or hard to portray character... The story was not particularly exciting. It was fairly clumsy and failed to capture my attention. I was repelled by Buffalo Bill but not interested in his character whatsoever. I watched the movie for the rare encounters with Hannibal Lector, and the search for Buffalo Bill was an uninteresting but necessary backdrop. Also, how on Earth would the FBI bring a SWAT team to a house that is a false tip, that is hundreds of miles away from the killings...? It makes no sense - they completely ignored the evidence and conclusions they had already made. And so, when the so-called thrilling doorbell scene took place, I was not surprised. Of course he's not in Chicago. Ridiculous. I can honestly say I enjoyed Lector's escape. It was clever and suspenseful (if a bit illogical) and to some degree makes the movie. And is this movie scary, as has been said? No. Definitely not. The serial killer is creepy, not terrifying. Hannibal is intriguing, but not too scary. I've heard of people not sleeping for days, others having horrific nightmares... I don't understand it. This movie is worth watching if you like thrillers/serial killer/ kind of movies, but if you go into this film expecting a great piece of cinema, some groundbreaking technique or idea, or a thrilling scene or two as I did, you will be disappointed. A good movie, yes. 23rd on IMDb Top 250? Absolutely not. An 8.7 on IMDb? No.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
