<filme>
 <id>
  981
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118927
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  &Aacute;rea de Risco
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Vusi Madlazi returns to the South African village he left as a young boy (he was organizing against apartheid, and left in fear of his life) to bury his father. He meets up with his brother... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Vusi Madlazi returns to the South African village he left as a young boy (he was organizing against apartheid, and left in fear of his life) to bury his father. He meets up with his brother Ernest, who tells him their other brother Stephen couldn't be contacted. Vusi goes to Johannesburg to find him, but at first can only find his neighbor/girlfriend, Karin, a stripper. Vusi proceeds to learn how conditions have changed since the end of apartheid, not always for the better for black men.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   apartheid
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   stripper
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female nudity
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   shovel
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   student
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Darrell Roodt
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Greg Latter
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Darrell Roodt
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Ice Cube
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Elizabeth Hurley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Thokozani Nkosi
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I got your boy right here......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vusi returns to the South African village he left as a young to bury his father. He meets up with his brother Ernest, who tells him their other brother Stephen couldn't be contacted. Vusi goes to Johannesburg to find him, but at first can only find his neighbour, Karin, a stripper. Vusi proceeds to learn how conditions have changed since the end of apartheid, not always for the better...... Ice Cube takes a trip, and its not long into the film before he could be anywhere. I mean S. Africa has some beautiful locations, but no, we focus on Cube and how many times he has a gun pointed to his head. He searches for his brother, who owes some money to special guest star Rhames, and takes a very wooden Hurley along for the ride ( this proves that Austin Powers was a one off)' a very long and boring ride. If this tries to deliver any sort of political message, it fails, because the characters are just so unlikable, even the faceless girlfriend of Cube. All people seem to do is kill, and take drugs in Dangerous Ground world, and the only decent people kill goats. Its really a pig of a film, but the supporting cast are really good, and really make your blood boil. On the plus side its the best film ever to feature Ving Rhames making chicken noises come the end...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Message wrapped in bad writing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bookwormgal
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes Hurley's accent gads all over the place but that is how English South Africans sound like (I should know I'm married to one). However the plot does meander all over the place, and with someone like Ice Cube and the general premise of the movie there should definitely be more action in it. Roodt should take some lessons from Hood because Tsotsi delivered on the same basic message whileas Dangerous Ground just comes off as a mildly entertaining, barely passable TV movie. While it has its good points (accurate SA visuals for the time depicted, accurate depiction of Afrikaneer thugs and black Tsotsi's) there are points where the acting needs to be taken up a notch or two. And of course the writing is so thin and predictable if it was a dress it'd be see-through. I don't think it's as horrible as the first reviewer (mainly because I have been to Johannesburg and it DOES look that old an worn-out) but agree that the writing and acting was not up to par.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hurley & Cube were Hot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    whpratt1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great acting by Ice Cube,(Vusi Madlazi) and Elizabeth Hurley,(Karen),"Method",'04 helped the viewer enjoy most of this film which dealt strictly with a wild goose chase in a large City in South Africa. Vusi Madlazi lives in San Francisco and his immediate family live in South Africa and his father dies and the family needs the help of Vusi to try and locate his brother. Apparently his brother is mixed up with drugs and gambling and some bad dudes are also interested in finding him. Elizabeth Hurley,(Karen),"Method",'04 is a good friend of Vusi's brother and meets up with Vusi who she immediately gets the hots for. However, Vusi has a girl friend in San Francisco who he is very serious with and could possibly marry her. I praise the great acting of Ice Cube and Elizabeth Hurley, who made this a some what interesting film. In other words, it is not a very great film and has so many twists and turns, you really begin to lose interest completely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peace63
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ice Cube has the ability to look human and down to earth, and that makes him a very believable character in most of his movies. Spoilers: In ON DANGEROUS GROUND, he is the older brother who returns to South Africa after many years "in exile" in the USA. His father has died, and his younger brother is missing. His other brother is frustrated with the new post-apartheid South Africa, and Cube will soon discover that drugs and crime have replaced racial oppression in South Africa. The movie moves along at a good pace. It is not too fast, a bit of action mixed with investigation. Cube sets out to find his missing brother, and meets Elizabeth Hurley, who is not very convincing as a Stripper-Crack Addict who is Steven's girlfriend. She looks too good, and too happy. If Crack Cocaine Addicts can look as gorgeous as Elizabeth...?? Aside from Elizabeth's beauty, the rest of the story is pretty solid, and Ice Cube does a good job in his role as someone who grew up in America and is returning to the native country that has changed a lot since he was a youth. There are some interesting twists when Cube finds his brother Steven, and those twists are what make this movie really good. Ving Rhames plays a really obnoxious Drug Lord in this film. Rhames really works hard on being arrogant and overbearing, and his final destination must have brought cheers of joy to any audience. The ending is not very realistic, but it was uplifting. The idea of Elizabeth Hurley living in a mud hut in the middle of the desert in South Africa was worth a chuckle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad Direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ampers
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Enjoyed the film, although nothing to write home about, and actually thought Liz Hurley played her part well, although I don't like her very much. I know a little Zulu and one scene fascinated me. It was at a funeral in the kraal of Ice Cube's family. He is supposed to be a Xhosa (ko-sa), but I swear the others were speaking in Zulu. I may be wrong, but if right, this is extremely amusing as the Zulus and Xhosas tend to start killing each other from the age of around twelve! I wondered why, when they were supposed to be at a funeral, they seemed to be laughing, perhaps they saw the funny side. :-) If I am right, then the producer and director ought to be shot for employing zulu actors playing Xhosa people, yet speaking Zulu.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Meaningful "gangsta" movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gorilla Punk
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ice Cube, believe it or not, was convincing as a scholarly South African exile who returns home after the end of apartheid. I felt this movie had more meaning than any other typical "gangsta" movie. I also enjoyed Elizabeth Hurley. Sure, some parts weren't believable, including the very last scene, which was really lame, but overall, I liked Dangerous Ground. Very few films have been made about South Africa, and I'm glad movie writers have managed to look beyond South Central L.A. for a black action thriller setting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ouch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    screamingfoot
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this on some lame cable channel that edited out certain things, and eliminated swearing ("bulldirt?"). The only reason I watched this was the Elizabeth Hurley credit in the beginning. She wasn't nearly naked enough. It's admirable that the producer's tried to make a movie with a message, but the social commentary was undeveloped, and not very moving. I just wanted to see Elizabeth Hurley after the first 3 minutes, and that's all I had to look forward to, once it became apparent that this movie SUCKED! The screenplay, and direction were laughable, and it seemed that the writer of this thing had no idea how people speak in South Africa. The ending showdown scene has been done to death, and was as cliche as the rest of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A punchline betraying not a jot of joy or insight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tom May (joycean_chap@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This 'motion picture' is an absolute joke. It simply cannot be taken seriously; taking on the South African situation and inserting Ice Cube and Elizabeth Hurley just about sums it up. And it can't even be 'taken humorously' as the whole charade is so utterly joyless and deadly dull. This film is clich&eacute;-addled in the extreme; South Africa is presented, pretty much, as any old place; only distinguished by the occasional accent and the excessive crime rate. Any sense of reality is out of the equation, as is entertaining or useful usage of melodrama or other non-naturalistic forms. One has to laugh really; there's nothing else to do when you are presented with the posturing and faux-sincerity invested in the film by its average team of actors. But it is a hollow laugh, betraying not a jot of joy or insight. The weak storyline, which does not engage the mind on any level, is sketched out through dialogue by turns dull and absurd. As ever in 'serious' films inflected by her presence, Liz Hurley is a liability. The woman just cannot act it seems; thus, she seems more effective simply hamming up her own image in "Austin Powers: International Man of Mystery" and "Bedazzled". Her attempts at a South Africa accent gad around all over the globe; an embarrassingly inept effort, in truth. Yes, she 'looks good', depending quite upon one's own tastes, but it appears that that is the only reason she is here - along with her ubiquitous, 'dat skirt'-fuelled star name. So, a damn well disastrous film, and a real waste of time spent watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tries to be meaningful but is really one big smug clich&eacute; with a stupid confused message
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When South African native Vusi returns from 15 years in America he finds himself a stranger in his own home. He has come to bury his father but is asked by his mother to find his youngest brother who has gone missing in Johannesburg. Checking out an address Vusi meets one of his brothers friends Karin, and finds that his brother has stolen money from a drug dealer - creating more problems for Vusi as Muki is willing to kill to get his money back. This starts with flashbacks to South Africa during the early 80's, where we find Ice Cube ys, you heard me  was one of the student leaders of the uprising for change. Years later he returns, bringing with him a heavy monologue that lectures us about drugs being the new trap for the black man and how he must help the kids etc. The story itself never really gets interesting  the only interest is the possibility to learn about life in S. Africa, however even that is a bit stereotyped. The monologue makes the film feel even heavier than it is, but when the film eventually settles in the guns n' gangstas ending that it promises it appears to have confused itself. The film lectures about making the right choice as men, about the evils of drugs  in fact Vusi makes it his mission in USA and S. Africa to help kids stay in education etc. However after all that lecturing, a happy ending only comes with murder, violence and guns  is that the films message? That drugs are bad and are a global trap for the black man and the only way to stop them is to leave education programmes and murder anyone involved in the deals? I wouldn't have seen it this way if it had just set itself out as another thriller with an African twist, but because it is message heavy until it gets guns, I feel that it wanted to have it both ways when it can't. Ice Cube is watchable, even when he is in rubbish films, here he is OK but is really pushing the laid-back yank thing too much. His voice over is so preachy and monotonous that at times I thought he was falling asleep in the studio. Hurley looks sexy (despite working in a strip cub where no-one gets naked!) but her accent wanders all over the place  from English to African and back again. Ving Rhames plays a sort of African Marcellus Wallace  the first dialogue scene he has all we see is the back of his headvery Pulp Fiction. His accent is good but his character is nothing new. Overall this `action' movie is dull  the interesting cast make it worth one watch but no more than that. The mix of `stay in school kids' and `just say no' is too heavy and labourious, but is made even more pointless by the film's conclusion that the best way to deal with criminals destroying an area is to get guns and kill them!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cube!Hollywood B-movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenandraf
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cube and Hurley do ok performances here in this below average action/drama.Big Cube and Hurley fans will tolerate this one.Ruined by bad screenplay,script and directing.The action sequences in the end is very cliche and un-original.Good to see Cube blasting away though.He has so much potential.......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I got your boy right here......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vusi returns to the South African village he left as a young to bury his father. He meets up with his brother Ernest, who tells him their other brother Stephen couldn't be contacted. Vusi goes to Johannesburg to find him, but at first can only find his neighbour, Karin, a stripper. Vusi proceeds to learn how conditions have changed since the end of apartheid, not always for the better...... Ice Cube takes a trip, and its not long into the film before he could be anywhere. I mean S. Africa has some beautiful locations, but no, we focus on Cube and how many times he has a gun pointed to his head. He searches for his brother, who owes some money to special guest star Rhames, and takes a very wooden Hurley along for the ride ( this proves that Austin Powers was a one off)' a very long and boring ride. If this tries to deliver any sort of political message, it fails, because the characters are just so unlikable, even the faceless girlfriend of Cube. All people seem to do is kill, and take drugs in Dangerous Ground world, and the only decent people kill goats. Its really a pig of a film, but the supporting cast are really good, and really make your blood boil. On the plus side its the best film ever to feature Ving Rhames making chicken noises come the end...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Message wrapped in bad writing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bookwormgal
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes Hurley's accent gads all over the place but that is how English South Africans sound like (I should know I'm married to one). However the plot does meander all over the place, and with someone like Ice Cube and the general premise of the movie there should definitely be more action in it. Roodt should take some lessons from Hood because Tsotsi delivered on the same basic message whileas Dangerous Ground just comes off as a mildly entertaining, barely passable TV movie. While it has its good points (accurate SA visuals for the time depicted, accurate depiction of Afrikaneer thugs and black Tsotsi's) there are points where the acting needs to be taken up a notch or two. And of course the writing is so thin and predictable if it was a dress it'd be see-through. I don't think it's as horrible as the first reviewer (mainly because I have been to Johannesburg and it DOES look that old an worn-out) but agree that the writing and acting was not up to par.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hurley & Cube were Hot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    whpratt1
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The great acting by Ice Cube,(Vusi Madlazi) and Elizabeth Hurley,(Karen),"Method",'04 helped the viewer enjoy most of this film which dealt strictly with a wild goose chase in a large City in South Africa. Vusi Madlazi lives in San Francisco and his immediate family live in South Africa and his father dies and the family needs the help of Vusi to try and locate his brother. Apparently his brother is mixed up with drugs and gambling and some bad dudes are also interested in finding him. Elizabeth Hurley,(Karen),"Method",'04 is a good friend of Vusi's brother and meets up with Vusi who she immediately gets the hots for. However, Vusi has a girl friend in San Francisco who he is very serious with and could possibly marry her. I praise the great acting of Ice Cube and Elizabeth Hurley, who made this a some what interesting film. In other words, it is not a very great film and has so many twists and turns, you really begin to lose interest completely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    peace63
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ice Cube has the ability to look human and down to earth, and that makes him a very believable character in most of his movies. Spoilers: In ON DANGEROUS GROUND, he is the older brother who returns to South Africa after many years "in exile" in the USA. His father has died, and his younger brother is missing. His other brother is frustrated with the new post-apartheid South Africa, and Cube will soon discover that drugs and crime have replaced racial oppression in South Africa. The movie moves along at a good pace. It is not too fast, a bit of action mixed with investigation. Cube sets out to find his missing brother, and meets Elizabeth Hurley, who is not very convincing as a Stripper-Crack Addict who is Steven's girlfriend. She looks too good, and too happy. If Crack Cocaine Addicts can look as gorgeous as Elizabeth...?? Aside from Elizabeth's beauty, the rest of the story is pretty solid, and Ice Cube does a good job in his role as someone who grew up in America and is returning to the native country that has changed a lot since he was a youth. There are some interesting twists when Cube finds his brother Steven, and those twists are what make this movie really good. Ving Rhames plays a really obnoxious Drug Lord in this film. Rhames really works hard on being arrogant and overbearing, and his final destination must have brought cheers of joy to any audience. The ending is not very realistic, but it was uplifting. The idea of Elizabeth Hurley living in a mud hut in the middle of the desert in South Africa was worth a chuckle.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad Direction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ampers
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Enjoyed the film, although nothing to write home about, and actually thought Liz Hurley played her part well, although I don't like her very much. I know a little Zulu and one scene fascinated me. It was at a funeral in the kraal of Ice Cube's family. He is supposed to be a Xhosa (ko-sa), but I swear the others were speaking in Zulu. I may be wrong, but if right, this is extremely amusing as the Zulus and Xhosas tend to start killing each other from the age of around twelve! I wondered why, when they were supposed to be at a funeral, they seemed to be laughing, perhaps they saw the funny side. :-) If I am right, then the producer and director ought to be shot for employing zulu actors playing Xhosa people, yet speaking Zulu.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Meaningful "gangsta" movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gorilla Punk
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ice Cube, believe it or not, was convincing as a scholarly South African exile who returns home after the end of apartheid. I felt this movie had more meaning than any other typical "gangsta" movie. I also enjoyed Elizabeth Hurley. Sure, some parts weren't believable, including the very last scene, which was really lame, but overall, I liked Dangerous Ground. Very few films have been made about South Africa, and I'm glad movie writers have managed to look beyond South Central L.A. for a black action thriller setting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ouch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    screamingfoot
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2003
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched this on some lame cable channel that edited out certain things, and eliminated swearing ("bulldirt?"). The only reason I watched this was the Elizabeth Hurley credit in the beginning. She wasn't nearly naked enough. It's admirable that the producer's tried to make a movie with a message, but the social commentary was undeveloped, and not very moving. I just wanted to see Elizabeth Hurley after the first 3 minutes, and that's all I had to look forward to, once it became apparent that this movie SUCKED! The screenplay, and direction were laughable, and it seemed that the writer of this thing had no idea how people speak in South Africa. The ending showdown scene has been done to death, and was as cliche as the rest of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A punchline betraying not a jot of joy or insight
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tom May (joycean_chap@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This 'motion picture' is an absolute joke. It simply cannot be taken seriously; taking on the South African situation and inserting Ice Cube and Elizabeth Hurley just about sums it up. And it can't even be 'taken humorously' as the whole charade is so utterly joyless and deadly dull. This film is clich&eacute;-addled in the extreme; South Africa is presented, pretty much, as any old place; only distinguished by the occasional accent and the excessive crime rate. Any sense of reality is out of the equation, as is entertaining or useful usage of melodrama or other non-naturalistic forms. One has to laugh really; there's nothing else to do when you are presented with the posturing and faux-sincerity invested in the film by its average team of actors. But it is a hollow laugh, betraying not a jot of joy or insight. The weak storyline, which does not engage the mind on any level, is sketched out through dialogue by turns dull and absurd. As ever in 'serious' films inflected by her presence, Liz Hurley is a liability. The woman just cannot act it seems; thus, she seems more effective simply hamming up her own image in "Austin Powers: International Man of Mystery" and "Bedazzled". Her attempts at a South Africa accent gad around all over the globe; an embarrassingly inept effort, in truth. Yes, she 'looks good', depending quite upon one's own tastes, but it appears that that is the only reason she is here - along with her ubiquitous, 'dat skirt'-fuelled star name. So, a damn well disastrous film, and a real waste of time spent watching it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tries to be meaningful but is really one big smug clich&eacute; with a stupid confused message
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bob the moo
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/4/2002
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When South African native Vusi returns from 15 years in America he finds himself a stranger in his own home. He has come to bury his father but is asked by his mother to find his youngest brother who has gone missing in Johannesburg. Checking out an address Vusi meets one of his brothers friends Karin, and finds that his brother has stolen money from a drug dealer - creating more problems for Vusi as Muki is willing to kill to get his money back. This starts with flashbacks to South Africa during the early 80's, where we find Ice Cube ys, you heard me  was one of the student leaders of the uprising for change. Years later he returns, bringing with him a heavy monologue that lectures us about drugs being the new trap for the black man and how he must help the kids etc. The story itself never really gets interesting  the only interest is the possibility to learn about life in S. Africa, however even that is a bit stereotyped. The monologue makes the film feel even heavier than it is, but when the film eventually settles in the guns n' gangstas ending that it promises it appears to have confused itself. The film lectures about making the right choice as men, about the evils of drugs  in fact Vusi makes it his mission in USA and S. Africa to help kids stay in education etc. However after all that lecturing, a happy ending only comes with murder, violence and guns  is that the films message? That drugs are bad and are a global trap for the black man and the only way to stop them is to leave education programmes and murder anyone involved in the deals? I wouldn't have seen it this way if it had just set itself out as another thriller with an African twist, but because it is message heavy until it gets guns, I feel that it wanted to have it both ways when it can't. Ice Cube is watchable, even when he is in rubbish films, here he is OK but is really pushing the laid-back yank thing too much. His voice over is so preachy and monotonous that at times I thought he was falling asleep in the studio. Hurley looks sexy (despite working in a strip cub where no-one gets naked!) but her accent wanders all over the place  from English to African and back again. Ving Rhames plays a sort of African Marcellus Wallace  the first dialogue scene he has all we see is the back of his headvery Pulp Fiction. His accent is good but his character is nothing new. Overall this `action' movie is dull  the interesting cast make it worth one watch but no more than that. The mix of `stay in school kids' and `just say no' is too heavy and labourious, but is made even more pointless by the film's conclusion that the best way to deal with criminals destroying an area is to get guns and kill them!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cube!Hollywood B-movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kenandraf
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2001
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cube and Hurley do ok performances here in this below average action/drama.Big Cube and Hurley fans will tolerate this one.Ruined by bad screenplay,script and directing.The action sequences in the end is very cliche and un-original.Good to see Cube blasting away though.He has so much potential.......
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
