<filme>
 <id>
  989
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118829
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Gatos N&atilde;o Sabem Dan&ccedil;ar
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Danny, an ambitious singing/dancing cat, goes to Hollywood and overcomes several obstacles to fulfill his dream of becoming a movie star.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Danny, an ambitious singing/dancing cat, goes to Hollywood and overcomes several obstacles to fulfill his dream of becoming a movie star.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Animation
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   cat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   star
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hollywood
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   animal
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   child star
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Mark Dindal
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Mark Dindal
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Robert Lence
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Scott Bakula
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jasmine Guy
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Natalie Cole
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit over the top.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I caught a rendering of a scene on Deviant Art, and was told that the scene was from an animated feature called "Cats Don't Dance". I took a chance on it, and saw a film that I think could have been better than it ultimately became. When I think of classic MGM cartoons I immediately think of Tom and Jerry, Droopy, Screwy Squirrel and a few others. Well, "Cats Don't Dance" is none of those, but it does have a certain charm. A lot of the classic ultra violent slapstick that is that hallmark of the classic cartoon has been replaced with high energy benign comic styleings that, to be honest, don't really hit the mark. I'm sorry, but even kids know that comedy is the misfortune of others, largely because it makes us feel superior to the poor guy who suffers misfortune, because he's done so through his own stupidity. Now, not all humor has its genesis in laughing at the other guy's plight, as there are a lot of humorous things that can be done through expressions, reactions and close calls of all sorts. But when you strictly base humor solely on the benign, or rather delegate the bad- taste humor because it involves cartoon violence to the "black hats" in the piece, then you're making a value judgment that the public is smart enough to figure out. People can get swept up in trends and hysteria, but to presuppose that children, or specifically all children, will mimic violent slapstick, is perhaps not unrealistic, but perhaps making too much of an assumption of the human character (regardless of age). And that's the real problem with this film. It tries to make up for a lack of humor by injecting tons of energy into every routine, every bit, every gag that's displayed for the audience. It thus feels like a quickly put together patch job of gags that were story boarded and retrofitted to a basic story and plot. The voice acting is fine, the sound effects and other facets of the production are first rate, but, as I say, we essentially have a neutered production. The small evil Shirley Temple like antagonist is over the top and clich&eacute;, the protagonist is clich&eacute;, pretty much the whole array of characters are from central casting. Even so Bakula and Guy do a respectable job of thesping the part, but they're hard pressed to carry a production that has other issues. To be honest it's not a production I'd take my kids to see (if I had any). Not because it's offensive or lacks morals, it's just not that good, and at times is so high energy as to be incomprehensible. Give it a whirl if you must, but watch at your own risk. An okay production, but nothing sterling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing's gonna stop me from loving this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ZachTheRunner
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing's more of a nostalgic movie for me than Cats Don't Dance, the energetic animated musical of Hollywood, passion, and the pursuit of dreams that is the most criminally underrated movie I have ever seen in my life. We are introduced to Danny, a cat full of ambition and dreams of making it AS A STAR! He arrives in Hollywood and quickly meets the other wonderful cast of animals: Tilly Hippo, Cranston Goat, T.W Turtle, later Woolly Mammoth, and another cat simply named Sawyer; who is not too pleased with Danny's dream-chasing, singing and dancing attitude. Shortly after the introduction to the others, he lands a spot on the latest movie "Little Ark Angel" starring "America's Sweetheart, Lover of Children and Animals" Darla Dimple: who's pretty much a cross between Shirley Temple, Baby-Doll from the animated Batman, and a Disney villain. While filming the movie, Danny makes himself noticed much to the displeasure of Darla who shows her true colors as a spoiled little munchkin who again is as heinously evil as some of Disneys most evil villains. Which results in the calling of the gargantuan servant of Darla known as Max, which results in Max teaching Danny a lesson that I'm not gonna lie is actually pretty funny. After that happens, we find out why no one liked his little number and why Sawyer is so despondent toward Danny. We find out that Hollywood, for no clear reason, wants talented human actors and not talented animals. And the other characters we've met have talent that was wrongfully overlooked, Sawyer being both the most promising and seemingly the most broken of the group. But Danny, still wanting to follow his dream, tries to convince the others to do the same. The result: the rest of the movie. If I took out the nostalgia, I would love Cats Don't Dance all the same. I love how fun it is, I love how sincere it is, but mostly I love how passionate and driven it is. Its not a flawless movie; some of the singing voices sound a bit odd when compared to the talking voices. Danny isn't THAT well developed but not enough that I think he brought the film down. But aside from a few nitpicks I truly do love it. The music is done by Randy Newman. And while I don't "love" Randy Newman, this is really good. The songs are both catchy and fit the moods appropriately. The orchestral work is impressive as well, fitting the 1930s Hollywood setting perfectly. The animation is fantastic too; offering a familiar Warner Bros. animation feel. Honestly, I love this movie. I love everything about it. It's great, fun to watch, memorable and very underrated. I love the characters, the music, the animation, the drama; but mostly the passion. Its serious nostalgia for me, and people should definitely watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    But they're expected to put on a helluva show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cats Don't Dance has gone down in history as one of the biggest risks in animation yet. It is one of the few full length animated features not to bare the Disney name, yet comes off as one just as cheerful and safe for kids. Clearly, parents didn't believe so, or possibly they didn't hear about the film due to Turner Feature Animation's miserable marketing tactics, not to mention the competition of the re-release of a Star Wars movie and Disney's film Hercules. Because of all those factors, Cats Don't Dance was a monstrous bomb, all the more considering it was an animated film, which are always expected to gross at least double their budget, and it remains as a curious piece of history and nostalgia. It comes off as so cheery and genial, that as you watch it, the name "Disney" never comes to mind. It's in a league of its own, where pitch-perfect realism doesn't always come first, and fun and livelihood always lead the way. It's a unique experience. The story concerns Danny (voiced by Scott Bakula), a plucky and anxious cat who leaves his humble roots in Kokomo, Indiana to travel to Hollywood, where he can hopefully make it big as an actor. One roadblock, he's a cat, and Hollywood's places for cats are few and far between. He manages to get cast in a movie with Darla Dimple (Ashley Peldon), a spoiled, heavily-pampered child actress who turns maniacal and practically evil as soon as the cameras stop rolling. Along the way, the naive soul runs into Sawyer (Jasmine Guy), a beautiful, yet heavily pessimistic female cat, who Danny is immediately smitten with. Sawyer explains how Hollywood's attitude towards animals would seem inviting, when it is just morose and neglectful towards the idea of stepping outside the box. This sort of makes Cats Don't Dance's life come full circle. Think of it as Danny. He steps out of his natural roots to find fame in Hollywood, winds up getting the cold shoulder, until the inevitable happens and he is looked on with great satisfaction. Now think of the film's life. It stepped out of the clich&eacute; Disney light, was created and brought to life by a studio no one knew, was ignored pretty much by everyone during its initial release, yet is looked on as a classic animated gem by many in the present. If serendipity could talk... The animation is beautiful. Rambunctiously neat, and very, very eye-appealing. Not to continue to rain on the film's parade, but at this point in time (1997), we were already met with the genius of Pixar and their groundbreaking film Toy Story. We knew all of what animation can do, and once you see what seems to be the best, do you have much interest in the rest? Regardless, this is sort of what I adore about Cats Don't Dance; it plays by its own rules. It's so lightweight and non-intrusive that it doesn't seem to care it's not on par with other pictures of its own league. It isn't heavy-handed or on a moral rush. It's just looking for a good time. One thing I enjoyed were the musical numbers, which are delightfully sung, wonderfully crafted, and beautifully choreographed with such kinetic energy. I believe the more exposure or knowledge you have with Hollywood, cinema, and how the big guys manipulate the little ones, the more you'll be inclined to enjoy Cats Don't Dance. It's one of the cheeriest films I've seen all year. Voiced by: Scott Bakula, Jasmine Guy, Natalie Cole, Ashley Peldon, John Rhys-Davies, Kathy Najimy, and Don Knotts. Directed by: Mark Dindal.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute, funny and incredibly enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the nineties, there were several attempts made by different studios in order to emulate the style from the animated films that the Disney company were producing at those years (Such as "Aladdin", "Beauty and the Beast" and "The Lion King") Some of those attempts were corny and lame, but fortunately, this nice animated film (Which was also the first animated movie directed by Mark Dindal, the same director "The Emperor's New Groove") instead of trying to imitate the Disney formula, prefers to be a light-hearted homage to all the classic musicals from the Golden Age of Hollywood, worked incredibly well in that aspect. The plot is fast-paced, but easy to follow, with very likable characters, and many funny situations and clever dialogues, not to mention the incredibly catchy songs, that were the best part of the movie. From my very personal point of view, I think that the combination of all those elements worked much better than in "The Emperor's New Groove" (Which is also a good movie, but I like this more) This is a nice movie for the whole family, and I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darla Steals the Show!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    idonnowho
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure, the animals were kinda cool, but, if you ask me, the REAL STAR (she'd certainly be pleased to hear me say that) was Darla Dimple. A beautiful little blonde girl, who, for some reason, was the VILLAIN. That may or may not have been for the better, because at least she certainly was far from completely saccharine (i.e. Anne-Marie in "All Dogs Go to Heaven" or Dot in "A Bug's Life") as she may have been if she were a good guy... Still, I couldn't help but feel sorry for her, maybe because she's just a kid, or maybe because she resembles (in terms of her appearance ONLY, and NOT personality) the sweet girl, short in stature, curly blonde hair, at my school, Zoezonna Brennan. Unlike Darla, who was cool and all, Zoe's just a nice girl (FAR from sickeningly sweet, though) and makes me feel love and compassion towards her. Anyways, a VERY interesting and satisfying film! 9/10 stars! You ARE the STAR, Darla Dimple! (AND YOU, ZOE, EVEN MORESO!!!!) :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    See you in the movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ravsten428
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cat's Don't Dance may not be what most movie buffs would call a classic cartoon. It's not made by a big name company but it is a good movie nonetheless. Danny is a cat who wants to make it big in Hollywood. He leaves his town of Kokomo, Indiana to head for big dreams. Once he gets to Hollywood he makes his debut in a film that mostly belongs to the cute but really evil Darla Dimple. Danny tests her patience by not saying his line but rather singing it. She is not happy and reminds him that he needs to know his place in the film as an animal. Danny is determined to make a name for himself and his friends Sawyer, Tilly, Cranston, Pudge and a few others. Sawyer a female cat tries to persuade him out of trying to have dreams because he is only an animal and they are treated differently and aren't given the bigger roles in films. After awhile he gets all his friends and the animals in Hollywood to realize that they are worth it. Darla doesn't like what she sees and decides that she is going to try and sabotage the animals from starring in any future films. She tells Danny that he needs to put on a show and make it big and loud. Danny however doesn't realize that it is a scam. Darla ruins their show and Danny and all the other animals get kicked out of the studios. Danny decides to head back home but after he is on a bus and sees Pudge being pushed around he comes up with a plan that helps his friends and the other animals to make it back into the filming industry. He makes it big for himself and wins back his support from his friends and ends up winning Sawyer's affection. Darla ends up being defeated and you see her having to put up movie posters at the very end of the credits. Cat's Don't Dance may not be big on special effects but it doesn't have to be. It sells itself with a great story and anybody who watches it probably won't be let down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Amazing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sonicfan21
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anyone remember 'Singin' in the Rain'? Well, this is quite the little knockoff.. a great one. Musical actors take part in an animated feature almost as great as the old movie. But with a spoiled child actress and cats. Danny is a naive but friendly cat who is picked to star in Darla Dimples' "Lil' Ark Angel", quite similar to the Shirley Temple movies and star. This cat becomes baffled by his line of "Meow" while a child (who's name is Darla) comes in and wreaks havoc. Her main plot is the cause trouble and lies about liking animals. The script is superb, much like something Pixar would make. The animation is good. The acting was magnificent. Ashley Pendon's voice was great and I loved her singing voice... Lindsey did great. And the characters' voices to the animals sounded and reminded me much like the ones in 'All Dogs Go To Heaven'. Not to mention, the music was great and my favorite has to be the final song. This movie will bring an instant smile to faces of children and adults alike. It will reminisce childhood memories and will never be forgotten. Always remember that 'Cats Don't Dance' is a heartwarming and lighthearted movie that will be in your heart... young or old.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fast-paced movie with a deliciously devilish antagonist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dean Richard Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm definitely not familiar with Mark Dindal, but kudos to him for making one heck of an animation. It's rather different, kiddish and yet there's stuff for adults too, it's fast-paced and yet there's some slow scenes, and all together it just ridiculously fun. Together with its cast of famous actors which includes John Rhys-Davies (Gimli in LOTR), Don Knotts (Andy Griffith Show, of course), and even Betty Lou Garson (the original Cruella De Vil). WARNING: if you want to see this movie, brace yourself for major Wackiness. The story follows optimisticsometimes air-headedDanny the Cat who journeys to Hollywood from Kokomo to fulfill his dream of becoming a star, but his ambition is trampled by the pernicious vile child star Miss Darla Dimple. Danny finds a band of unlikely dreamers consisting of a grumpy grandpa goat, a sweet yet over-social hippo, a Bette Davis style Fish, a pudgy penguin kid who just loves to eat (yeah, and he's pretty annoying too), a poor turtle who relies on his fortune cookies to determine his day, and last but not least Sawyer the cat who believes her dreams have been completely crushed. Together the wacky dreamers try to prove even "different species" can be stars, before the lovelymore like loathsomeDarla smashes their dreams to smithereens. Believe me; so many loony scenes are in this movie: Tilly Hippo and her ridiculous introducing method, the unbelievable flooding of Hollywood, any scene with Max and Darla, that eccentric director and many more! I just found it way too wacky when I was little. The intro cast was a great opening (and those jiving moles!). This is a 90's film so the animation is so-so and slightly incomplete, though I loved how they did Sawyer. This is a kid's flick so everything was berzerkly colorful. The voice acting was great for an animation like this (especially Ashley Peldon as Darla). The dialogue was simple and clean. Almost every scene is musical, there's music going on every where! the songs themselves gave such a good vibe. "I Got Rhythm" was very nice with a those animals! I rated this movie a 6 star because it's a fair animation, sincere movie; it's a little TOO fast-paced though (75 minutes, people!) and it's unrealistic, of course. The message is the usual fallow your dreams. Like I said before, brace yourself for wackiness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overall, a nice animated family feature, but one with an almost unbearable antagonist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This does not appear to be one of the most widely recognized animated films of the 90's, but I did see it once on video during that decade. I guess that would have been shortly after the movie came into stores. It definitely wasn't up there with certain other animated films I saw in my childhood, but I think I found it fairly entertaining. After that, I didn't see "Cats Don't Dance" again until this year, I think just a few weeks ago. It seemed to be well-liked among those who have seen it, so I wasn't expecting a lacklustre effort. However, I didn't like it much during what was my first viewing in a long time. A few weeks later, I've already given it another try. I think it did improve with this viewing, but a lot of it still didn't really impress me. Danny is an ambitious cat who leaves his hometown of Kokomo, Indiana to pursue a career in Hollywood. Very soon after arriving at his destination, he gets a role in a film with Darla Dimple, a child star who is known as "America's Sweetheart, Lover of Children and Animals." He is very excited about his role, until he learns that all he gets to say is "meow" and he doesn't get to dance and sing. When Danny tries to spice up his role, he soon sees Ms. Dimple's true colours and how misleading her on screen persona really is! She is actually a horribly spoiled, selfish, mean-spirited brat with a giant valet named Max, who makes sure she always gets her way! It turns out that animals only get to be extras in Hollywood, so Danny begins to work with other animals to try and change this and show Tinseltown their true talent, but Ms. Dimple knows this could threaten her career if they succeed, so she is determined to foil their plan! When the film begins, we soon see that the animation is nicely colourful and pleasing to the eye, but for at least a while, the movie is a little too fast-paced, making it less effective than it could be. There are some fairly funny parts early on, such as Danny accidentally slamming Sawyer's (a cat secretary in Hollywood who becomes a major part of the story) tail in a door, and the look she gives him, but at this point, I had trouble really getting into the film. It isn't long before Darla Dimple, the antagonist, comes into the story. This character is clearly supposed to be funny, but she didn't amuse me very much. I did not care for her loudness, faces, etc. After a while, the film improves. It eventually didn't seem quite as fast to me and the story got more intriguing, though Ms. Dimple continues to be hardly bearable in the scenes she appears in. The animal characters are generally likable, and viewers can easily find themselves rooting for them. The movie also has an interesting premise and some funny moments, even if there aren't as many good laughs as there are supposed to be. There are times when I'm not 100% sure about my rating for a movie, and this is one of those cases. I most definitely can't say I absolutely LOVE this movie like many others do, but feel I could be giving it a seven out of ten instead of a six. In fact, without the antics of the Darla Dimple character, I might not have any reason to give "Cats Don't Dance" a rating any lower than seven. It seems most people who have seen this 1997 animated feature like it more than I do, but I can still understand its appeal, as it certainly does have its charm. I wouldn't complain if it were to ever gain more recognition. The pace around the beginning, the antagonist, the film's songs which are not exactly bad but not the most memorable numbers for an animated musical, and maybe occasionally some other problems (minor ones) make the movie lose points, but there's also a lot to like. While this film can't match a number of other full-length animations made in the same decade, you could still easily find that it's good family fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant change of pace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Sirman
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film does what few animated musicals attempt but fail to accomplish. The energy and feeling of an old silver screen musical. Gene Kelly would be proud. The animation is quite the throwback to the Chuck Jones era of cartoons. The city is wonderfully drawn and given a slight art deco feel. The voice acting is spot on for all of the characters and the singing talent is some of the best. Randy Newman does a wonderful job of scoring this film. His musical arrangements are upbeat and fun when need be and pull at your heart's strings at the right time. It's quite sad that this film was brushed under the carpet by Warner Bros. The lack of popularity, besides not being a Disney movie, could also be due to the fact that the story deals with a subject that not many kids are familiar with, Racism. But the older audience will really appreciate this movie on a whole different level. Cats Don't Dance was a film that was destined to fail but at the same time left to be one of the best animations of our time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit over the top.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I caught a rendering of a scene on Deviant Art, and was told that the scene was from an animated feature called "Cats Don't Dance". I took a chance on it, and saw a film that I think could have been better than it ultimately became. When I think of classic MGM cartoons I immediately think of Tom and Jerry, Droopy, Screwy Squirrel and a few others. Well, "Cats Don't Dance" is none of those, but it does have a certain charm. A lot of the classic ultra violent slapstick that is that hallmark of the classic cartoon has been replaced with high energy benign comic styleings that, to be honest, don't really hit the mark. I'm sorry, but even kids know that comedy is the misfortune of others, largely because it makes us feel superior to the poor guy who suffers misfortune, because he's done so through his own stupidity. Now, not all humor has its genesis in laughing at the other guy's plight, as there are a lot of humorous things that can be done through expressions, reactions and close calls of all sorts. But when you strictly base humor solely on the benign, or rather delegate the bad- taste humor because it involves cartoon violence to the "black hats" in the piece, then you're making a value judgment that the public is smart enough to figure out. People can get swept up in trends and hysteria, but to presuppose that children, or specifically all children, will mimic violent slapstick, is perhaps not unrealistic, but perhaps making too much of an assumption of the human character (regardless of age). And that's the real problem with this film. It tries to make up for a lack of humor by injecting tons of energy into every routine, every bit, every gag that's displayed for the audience. It thus feels like a quickly put together patch job of gags that were story boarded and retrofitted to a basic story and plot. The voice acting is fine, the sound effects and other facets of the production are first rate, but, as I say, we essentially have a neutered production. The small evil Shirley Temple like antagonist is over the top and clich&eacute;, the protagonist is clich&eacute;, pretty much the whole array of characters are from central casting. Even so Bakula and Guy do a respectable job of thesping the part, but they're hard pressed to carry a production that has other issues. To be honest it's not a production I'd take my kids to see (if I had any). Not because it's offensive or lacks morals, it's just not that good, and at times is so high energy as to be incomprehensible. Give it a whirl if you must, but watch at your own risk. An okay production, but nothing sterling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing's gonna stop me from loving this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ZachTheRunner
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing's more of a nostalgic movie for me than Cats Don't Dance, the energetic animated musical of Hollywood, passion, and the pursuit of dreams that is the most criminally underrated movie I have ever seen in my life. We are introduced to Danny, a cat full of ambition and dreams of making it AS A STAR! He arrives in Hollywood and quickly meets the other wonderful cast of animals: Tilly Hippo, Cranston Goat, T.W Turtle, later Woolly Mammoth, and another cat simply named Sawyer; who is not too pleased with Danny's dream-chasing, singing and dancing attitude. Shortly after the introduction to the others, he lands a spot on the latest movie "Little Ark Angel" starring "America's Sweetheart, Lover of Children and Animals" Darla Dimple: who's pretty much a cross between Shirley Temple, Baby-Doll from the animated Batman, and a Disney villain. While filming the movie, Danny makes himself noticed much to the displeasure of Darla who shows her true colors as a spoiled little munchkin who again is as heinously evil as some of Disneys most evil villains. Which results in the calling of the gargantuan servant of Darla known as Max, which results in Max teaching Danny a lesson that I'm not gonna lie is actually pretty funny. After that happens, we find out why no one liked his little number and why Sawyer is so despondent toward Danny. We find out that Hollywood, for no clear reason, wants talented human actors and not talented animals. And the other characters we've met have talent that was wrongfully overlooked, Sawyer being both the most promising and seemingly the most broken of the group. But Danny, still wanting to follow his dream, tries to convince the others to do the same. The result: the rest of the movie. If I took out the nostalgia, I would love Cats Don't Dance all the same. I love how fun it is, I love how sincere it is, but mostly I love how passionate and driven it is. Its not a flawless movie; some of the singing voices sound a bit odd when compared to the talking voices. Danny isn't THAT well developed but not enough that I think he brought the film down. But aside from a few nitpicks I truly do love it. The music is done by Randy Newman. And while I don't "love" Randy Newman, this is really good. The songs are both catchy and fit the moods appropriately. The orchestral work is impressive as well, fitting the 1930s Hollywood setting perfectly. The animation is fantastic too; offering a familiar Warner Bros. animation feel. Honestly, I love this movie. I love everything about it. It's great, fun to watch, memorable and very underrated. I love the characters, the music, the animation, the drama; but mostly the passion. Its serious nostalgia for me, and people should definitely watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    But they're expected to put on a helluva show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cats Don't Dance has gone down in history as one of the biggest risks in animation yet. It is one of the few full length animated features not to bare the Disney name, yet comes off as one just as cheerful and safe for kids. Clearly, parents didn't believe so, or possibly they didn't hear about the film due to Turner Feature Animation's miserable marketing tactics, not to mention the competition of the re-release of a Star Wars movie and Disney's film Hercules. Because of all those factors, Cats Don't Dance was a monstrous bomb, all the more considering it was an animated film, which are always expected to gross at least double their budget, and it remains as a curious piece of history and nostalgia. It comes off as so cheery and genial, that as you watch it, the name "Disney" never comes to mind. It's in a league of its own, where pitch-perfect realism doesn't always come first, and fun and livelihood always lead the way. It's a unique experience. The story concerns Danny (voiced by Scott Bakula), a plucky and anxious cat who leaves his humble roots in Kokomo, Indiana to travel to Hollywood, where he can hopefully make it big as an actor. One roadblock, he's a cat, and Hollywood's places for cats are few and far between. He manages to get cast in a movie with Darla Dimple (Ashley Peldon), a spoiled, heavily-pampered child actress who turns maniacal and practically evil as soon as the cameras stop rolling. Along the way, the naive soul runs into Sawyer (Jasmine Guy), a beautiful, yet heavily pessimistic female cat, who Danny is immediately smitten with. Sawyer explains how Hollywood's attitude towards animals would seem inviting, when it is just morose and neglectful towards the idea of stepping outside the box. This sort of makes Cats Don't Dance's life come full circle. Think of it as Danny. He steps out of his natural roots to find fame in Hollywood, winds up getting the cold shoulder, until the inevitable happens and he is looked on with great satisfaction. Now think of the film's life. It stepped out of the clich&eacute; Disney light, was created and brought to life by a studio no one knew, was ignored pretty much by everyone during its initial release, yet is looked on as a classic animated gem by many in the present. If serendipity could talk... The animation is beautiful. Rambunctiously neat, and very, very eye-appealing. Not to continue to rain on the film's parade, but at this point in time (1997), we were already met with the genius of Pixar and their groundbreaking film Toy Story. We knew all of what animation can do, and once you see what seems to be the best, do you have much interest in the rest? Regardless, this is sort of what I adore about Cats Don't Dance; it plays by its own rules. It's so lightweight and non-intrusive that it doesn't seem to care it's not on par with other pictures of its own league. It isn't heavy-handed or on a moral rush. It's just looking for a good time. One thing I enjoyed were the musical numbers, which are delightfully sung, wonderfully crafted, and beautifully choreographed with such kinetic energy. I believe the more exposure or knowledge you have with Hollywood, cinema, and how the big guys manipulate the little ones, the more you'll be inclined to enjoy Cats Don't Dance. It's one of the cheeriest films I've seen all year. Voiced by: Scott Bakula, Jasmine Guy, Natalie Cole, Ashley Peldon, John Rhys-Davies, Kathy Najimy, and Don Knotts. Directed by: Mark Dindal.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute, funny and incredibly enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the nineties, there were several attempts made by different studios in order to emulate the style from the animated films that the Disney company were producing at those years (Such as "Aladdin", "Beauty and the Beast" and "The Lion King") Some of those attempts were corny and lame, but fortunately, this nice animated film (Which was also the first animated movie directed by Mark Dindal, the same director "The Emperor's New Groove") instead of trying to imitate the Disney formula, prefers to be a light-hearted homage to all the classic musicals from the Golden Age of Hollywood, worked incredibly well in that aspect. The plot is fast-paced, but easy to follow, with very likable characters, and many funny situations and clever dialogues, not to mention the incredibly catchy songs, that were the best part of the movie. From my very personal point of view, I think that the combination of all those elements worked much better than in "The Emperor's New Groove" (Which is also a good movie, but I like this more) This is a nice movie for the whole family, and I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darla Steals the Show!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    idonnowho
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure, the animals were kinda cool, but, if you ask me, the REAL STAR (she'd certainly be pleased to hear me say that) was Darla Dimple. A beautiful little blonde girl, who, for some reason, was the VILLAIN. That may or may not have been for the better, because at least she certainly was far from completely saccharine (i.e. Anne-Marie in "All Dogs Go to Heaven" or Dot in "A Bug's Life") as she may have been if she were a good guy... Still, I couldn't help but feel sorry for her, maybe because she's just a kid, or maybe because she resembles (in terms of her appearance ONLY, and NOT personality) the sweet girl, short in stature, curly blonde hair, at my school, Zoezonna Brennan. Unlike Darla, who was cool and all, Zoe's just a nice girl (FAR from sickeningly sweet, though) and makes me feel love and compassion towards her. Anyways, a VERY interesting and satisfying film! 9/10 stars! You ARE the STAR, Darla Dimple! (AND YOU, ZOE, EVEN MORESO!!!!) :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    See you in the movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ravsten428
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cat's Don't Dance may not be what most movie buffs would call a classic cartoon. It's not made by a big name company but it is a good movie nonetheless. Danny is a cat who wants to make it big in Hollywood. He leaves his town of Kokomo, Indiana to head for big dreams. Once he gets to Hollywood he makes his debut in a film that mostly belongs to the cute but really evil Darla Dimple. Danny tests her patience by not saying his line but rather singing it. She is not happy and reminds him that he needs to know his place in the film as an animal. Danny is determined to make a name for himself and his friends Sawyer, Tilly, Cranston, Pudge and a few others. Sawyer a female cat tries to persuade him out of trying to have dreams because he is only an animal and they are treated differently and aren't given the bigger roles in films. After awhile he gets all his friends and the animals in Hollywood to realize that they are worth it. Darla doesn't like what she sees and decides that she is going to try and sabotage the animals from starring in any future films. She tells Danny that he needs to put on a show and make it big and loud. Danny however doesn't realize that it is a scam. Darla ruins their show and Danny and all the other animals get kicked out of the studios. Danny decides to head back home but after he is on a bus and sees Pudge being pushed around he comes up with a plan that helps his friends and the other animals to make it back into the filming industry. He makes it big for himself and wins back his support from his friends and ends up winning Sawyer's affection. Darla ends up being defeated and you see her having to put up movie posters at the very end of the credits. Cat's Don't Dance may not be big on special effects but it doesn't have to be. It sells itself with a great story and anybody who watches it probably won't be let down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Amazing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sonicfan21
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anyone remember 'Singin' in the Rain'? Well, this is quite the little knockoff.. a great one. Musical actors take part in an animated feature almost as great as the old movie. But with a spoiled child actress and cats. Danny is a naive but friendly cat who is picked to star in Darla Dimples' "Lil' Ark Angel", quite similar to the Shirley Temple movies and star. This cat becomes baffled by his line of "Meow" while a child (who's name is Darla) comes in and wreaks havoc. Her main plot is the cause trouble and lies about liking animals. The script is superb, much like something Pixar would make. The animation is good. The acting was magnificent. Ashley Pendon's voice was great and I loved her singing voice... Lindsey did great. And the characters' voices to the animals sounded and reminded me much like the ones in 'All Dogs Go To Heaven'. Not to mention, the music was great and my favorite has to be the final song. This movie will bring an instant smile to faces of children and adults alike. It will reminisce childhood memories and will never be forgotten. Always remember that 'Cats Don't Dance' is a heartwarming and lighthearted movie that will be in your heart... young or old.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fast-paced movie with a deliciously devilish antagonist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dean Richard Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm definitely not familiar with Mark Dindal, but kudos to him for making one heck of an animation. It's rather different, kiddish and yet there's stuff for adults too, it's fast-paced and yet there's some slow scenes, and all together it just ridiculously fun. Together with its cast of famous actors which includes John Rhys-Davies (Gimli in LOTR), Don Knotts (Andy Griffith Show, of course), and even Betty Lou Garson (the original Cruella De Vil). WARNING: if you want to see this movie, brace yourself for major Wackiness. The story follows optimisticsometimes air-headedDanny the Cat who journeys to Hollywood from Kokomo to fulfill his dream of becoming a star, but his ambition is trampled by the pernicious vile child star Miss Darla Dimple. Danny finds a band of unlikely dreamers consisting of a grumpy grandpa goat, a sweet yet over-social hippo, a Bette Davis style Fish, a pudgy penguin kid who just loves to eat (yeah, and he's pretty annoying too), a poor turtle who relies on his fortune cookies to determine his day, and last but not least Sawyer the cat who believes her dreams have been completely crushed. Together the wacky dreamers try to prove even "different species" can be stars, before the lovelymore like loathsomeDarla smashes their dreams to smithereens. Believe me; so many loony scenes are in this movie: Tilly Hippo and her ridiculous introducing method, the unbelievable flooding of Hollywood, any scene with Max and Darla, that eccentric director and many more! I just found it way too wacky when I was little. The intro cast was a great opening (and those jiving moles!). This is a 90's film so the animation is so-so and slightly incomplete, though I loved how they did Sawyer. This is a kid's flick so everything was berzerkly colorful. The voice acting was great for an animation like this (especially Ashley Peldon as Darla). The dialogue was simple and clean. Almost every scene is musical, there's music going on every where! the songs themselves gave such a good vibe. "I Got Rhythm" was very nice with a those animals! I rated this movie a 6 star because it's a fair animation, sincere movie; it's a little TOO fast-paced though (75 minutes, people!) and it's unrealistic, of course. The message is the usual fallow your dreams. Like I said before, brace yourself for wackiness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overall, a nice animated family feature, but one with an almost unbearable antagonist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This does not appear to be one of the most widely recognized animated films of the 90's, but I did see it once on video during that decade. I guess that would have been shortly after the movie came into stores. It definitely wasn't up there with certain other animated films I saw in my childhood, but I think I found it fairly entertaining. After that, I didn't see "Cats Don't Dance" again until this year, I think just a few weeks ago. It seemed to be well-liked among those who have seen it, so I wasn't expecting a lacklustre effort. However, I didn't like it much during what was my first viewing in a long time. A few weeks later, I've already given it another try. I think it did improve with this viewing, but a lot of it still didn't really impress me. Danny is an ambitious cat who leaves his hometown of Kokomo, Indiana to pursue a career in Hollywood. Very soon after arriving at his destination, he gets a role in a film with Darla Dimple, a child star who is known as "America's Sweetheart, Lover of Children and Animals." He is very excited about his role, until he learns that all he gets to say is "meow" and he doesn't get to dance and sing. When Danny tries to spice up his role, he soon sees Ms. Dimple's true colours and how misleading her on screen persona really is! She is actually a horribly spoiled, selfish, mean-spirited brat with a giant valet named Max, who makes sure she always gets her way! It turns out that animals only get to be extras in Hollywood, so Danny begins to work with other animals to try and change this and show Tinseltown their true talent, but Ms. Dimple knows this could threaten her career if they succeed, so she is determined to foil their plan! When the film begins, we soon see that the animation is nicely colourful and pleasing to the eye, but for at least a while, the movie is a little too fast-paced, making it less effective than it could be. There are some fairly funny parts early on, such as Danny accidentally slamming Sawyer's (a cat secretary in Hollywood who becomes a major part of the story) tail in a door, and the look she gives him, but at this point, I had trouble really getting into the film. It isn't long before Darla Dimple, the antagonist, comes into the story. This character is clearly supposed to be funny, but she didn't amuse me very much. I did not care for her loudness, faces, etc. After a while, the film improves. It eventually didn't seem quite as fast to me and the story got more intriguing, though Ms. Dimple continues to be hardly bearable in the scenes she appears in. The animal characters are generally likable, and viewers can easily find themselves rooting for them. The movie also has an interesting premise and some funny moments, even if there aren't as many good laughs as there are supposed to be. There are times when I'm not 100% sure about my rating for a movie, and this is one of those cases. I most definitely can't say I absolutely LOVE this movie like many others do, but feel I could be giving it a seven out of ten instead of a six. In fact, without the antics of the Darla Dimple character, I might not have any reason to give "Cats Don't Dance" a rating any lower than seven. It seems most people who have seen this 1997 animated feature like it more than I do, but I can still understand its appeal, as it certainly does have its charm. I wouldn't complain if it were to ever gain more recognition. The pace around the beginning, the antagonist, the film's songs which are not exactly bad but not the most memorable numbers for an animated musical, and maybe occasionally some other problems (minor ones) make the movie lose points, but there's also a lot to like. While this film can't match a number of other full-length animations made in the same decade, you could still easily find that it's good family fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant change of pace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Sirman
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film does what few animated musicals attempt but fail to accomplish. The energy and feeling of an old silver screen musical. Gene Kelly would be proud. The animation is quite the throwback to the Chuck Jones era of cartoons. The city is wonderfully drawn and given a slight art deco feel. The voice acting is spot on for all of the characters and the singing talent is some of the best. Randy Newman does a wonderful job of scoring this film. His musical arrangements are upbeat and fun when need be and pull at your heart's strings at the right time. It's quite sad that this film was brushed under the carpet by Warner Bros. The lack of popularity, besides not being a Disney movie, could also be due to the fact that the story deals with a subject that not many kids are familiar with, Racism. But the older audience will really appreciate this movie on a whole different level. Cats Don't Dance was a film that was destined to fail but at the same time left to be one of the best animations of our time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit over the top.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I caught a rendering of a scene on Deviant Art, and was told that the scene was from an animated feature called "Cats Don't Dance". I took a chance on it, and saw a film that I think could have been better than it ultimately became. When I think of classic MGM cartoons I immediately think of Tom and Jerry, Droopy, Screwy Squirrel and a few others. Well, "Cats Don't Dance" is none of those, but it does have a certain charm. A lot of the classic ultra violent slapstick that is that hallmark of the classic cartoon has been replaced with high energy benign comic styleings that, to be honest, don't really hit the mark. I'm sorry, but even kids know that comedy is the misfortune of others, largely because it makes us feel superior to the poor guy who suffers misfortune, because he's done so through his own stupidity. Now, not all humor has its genesis in laughing at the other guy's plight, as there are a lot of humorous things that can be done through expressions, reactions and close calls of all sorts. But when you strictly base humor solely on the benign, or rather delegate the bad- taste humor because it involves cartoon violence to the "black hats" in the piece, then you're making a value judgment that the public is smart enough to figure out. People can get swept up in trends and hysteria, but to presuppose that children, or specifically all children, will mimic violent slapstick, is perhaps not unrealistic, but perhaps making too much of an assumption of the human character (regardless of age). And that's the real problem with this film. It tries to make up for a lack of humor by injecting tons of energy into every routine, every bit, every gag that's displayed for the audience. It thus feels like a quickly put together patch job of gags that were story boarded and retrofitted to a basic story and plot. The voice acting is fine, the sound effects and other facets of the production are first rate, but, as I say, we essentially have a neutered production. The small evil Shirley Temple like antagonist is over the top and clich&eacute;, the protagonist is clich&eacute;, pretty much the whole array of characters are from central casting. Even so Bakula and Guy do a respectable job of thesping the part, but they're hard pressed to carry a production that has other issues. To be honest it's not a production I'd take my kids to see (if I had any). Not because it's offensive or lacks morals, it's just not that good, and at times is so high energy as to be incomprehensible. Give it a whirl if you must, but watch at your own risk. An okay production, but nothing sterling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing's gonna stop me from loving this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ZachTheRunner
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing's more of a nostalgic movie for me than Cats Don't Dance, the energetic animated musical of Hollywood, passion, and the pursuit of dreams that is the most criminally underrated movie I have ever seen in my life. We are introduced to Danny, a cat full of ambition and dreams of making it AS A STAR! He arrives in Hollywood and quickly meets the other wonderful cast of animals: Tilly Hippo, Cranston Goat, T.W Turtle, later Woolly Mammoth, and another cat simply named Sawyer; who is not too pleased with Danny's dream-chasing, singing and dancing attitude. Shortly after the introduction to the others, he lands a spot on the latest movie "Little Ark Angel" starring "America's Sweetheart, Lover of Children and Animals" Darla Dimple: who's pretty much a cross between Shirley Temple, Baby-Doll from the animated Batman, and a Disney villain. While filming the movie, Danny makes himself noticed much to the displeasure of Darla who shows her true colors as a spoiled little munchkin who again is as heinously evil as some of Disneys most evil villains. Which results in the calling of the gargantuan servant of Darla known as Max, which results in Max teaching Danny a lesson that I'm not gonna lie is actually pretty funny. After that happens, we find out why no one liked his little number and why Sawyer is so despondent toward Danny. We find out that Hollywood, for no clear reason, wants talented human actors and not talented animals. And the other characters we've met have talent that was wrongfully overlooked, Sawyer being both the most promising and seemingly the most broken of the group. But Danny, still wanting to follow his dream, tries to convince the others to do the same. The result: the rest of the movie. If I took out the nostalgia, I would love Cats Don't Dance all the same. I love how fun it is, I love how sincere it is, but mostly I love how passionate and driven it is. Its not a flawless movie; some of the singing voices sound a bit odd when compared to the talking voices. Danny isn't THAT well developed but not enough that I think he brought the film down. But aside from a few nitpicks I truly do love it. The music is done by Randy Newman. And while I don't "love" Randy Newman, this is really good. The songs are both catchy and fit the moods appropriately. The orchestral work is impressive as well, fitting the 1930s Hollywood setting perfectly. The animation is fantastic too; offering a familiar Warner Bros. animation feel. Honestly, I love this movie. I love everything about it. It's great, fun to watch, memorable and very underrated. I love the characters, the music, the animation, the drama; but mostly the passion. Its serious nostalgia for me, and people should definitely watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    But they're expected to put on a helluva show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cats Don't Dance has gone down in history as one of the biggest risks in animation yet. It is one of the few full length animated features not to bare the Disney name, yet comes off as one just as cheerful and safe for kids. Clearly, parents didn't believe so, or possibly they didn't hear about the film due to Turner Feature Animation's miserable marketing tactics, not to mention the competition of the re-release of a Star Wars movie and Disney's film Hercules. Because of all those factors, Cats Don't Dance was a monstrous bomb, all the more considering it was an animated film, which are always expected to gross at least double their budget, and it remains as a curious piece of history and nostalgia. It comes off as so cheery and genial, that as you watch it, the name "Disney" never comes to mind. It's in a league of its own, where pitch-perfect realism doesn't always come first, and fun and livelihood always lead the way. It's a unique experience. The story concerns Danny (voiced by Scott Bakula), a plucky and anxious cat who leaves his humble roots in Kokomo, Indiana to travel to Hollywood, where he can hopefully make it big as an actor. One roadblock, he's a cat, and Hollywood's places for cats are few and far between. He manages to get cast in a movie with Darla Dimple (Ashley Peldon), a spoiled, heavily-pampered child actress who turns maniacal and practically evil as soon as the cameras stop rolling. Along the way, the naive soul runs into Sawyer (Jasmine Guy), a beautiful, yet heavily pessimistic female cat, who Danny is immediately smitten with. Sawyer explains how Hollywood's attitude towards animals would seem inviting, when it is just morose and neglectful towards the idea of stepping outside the box. This sort of makes Cats Don't Dance's life come full circle. Think of it as Danny. He steps out of his natural roots to find fame in Hollywood, winds up getting the cold shoulder, until the inevitable happens and he is looked on with great satisfaction. Now think of the film's life. It stepped out of the clich&eacute; Disney light, was created and brought to life by a studio no one knew, was ignored pretty much by everyone during its initial release, yet is looked on as a classic animated gem by many in the present. If serendipity could talk... The animation is beautiful. Rambunctiously neat, and very, very eye-appealing. Not to continue to rain on the film's parade, but at this point in time (1997), we were already met with the genius of Pixar and their groundbreaking film Toy Story. We knew all of what animation can do, and once you see what seems to be the best, do you have much interest in the rest? Regardless, this is sort of what I adore about Cats Don't Dance; it plays by its own rules. It's so lightweight and non-intrusive that it doesn't seem to care it's not on par with other pictures of its own league. It isn't heavy-handed or on a moral rush. It's just looking for a good time. One thing I enjoyed were the musical numbers, which are delightfully sung, wonderfully crafted, and beautifully choreographed with such kinetic energy. I believe the more exposure or knowledge you have with Hollywood, cinema, and how the big guys manipulate the little ones, the more you'll be inclined to enjoy Cats Don't Dance. It's one of the cheeriest films I've seen all year. Voiced by: Scott Bakula, Jasmine Guy, Natalie Cole, Ashley Peldon, John Rhys-Davies, Kathy Najimy, and Don Knotts. Directed by: Mark Dindal.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute, funny and incredibly enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the nineties, there were several attempts made by different studios in order to emulate the style from the animated films that the Disney company were producing at those years (Such as "Aladdin", "Beauty and the Beast" and "The Lion King") Some of those attempts were corny and lame, but fortunately, this nice animated film (Which was also the first animated movie directed by Mark Dindal, the same director "The Emperor's New Groove") instead of trying to imitate the Disney formula, prefers to be a light-hearted homage to all the classic musicals from the Golden Age of Hollywood, worked incredibly well in that aspect. The plot is fast-paced, but easy to follow, with very likable characters, and many funny situations and clever dialogues, not to mention the incredibly catchy songs, that were the best part of the movie. From my very personal point of view, I think that the combination of all those elements worked much better than in "The Emperor's New Groove" (Which is also a good movie, but I like this more) This is a nice movie for the whole family, and I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darla Steals the Show!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    idonnowho
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure, the animals were kinda cool, but, if you ask me, the REAL STAR (she'd certainly be pleased to hear me say that) was Darla Dimple. A beautiful little blonde girl, who, for some reason, was the VILLAIN. That may or may not have been for the better, because at least she certainly was far from completely saccharine (i.e. Anne-Marie in "All Dogs Go to Heaven" or Dot in "A Bug's Life") as she may have been if she were a good guy... Still, I couldn't help but feel sorry for her, maybe because she's just a kid, or maybe because she resembles (in terms of her appearance ONLY, and NOT personality) the sweet girl, short in stature, curly blonde hair, at my school, Zoezonna Brennan. Unlike Darla, who was cool and all, Zoe's just a nice girl (FAR from sickeningly sweet, though) and makes me feel love and compassion towards her. Anyways, a VERY interesting and satisfying film! 9/10 stars! You ARE the STAR, Darla Dimple! (AND YOU, ZOE, EVEN MORESO!!!!) :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    See you in the movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ravsten428
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cat's Don't Dance may not be what most movie buffs would call a classic cartoon. It's not made by a big name company but it is a good movie nonetheless. Danny is a cat who wants to make it big in Hollywood. He leaves his town of Kokomo, Indiana to head for big dreams. Once he gets to Hollywood he makes his debut in a film that mostly belongs to the cute but really evil Darla Dimple. Danny tests her patience by not saying his line but rather singing it. She is not happy and reminds him that he needs to know his place in the film as an animal. Danny is determined to make a name for himself and his friends Sawyer, Tilly, Cranston, Pudge and a few others. Sawyer a female cat tries to persuade him out of trying to have dreams because he is only an animal and they are treated differently and aren't given the bigger roles in films. After awhile he gets all his friends and the animals in Hollywood to realize that they are worth it. Darla doesn't like what she sees and decides that she is going to try and sabotage the animals from starring in any future films. She tells Danny that he needs to put on a show and make it big and loud. Danny however doesn't realize that it is a scam. Darla ruins their show and Danny and all the other animals get kicked out of the studios. Danny decides to head back home but after he is on a bus and sees Pudge being pushed around he comes up with a plan that helps his friends and the other animals to make it back into the filming industry. He makes it big for himself and wins back his support from his friends and ends up winning Sawyer's affection. Darla ends up being defeated and you see her having to put up movie posters at the very end of the credits. Cat's Don't Dance may not be big on special effects but it doesn't have to be. It sells itself with a great story and anybody who watches it probably won't be let down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Amazing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sonicfan21
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anyone remember 'Singin' in the Rain'? Well, this is quite the little knockoff.. a great one. Musical actors take part in an animated feature almost as great as the old movie. But with a spoiled child actress and cats. Danny is a naive but friendly cat who is picked to star in Darla Dimples' "Lil' Ark Angel", quite similar to the Shirley Temple movies and star. This cat becomes baffled by his line of "Meow" while a child (who's name is Darla) comes in and wreaks havoc. Her main plot is the cause trouble and lies about liking animals. The script is superb, much like something Pixar would make. The animation is good. The acting was magnificent. Ashley Pendon's voice was great and I loved her singing voice... Lindsey did great. And the characters' voices to the animals sounded and reminded me much like the ones in 'All Dogs Go To Heaven'. Not to mention, the music was great and my favorite has to be the final song. This movie will bring an instant smile to faces of children and adults alike. It will reminisce childhood memories and will never be forgotten. Always remember that 'Cats Don't Dance' is a heartwarming and lighthearted movie that will be in your heart... young or old.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fast-paced movie with a deliciously devilish antagonist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dean Richard Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm definitely not familiar with Mark Dindal, but kudos to him for making one heck of an animation. It's rather different, kiddish and yet there's stuff for adults too, it's fast-paced and yet there's some slow scenes, and all together it just ridiculously fun. Together with its cast of famous actors which includes John Rhys-Davies (Gimli in LOTR), Don Knotts (Andy Griffith Show, of course), and even Betty Lou Garson (the original Cruella De Vil). WARNING: if you want to see this movie, brace yourself for major Wackiness. The story follows optimisticsometimes air-headedDanny the Cat who journeys to Hollywood from Kokomo to fulfill his dream of becoming a star, but his ambition is trampled by the pernicious vile child star Miss Darla Dimple. Danny finds a band of unlikely dreamers consisting of a grumpy grandpa goat, a sweet yet over-social hippo, a Bette Davis style Fish, a pudgy penguin kid who just loves to eat (yeah, and he's pretty annoying too), a poor turtle who relies on his fortune cookies to determine his day, and last but not least Sawyer the cat who believes her dreams have been completely crushed. Together the wacky dreamers try to prove even "different species" can be stars, before the lovelymore like loathsomeDarla smashes their dreams to smithereens. Believe me; so many loony scenes are in this movie: Tilly Hippo and her ridiculous introducing method, the unbelievable flooding of Hollywood, any scene with Max and Darla, that eccentric director and many more! I just found it way too wacky when I was little. The intro cast was a great opening (and those jiving moles!). This is a 90's film so the animation is so-so and slightly incomplete, though I loved how they did Sawyer. This is a kid's flick so everything was berzerkly colorful. The voice acting was great for an animation like this (especially Ashley Peldon as Darla). The dialogue was simple and clean. Almost every scene is musical, there's music going on every where! the songs themselves gave such a good vibe. "I Got Rhythm" was very nice with a those animals! I rated this movie a 6 star because it's a fair animation, sincere movie; it's a little TOO fast-paced though (75 minutes, people!) and it's unrealistic, of course. The message is the usual fallow your dreams. Like I said before, brace yourself for wackiness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overall, a nice animated family feature, but one with an almost unbearable antagonist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This does not appear to be one of the most widely recognized animated films of the 90's, but I did see it once on video during that decade. I guess that would have been shortly after the movie came into stores. It definitely wasn't up there with certain other animated films I saw in my childhood, but I think I found it fairly entertaining. After that, I didn't see "Cats Don't Dance" again until this year, I think just a few weeks ago. It seemed to be well-liked among those who have seen it, so I wasn't expecting a lacklustre effort. However, I didn't like it much during what was my first viewing in a long time. A few weeks later, I've already given it another try. I think it did improve with this viewing, but a lot of it still didn't really impress me. Danny is an ambitious cat who leaves his hometown of Kokomo, Indiana to pursue a career in Hollywood. Very soon after arriving at his destination, he gets a role in a film with Darla Dimple, a child star who is known as "America's Sweetheart, Lover of Children and Animals." He is very excited about his role, until he learns that all he gets to say is "meow" and he doesn't get to dance and sing. When Danny tries to spice up his role, he soon sees Ms. Dimple's true colours and how misleading her on screen persona really is! She is actually a horribly spoiled, selfish, mean-spirited brat with a giant valet named Max, who makes sure she always gets her way! It turns out that animals only get to be extras in Hollywood, so Danny begins to work with other animals to try and change this and show Tinseltown their true talent, but Ms. Dimple knows this could threaten her career if they succeed, so she is determined to foil their plan! When the film begins, we soon see that the animation is nicely colourful and pleasing to the eye, but for at least a while, the movie is a little too fast-paced, making it less effective than it could be. There are some fairly funny parts early on, such as Danny accidentally slamming Sawyer's (a cat secretary in Hollywood who becomes a major part of the story) tail in a door, and the look she gives him, but at this point, I had trouble really getting into the film. It isn't long before Darla Dimple, the antagonist, comes into the story. This character is clearly supposed to be funny, but she didn't amuse me very much. I did not care for her loudness, faces, etc. After a while, the film improves. It eventually didn't seem quite as fast to me and the story got more intriguing, though Ms. Dimple continues to be hardly bearable in the scenes she appears in. The animal characters are generally likable, and viewers can easily find themselves rooting for them. The movie also has an interesting premise and some funny moments, even if there aren't as many good laughs as there are supposed to be. There are times when I'm not 100% sure about my rating for a movie, and this is one of those cases. I most definitely can't say I absolutely LOVE this movie like many others do, but feel I could be giving it a seven out of ten instead of a six. In fact, without the antics of the Darla Dimple character, I might not have any reason to give "Cats Don't Dance" a rating any lower than seven. It seems most people who have seen this 1997 animated feature like it more than I do, but I can still understand its appeal, as it certainly does have its charm. I wouldn't complain if it were to ever gain more recognition. The pace around the beginning, the antagonist, the film's songs which are not exactly bad but not the most memorable numbers for an animated musical, and maybe occasionally some other problems (minor ones) make the movie lose points, but there's also a lot to like. While this film can't match a number of other full-length animations made in the same decade, you could still easily find that it's good family fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant change of pace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Sirman
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film does what few animated musicals attempt but fail to accomplish. The energy and feeling of an old silver screen musical. Gene Kelly would be proud. The animation is quite the throwback to the Chuck Jones era of cartoons. The city is wonderfully drawn and given a slight art deco feel. The voice acting is spot on for all of the characters and the singing talent is some of the best. Randy Newman does a wonderful job of scoring this film. His musical arrangements are upbeat and fun when need be and pull at your heart's strings at the right time. It's quite sad that this film was brushed under the carpet by Warner Bros. The lack of popularity, besides not being a Disney movie, could also be due to the fact that the story deals with a subject that not many kids are familiar with, Racism. But the older audience will really appreciate this movie on a whole different level. Cats Don't Dance was a film that was destined to fail but at the same time left to be one of the best animations of our time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit over the top.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I caught a rendering of a scene on Deviant Art, and was told that the scene was from an animated feature called "Cats Don't Dance". I took a chance on it, and saw a film that I think could have been better than it ultimately became. When I think of classic MGM cartoons I immediately think of Tom and Jerry, Droopy, Screwy Squirrel and a few others. Well, "Cats Don't Dance" is none of those, but it does have a certain charm. A lot of the classic ultra violent slapstick that is that hallmark of the classic cartoon has been replaced with high energy benign comic styleings that, to be honest, don't really hit the mark. I'm sorry, but even kids know that comedy is the misfortune of others, largely because it makes us feel superior to the poor guy who suffers misfortune, because he's done so through his own stupidity. Now, not all humor has its genesis in laughing at the other guy's plight, as there are a lot of humorous things that can be done through expressions, reactions and close calls of all sorts. But when you strictly base humor solely on the benign, or rather delegate the bad- taste humor because it involves cartoon violence to the "black hats" in the piece, then you're making a value judgment that the public is smart enough to figure out. People can get swept up in trends and hysteria, but to presuppose that children, or specifically all children, will mimic violent slapstick, is perhaps not unrealistic, but perhaps making too much of an assumption of the human character (regardless of age). And that's the real problem with this film. It tries to make up for a lack of humor by injecting tons of energy into every routine, every bit, every gag that's displayed for the audience. It thus feels like a quickly put together patch job of gags that were story boarded and retrofitted to a basic story and plot. The voice acting is fine, the sound effects and other facets of the production are first rate, but, as I say, we essentially have a neutered production. The small evil Shirley Temple like antagonist is over the top and clich&eacute;, the protagonist is clich&eacute;, pretty much the whole array of characters are from central casting. Even so Bakula and Guy do a respectable job of thesping the part, but they're hard pressed to carry a production that has other issues. To be honest it's not a production I'd take my kids to see (if I had any). Not because it's offensive or lacks morals, it's just not that good, and at times is so high energy as to be incomprehensible. Give it a whirl if you must, but watch at your own risk. An okay production, but nothing sterling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing's gonna stop me from loving this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ZachTheRunner
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing's more of a nostalgic movie for me than Cats Don't Dance, the energetic animated musical of Hollywood, passion, and the pursuit of dreams that is the most criminally underrated movie I have ever seen in my life. We are introduced to Danny, a cat full of ambition and dreams of making it AS A STAR! He arrives in Hollywood and quickly meets the other wonderful cast of animals: Tilly Hippo, Cranston Goat, T.W Turtle, later Woolly Mammoth, and another cat simply named Sawyer; who is not too pleased with Danny's dream-chasing, singing and dancing attitude. Shortly after the introduction to the others, he lands a spot on the latest movie "Little Ark Angel" starring "America's Sweetheart, Lover of Children and Animals" Darla Dimple: who's pretty much a cross between Shirley Temple, Baby-Doll from the animated Batman, and a Disney villain. While filming the movie, Danny makes himself noticed much to the displeasure of Darla who shows her true colors as a spoiled little munchkin who again is as heinously evil as some of Disneys most evil villains. Which results in the calling of the gargantuan servant of Darla known as Max, which results in Max teaching Danny a lesson that I'm not gonna lie is actually pretty funny. After that happens, we find out why no one liked his little number and why Sawyer is so despondent toward Danny. We find out that Hollywood, for no clear reason, wants talented human actors and not talented animals. And the other characters we've met have talent that was wrongfully overlooked, Sawyer being both the most promising and seemingly the most broken of the group. But Danny, still wanting to follow his dream, tries to convince the others to do the same. The result: the rest of the movie. If I took out the nostalgia, I would love Cats Don't Dance all the same. I love how fun it is, I love how sincere it is, but mostly I love how passionate and driven it is. Its not a flawless movie; some of the singing voices sound a bit odd when compared to the talking voices. Danny isn't THAT well developed but not enough that I think he brought the film down. But aside from a few nitpicks I truly do love it. The music is done by Randy Newman. And while I don't "love" Randy Newman, this is really good. The songs are both catchy and fit the moods appropriately. The orchestral work is impressive as well, fitting the 1930s Hollywood setting perfectly. The animation is fantastic too; offering a familiar Warner Bros. animation feel. Honestly, I love this movie. I love everything about it. It's great, fun to watch, memorable and very underrated. I love the characters, the music, the animation, the drama; but mostly the passion. Its serious nostalgia for me, and people should definitely watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    But they're expected to put on a helluva show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cats Don't Dance has gone down in history as one of the biggest risks in animation yet. It is one of the few full length animated features not to bare the Disney name, yet comes off as one just as cheerful and safe for kids. Clearly, parents didn't believe so, or possibly they didn't hear about the film due to Turner Feature Animation's miserable marketing tactics, not to mention the competition of the re-release of a Star Wars movie and Disney's film Hercules. Because of all those factors, Cats Don't Dance was a monstrous bomb, all the more considering it was an animated film, which are always expected to gross at least double their budget, and it remains as a curious piece of history and nostalgia. It comes off as so cheery and genial, that as you watch it, the name "Disney" never comes to mind. It's in a league of its own, where pitch-perfect realism doesn't always come first, and fun and livelihood always lead the way. It's a unique experience. The story concerns Danny (voiced by Scott Bakula), a plucky and anxious cat who leaves his humble roots in Kokomo, Indiana to travel to Hollywood, where he can hopefully make it big as an actor. One roadblock, he's a cat, and Hollywood's places for cats are few and far between. He manages to get cast in a movie with Darla Dimple (Ashley Peldon), a spoiled, heavily-pampered child actress who turns maniacal and practically evil as soon as the cameras stop rolling. Along the way, the naive soul runs into Sawyer (Jasmine Guy), a beautiful, yet heavily pessimistic female cat, who Danny is immediately smitten with. Sawyer explains how Hollywood's attitude towards animals would seem inviting, when it is just morose and neglectful towards the idea of stepping outside the box. This sort of makes Cats Don't Dance's life come full circle. Think of it as Danny. He steps out of his natural roots to find fame in Hollywood, winds up getting the cold shoulder, until the inevitable happens and he is looked on with great satisfaction. Now think of the film's life. It stepped out of the clich&eacute; Disney light, was created and brought to life by a studio no one knew, was ignored pretty much by everyone during its initial release, yet is looked on as a classic animated gem by many in the present. If serendipity could talk... The animation is beautiful. Rambunctiously neat, and very, very eye-appealing. Not to continue to rain on the film's parade, but at this point in time (1997), we were already met with the genius of Pixar and their groundbreaking film Toy Story. We knew all of what animation can do, and once you see what seems to be the best, do you have much interest in the rest? Regardless, this is sort of what I adore about Cats Don't Dance; it plays by its own rules. It's so lightweight and non-intrusive that it doesn't seem to care it's not on par with other pictures of its own league. It isn't heavy-handed or on a moral rush. It's just looking for a good time. One thing I enjoyed were the musical numbers, which are delightfully sung, wonderfully crafted, and beautifully choreographed with such kinetic energy. I believe the more exposure or knowledge you have with Hollywood, cinema, and how the big guys manipulate the little ones, the more you'll be inclined to enjoy Cats Don't Dance. It's one of the cheeriest films I've seen all year. Voiced by: Scott Bakula, Jasmine Guy, Natalie Cole, Ashley Peldon, John Rhys-Davies, Kathy Najimy, and Don Knotts. Directed by: Mark Dindal.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute, funny and incredibly enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the nineties, there were several attempts made by different studios in order to emulate the style from the animated films that the Disney company were producing at those years (Such as "Aladdin", "Beauty and the Beast" and "The Lion King") Some of those attempts were corny and lame, but fortunately, this nice animated film (Which was also the first animated movie directed by Mark Dindal, the same director "The Emperor's New Groove") instead of trying to imitate the Disney formula, prefers to be a light-hearted homage to all the classic musicals from the Golden Age of Hollywood, worked incredibly well in that aspect. The plot is fast-paced, but easy to follow, with very likable characters, and many funny situations and clever dialogues, not to mention the incredibly catchy songs, that were the best part of the movie. From my very personal point of view, I think that the combination of all those elements worked much better than in "The Emperor's New Groove" (Which is also a good movie, but I like this more) This is a nice movie for the whole family, and I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darla Steals the Show!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    idonnowho
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure, the animals were kinda cool, but, if you ask me, the REAL STAR (she'd certainly be pleased to hear me say that) was Darla Dimple. A beautiful little blonde girl, who, for some reason, was the VILLAIN. That may or may not have been for the better, because at least she certainly was far from completely saccharine (i.e. Anne-Marie in "All Dogs Go to Heaven" or Dot in "A Bug's Life") as she may have been if she were a good guy... Still, I couldn't help but feel sorry for her, maybe because she's just a kid, or maybe because she resembles (in terms of her appearance ONLY, and NOT personality) the sweet girl, short in stature, curly blonde hair, at my school, Zoezonna Brennan. Unlike Darla, who was cool and all, Zoe's just a nice girl (FAR from sickeningly sweet, though) and makes me feel love and compassion towards her. Anyways, a VERY interesting and satisfying film! 9/10 stars! You ARE the STAR, Darla Dimple! (AND YOU, ZOE, EVEN MORESO!!!!) :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    See you in the movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ravsten428
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cat's Don't Dance may not be what most movie buffs would call a classic cartoon. It's not made by a big name company but it is a good movie nonetheless. Danny is a cat who wants to make it big in Hollywood. He leaves his town of Kokomo, Indiana to head for big dreams. Once he gets to Hollywood he makes his debut in a film that mostly belongs to the cute but really evil Darla Dimple. Danny tests her patience by not saying his line but rather singing it. She is not happy and reminds him that he needs to know his place in the film as an animal. Danny is determined to make a name for himself and his friends Sawyer, Tilly, Cranston, Pudge and a few others. Sawyer a female cat tries to persuade him out of trying to have dreams because he is only an animal and they are treated differently and aren't given the bigger roles in films. After awhile he gets all his friends and the animals in Hollywood to realize that they are worth it. Darla doesn't like what she sees and decides that she is going to try and sabotage the animals from starring in any future films. She tells Danny that he needs to put on a show and make it big and loud. Danny however doesn't realize that it is a scam. Darla ruins their show and Danny and all the other animals get kicked out of the studios. Danny decides to head back home but after he is on a bus and sees Pudge being pushed around he comes up with a plan that helps his friends and the other animals to make it back into the filming industry. He makes it big for himself and wins back his support from his friends and ends up winning Sawyer's affection. Darla ends up being defeated and you see her having to put up movie posters at the very end of the credits. Cat's Don't Dance may not be big on special effects but it doesn't have to be. It sells itself with a great story and anybody who watches it probably won't be let down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Amazing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sonicfan21
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anyone remember 'Singin' in the Rain'? Well, this is quite the little knockoff.. a great one. Musical actors take part in an animated feature almost as great as the old movie. But with a spoiled child actress and cats. Danny is a naive but friendly cat who is picked to star in Darla Dimples' "Lil' Ark Angel", quite similar to the Shirley Temple movies and star. This cat becomes baffled by his line of "Meow" while a child (who's name is Darla) comes in and wreaks havoc. Her main plot is the cause trouble and lies about liking animals. The script is superb, much like something Pixar would make. The animation is good. The acting was magnificent. Ashley Pendon's voice was great and I loved her singing voice... Lindsey did great. And the characters' voices to the animals sounded and reminded me much like the ones in 'All Dogs Go To Heaven'. Not to mention, the music was great and my favorite has to be the final song. This movie will bring an instant smile to faces of children and adults alike. It will reminisce childhood memories and will never be forgotten. Always remember that 'Cats Don't Dance' is a heartwarming and lighthearted movie that will be in your heart... young or old.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fast-paced movie with a deliciously devilish antagonist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dean Richard Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm definitely not familiar with Mark Dindal, but kudos to him for making one heck of an animation. It's rather different, kiddish and yet there's stuff for adults too, it's fast-paced and yet there's some slow scenes, and all together it just ridiculously fun. Together with its cast of famous actors which includes John Rhys-Davies (Gimli in LOTR), Don Knotts (Andy Griffith Show, of course), and even Betty Lou Garson (the original Cruella De Vil). WARNING: if you want to see this movie, brace yourself for major Wackiness. The story follows optimisticsometimes air-headedDanny the Cat who journeys to Hollywood from Kokomo to fulfill his dream of becoming a star, but his ambition is trampled by the pernicious vile child star Miss Darla Dimple. Danny finds a band of unlikely dreamers consisting of a grumpy grandpa goat, a sweet yet over-social hippo, a Bette Davis style Fish, a pudgy penguin kid who just loves to eat (yeah, and he's pretty annoying too), a poor turtle who relies on his fortune cookies to determine his day, and last but not least Sawyer the cat who believes her dreams have been completely crushed. Together the wacky dreamers try to prove even "different species" can be stars, before the lovelymore like loathsomeDarla smashes their dreams to smithereens. Believe me; so many loony scenes are in this movie: Tilly Hippo and her ridiculous introducing method, the unbelievable flooding of Hollywood, any scene with Max and Darla, that eccentric director and many more! I just found it way too wacky when I was little. The intro cast was a great opening (and those jiving moles!). This is a 90's film so the animation is so-so and slightly incomplete, though I loved how they did Sawyer. This is a kid's flick so everything was berzerkly colorful. The voice acting was great for an animation like this (especially Ashley Peldon as Darla). The dialogue was simple and clean. Almost every scene is musical, there's music going on every where! the songs themselves gave such a good vibe. "I Got Rhythm" was very nice with a those animals! I rated this movie a 6 star because it's a fair animation, sincere movie; it's a little TOO fast-paced though (75 minutes, people!) and it's unrealistic, of course. The message is the usual fallow your dreams. Like I said before, brace yourself for wackiness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overall, a nice animated family feature, but one with an almost unbearable antagonist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This does not appear to be one of the most widely recognized animated films of the 90's, but I did see it once on video during that decade. I guess that would have been shortly after the movie came into stores. It definitely wasn't up there with certain other animated films I saw in my childhood, but I think I found it fairly entertaining. After that, I didn't see "Cats Don't Dance" again until this year, I think just a few weeks ago. It seemed to be well-liked among those who have seen it, so I wasn't expecting a lacklustre effort. However, I didn't like it much during what was my first viewing in a long time. A few weeks later, I've already given it another try. I think it did improve with this viewing, but a lot of it still didn't really impress me. Danny is an ambitious cat who leaves his hometown of Kokomo, Indiana to pursue a career in Hollywood. Very soon after arriving at his destination, he gets a role in a film with Darla Dimple, a child star who is known as "America's Sweetheart, Lover of Children and Animals." He is very excited about his role, until he learns that all he gets to say is "meow" and he doesn't get to dance and sing. When Danny tries to spice up his role, he soon sees Ms. Dimple's true colours and how misleading her on screen persona really is! She is actually a horribly spoiled, selfish, mean-spirited brat with a giant valet named Max, who makes sure she always gets her way! It turns out that animals only get to be extras in Hollywood, so Danny begins to work with other animals to try and change this and show Tinseltown their true talent, but Ms. Dimple knows this could threaten her career if they succeed, so she is determined to foil their plan! When the film begins, we soon see that the animation is nicely colourful and pleasing to the eye, but for at least a while, the movie is a little too fast-paced, making it less effective than it could be. There are some fairly funny parts early on, such as Danny accidentally slamming Sawyer's (a cat secretary in Hollywood who becomes a major part of the story) tail in a door, and the look she gives him, but at this point, I had trouble really getting into the film. It isn't long before Darla Dimple, the antagonist, comes into the story. This character is clearly supposed to be funny, but she didn't amuse me very much. I did not care for her loudness, faces, etc. After a while, the film improves. It eventually didn't seem quite as fast to me and the story got more intriguing, though Ms. Dimple continues to be hardly bearable in the scenes she appears in. The animal characters are generally likable, and viewers can easily find themselves rooting for them. The movie also has an interesting premise and some funny moments, even if there aren't as many good laughs as there are supposed to be. There are times when I'm not 100% sure about my rating for a movie, and this is one of those cases. I most definitely can't say I absolutely LOVE this movie like many others do, but feel I could be giving it a seven out of ten instead of a six. In fact, without the antics of the Darla Dimple character, I might not have any reason to give "Cats Don't Dance" a rating any lower than seven. It seems most people who have seen this 1997 animated feature like it more than I do, but I can still understand its appeal, as it certainly does have its charm. I wouldn't complain if it were to ever gain more recognition. The pace around the beginning, the antagonist, the film's songs which are not exactly bad but not the most memorable numbers for an animated musical, and maybe occasionally some other problems (minor ones) make the movie lose points, but there's also a lot to like. While this film can't match a number of other full-length animations made in the same decade, you could still easily find that it's good family fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant change of pace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Sirman
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film does what few animated musicals attempt but fail to accomplish. The energy and feeling of an old silver screen musical. Gene Kelly would be proud. The animation is quite the throwback to the Chuck Jones era of cartoons. The city is wonderfully drawn and given a slight art deco feel. The voice acting is spot on for all of the characters and the singing talent is some of the best. Randy Newman does a wonderful job of scoring this film. His musical arrangements are upbeat and fun when need be and pull at your heart's strings at the right time. It's quite sad that this film was brushed under the carpet by Warner Bros. The lack of popularity, besides not being a Disney movie, could also be due to the fact that the story deals with a subject that not many kids are familiar with, Racism. But the older audience will really appreciate this movie on a whole different level. Cats Don't Dance was a film that was destined to fail but at the same time left to be one of the best animations of our time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit over the top.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I caught a rendering of a scene on Deviant Art, and was told that the scene was from an animated feature called "Cats Don't Dance". I took a chance on it, and saw a film that I think could have been better than it ultimately became. When I think of classic MGM cartoons I immediately think of Tom and Jerry, Droopy, Screwy Squirrel and a few others. Well, "Cats Don't Dance" is none of those, but it does have a certain charm. A lot of the classic ultra violent slapstick that is that hallmark of the classic cartoon has been replaced with high energy benign comic styleings that, to be honest, don't really hit the mark. I'm sorry, but even kids know that comedy is the misfortune of others, largely because it makes us feel superior to the poor guy who suffers misfortune, because he's done so through his own stupidity. Now, not all humor has its genesis in laughing at the other guy's plight, as there are a lot of humorous things that can be done through expressions, reactions and close calls of all sorts. But when you strictly base humor solely on the benign, or rather delegate the bad- taste humor because it involves cartoon violence to the "black hats" in the piece, then you're making a value judgment that the public is smart enough to figure out. People can get swept up in trends and hysteria, but to presuppose that children, or specifically all children, will mimic violent slapstick, is perhaps not unrealistic, but perhaps making too much of an assumption of the human character (regardless of age). And that's the real problem with this film. It tries to make up for a lack of humor by injecting tons of energy into every routine, every bit, every gag that's displayed for the audience. It thus feels like a quickly put together patch job of gags that were story boarded and retrofitted to a basic story and plot. The voice acting is fine, the sound effects and other facets of the production are first rate, but, as I say, we essentially have a neutered production. The small evil Shirley Temple like antagonist is over the top and clich&eacute;, the protagonist is clich&eacute;, pretty much the whole array of characters are from central casting. Even so Bakula and Guy do a respectable job of thesping the part, but they're hard pressed to carry a production that has other issues. To be honest it's not a production I'd take my kids to see (if I had any). Not because it's offensive or lacks morals, it's just not that good, and at times is so high energy as to be incomprehensible. Give it a whirl if you must, but watch at your own risk. An okay production, but nothing sterling.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing's gonna stop me from loving this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ZachTheRunner
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing's more of a nostalgic movie for me than Cats Don't Dance, the energetic animated musical of Hollywood, passion, and the pursuit of dreams that is the most criminally underrated movie I have ever seen in my life. We are introduced to Danny, a cat full of ambition and dreams of making it AS A STAR! He arrives in Hollywood and quickly meets the other wonderful cast of animals: Tilly Hippo, Cranston Goat, T.W Turtle, later Woolly Mammoth, and another cat simply named Sawyer; who is not too pleased with Danny's dream-chasing, singing and dancing attitude. Shortly after the introduction to the others, he lands a spot on the latest movie "Little Ark Angel" starring "America's Sweetheart, Lover of Children and Animals" Darla Dimple: who's pretty much a cross between Shirley Temple, Baby-Doll from the animated Batman, and a Disney villain. While filming the movie, Danny makes himself noticed much to the displeasure of Darla who shows her true colors as a spoiled little munchkin who again is as heinously evil as some of Disneys most evil villains. Which results in the calling of the gargantuan servant of Darla known as Max, which results in Max teaching Danny a lesson that I'm not gonna lie is actually pretty funny. After that happens, we find out why no one liked his little number and why Sawyer is so despondent toward Danny. We find out that Hollywood, for no clear reason, wants talented human actors and not talented animals. And the other characters we've met have talent that was wrongfully overlooked, Sawyer being both the most promising and seemingly the most broken of the group. But Danny, still wanting to follow his dream, tries to convince the others to do the same. The result: the rest of the movie. If I took out the nostalgia, I would love Cats Don't Dance all the same. I love how fun it is, I love how sincere it is, but mostly I love how passionate and driven it is. Its not a flawless movie; some of the singing voices sound a bit odd when compared to the talking voices. Danny isn't THAT well developed but not enough that I think he brought the film down. But aside from a few nitpicks I truly do love it. The music is done by Randy Newman. And while I don't "love" Randy Newman, this is really good. The songs are both catchy and fit the moods appropriately. The orchestral work is impressive as well, fitting the 1930s Hollywood setting perfectly. The animation is fantastic too; offering a familiar Warner Bros. animation feel. Honestly, I love this movie. I love everything about it. It's great, fun to watch, memorable and very underrated. I love the characters, the music, the animation, the drama; but mostly the passion. Its serious nostalgia for me, and people should definitely watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    But they're expected to put on a helluva show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cats Don't Dance has gone down in history as one of the biggest risks in animation yet. It is one of the few full length animated features not to bare the Disney name, yet comes off as one just as cheerful and safe for kids. Clearly, parents didn't believe so, or possibly they didn't hear about the film due to Turner Feature Animation's miserable marketing tactics, not to mention the competition of the re-release of a Star Wars movie and Disney's film Hercules. Because of all those factors, Cats Don't Dance was a monstrous bomb, all the more considering it was an animated film, which are always expected to gross at least double their budget, and it remains as a curious piece of history and nostalgia. It comes off as so cheery and genial, that as you watch it, the name "Disney" never comes to mind. It's in a league of its own, where pitch-perfect realism doesn't always come first, and fun and livelihood always lead the way. It's a unique experience. The story concerns Danny (voiced by Scott Bakula), a plucky and anxious cat who leaves his humble roots in Kokomo, Indiana to travel to Hollywood, where he can hopefully make it big as an actor. One roadblock, he's a cat, and Hollywood's places for cats are few and far between. He manages to get cast in a movie with Darla Dimple (Ashley Peldon), a spoiled, heavily-pampered child actress who turns maniacal and practically evil as soon as the cameras stop rolling. Along the way, the naive soul runs into Sawyer (Jasmine Guy), a beautiful, yet heavily pessimistic female cat, who Danny is immediately smitten with. Sawyer explains how Hollywood's attitude towards animals would seem inviting, when it is just morose and neglectful towards the idea of stepping outside the box. This sort of makes Cats Don't Dance's life come full circle. Think of it as Danny. He steps out of his natural roots to find fame in Hollywood, winds up getting the cold shoulder, until the inevitable happens and he is looked on with great satisfaction. Now think of the film's life. It stepped out of the clich&eacute; Disney light, was created and brought to life by a studio no one knew, was ignored pretty much by everyone during its initial release, yet is looked on as a classic animated gem by many in the present. If serendipity could talk... The animation is beautiful. Rambunctiously neat, and very, very eye-appealing. Not to continue to rain on the film's parade, but at this point in time (1997), we were already met with the genius of Pixar and their groundbreaking film Toy Story. We knew all of what animation can do, and once you see what seems to be the best, do you have much interest in the rest? Regardless, this is sort of what I adore about Cats Don't Dance; it plays by its own rules. It's so lightweight and non-intrusive that it doesn't seem to care it's not on par with other pictures of its own league. It isn't heavy-handed or on a moral rush. It's just looking for a good time. One thing I enjoyed were the musical numbers, which are delightfully sung, wonderfully crafted, and beautifully choreographed with such kinetic energy. I believe the more exposure or knowledge you have with Hollywood, cinema, and how the big guys manipulate the little ones, the more you'll be inclined to enjoy Cats Don't Dance. It's one of the cheeriest films I've seen all year. Voiced by: Scott Bakula, Jasmine Guy, Natalie Cole, Ashley Peldon, John Rhys-Davies, Kathy Najimy, and Don Knotts. Directed by: Mark Dindal.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute, funny and incredibly enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rectangular_businessman
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the nineties, there were several attempts made by different studios in order to emulate the style from the animated films that the Disney company were producing at those years (Such as "Aladdin", "Beauty and the Beast" and "The Lion King") Some of those attempts were corny and lame, but fortunately, this nice animated film (Which was also the first animated movie directed by Mark Dindal, the same director "The Emperor's New Groove") instead of trying to imitate the Disney formula, prefers to be a light-hearted homage to all the classic musicals from the Golden Age of Hollywood, worked incredibly well in that aspect. The plot is fast-paced, but easy to follow, with very likable characters, and many funny situations and clever dialogues, not to mention the incredibly catchy songs, that were the best part of the movie. From my very personal point of view, I think that the combination of all those elements worked much better than in "The Emperor's New Groove" (Which is also a good movie, but I like this more) This is a nice movie for the whole family, and I highly recommend it to anyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Darla Steals the Show!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    idonnowho
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sure, the animals were kinda cool, but, if you ask me, the REAL STAR (she'd certainly be pleased to hear me say that) was Darla Dimple. A beautiful little blonde girl, who, for some reason, was the VILLAIN. That may or may not have been for the better, because at least she certainly was far from completely saccharine (i.e. Anne-Marie in "All Dogs Go to Heaven" or Dot in "A Bug's Life") as she may have been if she were a good guy... Still, I couldn't help but feel sorry for her, maybe because she's just a kid, or maybe because she resembles (in terms of her appearance ONLY, and NOT personality) the sweet girl, short in stature, curly blonde hair, at my school, Zoezonna Brennan. Unlike Darla, who was cool and all, Zoe's just a nice girl (FAR from sickeningly sweet, though) and makes me feel love and compassion towards her. Anyways, a VERY interesting and satisfying film! 9/10 stars! You ARE the STAR, Darla Dimple! (AND YOU, ZOE, EVEN MORESO!!!!) :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    See you in the movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ravsten428
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cat's Don't Dance may not be what most movie buffs would call a classic cartoon. It's not made by a big name company but it is a good movie nonetheless. Danny is a cat who wants to make it big in Hollywood. He leaves his town of Kokomo, Indiana to head for big dreams. Once he gets to Hollywood he makes his debut in a film that mostly belongs to the cute but really evil Darla Dimple. Danny tests her patience by not saying his line but rather singing it. She is not happy and reminds him that he needs to know his place in the film as an animal. Danny is determined to make a name for himself and his friends Sawyer, Tilly, Cranston, Pudge and a few others. Sawyer a female cat tries to persuade him out of trying to have dreams because he is only an animal and they are treated differently and aren't given the bigger roles in films. After awhile he gets all his friends and the animals in Hollywood to realize that they are worth it. Darla doesn't like what she sees and decides that she is going to try and sabotage the animals from starring in any future films. She tells Danny that he needs to put on a show and make it big and loud. Danny however doesn't realize that it is a scam. Darla ruins their show and Danny and all the other animals get kicked out of the studios. Danny decides to head back home but after he is on a bus and sees Pudge being pushed around he comes up with a plan that helps his friends and the other animals to make it back into the filming industry. He makes it big for himself and wins back his support from his friends and ends up winning Sawyer's affection. Darla ends up being defeated and you see her having to put up movie posters at the very end of the credits. Cat's Don't Dance may not be big on special effects but it doesn't have to be. It sells itself with a great story and anybody who watches it probably won't be let down.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Amazing Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sonicfan21
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Anyone remember 'Singin' in the Rain'? Well, this is quite the little knockoff.. a great one. Musical actors take part in an animated feature almost as great as the old movie. But with a spoiled child actress and cats. Danny is a naive but friendly cat who is picked to star in Darla Dimples' "Lil' Ark Angel", quite similar to the Shirley Temple movies and star. This cat becomes baffled by his line of "Meow" while a child (who's name is Darla) comes in and wreaks havoc. Her main plot is the cause trouble and lies about liking animals. The script is superb, much like something Pixar would make. The animation is good. The acting was magnificent. Ashley Pendon's voice was great and I loved her singing voice... Lindsey did great. And the characters' voices to the animals sounded and reminded me much like the ones in 'All Dogs Go To Heaven'. Not to mention, the music was great and my favorite has to be the final song. This movie will bring an instant smile to faces of children and adults alike. It will reminisce childhood memories and will never be forgotten. Always remember that 'Cats Don't Dance' is a heartwarming and lighthearted movie that will be in your heart... young or old.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A fast-paced movie with a deliciously devilish antagonist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dean Richard Collins
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm definitely not familiar with Mark Dindal, but kudos to him for making one heck of an animation. It's rather different, kiddish and yet there's stuff for adults too, it's fast-paced and yet there's some slow scenes, and all together it just ridiculously fun. Together with its cast of famous actors which includes John Rhys-Davies (Gimli in LOTR), Don Knotts (Andy Griffith Show, of course), and even Betty Lou Garson (the original Cruella De Vil). WARNING: if you want to see this movie, brace yourself for major Wackiness. The story follows optimisticsometimes air-headedDanny the Cat who journeys to Hollywood from Kokomo to fulfill his dream of becoming a star, but his ambition is trampled by the pernicious vile child star Miss Darla Dimple. Danny finds a band of unlikely dreamers consisting of a grumpy grandpa goat, a sweet yet over-social hippo, a Bette Davis style Fish, a pudgy penguin kid who just loves to eat (yeah, and he's pretty annoying too), a poor turtle who relies on his fortune cookies to determine his day, and last but not least Sawyer the cat who believes her dreams have been completely crushed. Together the wacky dreamers try to prove even "different species" can be stars, before the lovelymore like loathsomeDarla smashes their dreams to smithereens. Believe me; so many loony scenes are in this movie: Tilly Hippo and her ridiculous introducing method, the unbelievable flooding of Hollywood, any scene with Max and Darla, that eccentric director and many more! I just found it way too wacky when I was little. The intro cast was a great opening (and those jiving moles!). This is a 90's film so the animation is so-so and slightly incomplete, though I loved how they did Sawyer. This is a kid's flick so everything was berzerkly colorful. The voice acting was great for an animation like this (especially Ashley Peldon as Darla). The dialogue was simple and clean. Almost every scene is musical, there's music going on every where! the songs themselves gave such a good vibe. "I Got Rhythm" was very nice with a those animals! I rated this movie a 6 star because it's a fair animation, sincere movie; it's a little TOO fast-paced though (75 minutes, people!) and it's unrealistic, of course. The message is the usual fallow your dreams. Like I said before, brace yourself for wackiness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overall, a nice animated family feature, but one with an almost unbearable antagonist
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electrified_Voltage
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/10/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This does not appear to be one of the most widely recognized animated films of the 90's, but I did see it once on video during that decade. I guess that would have been shortly after the movie came into stores. It definitely wasn't up there with certain other animated films I saw in my childhood, but I think I found it fairly entertaining. After that, I didn't see "Cats Don't Dance" again until this year, I think just a few weeks ago. It seemed to be well-liked among those who have seen it, so I wasn't expecting a lacklustre effort. However, I didn't like it much during what was my first viewing in a long time. A few weeks later, I've already given it another try. I think it did improve with this viewing, but a lot of it still didn't really impress me. Danny is an ambitious cat who leaves his hometown of Kokomo, Indiana to pursue a career in Hollywood. Very soon after arriving at his destination, he gets a role in a film with Darla Dimple, a child star who is known as "America's Sweetheart, Lover of Children and Animals." He is very excited about his role, until he learns that all he gets to say is "meow" and he doesn't get to dance and sing. When Danny tries to spice up his role, he soon sees Ms. Dimple's true colours and how misleading her on screen persona really is! She is actually a horribly spoiled, selfish, mean-spirited brat with a giant valet named Max, who makes sure she always gets her way! It turns out that animals only get to be extras in Hollywood, so Danny begins to work with other animals to try and change this and show Tinseltown their true talent, but Ms. Dimple knows this could threaten her career if they succeed, so she is determined to foil their plan! When the film begins, we soon see that the animation is nicely colourful and pleasing to the eye, but for at least a while, the movie is a little too fast-paced, making it less effective than it could be. There are some fairly funny parts early on, such as Danny accidentally slamming Sawyer's (a cat secretary in Hollywood who becomes a major part of the story) tail in a door, and the look she gives him, but at this point, I had trouble really getting into the film. It isn't long before Darla Dimple, the antagonist, comes into the story. This character is clearly supposed to be funny, but she didn't amuse me very much. I did not care for her loudness, faces, etc. After a while, the film improves. It eventually didn't seem quite as fast to me and the story got more intriguing, though Ms. Dimple continues to be hardly bearable in the scenes she appears in. The animal characters are generally likable, and viewers can easily find themselves rooting for them. The movie also has an interesting premise and some funny moments, even if there aren't as many good laughs as there are supposed to be. There are times when I'm not 100% sure about my rating for a movie, and this is one of those cases. I most definitely can't say I absolutely LOVE this movie like many others do, but feel I could be giving it a seven out of ten instead of a six. In fact, without the antics of the Darla Dimple character, I might not have any reason to give "Cats Don't Dance" a rating any lower than seven. It seems most people who have seen this 1997 animated feature like it more than I do, but I can still understand its appeal, as it certainly does have its charm. I wouldn't complain if it were to ever gain more recognition. The pace around the beginning, the antagonist, the film's songs which are not exactly bad but not the most memorable numbers for an animated musical, and maybe occasionally some other problems (minor ones) make the movie lose points, but there's also a lot to like. While this film can't match a number of other full-length animations made in the same decade, you could still easily find that it's good family fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brilliant change of pace
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Taylor Sirman
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film does what few animated musicals attempt but fail to accomplish. The energy and feeling of an old silver screen musical. Gene Kelly would be proud. The animation is quite the throwback to the Chuck Jones era of cartoons. The city is wonderfully drawn and given a slight art deco feel. The voice acting is spot on for all of the characters and the singing talent is some of the best. Randy Newman does a wonderful job of scoring this film. His musical arrangements are upbeat and fun when need be and pull at your heart's strings at the right time. It's quite sad that this film was brushed under the carpet by Warner Bros. The lack of popularity, besides not being a Disney movie, could also be due to the fact that the story deals with a subject that not many kids are familiar with, Racism. But the older audience will really appreciate this movie on a whole different level. Cats Don't Dance was a film that was destined to fail but at the same time left to be one of the best animations of our time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
