<filme>
 <id>
  990
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118623
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Anna Karenina
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Anna (Marceau) is a wife and mother who has an affair with the handsome Count Vronsky (Bean). Based on the novel by Tolstoy.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Anna is a young and elegant wife of Mr. Karenin, who is wealthy and old. She meets the handsome Count Vronsky. Anna and Vronsky fall in love with each other, and he comes to be with her in St. Petersburg. They are very happy together and make a great looking couple, but soon their happiness gets under social pressures. Anna is hopelessly begging Mr. Karenin for a divorce, but he wants to keep the mother of their child. She has another baby born from her lover Vronsky. Conflict between her untamed desires and painful reality causes her a depression and suicidal thoughts.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   count
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   divorce
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   governess
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   passion
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Bernard Rose
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Leo Tolstoy
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Bernard Rose
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Sophie Marceau
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sean Bean
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Alfred Molina
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very beautiful in it's own way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_watcher 1234
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though not a faithful adaptation like any other until now, it's a very decent and well done with no doubt. Sophie Marceau played Anna beautifully and Sean Bean was very good as Vronsky. The only versions I watched about Leo Tolstoy's novel are this and the 2012 one, which I consider a gorgeous adaptation, despite the critics and public review, and also refreshing and interesting which it's what I admire from an new adaptation. This adaptation retains most of the Russian feeling and atmosphere, being filmed there, and also including some Russian dialog from time to time. It's something that inspires a lot of respect indeed, but that doesn't mean we should criticize the other adaptations for being filmed in Britain or America or, the most common complain nowadays, for having British accents. This one has British accents too, but because there are more well-known actors/actress appreciated by the public and most important because it was filmed in Russia with some mild Russian dialog, some parts for which other adaptations suffer has been overlooked here. I, as a viewer and a fan of movies, never ever paid attention that much to accents. If that's a good thing or not, it's up to every persons personal view, but for me it's a very silly and childish thing to judge a movie and the actors performances 70% based on what accents they perform. This brings in my view the theory that people get very bored in this life lately and prefer to pick up on silly matters in every aspect of his life. This only will downfall this world. One should learn to appreciate simple things more and pay attention to what matters. I recommend this one, for being a very decent adaptation, not all faithful but it doesn't matter in my opinion.The performances were great, the actors did a superb job, and Russia looks stunning. But I also recommend the 2012 version too. They are both brilliant in their own way, but warning: tell them apart and don't compare them. They are different. For me Keira was a perfect Anna Karenina. Sophie did a wonderful job too, but I love Keira more and so does my mother, who loves the book and this version, but admires the new one too. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On the whole, a fantastic adaptation of a great novel!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tppowierza
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt compelled to create an IMDb account and write this review after reading some of the negative reviews that exist for this movie. First of all, let me say that this movie is underrated on IMDb. It should have a rating of at least a 7.0. At the time of this review, this movie has a lower rating than Star Wars I Phantom Menace. Come on people, that's an outrage! I feel an 8.0 is a solid and reasonable rating when you compare this film to most of the movies that are overrated on this site. Now to the bulk of the review. First of all, I think most people would agree that the film is visually stunning. Everything from the costumes, to the landscapes, to the buildings, all of it is eye candy. While this is only one aspect of the film, I think it is an important one because the visuals help set the right tone and romantic atmosphere that is found in the novel. The visuals themselves are enough reason to see this film, even if you know nothing about the story or don't care for it. Secondly, the performances by Sophie Marceau, Sean Bean, and the rest of the cast were superb. There was only one major issue with the acting in my opinion.I wasn't fond of how Stepan (Stiva) was portrayed in the movie. The actor who played him was too dull and flat. In the novel, Stepan is supposed to be charming and sort of opposite to Levin in personality. Other than that, I found everyone to be excellent in their roles. Contrary to what you may think after reading some of the negative reviews, Sophie Marceau was a wonderful Anna. As a previous review stated, I think her French accent was positive and enhanced her performance. After all, in the novel it says that Anna and Vronsky spoke French with each other most of the time. Secondly, I found that both her and Sean Bean made the affair between Anna and Vronsky credible, believable, and every bit dramatic as it is in the novel. Some have complained that Sophie did not capture Anna's simplicity or elegance, but this is just outright wrong. Sean Bean, despite not having the mustache, played Vronsky well. As a guy, I generally hate love scenes in films because the lines are so cheesy and the actors/actresses have no chemistry. While some of the things Vronsky says in the movie/and the novel may seem cheesy and overly dramatic, Sean Bean's delivery is perfect and not overly done. On the whole, Sophie Marceau and Sean Bean had great chemistry in this film. Alfred Molina and Mia Kirshner were great as Levin and Kitty, although I thought her accent was a little weird and out of place. Lastly, the director did a really good job of selecting appropriate scenes and making them fit together to do justice to the novel. As with any other film based off a long novel, much had to be cut out. However, all the important scenes that compromise the essence of the many themes in the novel were all present. With that being said, the movie still had its flaws. For example, I did not like the few narrations that were placed in the film and thought they were unnecessary and detracted from the film's flow. Maybe this is because I watched the film right after finishing the book for the second time, so the plot was fresh in my head. The film also had a few oddball scenes that were not done well, such as in the beginning with the conversation between Dolly and Anna. For me, this whole scene seemed wrong because of how they changed Anna's lines. However, on the whole most of the scenes were not only faithful to the novel, but due to the wonderful visuals and performances, brought it to life. On the whole, I wasn't expecting much from this film. I thought it was going to be a crummy "Hollywood" version of one of my favorite novels and wasn't expecting much from Sophie Marceau or Sean Bean. While there were some of these "Hollywood" style elements, ( just look at the waltz they had in the movie) the movie overall was surprisingly refreshing and well done. Definitely worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Half the material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ferdinand1932
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the production design, photography costumes etc are all quite spectacular this is only half the book. That it is not really the book which may seem a normal quibble, but all the other details which are so rich in the original, is lost here and what is left is a melodrama. One reason is that the length of a great novel cannot ever be crammed into a film of normal endurance. The problem then becomes one of audience engagement and also character motivation because the characters are so attenuated in the film. The rich back histories and the social settings and discussion of current ideas is also fundamental to a Tolstoy novel and here it is only hinted at in parts. Some level of implication is good in a film, unlike a novel, but in this case it is reduces a novel to a text message. The result is not a bad film, but is unfortunately superficial. The task the filmmakers set is enormous - too big for what is accomplished. It's solution is not in this medium and at this length: a multi-part TV series would be have been better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully filmed version with a great score but why Sean Bean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the better versions of Anna Karenina. It's not too old or too new. It's hard to watch the slightly cheap BBC versions or the old black and white Hollywood versions. It is modern enough to have a fresh feel and great on location filming. It's also not too long. The score is wonderful - Tchaikovsky. Sophie Marceau looks beautiful and tragic. Her acting is good too although her accent isn't Russian. Supporting cast are all good including Alfred Molina. The main problem is Sean Bean was a strange choice. He doesn't look Russian and he isn't dashing enough. He's more the villain with his cruel look. It is interesting to compare this with the Jacqueline Bisset and Christopher Reeve version. I think this one is better overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It would be perfect if...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sp_rose2005
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do not agree with the earlier reviews that Vivian Leigh played Anna better than Sophy Marceau. It is just that the 1948 version was by itself a better film. The weakness of the 1997 version is that it the scenes are too short and scattered together, and this makes it difficult to express the emotions of the characters and the overall idea behind Tolstoy's novel. But this is the weakness of the movie makers, not the actors. In the 1948 version, the scenes are very detailed and the conversations are long enough to express the idea of each scene. 1948 version is good, but not the best. I don't know if anyone has seen the British miniseries of 2000-2001, but if you want to understand the idea of the book, you should watch it. The cast is not the best, Anna looks old and not suited for this role although she acts perfectly, Vronsky cannot even be compared with Sean Bean, but it's very detailed and just gets deep down to the main core of the novel. It also covers Levin perfectly. The 1997 version pays significant attention to Levin's character as well, but again, because the scenes are too confusing, it will be difficult for those who haven't read the book to understand the true meaning of it. So if the makers of the 1997 version spent a little more time on each scene and included the small details (they make a huge difference), this movie would be absolutely perfect. Other than that, this version is just beautiful with its costumes, music, settings, and cast. It pictures 19th century Russia perfectly unlike any other version before or after it (including the 2000 version).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice backdrop, shame about the acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Chapman
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The BBC made a serial of this in the 70's and despite the lack of funding that went into that series, they pulled it off rather well. So finally about the iron curtain had been taken down, the filmmakers could use the best scenery Russia had to offer including the Romanov palace. And you would have thought Sean Bean in a 'Sharpe' style uniform would have made it a certain winner. Afraid not. This is a story of passion and romance and forbidden love, one where you feel for the characters, get entwined with them and almost beg them to stop whilst wishing they could get away with there illicit affair. This 1997 version, I felt no connection to the characters and couldn't really care less about the 2 dimensional performance. If I had bothered to watch it to the end, instead of hanging on the edge of the seat to stop Anna from jumping on the rail tracks, I probably would have volunteers to give her a push. A wonderful Russian tragic love story, though the only tragedy here being this lot bothered to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The usual story but with a vaginal hemorrhage bonus!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Beno&icirc;t A. Racine (benoit-3)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To think this story has been filmed probably most often of all the Russian novels and that all the preceding versions managed to preserve their dignity while never quite getting to the point of the original novel... And then, this little bit of fluff had to come along. I caught this on Canadian Bravo tonight and what a disappointment. It strictly adheres to the European school of literary-adaptations-as-a-series-of-medical-emergencies-and-body fluids-melodrama. Sophie Marceau is no Greta Garbo or Russian grande bourgeoise, Lord knows. But would it be too much to ask for her to keep her facial features from contorting into a very anachronistic crack addict's at the slightest hint of "drama"? And the scene of her violent vaginal hemorrhage is definitely not in the novel but must have seemed de rigueur for the producers' sensibilities: childbirth was such an ordeal in those barbaric times, don't you know - we just had to show it... The music is by Tchaikowsky, Sean Bean is the sexiest man alive even when forced to wear clothes, the sets and costumes are by God, but the script is strictly Extreme Harlequin. As my late mother wisely used to say about most modern pap of this type: "Ils font expr&egrave;s pour nous &eacute;coeurer!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely.... absolutely lovely.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nessa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was surprisingly good. I'm not that much a fan of the Romance genre, if truth be told, but I'll make an exception for this one. The film is carefully crafted. Every emotion, every dialogue enhanced the overall tone of the film, slowly but surely escalating in its momentum up to its tragic climax. Sophie Marceau was brilliant. As was Sean Bean. I wasn't quite sure if they would be able to possess the kind of chemistry needed to pull this off, if truth be told, considering how they (in my opinion) seem to be of different temperament artistically (Sophie being more sensitive as seen in Braveheart and Marquis, while Bean is more explosive). Nevertheless, it worked out fine although, ironically, their relationship seem to be more believable whenever they fell out of odds with each other. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, but the relationship does not work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blumenwiesen
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In general I liked this movie very much. It has a very authentic atmosphere and is the only movie version of "Anna Karenina" that actually follows the point of view of the book. The setting is amazing and the costumes are brilliant. The actors are great: Karenin - James Fox is amazing. I've always had a weak spot for Sean Bean as well and I think (although in his usual roles he is more of a rogue) he carries off the part of the count rather well. When I said the actors are great however, that does not stretch to Marceau. She's just not good as Anna Karenina. And, more important, the relationship between Wronsky and Anna does not work - I don't know, but the acting between those two could not have been worse if the actors actually despised each other. And the relationship has no development. The audience does not even get an idea what their relationship is about - there is no tension between them. Anna Karenina seems to be more hysterical than anything else. To Summarize: Yes, this movie is worth seeing. It is a wonderful story, told in a great setting with a lot of good actors. Just ignore the performance of Marceau.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Eye candy which barely misses the mark!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kriddd
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not sure how this movie slipped past me, as I try to stay on top of the period movies that come out. Nonetheless I caught it on one of the Encore channels last night, and I'm glad I did. Visually this movie is incredible! The cinematography could not have been much better, down to small details such as Levin "mowing" in the fields with the scythe in perfect rhythm with the workers. As much as I like the film, however, I'm disappointed that Sophie Marceau's portrayal of Anna was not more passionate. On the whole I thought her performance was pretty good, but I agree with the comments above that she could have exhibited a much more involved and emotional presence in the face of a love that she could not resist. Ditto for Sean Bean, although he was somewhat better at it than Sophie. It's a situation where one fervently wishes that the actors were better than they were, because you know that it would have made the movie a "10." Both Bean and Marceau did provide some excellent glimpses into the souls of their characters, but only glimpses. One would wish for more intimate looks into their motivations and their respective desolations. I was not at all put off by accents of the actors. So Marceau has a mild French accent...French was the dominant language of the Russian court up to the Revolution, so it would not have been out of place at all. The story of Levin and Kitty fares better, if only because of the stellar performance of Alfred Molina. Offhand I can't think of a more underrated actor (save perhaps Ron Perlman). Ms. Kirshner was fine as Kitty, although her journey from infatuation with Vronsky to love for Levin was given short shrift. Overall I loved this movie, but I just wish it had been two marks better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very beautiful in it's own way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_watcher 1234
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though not a faithful adaptation like any other until now, it's a very decent and well done with no doubt. Sophie Marceau played Anna beautifully and Sean Bean was very good as Vronsky. The only versions I watched about Leo Tolstoy's novel are this and the 2012 one, which I consider a gorgeous adaptation, despite the critics and public review, and also refreshing and interesting which it's what I admire from an new adaptation. This adaptation retains most of the Russian feeling and atmosphere, being filmed there, and also including some Russian dialog from time to time. It's something that inspires a lot of respect indeed, but that doesn't mean we should criticize the other adaptations for being filmed in Britain or America or, the most common complain nowadays, for having British accents. This one has British accents too, but because there are more well-known actors/actress appreciated by the public and most important because it was filmed in Russia with some mild Russian dialog, some parts for which other adaptations suffer has been overlooked here. I, as a viewer and a fan of movies, never ever paid attention that much to accents. If that's a good thing or not, it's up to every persons personal view, but for me it's a very silly and childish thing to judge a movie and the actors performances 70% based on what accents they perform. This brings in my view the theory that people get very bored in this life lately and prefer to pick up on silly matters in every aspect of his life. This only will downfall this world. One should learn to appreciate simple things more and pay attention to what matters. I recommend this one, for being a very decent adaptation, not all faithful but it doesn't matter in my opinion.The performances were great, the actors did a superb job, and Russia looks stunning. But I also recommend the 2012 version too. They are both brilliant in their own way, but warning: tell them apart and don't compare them. They are different. For me Keira was a perfect Anna Karenina. Sophie did a wonderful job too, but I love Keira more and so does my mother, who loves the book and this version, but admires the new one too. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On the whole, a fantastic adaptation of a great novel!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tppowierza
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt compelled to create an IMDb account and write this review after reading some of the negative reviews that exist for this movie. First of all, let me say that this movie is underrated on IMDb. It should have a rating of at least a 7.0. At the time of this review, this movie has a lower rating than Star Wars I Phantom Menace. Come on people, that's an outrage! I feel an 8.0 is a solid and reasonable rating when you compare this film to most of the movies that are overrated on this site. Now to the bulk of the review. First of all, I think most people would agree that the film is visually stunning. Everything from the costumes, to the landscapes, to the buildings, all of it is eye candy. While this is only one aspect of the film, I think it is an important one because the visuals help set the right tone and romantic atmosphere that is found in the novel. The visuals themselves are enough reason to see this film, even if you know nothing about the story or don't care for it. Secondly, the performances by Sophie Marceau, Sean Bean, and the rest of the cast were superb. There was only one major issue with the acting in my opinion.I wasn't fond of how Stepan (Stiva) was portrayed in the movie. The actor who played him was too dull and flat. In the novel, Stepan is supposed to be charming and sort of opposite to Levin in personality. Other than that, I found everyone to be excellent in their roles. Contrary to what you may think after reading some of the negative reviews, Sophie Marceau was a wonderful Anna. As a previous review stated, I think her French accent was positive and enhanced her performance. After all, in the novel it says that Anna and Vronsky spoke French with each other most of the time. Secondly, I found that both her and Sean Bean made the affair between Anna and Vronsky credible, believable, and every bit dramatic as it is in the novel. Some have complained that Sophie did not capture Anna's simplicity or elegance, but this is just outright wrong. Sean Bean, despite not having the mustache, played Vronsky well. As a guy, I generally hate love scenes in films because the lines are so cheesy and the actors/actresses have no chemistry. While some of the things Vronsky says in the movie/and the novel may seem cheesy and overly dramatic, Sean Bean's delivery is perfect and not overly done. On the whole, Sophie Marceau and Sean Bean had great chemistry in this film. Alfred Molina and Mia Kirshner were great as Levin and Kitty, although I thought her accent was a little weird and out of place. Lastly, the director did a really good job of selecting appropriate scenes and making them fit together to do justice to the novel. As with any other film based off a long novel, much had to be cut out. However, all the important scenes that compromise the essence of the many themes in the novel were all present. With that being said, the movie still had its flaws. For example, I did not like the few narrations that were placed in the film and thought they were unnecessary and detracted from the film's flow. Maybe this is because I watched the film right after finishing the book for the second time, so the plot was fresh in my head. The film also had a few oddball scenes that were not done well, such as in the beginning with the conversation between Dolly and Anna. For me, this whole scene seemed wrong because of how they changed Anna's lines. However, on the whole most of the scenes were not only faithful to the novel, but due to the wonderful visuals and performances, brought it to life. On the whole, I wasn't expecting much from this film. I thought it was going to be a crummy "Hollywood" version of one of my favorite novels and wasn't expecting much from Sophie Marceau or Sean Bean. While there were some of these "Hollywood" style elements, ( just look at the waltz they had in the movie) the movie overall was surprisingly refreshing and well done. Definitely worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Half the material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ferdinand1932
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the production design, photography costumes etc are all quite spectacular this is only half the book. That it is not really the book which may seem a normal quibble, but all the other details which are so rich in the original, is lost here and what is left is a melodrama. One reason is that the length of a great novel cannot ever be crammed into a film of normal endurance. The problem then becomes one of audience engagement and also character motivation because the characters are so attenuated in the film. The rich back histories and the social settings and discussion of current ideas is also fundamental to a Tolstoy novel and here it is only hinted at in parts. Some level of implication is good in a film, unlike a novel, but in this case it is reduces a novel to a text message. The result is not a bad film, but is unfortunately superficial. The task the filmmakers set is enormous - too big for what is accomplished. It's solution is not in this medium and at this length: a multi-part TV series would be have been better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully filmed version with a great score but why Sean Bean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the better versions of Anna Karenina. It's not too old or too new. It's hard to watch the slightly cheap BBC versions or the old black and white Hollywood versions. It is modern enough to have a fresh feel and great on location filming. It's also not too long. The score is wonderful - Tchaikovsky. Sophie Marceau looks beautiful and tragic. Her acting is good too although her accent isn't Russian. Supporting cast are all good including Alfred Molina. The main problem is Sean Bean was a strange choice. He doesn't look Russian and he isn't dashing enough. He's more the villain with his cruel look. It is interesting to compare this with the Jacqueline Bisset and Christopher Reeve version. I think this one is better overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It would be perfect if...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sp_rose2005
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do not agree with the earlier reviews that Vivian Leigh played Anna better than Sophy Marceau. It is just that the 1948 version was by itself a better film. The weakness of the 1997 version is that it the scenes are too short and scattered together, and this makes it difficult to express the emotions of the characters and the overall idea behind Tolstoy's novel. But this is the weakness of the movie makers, not the actors. In the 1948 version, the scenes are very detailed and the conversations are long enough to express the idea of each scene. 1948 version is good, but not the best. I don't know if anyone has seen the British miniseries of 2000-2001, but if you want to understand the idea of the book, you should watch it. The cast is not the best, Anna looks old and not suited for this role although she acts perfectly, Vronsky cannot even be compared with Sean Bean, but it's very detailed and just gets deep down to the main core of the novel. It also covers Levin perfectly. The 1997 version pays significant attention to Levin's character as well, but again, because the scenes are too confusing, it will be difficult for those who haven't read the book to understand the true meaning of it. So if the makers of the 1997 version spent a little more time on each scene and included the small details (they make a huge difference), this movie would be absolutely perfect. Other than that, this version is just beautiful with its costumes, music, settings, and cast. It pictures 19th century Russia perfectly unlike any other version before or after it (including the 2000 version).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice backdrop, shame about the acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Chapman
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The BBC made a serial of this in the 70's and despite the lack of funding that went into that series, they pulled it off rather well. So finally about the iron curtain had been taken down, the filmmakers could use the best scenery Russia had to offer including the Romanov palace. And you would have thought Sean Bean in a 'Sharpe' style uniform would have made it a certain winner. Afraid not. This is a story of passion and romance and forbidden love, one where you feel for the characters, get entwined with them and almost beg them to stop whilst wishing they could get away with there illicit affair. This 1997 version, I felt no connection to the characters and couldn't really care less about the 2 dimensional performance. If I had bothered to watch it to the end, instead of hanging on the edge of the seat to stop Anna from jumping on the rail tracks, I probably would have volunteers to give her a push. A wonderful Russian tragic love story, though the only tragedy here being this lot bothered to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The usual story but with a vaginal hemorrhage bonus!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Beno&icirc;t A. Racine (benoit-3)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To think this story has been filmed probably most often of all the Russian novels and that all the preceding versions managed to preserve their dignity while never quite getting to the point of the original novel... And then, this little bit of fluff had to come along. I caught this on Canadian Bravo tonight and what a disappointment. It strictly adheres to the European school of literary-adaptations-as-a-series-of-medical-emergencies-and-body fluids-melodrama. Sophie Marceau is no Greta Garbo or Russian grande bourgeoise, Lord knows. But would it be too much to ask for her to keep her facial features from contorting into a very anachronistic crack addict's at the slightest hint of "drama"? And the scene of her violent vaginal hemorrhage is definitely not in the novel but must have seemed de rigueur for the producers' sensibilities: childbirth was such an ordeal in those barbaric times, don't you know - we just had to show it... The music is by Tchaikowsky, Sean Bean is the sexiest man alive even when forced to wear clothes, the sets and costumes are by God, but the script is strictly Extreme Harlequin. As my late mother wisely used to say about most modern pap of this type: "Ils font expr&egrave;s pour nous &eacute;coeurer!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely.... absolutely lovely.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nessa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was surprisingly good. I'm not that much a fan of the Romance genre, if truth be told, but I'll make an exception for this one. The film is carefully crafted. Every emotion, every dialogue enhanced the overall tone of the film, slowly but surely escalating in its momentum up to its tragic climax. Sophie Marceau was brilliant. As was Sean Bean. I wasn't quite sure if they would be able to possess the kind of chemistry needed to pull this off, if truth be told, considering how they (in my opinion) seem to be of different temperament artistically (Sophie being more sensitive as seen in Braveheart and Marquis, while Bean is more explosive). Nevertheless, it worked out fine although, ironically, their relationship seem to be more believable whenever they fell out of odds with each other. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, but the relationship does not work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blumenwiesen
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In general I liked this movie very much. It has a very authentic atmosphere and is the only movie version of "Anna Karenina" that actually follows the point of view of the book. The setting is amazing and the costumes are brilliant. The actors are great: Karenin - James Fox is amazing. I've always had a weak spot for Sean Bean as well and I think (although in his usual roles he is more of a rogue) he carries off the part of the count rather well. When I said the actors are great however, that does not stretch to Marceau. She's just not good as Anna Karenina. And, more important, the relationship between Wronsky and Anna does not work - I don't know, but the acting between those two could not have been worse if the actors actually despised each other. And the relationship has no development. The audience does not even get an idea what their relationship is about - there is no tension between them. Anna Karenina seems to be more hysterical than anything else. To Summarize: Yes, this movie is worth seeing. It is a wonderful story, told in a great setting with a lot of good actors. Just ignore the performance of Marceau.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Eye candy which barely misses the mark!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kriddd
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not sure how this movie slipped past me, as I try to stay on top of the period movies that come out. Nonetheless I caught it on one of the Encore channels last night, and I'm glad I did. Visually this movie is incredible! The cinematography could not have been much better, down to small details such as Levin "mowing" in the fields with the scythe in perfect rhythm with the workers. As much as I like the film, however, I'm disappointed that Sophie Marceau's portrayal of Anna was not more passionate. On the whole I thought her performance was pretty good, but I agree with the comments above that she could have exhibited a much more involved and emotional presence in the face of a love that she could not resist. Ditto for Sean Bean, although he was somewhat better at it than Sophie. It's a situation where one fervently wishes that the actors were better than they were, because you know that it would have made the movie a "10." Both Bean and Marceau did provide some excellent glimpses into the souls of their characters, but only glimpses. One would wish for more intimate looks into their motivations and their respective desolations. I was not at all put off by accents of the actors. So Marceau has a mild French accent...French was the dominant language of the Russian court up to the Revolution, so it would not have been out of place at all. The story of Levin and Kitty fares better, if only because of the stellar performance of Alfred Molina. Offhand I can't think of a more underrated actor (save perhaps Ron Perlman). Ms. Kirshner was fine as Kitty, although her journey from infatuation with Vronsky to love for Levin was given short shrift. Overall I loved this movie, but I just wish it had been two marks better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very beautiful in it's own way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_watcher 1234
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though not a faithful adaptation like any other until now, it's a very decent and well done with no doubt. Sophie Marceau played Anna beautifully and Sean Bean was very good as Vronsky. The only versions I watched about Leo Tolstoy's novel are this and the 2012 one, which I consider a gorgeous adaptation, despite the critics and public review, and also refreshing and interesting which it's what I admire from an new adaptation. This adaptation retains most of the Russian feeling and atmosphere, being filmed there, and also including some Russian dialog from time to time. It's something that inspires a lot of respect indeed, but that doesn't mean we should criticize the other adaptations for being filmed in Britain or America or, the most common complain nowadays, for having British accents. This one has British accents too, but because there are more well-known actors/actress appreciated by the public and most important because it was filmed in Russia with some mild Russian dialog, some parts for which other adaptations suffer has been overlooked here. I, as a viewer and a fan of movies, never ever paid attention that much to accents. If that's a good thing or not, it's up to every persons personal view, but for me it's a very silly and childish thing to judge a movie and the actors performances 70% based on what accents they perform. This brings in my view the theory that people get very bored in this life lately and prefer to pick up on silly matters in every aspect of his life. This only will downfall this world. One should learn to appreciate simple things more and pay attention to what matters. I recommend this one, for being a very decent adaptation, not all faithful but it doesn't matter in my opinion.The performances were great, the actors did a superb job, and Russia looks stunning. But I also recommend the 2012 version too. They are both brilliant in their own way, but warning: tell them apart and don't compare them. They are different. For me Keira was a perfect Anna Karenina. Sophie did a wonderful job too, but I love Keira more and so does my mother, who loves the book and this version, but admires the new one too. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On the whole, a fantastic adaptation of a great novel!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tppowierza
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt compelled to create an IMDb account and write this review after reading some of the negative reviews that exist for this movie. First of all, let me say that this movie is underrated on IMDb. It should have a rating of at least a 7.0. At the time of this review, this movie has a lower rating than Star Wars I Phantom Menace. Come on people, that's an outrage! I feel an 8.0 is a solid and reasonable rating when you compare this film to most of the movies that are overrated on this site. Now to the bulk of the review. First of all, I think most people would agree that the film is visually stunning. Everything from the costumes, to the landscapes, to the buildings, all of it is eye candy. While this is only one aspect of the film, I think it is an important one because the visuals help set the right tone and romantic atmosphere that is found in the novel. The visuals themselves are enough reason to see this film, even if you know nothing about the story or don't care for it. Secondly, the performances by Sophie Marceau, Sean Bean, and the rest of the cast were superb. There was only one major issue with the acting in my opinion.I wasn't fond of how Stepan (Stiva) was portrayed in the movie. The actor who played him was too dull and flat. In the novel, Stepan is supposed to be charming and sort of opposite to Levin in personality. Other than that, I found everyone to be excellent in their roles. Contrary to what you may think after reading some of the negative reviews, Sophie Marceau was a wonderful Anna. As a previous review stated, I think her French accent was positive and enhanced her performance. After all, in the novel it says that Anna and Vronsky spoke French with each other most of the time. Secondly, I found that both her and Sean Bean made the affair between Anna and Vronsky credible, believable, and every bit dramatic as it is in the novel. Some have complained that Sophie did not capture Anna's simplicity or elegance, but this is just outright wrong. Sean Bean, despite not having the mustache, played Vronsky well. As a guy, I generally hate love scenes in films because the lines are so cheesy and the actors/actresses have no chemistry. While some of the things Vronsky says in the movie/and the novel may seem cheesy and overly dramatic, Sean Bean's delivery is perfect and not overly done. On the whole, Sophie Marceau and Sean Bean had great chemistry in this film. Alfred Molina and Mia Kirshner were great as Levin and Kitty, although I thought her accent was a little weird and out of place. Lastly, the director did a really good job of selecting appropriate scenes and making them fit together to do justice to the novel. As with any other film based off a long novel, much had to be cut out. However, all the important scenes that compromise the essence of the many themes in the novel were all present. With that being said, the movie still had its flaws. For example, I did not like the few narrations that were placed in the film and thought they were unnecessary and detracted from the film's flow. Maybe this is because I watched the film right after finishing the book for the second time, so the plot was fresh in my head. The film also had a few oddball scenes that were not done well, such as in the beginning with the conversation between Dolly and Anna. For me, this whole scene seemed wrong because of how they changed Anna's lines. However, on the whole most of the scenes were not only faithful to the novel, but due to the wonderful visuals and performances, brought it to life. On the whole, I wasn't expecting much from this film. I thought it was going to be a crummy "Hollywood" version of one of my favorite novels and wasn't expecting much from Sophie Marceau or Sean Bean. While there were some of these "Hollywood" style elements, ( just look at the waltz they had in the movie) the movie overall was surprisingly refreshing and well done. Definitely worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Half the material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ferdinand1932
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the production design, photography costumes etc are all quite spectacular this is only half the book. That it is not really the book which may seem a normal quibble, but all the other details which are so rich in the original, is lost here and what is left is a melodrama. One reason is that the length of a great novel cannot ever be crammed into a film of normal endurance. The problem then becomes one of audience engagement and also character motivation because the characters are so attenuated in the film. The rich back histories and the social settings and discussion of current ideas is also fundamental to a Tolstoy novel and here it is only hinted at in parts. Some level of implication is good in a film, unlike a novel, but in this case it is reduces a novel to a text message. The result is not a bad film, but is unfortunately superficial. The task the filmmakers set is enormous - too big for what is accomplished. It's solution is not in this medium and at this length: a multi-part TV series would be have been better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully filmed version with a great score but why Sean Bean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the better versions of Anna Karenina. It's not too old or too new. It's hard to watch the slightly cheap BBC versions or the old black and white Hollywood versions. It is modern enough to have a fresh feel and great on location filming. It's also not too long. The score is wonderful - Tchaikovsky. Sophie Marceau looks beautiful and tragic. Her acting is good too although her accent isn't Russian. Supporting cast are all good including Alfred Molina. The main problem is Sean Bean was a strange choice. He doesn't look Russian and he isn't dashing enough. He's more the villain with his cruel look. It is interesting to compare this with the Jacqueline Bisset and Christopher Reeve version. I think this one is better overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It would be perfect if...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sp_rose2005
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do not agree with the earlier reviews that Vivian Leigh played Anna better than Sophy Marceau. It is just that the 1948 version was by itself a better film. The weakness of the 1997 version is that it the scenes are too short and scattered together, and this makes it difficult to express the emotions of the characters and the overall idea behind Tolstoy's novel. But this is the weakness of the movie makers, not the actors. In the 1948 version, the scenes are very detailed and the conversations are long enough to express the idea of each scene. 1948 version is good, but not the best. I don't know if anyone has seen the British miniseries of 2000-2001, but if you want to understand the idea of the book, you should watch it. The cast is not the best, Anna looks old and not suited for this role although she acts perfectly, Vronsky cannot even be compared with Sean Bean, but it's very detailed and just gets deep down to the main core of the novel. It also covers Levin perfectly. The 1997 version pays significant attention to Levin's character as well, but again, because the scenes are too confusing, it will be difficult for those who haven't read the book to understand the true meaning of it. So if the makers of the 1997 version spent a little more time on each scene and included the small details (they make a huge difference), this movie would be absolutely perfect. Other than that, this version is just beautiful with its costumes, music, settings, and cast. It pictures 19th century Russia perfectly unlike any other version before or after it (including the 2000 version).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice backdrop, shame about the acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Chapman
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The BBC made a serial of this in the 70's and despite the lack of funding that went into that series, they pulled it off rather well. So finally about the iron curtain had been taken down, the filmmakers could use the best scenery Russia had to offer including the Romanov palace. And you would have thought Sean Bean in a 'Sharpe' style uniform would have made it a certain winner. Afraid not. This is a story of passion and romance and forbidden love, one where you feel for the characters, get entwined with them and almost beg them to stop whilst wishing they could get away with there illicit affair. This 1997 version, I felt no connection to the characters and couldn't really care less about the 2 dimensional performance. If I had bothered to watch it to the end, instead of hanging on the edge of the seat to stop Anna from jumping on the rail tracks, I probably would have volunteers to give her a push. A wonderful Russian tragic love story, though the only tragedy here being this lot bothered to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The usual story but with a vaginal hemorrhage bonus!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Beno&icirc;t A. Racine (benoit-3)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To think this story has been filmed probably most often of all the Russian novels and that all the preceding versions managed to preserve their dignity while never quite getting to the point of the original novel... And then, this little bit of fluff had to come along. I caught this on Canadian Bravo tonight and what a disappointment. It strictly adheres to the European school of literary-adaptations-as-a-series-of-medical-emergencies-and-body fluids-melodrama. Sophie Marceau is no Greta Garbo or Russian grande bourgeoise, Lord knows. But would it be too much to ask for her to keep her facial features from contorting into a very anachronistic crack addict's at the slightest hint of "drama"? And the scene of her violent vaginal hemorrhage is definitely not in the novel but must have seemed de rigueur for the producers' sensibilities: childbirth was such an ordeal in those barbaric times, don't you know - we just had to show it... The music is by Tchaikowsky, Sean Bean is the sexiest man alive even when forced to wear clothes, the sets and costumes are by God, but the script is strictly Extreme Harlequin. As my late mother wisely used to say about most modern pap of this type: "Ils font expr&egrave;s pour nous &eacute;coeurer!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely.... absolutely lovely.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nessa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was surprisingly good. I'm not that much a fan of the Romance genre, if truth be told, but I'll make an exception for this one. The film is carefully crafted. Every emotion, every dialogue enhanced the overall tone of the film, slowly but surely escalating in its momentum up to its tragic climax. Sophie Marceau was brilliant. As was Sean Bean. I wasn't quite sure if they would be able to possess the kind of chemistry needed to pull this off, if truth be told, considering how they (in my opinion) seem to be of different temperament artistically (Sophie being more sensitive as seen in Braveheart and Marquis, while Bean is more explosive). Nevertheless, it worked out fine although, ironically, their relationship seem to be more believable whenever they fell out of odds with each other. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, but the relationship does not work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blumenwiesen
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In general I liked this movie very much. It has a very authentic atmosphere and is the only movie version of "Anna Karenina" that actually follows the point of view of the book. The setting is amazing and the costumes are brilliant. The actors are great: Karenin - James Fox is amazing. I've always had a weak spot for Sean Bean as well and I think (although in his usual roles he is more of a rogue) he carries off the part of the count rather well. When I said the actors are great however, that does not stretch to Marceau. She's just not good as Anna Karenina. And, more important, the relationship between Wronsky and Anna does not work - I don't know, but the acting between those two could not have been worse if the actors actually despised each other. And the relationship has no development. The audience does not even get an idea what their relationship is about - there is no tension between them. Anna Karenina seems to be more hysterical than anything else. To Summarize: Yes, this movie is worth seeing. It is a wonderful story, told in a great setting with a lot of good actors. Just ignore the performance of Marceau.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Eye candy which barely misses the mark!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kriddd
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not sure how this movie slipped past me, as I try to stay on top of the period movies that come out. Nonetheless I caught it on one of the Encore channels last night, and I'm glad I did. Visually this movie is incredible! The cinematography could not have been much better, down to small details such as Levin "mowing" in the fields with the scythe in perfect rhythm with the workers. As much as I like the film, however, I'm disappointed that Sophie Marceau's portrayal of Anna was not more passionate. On the whole I thought her performance was pretty good, but I agree with the comments above that she could have exhibited a much more involved and emotional presence in the face of a love that she could not resist. Ditto for Sean Bean, although he was somewhat better at it than Sophie. It's a situation where one fervently wishes that the actors were better than they were, because you know that it would have made the movie a "10." Both Bean and Marceau did provide some excellent glimpses into the souls of their characters, but only glimpses. One would wish for more intimate looks into their motivations and their respective desolations. I was not at all put off by accents of the actors. So Marceau has a mild French accent...French was the dominant language of the Russian court up to the Revolution, so it would not have been out of place at all. The story of Levin and Kitty fares better, if only because of the stellar performance of Alfred Molina. Offhand I can't think of a more underrated actor (save perhaps Ron Perlman). Ms. Kirshner was fine as Kitty, although her journey from infatuation with Vronsky to love for Levin was given short shrift. Overall I loved this movie, but I just wish it had been two marks better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very beautiful in it's own way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    movie_watcher 1234
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Though not a faithful adaptation like any other until now, it's a very decent and well done with no doubt. Sophie Marceau played Anna beautifully and Sean Bean was very good as Vronsky. The only versions I watched about Leo Tolstoy's novel are this and the 2012 one, which I consider a gorgeous adaptation, despite the critics and public review, and also refreshing and interesting which it's what I admire from an new adaptation. This adaptation retains most of the Russian feeling and atmosphere, being filmed there, and also including some Russian dialog from time to time. It's something that inspires a lot of respect indeed, but that doesn't mean we should criticize the other adaptations for being filmed in Britain or America or, the most common complain nowadays, for having British accents. This one has British accents too, but because there are more well-known actors/actress appreciated by the public and most important because it was filmed in Russia with some mild Russian dialog, some parts for which other adaptations suffer has been overlooked here. I, as a viewer and a fan of movies, never ever paid attention that much to accents. If that's a good thing or not, it's up to every persons personal view, but for me it's a very silly and childish thing to judge a movie and the actors performances 70% based on what accents they perform. This brings in my view the theory that people get very bored in this life lately and prefer to pick up on silly matters in every aspect of his life. This only will downfall this world. One should learn to appreciate simple things more and pay attention to what matters. I recommend this one, for being a very decent adaptation, not all faithful but it doesn't matter in my opinion.The performances were great, the actors did a superb job, and Russia looks stunning. But I also recommend the 2012 version too. They are both brilliant in their own way, but warning: tell them apart and don't compare them. They are different. For me Keira was a perfect Anna Karenina. Sophie did a wonderful job too, but I love Keira more and so does my mother, who loves the book and this version, but admires the new one too. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    On the whole, a fantastic adaptation of a great novel!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tppowierza
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I felt compelled to create an IMDb account and write this review after reading some of the negative reviews that exist for this movie. First of all, let me say that this movie is underrated on IMDb. It should have a rating of at least a 7.0. At the time of this review, this movie has a lower rating than Star Wars I Phantom Menace. Come on people, that's an outrage! I feel an 8.0 is a solid and reasonable rating when you compare this film to most of the movies that are overrated on this site. Now to the bulk of the review. First of all, I think most people would agree that the film is visually stunning. Everything from the costumes, to the landscapes, to the buildings, all of it is eye candy. While this is only one aspect of the film, I think it is an important one because the visuals help set the right tone and romantic atmosphere that is found in the novel. The visuals themselves are enough reason to see this film, even if you know nothing about the story or don't care for it. Secondly, the performances by Sophie Marceau, Sean Bean, and the rest of the cast were superb. There was only one major issue with the acting in my opinion.I wasn't fond of how Stepan (Stiva) was portrayed in the movie. The actor who played him was too dull and flat. In the novel, Stepan is supposed to be charming and sort of opposite to Levin in personality. Other than that, I found everyone to be excellent in their roles. Contrary to what you may think after reading some of the negative reviews, Sophie Marceau was a wonderful Anna. As a previous review stated, I think her French accent was positive and enhanced her performance. After all, in the novel it says that Anna and Vronsky spoke French with each other most of the time. Secondly, I found that both her and Sean Bean made the affair between Anna and Vronsky credible, believable, and every bit dramatic as it is in the novel. Some have complained that Sophie did not capture Anna's simplicity or elegance, but this is just outright wrong. Sean Bean, despite not having the mustache, played Vronsky well. As a guy, I generally hate love scenes in films because the lines are so cheesy and the actors/actresses have no chemistry. While some of the things Vronsky says in the movie/and the novel may seem cheesy and overly dramatic, Sean Bean's delivery is perfect and not overly done. On the whole, Sophie Marceau and Sean Bean had great chemistry in this film. Alfred Molina and Mia Kirshner were great as Levin and Kitty, although I thought her accent was a little weird and out of place. Lastly, the director did a really good job of selecting appropriate scenes and making them fit together to do justice to the novel. As with any other film based off a long novel, much had to be cut out. However, all the important scenes that compromise the essence of the many themes in the novel were all present. With that being said, the movie still had its flaws. For example, I did not like the few narrations that were placed in the film and thought they were unnecessary and detracted from the film's flow. Maybe this is because I watched the film right after finishing the book for the second time, so the plot was fresh in my head. The film also had a few oddball scenes that were not done well, such as in the beginning with the conversation between Dolly and Anna. For me, this whole scene seemed wrong because of how they changed Anna's lines. However, on the whole most of the scenes were not only faithful to the novel, but due to the wonderful visuals and performances, brought it to life. On the whole, I wasn't expecting much from this film. I thought it was going to be a crummy "Hollywood" version of one of my favorite novels and wasn't expecting much from Sophie Marceau or Sean Bean. While there were some of these "Hollywood" style elements, ( just look at the waltz they had in the movie) the movie overall was surprisingly refreshing and well done. Definitely worth seeing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Half the material
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ferdinand1932
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While the production design, photography costumes etc are all quite spectacular this is only half the book. That it is not really the book which may seem a normal quibble, but all the other details which are so rich in the original, is lost here and what is left is a melodrama. One reason is that the length of a great novel cannot ever be crammed into a film of normal endurance. The problem then becomes one of audience engagement and also character motivation because the characters are so attenuated in the film. The rich back histories and the social settings and discussion of current ideas is also fundamental to a Tolstoy novel and here it is only hinted at in parts. Some level of implication is good in a film, unlike a novel, but in this case it is reduces a novel to a text message. The result is not a bad film, but is unfortunately superficial. The task the filmmakers set is enormous - too big for what is accomplished. It's solution is not in this medium and at this length: a multi-part TV series would be have been better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully filmed version with a great score but why Sean Bean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    phd_travel
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the better versions of Anna Karenina. It's not too old or too new. It's hard to watch the slightly cheap BBC versions or the old black and white Hollywood versions. It is modern enough to have a fresh feel and great on location filming. It's also not too long. The score is wonderful - Tchaikovsky. Sophie Marceau looks beautiful and tragic. Her acting is good too although her accent isn't Russian. Supporting cast are all good including Alfred Molina. The main problem is Sean Bean was a strange choice. He doesn't look Russian and he isn't dashing enough. He's more the villain with his cruel look. It is interesting to compare this with the Jacqueline Bisset and Christopher Reeve version. I think this one is better overall.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It would be perfect if...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sp_rose2005
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do not agree with the earlier reviews that Vivian Leigh played Anna better than Sophy Marceau. It is just that the 1948 version was by itself a better film. The weakness of the 1997 version is that it the scenes are too short and scattered together, and this makes it difficult to express the emotions of the characters and the overall idea behind Tolstoy's novel. But this is the weakness of the movie makers, not the actors. In the 1948 version, the scenes are very detailed and the conversations are long enough to express the idea of each scene. 1948 version is good, but not the best. I don't know if anyone has seen the British miniseries of 2000-2001, but if you want to understand the idea of the book, you should watch it. The cast is not the best, Anna looks old and not suited for this role although she acts perfectly, Vronsky cannot even be compared with Sean Bean, but it's very detailed and just gets deep down to the main core of the novel. It also covers Levin perfectly. The 1997 version pays significant attention to Levin's character as well, but again, because the scenes are too confusing, it will be difficult for those who haven't read the book to understand the true meaning of it. So if the makers of the 1997 version spent a little more time on each scene and included the small details (they make a huge difference), this movie would be absolutely perfect. Other than that, this version is just beautiful with its costumes, music, settings, and cast. It pictures 19th century Russia perfectly unlike any other version before or after it (including the 2000 version).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice backdrop, shame about the acting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Chapman
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The BBC made a serial of this in the 70's and despite the lack of funding that went into that series, they pulled it off rather well. So finally about the iron curtain had been taken down, the filmmakers could use the best scenery Russia had to offer including the Romanov palace. And you would have thought Sean Bean in a 'Sharpe' style uniform would have made it a certain winner. Afraid not. This is a story of passion and romance and forbidden love, one where you feel for the characters, get entwined with them and almost beg them to stop whilst wishing they could get away with there illicit affair. This 1997 version, I felt no connection to the characters and couldn't really care less about the 2 dimensional performance. If I had bothered to watch it to the end, instead of hanging on the edge of the seat to stop Anna from jumping on the rail tracks, I probably would have volunteers to give her a push. A wonderful Russian tragic love story, though the only tragedy here being this lot bothered to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The usual story but with a vaginal hemorrhage bonus!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Beno&icirc;t A. Racine (benoit-3)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To think this story has been filmed probably most often of all the Russian novels and that all the preceding versions managed to preserve their dignity while never quite getting to the point of the original novel... And then, this little bit of fluff had to come along. I caught this on Canadian Bravo tonight and what a disappointment. It strictly adheres to the European school of literary-adaptations-as-a-series-of-medical-emergencies-and-body fluids-melodrama. Sophie Marceau is no Greta Garbo or Russian grande bourgeoise, Lord knows. But would it be too much to ask for her to keep her facial features from contorting into a very anachronistic crack addict's at the slightest hint of "drama"? And the scene of her violent vaginal hemorrhage is definitely not in the novel but must have seemed de rigueur for the producers' sensibilities: childbirth was such an ordeal in those barbaric times, don't you know - we just had to show it... The music is by Tchaikowsky, Sean Bean is the sexiest man alive even when forced to wear clothes, the sets and costumes are by God, but the script is strictly Extreme Harlequin. As my late mother wisely used to say about most modern pap of this type: "Ils font expr&egrave;s pour nous &eacute;coeurer!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely.... absolutely lovely.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nessa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was surprisingly good. I'm not that much a fan of the Romance genre, if truth be told, but I'll make an exception for this one. The film is carefully crafted. Every emotion, every dialogue enhanced the overall tone of the film, slowly but surely escalating in its momentum up to its tragic climax. Sophie Marceau was brilliant. As was Sean Bean. I wasn't quite sure if they would be able to possess the kind of chemistry needed to pull this off, if truth be told, considering how they (in my opinion) seem to be of different temperament artistically (Sophie being more sensitive as seen in Braveheart and Marquis, while Bean is more explosive). Nevertheless, it worked out fine although, ironically, their relationship seem to be more believable whenever they fell out of odds with each other. :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good, but the relationship does not work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    blumenwiesen
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In general I liked this movie very much. It has a very authentic atmosphere and is the only movie version of "Anna Karenina" that actually follows the point of view of the book. The setting is amazing and the costumes are brilliant. The actors are great: Karenin - James Fox is amazing. I've always had a weak spot for Sean Bean as well and I think (although in his usual roles he is more of a rogue) he carries off the part of the count rather well. When I said the actors are great however, that does not stretch to Marceau. She's just not good as Anna Karenina. And, more important, the relationship between Wronsky and Anna does not work - I don't know, but the acting between those two could not have been worse if the actors actually despised each other. And the relationship has no development. The audience does not even get an idea what their relationship is about - there is no tension between them. Anna Karenina seems to be more hysterical than anything else. To Summarize: Yes, this movie is worth seeing. It is a wonderful story, told in a great setting with a lot of good actors. Just ignore the performance of Marceau.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Eye candy which barely misses the mark!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kriddd
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not sure how this movie slipped past me, as I try to stay on top of the period movies that come out. Nonetheless I caught it on one of the Encore channels last night, and I'm glad I did. Visually this movie is incredible! The cinematography could not have been much better, down to small details such as Levin "mowing" in the fields with the scythe in perfect rhythm with the workers. As much as I like the film, however, I'm disappointed that Sophie Marceau's portrayal of Anna was not more passionate. On the whole I thought her performance was pretty good, but I agree with the comments above that she could have exhibited a much more involved and emotional presence in the face of a love that she could not resist. Ditto for Sean Bean, although he was somewhat better at it than Sophie. It's a situation where one fervently wishes that the actors were better than they were, because you know that it would have made the movie a "10." Both Bean and Marceau did provide some excellent glimpses into the souls of their characters, but only glimpses. One would wish for more intimate looks into their motivations and their respective desolations. I was not at all put off by accents of the actors. So Marceau has a mild French accent...French was the dominant language of the Russian court up to the Revolution, so it would not have been out of place at all. The story of Levin and Kitty fares better, if only because of the stellar performance of Alfred Molina. Offhand I can't think of a more underrated actor (save perhaps Ron Perlman). Ms. Kirshner was fine as Kitty, although her journey from infatuation with Vronsky to love for Levin was given short shrift. Overall I loved this movie, but I just wish it had been two marks better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
