<filme>
 <id>
  997
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114571
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Como Salvar Sua Fam&iacute;lia
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Stuart Smalley, the Saturday Night Live character, comes to the big screen. Stuart, the disciple of the 12 step program, is challenged by lifes injustices. He loses his Public Access Cable ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Stuart Smalley, the Saturday Night Live character, comes to the big screen. Stuart, the disciple of the 12 step program, is challenged by lifes injustices. He loses his Public Access Cable Television Show, must beg his manipulative overbearing boss for his job back, rehabilitate his alcoholic father and drug abuser brother, and support his over-weight mother and sister in their lack of ability in handling their relationships with their husbands. Stuart is supported by his 12 step sponsors as a he regresses back to his negative behaviors each time he faces these challenges.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   public access
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   alcohol
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   based on sketch comedy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   based on tv series
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   accidental shooting
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Harold Ramis
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Al Franken
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Al Franken
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Laura San Giacomo
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Vincent D'Onofrio
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No belly laughs, but good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Derek237
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A not-so-well-remembered SNL movie based on a not-so-well-remembered SNL sketch. I watched it last night, and I don't think I've ever seen it before so it was kind of surprising at how unfunny it was. Not necessarily in a bad way, but it just felt more like an offbeat drama than a comedy. It dealt with real issues and didn't have pristine solutions and I've left it feeling contemplative and, to be honest, a little sad, which is sort of a compliment and sort of isn't. But the acting in the movie is great. I have this idea in my head of Al Franken as this gruff, intense comedic force but here he's so soft-spoken and calm so you gotta hand it to him, the guy is COMMITTED. Laura San Giacomo is also excellent and has a heartbreaking little speech. And Vincent D'Onofrio as the pothead slacker brother is good stuff. I don't know. Not sure how I altogether feel about it. I'd probably give it a 6/10, not great but by no means bad. I think it's on Netflix. Check it out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been more, but not bad!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    southwest3210-156-400970
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think that the problem with this movie is that it has difficulty handling it's tragicomic aspect. That is so hard to pull off. In my mind, the perfect example of a movie that DOES would be Steve Martin's "Roxanne". Most tragicomic movies either err on being too dramatic or too comic. This one just leaned too far in the dramatic department. While it did really flesh out the smalley characters, it did so at the expense of being funny. It needed a little more crazy/absurd moments to be a truly good comedy. I should mention that at essentially every "skit" character based movie from SNL has fallen flat, so there is not exactly much to match or beat here. Regardless of that low-bar, I truly think this could have been a riot if made differently. I had in mind something like "Stuart saves the world', like an Austin Powers flick(how ironic, BTW, that the most successful SNL alumni movies are NOT based on SNL characters, ala Bill Murray's Stripes, Groundhog Day, et al., or Chevy Chases Vacation flicks, The "Blues Brothers" being the one exception here)....Again, it would have been perfect if he saved the world through his insipid motivational drivel, seeing as how some of the actual gurus, especially the religious ones disguised as preachers, such as Joel Osteen, come close to at least "attempting" to do that right now. Actually, Joel Osteen is not at all dissimilar to Stuart Smiley. Scary but true. It could have been classic, but this little movie is still sweet, and far better then the manure 99% of the character skit SNL movies are. And now Franken has the last laugh, being one of only two US Senators that were former movie stars. Reagan will prob forever hold the record of being the only president of that ilk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alcoholism portrayed right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A better movie than expected, but what is with all the comments about it being a comedy. If it is, it must have been the first one where i didn't laugh once. Al Franken takes on a gutsy project but it is really not that interesting. It has some nice characters but it is a little too nice. Maybe it was watered down for a PG-13 rating to sell it to a teen audience. If it was, it shows a serious miscalculation of marketing strategy. There is virtually nothing here that appeal to that group. It did get the addiction part almost right, although the ending is a little too nice again. I wish they would have ended it on the intervention stuff and left the last scene out. Still, I am glad I saw it, because it was somewhat different and the main character wasn't as annoying as I thought. Just wish they had made it a little more raw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In its own way, the best SNL-character based film ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    somehope
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For those you who don't know that Al Franken became a political author/congressional candidate, he was a funny comedian who had entertained "Saturday Night Live" audiences since the 70's, and into the 1990's (off-and-on). His most famous character was a self-help, for lack of a better word, addict; i.e., his character was addicted to self-help groups, sponsors, 12 step meetings, etc., because he lacked or was coming to terms with his low self-confidence everyday and was trying to spreading self-esteem to others through a fictional cable access show on SNL called "Daily Affirmations with Stuart Smalley." He would say things like "Doggone it, people like me." Okay, that's a lousy summation of an SNL character made into a film, but if I told you about two blues singing brothers who were wanted by all of Chicago ... of two rock n' roll delinquents who had their own cable show ... or two party guys whose heads moved when they heard "What is Love ..." ... would you know what the hell the fess is about in every case? If you want to look up Stuart on YouTube, or DVD feel free. He was funny, at times. But for this movie, know that it is both funny and sad (in a dark humor way) as we see a child of alcoholics and food addicts overcome his past, this film is a pretty damn good one. Directed by Harold Ramis, it doesn't go for any real forced SNL-inspired laughs, even though there are a lot in there if you want to look. The laughs basically occur because they come from pain, comedy's actual twin. There is a both sad and happy ending (or is it happy and sad?) from this film, but its never forced because Ramis, Franken, Vincent D'Onofrio, Juila Sweeny, and Laura San Giacomo know how to play the tightrope between pain and humor. It's not perfect, but its easily one of the best SNL character movies ever made, and one of the best about family alcoholism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This in a sweet, under rated movie....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bill04250
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies inspired by SNL characters seem to have a consistently bad reputation. But that reputation is usually based on the fact that the films failed at the box office. The truth is, they are good solid comedies that were never meant to be blockbusters. 'Stuart Saves His Family' is just such a film. This film has a cast of excellent actors who portray tragedy and comedy with sublime skill. The script is heartfelt and funny. There is no mockery of recovery programs or the self-help movement. Instead, 'Stuart Saves His Family' evokes the all too real humor amid the tragedy that comes from being part of a dysfunctional family (and world). AL Franken's deadpan deliver of Stuart's ridiculous, but charming self is the the heart of the movie. But equally good are Piper Laurie, Vincent D'Onofrio, Lesley Boone & Harris Yulin. All four play characters who could easily descend into shrill, two-dimensional background support to the wacky lead character. Thankfully, the actors all bring out the human beings inside their characters. The message about finding your own definition of happiness and family is another of the movie's strong points. I also recommend "Superstar", another SNL character driven movie, starring Molly Shannon. She's an excellent actress with a wicked, silly streak.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alba500
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of best comedies of all times. The psychology of the main character is very incisive and realistic. However it is put in a grotesque context. Other characters are also very true to life or rather caricatures of certain types of people. The brother and the father of the main character seem to bring up the politically correct goofiness and dorkines of Al Franken. The Mother cuts also a very real and yet exaggerated person. The plot flows well and the whole dysfunctional family is funny and sad at the same time. The friends of Al Franken are also funny in their pseudo psychological babble and pretense. I find this film to be so good that I have bought the DVD.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not quite good enough or smart enough, but kind of likable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Stuart Saves His Family" came out before I had heard of Al Franken, so I took no notice. After I read Franken's book "Rush Limbaugh is a Big, Fat Idiot and Other Observations", I decided to check it out. It turns out that there's not really very much here. Franken plays Stuart Smalley, a character from "Saturday Night Live", and the movie portrays him having a crazy family. Why do movies and TV shows always seem to portray families as nearly mental? I actually giggled when he resorts to name-calling ("You are a big...!), but it seemed like the movie didn't have much of a point beyond that. Then again, few "SNL" skits make good movies. Of course, I might just be too tough on Al Franken; having read his political satires, I expect the highest quality from him. So I don't recommend it. I do think that Al Franken would make a really good senator (in case you haven't heard, he's running for senate in Minnesota), but for entertainment, he should stick to mocking the Bush administration and right-wing commentators.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not what I expected yet loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    skydvr38
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    surprisingly, what I thought would be a farce had some interesting depth. What's starts off as lampooning 12 step programs becomes a touching and somewhat tragic ride through recovery. Laced with humor, this is a dry, yet poignant study in recovery from 'our family of origin'. I watched this with several friends and we were stunned at the ending, namely,Stauart did not save all his family because it was their choice not to be saved. As Stuart says, he needed to move on with his life.Its easier to wear slippers than to carpet the whole world. True enough,you cannot fix others, particularly those who do not want to be fixed. Some revel in their misery or are so addicted to it some real peace would be disturbing. D'on't expect a major laugh riot here in this movie, expect the subtleties of humanity and conditions to give you a smirk, a grin,an 'aha' here and there. The real humor comes in Stuarts' journey. I salute the filmmakers for adding some really 'teary' moments.Alcoholism isn't fun. Perhapsthose touched by this disease,particularly those children (grown or not) who still ache from the hurts. You'll cheer Stauart for his own personal choices, not because he couldn't get his father into rehab.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A kind of serious comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bloewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a fan of Al Frankin and had wanted to see this movie for quite a while. As it turns out, that was 12 years, but I finally saw Stuart Saves His Family on HBO. The short answer is that I liked it a lot, but not for the reasons that I was expecting to like it for. The movie was funny, but not really laugh out loud funny. The characters were too well developed for "laugh out loud". It would have felt mean to laugh at the alcoholic father who has no clue that he has a problem. The stoner brother who eventually figures out he's wasted his life. The enabler mother. The obese sister who deals with her stress by eating pound cake. I found myself rooting for these people, and not really wanting to laugh at them. There are certainly funny parts of the movie, and Al Frankin is a funny guy, but I think that the problem with Stuart Saves His Family is that it is too well done for an audience who want Wayne's World (One of my favorites, BTW) and instead got a serious movie about dysfunctional people with very real problems where you laugh with them and not at them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Save yourself from this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamimarie228
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stuart is a whiny spoiled man who looks in the mirror and talks to himself. It is seriously annoying and people do NOT like him because his cable access show gets canceled. You would that is the end of the movie but it goes on and on. Stuart is in every 12 step program that there is but still cannot deal with his fat mom or drunk dad. When you see this you will want to take a billion steps and runaway. The acting is terrible and throughout the whole movie I could not stand the guy with the sweater. That's okay because I could only watch about half of this movie before watching something else. This movie isn't good enough or smart enough. A better SNL movie is "Tommy Boy" so watch that instead and save yourself!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No belly laughs, but good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Derek237
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A not-so-well-remembered SNL movie based on a not-so-well-remembered SNL sketch. I watched it last night, and I don't think I've ever seen it before so it was kind of surprising at how unfunny it was. Not necessarily in a bad way, but it just felt more like an offbeat drama than a comedy. It dealt with real issues and didn't have pristine solutions and I've left it feeling contemplative and, to be honest, a little sad, which is sort of a compliment and sort of isn't. But the acting in the movie is great. I have this idea in my head of Al Franken as this gruff, intense comedic force but here he's so soft-spoken and calm so you gotta hand it to him, the guy is COMMITTED. Laura San Giacomo is also excellent and has a heartbreaking little speech. And Vincent D'Onofrio as the pothead slacker brother is good stuff. I don't know. Not sure how I altogether feel about it. I'd probably give it a 6/10, not great but by no means bad. I think it's on Netflix. Check it out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been more, but not bad!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    southwest3210-156-400970
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think that the problem with this movie is that it has difficulty handling it's tragicomic aspect. That is so hard to pull off. In my mind, the perfect example of a movie that DOES would be Steve Martin's "Roxanne". Most tragicomic movies either err on being too dramatic or too comic. This one just leaned too far in the dramatic department. While it did really flesh out the smalley characters, it did so at the expense of being funny. It needed a little more crazy/absurd moments to be a truly good comedy. I should mention that at essentially every "skit" character based movie from SNL has fallen flat, so there is not exactly much to match or beat here. Regardless of that low-bar, I truly think this could have been a riot if made differently. I had in mind something like "Stuart saves the world', like an Austin Powers flick(how ironic, BTW, that the most successful SNL alumni movies are NOT based on SNL characters, ala Bill Murray's Stripes, Groundhog Day, et al., or Chevy Chases Vacation flicks, The "Blues Brothers" being the one exception here)....Again, it would have been perfect if he saved the world through his insipid motivational drivel, seeing as how some of the actual gurus, especially the religious ones disguised as preachers, such as Joel Osteen, come close to at least "attempting" to do that right now. Actually, Joel Osteen is not at all dissimilar to Stuart Smiley. Scary but true. It could have been classic, but this little movie is still sweet, and far better then the manure 99% of the character skit SNL movies are. And now Franken has the last laugh, being one of only two US Senators that were former movie stars. Reagan will prob forever hold the record of being the only president of that ilk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alcoholism portrayed right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A better movie than expected, but what is with all the comments about it being a comedy. If it is, it must have been the first one where i didn't laugh once. Al Franken takes on a gutsy project but it is really not that interesting. It has some nice characters but it is a little too nice. Maybe it was watered down for a PG-13 rating to sell it to a teen audience. If it was, it shows a serious miscalculation of marketing strategy. There is virtually nothing here that appeal to that group. It did get the addiction part almost right, although the ending is a little too nice again. I wish they would have ended it on the intervention stuff and left the last scene out. Still, I am glad I saw it, because it was somewhat different and the main character wasn't as annoying as I thought. Just wish they had made it a little more raw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In its own way, the best SNL-character based film ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    somehope
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For those you who don't know that Al Franken became a political author/congressional candidate, he was a funny comedian who had entertained "Saturday Night Live" audiences since the 70's, and into the 1990's (off-and-on). His most famous character was a self-help, for lack of a better word, addict; i.e., his character was addicted to self-help groups, sponsors, 12 step meetings, etc., because he lacked or was coming to terms with his low self-confidence everyday and was trying to spreading self-esteem to others through a fictional cable access show on SNL called "Daily Affirmations with Stuart Smalley." He would say things like "Doggone it, people like me." Okay, that's a lousy summation of an SNL character made into a film, but if I told you about two blues singing brothers who were wanted by all of Chicago ... of two rock n' roll delinquents who had their own cable show ... or two party guys whose heads moved when they heard "What is Love ..." ... would you know what the hell the fess is about in every case? If you want to look up Stuart on YouTube, or DVD feel free. He was funny, at times. But for this movie, know that it is both funny and sad (in a dark humor way) as we see a child of alcoholics and food addicts overcome his past, this film is a pretty damn good one. Directed by Harold Ramis, it doesn't go for any real forced SNL-inspired laughs, even though there are a lot in there if you want to look. The laughs basically occur because they come from pain, comedy's actual twin. There is a both sad and happy ending (or is it happy and sad?) from this film, but its never forced because Ramis, Franken, Vincent D'Onofrio, Juila Sweeny, and Laura San Giacomo know how to play the tightrope between pain and humor. It's not perfect, but its easily one of the best SNL character movies ever made, and one of the best about family alcoholism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This in a sweet, under rated movie....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bill04250
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies inspired by SNL characters seem to have a consistently bad reputation. But that reputation is usually based on the fact that the films failed at the box office. The truth is, they are good solid comedies that were never meant to be blockbusters. 'Stuart Saves His Family' is just such a film. This film has a cast of excellent actors who portray tragedy and comedy with sublime skill. The script is heartfelt and funny. There is no mockery of recovery programs or the self-help movement. Instead, 'Stuart Saves His Family' evokes the all too real humor amid the tragedy that comes from being part of a dysfunctional family (and world). AL Franken's deadpan deliver of Stuart's ridiculous, but charming self is the the heart of the movie. But equally good are Piper Laurie, Vincent D'Onofrio, Lesley Boone & Harris Yulin. All four play characters who could easily descend into shrill, two-dimensional background support to the wacky lead character. Thankfully, the actors all bring out the human beings inside their characters. The message about finding your own definition of happiness and family is another of the movie's strong points. I also recommend "Superstar", another SNL character driven movie, starring Molly Shannon. She's an excellent actress with a wicked, silly streak.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alba500
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of best comedies of all times. The psychology of the main character is very incisive and realistic. However it is put in a grotesque context. Other characters are also very true to life or rather caricatures of certain types of people. The brother and the father of the main character seem to bring up the politically correct goofiness and dorkines of Al Franken. The Mother cuts also a very real and yet exaggerated person. The plot flows well and the whole dysfunctional family is funny and sad at the same time. The friends of Al Franken are also funny in their pseudo psychological babble and pretense. I find this film to be so good that I have bought the DVD.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not quite good enough or smart enough, but kind of likable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Stuart Saves His Family" came out before I had heard of Al Franken, so I took no notice. After I read Franken's book "Rush Limbaugh is a Big, Fat Idiot and Other Observations", I decided to check it out. It turns out that there's not really very much here. Franken plays Stuart Smalley, a character from "Saturday Night Live", and the movie portrays him having a crazy family. Why do movies and TV shows always seem to portray families as nearly mental? I actually giggled when he resorts to name-calling ("You are a big...!), but it seemed like the movie didn't have much of a point beyond that. Then again, few "SNL" skits make good movies. Of course, I might just be too tough on Al Franken; having read his political satires, I expect the highest quality from him. So I don't recommend it. I do think that Al Franken would make a really good senator (in case you haven't heard, he's running for senate in Minnesota), but for entertainment, he should stick to mocking the Bush administration and right-wing commentators.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not what I expected yet loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    skydvr38
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    surprisingly, what I thought would be a farce had some interesting depth. What's starts off as lampooning 12 step programs becomes a touching and somewhat tragic ride through recovery. Laced with humor, this is a dry, yet poignant study in recovery from 'our family of origin'. I watched this with several friends and we were stunned at the ending, namely,Stauart did not save all his family because it was their choice not to be saved. As Stuart says, he needed to move on with his life.Its easier to wear slippers than to carpet the whole world. True enough,you cannot fix others, particularly those who do not want to be fixed. Some revel in their misery or are so addicted to it some real peace would be disturbing. D'on't expect a major laugh riot here in this movie, expect the subtleties of humanity and conditions to give you a smirk, a grin,an 'aha' here and there. The real humor comes in Stuarts' journey. I salute the filmmakers for adding some really 'teary' moments.Alcoholism isn't fun. Perhapsthose touched by this disease,particularly those children (grown or not) who still ache from the hurts. You'll cheer Stauart for his own personal choices, not because he couldn't get his father into rehab.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A kind of serious comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bloewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a fan of Al Frankin and had wanted to see this movie for quite a while. As it turns out, that was 12 years, but I finally saw Stuart Saves His Family on HBO. The short answer is that I liked it a lot, but not for the reasons that I was expecting to like it for. The movie was funny, but not really laugh out loud funny. The characters were too well developed for "laugh out loud". It would have felt mean to laugh at the alcoholic father who has no clue that he has a problem. The stoner brother who eventually figures out he's wasted his life. The enabler mother. The obese sister who deals with her stress by eating pound cake. I found myself rooting for these people, and not really wanting to laugh at them. There are certainly funny parts of the movie, and Al Frankin is a funny guy, but I think that the problem with Stuart Saves His Family is that it is too well done for an audience who want Wayne's World (One of my favorites, BTW) and instead got a serious movie about dysfunctional people with very real problems where you laugh with them and not at them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Save yourself from this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamimarie228
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stuart is a whiny spoiled man who looks in the mirror and talks to himself. It is seriously annoying and people do NOT like him because his cable access show gets canceled. You would that is the end of the movie but it goes on and on. Stuart is in every 12 step program that there is but still cannot deal with his fat mom or drunk dad. When you see this you will want to take a billion steps and runaway. The acting is terrible and throughout the whole movie I could not stand the guy with the sweater. That's okay because I could only watch about half of this movie before watching something else. This movie isn't good enough or smart enough. A better SNL movie is "Tommy Boy" so watch that instead and save yourself!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No belly laughs, but good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Derek237
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A not-so-well-remembered SNL movie based on a not-so-well-remembered SNL sketch. I watched it last night, and I don't think I've ever seen it before so it was kind of surprising at how unfunny it was. Not necessarily in a bad way, but it just felt more like an offbeat drama than a comedy. It dealt with real issues and didn't have pristine solutions and I've left it feeling contemplative and, to be honest, a little sad, which is sort of a compliment and sort of isn't. But the acting in the movie is great. I have this idea in my head of Al Franken as this gruff, intense comedic force but here he's so soft-spoken and calm so you gotta hand it to him, the guy is COMMITTED. Laura San Giacomo is also excellent and has a heartbreaking little speech. And Vincent D'Onofrio as the pothead slacker brother is good stuff. I don't know. Not sure how I altogether feel about it. I'd probably give it a 6/10, not great but by no means bad. I think it's on Netflix. Check it out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been more, but not bad!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    southwest3210-156-400970
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think that the problem with this movie is that it has difficulty handling it's tragicomic aspect. That is so hard to pull off. In my mind, the perfect example of a movie that DOES would be Steve Martin's "Roxanne". Most tragicomic movies either err on being too dramatic or too comic. This one just leaned too far in the dramatic department. While it did really flesh out the smalley characters, it did so at the expense of being funny. It needed a little more crazy/absurd moments to be a truly good comedy. I should mention that at essentially every "skit" character based movie from SNL has fallen flat, so there is not exactly much to match or beat here. Regardless of that low-bar, I truly think this could have been a riot if made differently. I had in mind something like "Stuart saves the world', like an Austin Powers flick(how ironic, BTW, that the most successful SNL alumni movies are NOT based on SNL characters, ala Bill Murray's Stripes, Groundhog Day, et al., or Chevy Chases Vacation flicks, The "Blues Brothers" being the one exception here)....Again, it would have been perfect if he saved the world through his insipid motivational drivel, seeing as how some of the actual gurus, especially the religious ones disguised as preachers, such as Joel Osteen, come close to at least "attempting" to do that right now. Actually, Joel Osteen is not at all dissimilar to Stuart Smiley. Scary but true. It could have been classic, but this little movie is still sweet, and far better then the manure 99% of the character skit SNL movies are. And now Franken has the last laugh, being one of only two US Senators that were former movie stars. Reagan will prob forever hold the record of being the only president of that ilk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alcoholism portrayed right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A better movie than expected, but what is with all the comments about it being a comedy. If it is, it must have been the first one where i didn't laugh once. Al Franken takes on a gutsy project but it is really not that interesting. It has some nice characters but it is a little too nice. Maybe it was watered down for a PG-13 rating to sell it to a teen audience. If it was, it shows a serious miscalculation of marketing strategy. There is virtually nothing here that appeal to that group. It did get the addiction part almost right, although the ending is a little too nice again. I wish they would have ended it on the intervention stuff and left the last scene out. Still, I am glad I saw it, because it was somewhat different and the main character wasn't as annoying as I thought. Just wish they had made it a little more raw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In its own way, the best SNL-character based film ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    somehope
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For those you who don't know that Al Franken became a political author/congressional candidate, he was a funny comedian who had entertained "Saturday Night Live" audiences since the 70's, and into the 1990's (off-and-on). His most famous character was a self-help, for lack of a better word, addict; i.e., his character was addicted to self-help groups, sponsors, 12 step meetings, etc., because he lacked or was coming to terms with his low self-confidence everyday and was trying to spreading self-esteem to others through a fictional cable access show on SNL called "Daily Affirmations with Stuart Smalley." He would say things like "Doggone it, people like me." Okay, that's a lousy summation of an SNL character made into a film, but if I told you about two blues singing brothers who were wanted by all of Chicago ... of two rock n' roll delinquents who had their own cable show ... or two party guys whose heads moved when they heard "What is Love ..." ... would you know what the hell the fess is about in every case? If you want to look up Stuart on YouTube, or DVD feel free. He was funny, at times. But for this movie, know that it is both funny and sad (in a dark humor way) as we see a child of alcoholics and food addicts overcome his past, this film is a pretty damn good one. Directed by Harold Ramis, it doesn't go for any real forced SNL-inspired laughs, even though there are a lot in there if you want to look. The laughs basically occur because they come from pain, comedy's actual twin. There is a both sad and happy ending (or is it happy and sad?) from this film, but its never forced because Ramis, Franken, Vincent D'Onofrio, Juila Sweeny, and Laura San Giacomo know how to play the tightrope between pain and humor. It's not perfect, but its easily one of the best SNL character movies ever made, and one of the best about family alcoholism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This in a sweet, under rated movie....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bill04250
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies inspired by SNL characters seem to have a consistently bad reputation. But that reputation is usually based on the fact that the films failed at the box office. The truth is, they are good solid comedies that were never meant to be blockbusters. 'Stuart Saves His Family' is just such a film. This film has a cast of excellent actors who portray tragedy and comedy with sublime skill. The script is heartfelt and funny. There is no mockery of recovery programs or the self-help movement. Instead, 'Stuart Saves His Family' evokes the all too real humor amid the tragedy that comes from being part of a dysfunctional family (and world). AL Franken's deadpan deliver of Stuart's ridiculous, but charming self is the the heart of the movie. But equally good are Piper Laurie, Vincent D'Onofrio, Lesley Boone & Harris Yulin. All four play characters who could easily descend into shrill, two-dimensional background support to the wacky lead character. Thankfully, the actors all bring out the human beings inside their characters. The message about finding your own definition of happiness and family is another of the movie's strong points. I also recommend "Superstar", another SNL character driven movie, starring Molly Shannon. She's an excellent actress with a wicked, silly streak.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alba500
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of best comedies of all times. The psychology of the main character is very incisive and realistic. However it is put in a grotesque context. Other characters are also very true to life or rather caricatures of certain types of people. The brother and the father of the main character seem to bring up the politically correct goofiness and dorkines of Al Franken. The Mother cuts also a very real and yet exaggerated person. The plot flows well and the whole dysfunctional family is funny and sad at the same time. The friends of Al Franken are also funny in their pseudo psychological babble and pretense. I find this film to be so good that I have bought the DVD.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not quite good enough or smart enough, but kind of likable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Stuart Saves His Family" came out before I had heard of Al Franken, so I took no notice. After I read Franken's book "Rush Limbaugh is a Big, Fat Idiot and Other Observations", I decided to check it out. It turns out that there's not really very much here. Franken plays Stuart Smalley, a character from "Saturday Night Live", and the movie portrays him having a crazy family. Why do movies and TV shows always seem to portray families as nearly mental? I actually giggled when he resorts to name-calling ("You are a big...!), but it seemed like the movie didn't have much of a point beyond that. Then again, few "SNL" skits make good movies. Of course, I might just be too tough on Al Franken; having read his political satires, I expect the highest quality from him. So I don't recommend it. I do think that Al Franken would make a really good senator (in case you haven't heard, he's running for senate in Minnesota), but for entertainment, he should stick to mocking the Bush administration and right-wing commentators.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not what I expected yet loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    skydvr38
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    surprisingly, what I thought would be a farce had some interesting depth. What's starts off as lampooning 12 step programs becomes a touching and somewhat tragic ride through recovery. Laced with humor, this is a dry, yet poignant study in recovery from 'our family of origin'. I watched this with several friends and we were stunned at the ending, namely,Stauart did not save all his family because it was their choice not to be saved. As Stuart says, he needed to move on with his life.Its easier to wear slippers than to carpet the whole world. True enough,you cannot fix others, particularly those who do not want to be fixed. Some revel in their misery or are so addicted to it some real peace would be disturbing. D'on't expect a major laugh riot here in this movie, expect the subtleties of humanity and conditions to give you a smirk, a grin,an 'aha' here and there. The real humor comes in Stuarts' journey. I salute the filmmakers for adding some really 'teary' moments.Alcoholism isn't fun. Perhapsthose touched by this disease,particularly those children (grown or not) who still ache from the hurts. You'll cheer Stauart for his own personal choices, not because he couldn't get his father into rehab.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A kind of serious comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bloewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a fan of Al Frankin and had wanted to see this movie for quite a while. As it turns out, that was 12 years, but I finally saw Stuart Saves His Family on HBO. The short answer is that I liked it a lot, but not for the reasons that I was expecting to like it for. The movie was funny, but not really laugh out loud funny. The characters were too well developed for "laugh out loud". It would have felt mean to laugh at the alcoholic father who has no clue that he has a problem. The stoner brother who eventually figures out he's wasted his life. The enabler mother. The obese sister who deals with her stress by eating pound cake. I found myself rooting for these people, and not really wanting to laugh at them. There are certainly funny parts of the movie, and Al Frankin is a funny guy, but I think that the problem with Stuart Saves His Family is that it is too well done for an audience who want Wayne's World (One of my favorites, BTW) and instead got a serious movie about dysfunctional people with very real problems where you laugh with them and not at them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Save yourself from this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamimarie228
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stuart is a whiny spoiled man who looks in the mirror and talks to himself. It is seriously annoying and people do NOT like him because his cable access show gets canceled. You would that is the end of the movie but it goes on and on. Stuart is in every 12 step program that there is but still cannot deal with his fat mom or drunk dad. When you see this you will want to take a billion steps and runaway. The acting is terrible and throughout the whole movie I could not stand the guy with the sweater. That's okay because I could only watch about half of this movie before watching something else. This movie isn't good enough or smart enough. A better SNL movie is "Tommy Boy" so watch that instead and save yourself!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No belly laughs, but good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Derek237
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A not-so-well-remembered SNL movie based on a not-so-well-remembered SNL sketch. I watched it last night, and I don't think I've ever seen it before so it was kind of surprising at how unfunny it was. Not necessarily in a bad way, but it just felt more like an offbeat drama than a comedy. It dealt with real issues and didn't have pristine solutions and I've left it feeling contemplative and, to be honest, a little sad, which is sort of a compliment and sort of isn't. But the acting in the movie is great. I have this idea in my head of Al Franken as this gruff, intense comedic force but here he's so soft-spoken and calm so you gotta hand it to him, the guy is COMMITTED. Laura San Giacomo is also excellent and has a heartbreaking little speech. And Vincent D'Onofrio as the pothead slacker brother is good stuff. I don't know. Not sure how I altogether feel about it. I'd probably give it a 6/10, not great but by no means bad. I think it's on Netflix. Check it out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been more, but not bad!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    southwest3210-156-400970
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think that the problem with this movie is that it has difficulty handling it's tragicomic aspect. That is so hard to pull off. In my mind, the perfect example of a movie that DOES would be Steve Martin's "Roxanne". Most tragicomic movies either err on being too dramatic or too comic. This one just leaned too far in the dramatic department. While it did really flesh out the smalley characters, it did so at the expense of being funny. It needed a little more crazy/absurd moments to be a truly good comedy. I should mention that at essentially every "skit" character based movie from SNL has fallen flat, so there is not exactly much to match or beat here. Regardless of that low-bar, I truly think this could have been a riot if made differently. I had in mind something like "Stuart saves the world', like an Austin Powers flick(how ironic, BTW, that the most successful SNL alumni movies are NOT based on SNL characters, ala Bill Murray's Stripes, Groundhog Day, et al., or Chevy Chases Vacation flicks, The "Blues Brothers" being the one exception here)....Again, it would have been perfect if he saved the world through his insipid motivational drivel, seeing as how some of the actual gurus, especially the religious ones disguised as preachers, such as Joel Osteen, come close to at least "attempting" to do that right now. Actually, Joel Osteen is not at all dissimilar to Stuart Smiley. Scary but true. It could have been classic, but this little movie is still sweet, and far better then the manure 99% of the character skit SNL movies are. And now Franken has the last laugh, being one of only two US Senators that were former movie stars. Reagan will prob forever hold the record of being the only president of that ilk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alcoholism portrayed right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A better movie than expected, but what is with all the comments about it being a comedy. If it is, it must have been the first one where i didn't laugh once. Al Franken takes on a gutsy project but it is really not that interesting. It has some nice characters but it is a little too nice. Maybe it was watered down for a PG-13 rating to sell it to a teen audience. If it was, it shows a serious miscalculation of marketing strategy. There is virtually nothing here that appeal to that group. It did get the addiction part almost right, although the ending is a little too nice again. I wish they would have ended it on the intervention stuff and left the last scene out. Still, I am glad I saw it, because it was somewhat different and the main character wasn't as annoying as I thought. Just wish they had made it a little more raw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In its own way, the best SNL-character based film ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    somehope
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For those you who don't know that Al Franken became a political author/congressional candidate, he was a funny comedian who had entertained "Saturday Night Live" audiences since the 70's, and into the 1990's (off-and-on). His most famous character was a self-help, for lack of a better word, addict; i.e., his character was addicted to self-help groups, sponsors, 12 step meetings, etc., because he lacked or was coming to terms with his low self-confidence everyday and was trying to spreading self-esteem to others through a fictional cable access show on SNL called "Daily Affirmations with Stuart Smalley." He would say things like "Doggone it, people like me." Okay, that's a lousy summation of an SNL character made into a film, but if I told you about two blues singing brothers who were wanted by all of Chicago ... of two rock n' roll delinquents who had their own cable show ... or two party guys whose heads moved when they heard "What is Love ..." ... would you know what the hell the fess is about in every case? If you want to look up Stuart on YouTube, or DVD feel free. He was funny, at times. But for this movie, know that it is both funny and sad (in a dark humor way) as we see a child of alcoholics and food addicts overcome his past, this film is a pretty damn good one. Directed by Harold Ramis, it doesn't go for any real forced SNL-inspired laughs, even though there are a lot in there if you want to look. The laughs basically occur because they come from pain, comedy's actual twin. There is a both sad and happy ending (or is it happy and sad?) from this film, but its never forced because Ramis, Franken, Vincent D'Onofrio, Juila Sweeny, and Laura San Giacomo know how to play the tightrope between pain and humor. It's not perfect, but its easily one of the best SNL character movies ever made, and one of the best about family alcoholism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This in a sweet, under rated movie....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bill04250
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies inspired by SNL characters seem to have a consistently bad reputation. But that reputation is usually based on the fact that the films failed at the box office. The truth is, they are good solid comedies that were never meant to be blockbusters. 'Stuart Saves His Family' is just such a film. This film has a cast of excellent actors who portray tragedy and comedy with sublime skill. The script is heartfelt and funny. There is no mockery of recovery programs or the self-help movement. Instead, 'Stuart Saves His Family' evokes the all too real humor amid the tragedy that comes from being part of a dysfunctional family (and world). AL Franken's deadpan deliver of Stuart's ridiculous, but charming self is the the heart of the movie. But equally good are Piper Laurie, Vincent D'Onofrio, Lesley Boone & Harris Yulin. All four play characters who could easily descend into shrill, two-dimensional background support to the wacky lead character. Thankfully, the actors all bring out the human beings inside their characters. The message about finding your own definition of happiness and family is another of the movie's strong points. I also recommend "Superstar", another SNL character driven movie, starring Molly Shannon. She's an excellent actress with a wicked, silly streak.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alba500
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of best comedies of all times. The psychology of the main character is very incisive and realistic. However it is put in a grotesque context. Other characters are also very true to life or rather caricatures of certain types of people. The brother and the father of the main character seem to bring up the politically correct goofiness and dorkines of Al Franken. The Mother cuts also a very real and yet exaggerated person. The plot flows well and the whole dysfunctional family is funny and sad at the same time. The friends of Al Franken are also funny in their pseudo psychological babble and pretense. I find this film to be so good that I have bought the DVD.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not quite good enough or smart enough, but kind of likable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Stuart Saves His Family" came out before I had heard of Al Franken, so I took no notice. After I read Franken's book "Rush Limbaugh is a Big, Fat Idiot and Other Observations", I decided to check it out. It turns out that there's not really very much here. Franken plays Stuart Smalley, a character from "Saturday Night Live", and the movie portrays him having a crazy family. Why do movies and TV shows always seem to portray families as nearly mental? I actually giggled when he resorts to name-calling ("You are a big...!), but it seemed like the movie didn't have much of a point beyond that. Then again, few "SNL" skits make good movies. Of course, I might just be too tough on Al Franken; having read his political satires, I expect the highest quality from him. So I don't recommend it. I do think that Al Franken would make a really good senator (in case you haven't heard, he's running for senate in Minnesota), but for entertainment, he should stick to mocking the Bush administration and right-wing commentators.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not what I expected yet loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    skydvr38
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    surprisingly, what I thought would be a farce had some interesting depth. What's starts off as lampooning 12 step programs becomes a touching and somewhat tragic ride through recovery. Laced with humor, this is a dry, yet poignant study in recovery from 'our family of origin'. I watched this with several friends and we were stunned at the ending, namely,Stauart did not save all his family because it was their choice not to be saved. As Stuart says, he needed to move on with his life.Its easier to wear slippers than to carpet the whole world. True enough,you cannot fix others, particularly those who do not want to be fixed. Some revel in their misery or are so addicted to it some real peace would be disturbing. D'on't expect a major laugh riot here in this movie, expect the subtleties of humanity and conditions to give you a smirk, a grin,an 'aha' here and there. The real humor comes in Stuarts' journey. I salute the filmmakers for adding some really 'teary' moments.Alcoholism isn't fun. Perhapsthose touched by this disease,particularly those children (grown or not) who still ache from the hurts. You'll cheer Stauart for his own personal choices, not because he couldn't get his father into rehab.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A kind of serious comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bloewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a fan of Al Frankin and had wanted to see this movie for quite a while. As it turns out, that was 12 years, but I finally saw Stuart Saves His Family on HBO. The short answer is that I liked it a lot, but not for the reasons that I was expecting to like it for. The movie was funny, but not really laugh out loud funny. The characters were too well developed for "laugh out loud". It would have felt mean to laugh at the alcoholic father who has no clue that he has a problem. The stoner brother who eventually figures out he's wasted his life. The enabler mother. The obese sister who deals with her stress by eating pound cake. I found myself rooting for these people, and not really wanting to laugh at them. There are certainly funny parts of the movie, and Al Frankin is a funny guy, but I think that the problem with Stuart Saves His Family is that it is too well done for an audience who want Wayne's World (One of my favorites, BTW) and instead got a serious movie about dysfunctional people with very real problems where you laugh with them and not at them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Save yourself from this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamimarie228
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stuart is a whiny spoiled man who looks in the mirror and talks to himself. It is seriously annoying and people do NOT like him because his cable access show gets canceled. You would that is the end of the movie but it goes on and on. Stuart is in every 12 step program that there is but still cannot deal with his fat mom or drunk dad. When you see this you will want to take a billion steps and runaway. The acting is terrible and throughout the whole movie I could not stand the guy with the sweater. That's okay because I could only watch about half of this movie before watching something else. This movie isn't good enough or smart enough. A better SNL movie is "Tommy Boy" so watch that instead and save yourself!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    No belly laughs, but good.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Derek237
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A not-so-well-remembered SNL movie based on a not-so-well-remembered SNL sketch. I watched it last night, and I don't think I've ever seen it before so it was kind of surprising at how unfunny it was. Not necessarily in a bad way, but it just felt more like an offbeat drama than a comedy. It dealt with real issues and didn't have pristine solutions and I've left it feeling contemplative and, to be honest, a little sad, which is sort of a compliment and sort of isn't. But the acting in the movie is great. I have this idea in my head of Al Franken as this gruff, intense comedic force but here he's so soft-spoken and calm so you gotta hand it to him, the guy is COMMITTED. Laura San Giacomo is also excellent and has a heartbreaking little speech. And Vincent D'Onofrio as the pothead slacker brother is good stuff. I don't know. Not sure how I altogether feel about it. I'd probably give it a 6/10, not great but by no means bad. I think it's on Netflix. Check it out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Could have been more, but not bad!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    southwest3210-156-400970
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think that the problem with this movie is that it has difficulty handling it's tragicomic aspect. That is so hard to pull off. In my mind, the perfect example of a movie that DOES would be Steve Martin's "Roxanne". Most tragicomic movies either err on being too dramatic or too comic. This one just leaned too far in the dramatic department. While it did really flesh out the smalley characters, it did so at the expense of being funny. It needed a little more crazy/absurd moments to be a truly good comedy. I should mention that at essentially every "skit" character based movie from SNL has fallen flat, so there is not exactly much to match or beat here. Regardless of that low-bar, I truly think this could have been a riot if made differently. I had in mind something like "Stuart saves the world', like an Austin Powers flick(how ironic, BTW, that the most successful SNL alumni movies are NOT based on SNL characters, ala Bill Murray's Stripes, Groundhog Day, et al., or Chevy Chases Vacation flicks, The "Blues Brothers" being the one exception here)....Again, it would have been perfect if he saved the world through his insipid motivational drivel, seeing as how some of the actual gurus, especially the religious ones disguised as preachers, such as Joel Osteen, come close to at least "attempting" to do that right now. Actually, Joel Osteen is not at all dissimilar to Stuart Smiley. Scary but true. It could have been classic, but this little movie is still sweet, and far better then the manure 99% of the character skit SNL movies are. And now Franken has the last laugh, being one of only two US Senators that were former movie stars. Reagan will prob forever hold the record of being the only president of that ilk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Alcoholism portrayed right
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    policy134
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A better movie than expected, but what is with all the comments about it being a comedy. If it is, it must have been the first one where i didn't laugh once. Al Franken takes on a gutsy project but it is really not that interesting. It has some nice characters but it is a little too nice. Maybe it was watered down for a PG-13 rating to sell it to a teen audience. If it was, it shows a serious miscalculation of marketing strategy. There is virtually nothing here that appeal to that group. It did get the addiction part almost right, although the ending is a little too nice again. I wish they would have ended it on the intervention stuff and left the last scene out. Still, I am glad I saw it, because it was somewhat different and the main character wasn't as annoying as I thought. Just wish they had made it a little more raw.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In its own way, the best SNL-character based film ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    somehope
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For those you who don't know that Al Franken became a political author/congressional candidate, he was a funny comedian who had entertained "Saturday Night Live" audiences since the 70's, and into the 1990's (off-and-on). His most famous character was a self-help, for lack of a better word, addict; i.e., his character was addicted to self-help groups, sponsors, 12 step meetings, etc., because he lacked or was coming to terms with his low self-confidence everyday and was trying to spreading self-esteem to others through a fictional cable access show on SNL called "Daily Affirmations with Stuart Smalley." He would say things like "Doggone it, people like me." Okay, that's a lousy summation of an SNL character made into a film, but if I told you about two blues singing brothers who were wanted by all of Chicago ... of two rock n' roll delinquents who had their own cable show ... or two party guys whose heads moved when they heard "What is Love ..." ... would you know what the hell the fess is about in every case? If you want to look up Stuart on YouTube, or DVD feel free. He was funny, at times. But for this movie, know that it is both funny and sad (in a dark humor way) as we see a child of alcoholics and food addicts overcome his past, this film is a pretty damn good one. Directed by Harold Ramis, it doesn't go for any real forced SNL-inspired laughs, even though there are a lot in there if you want to look. The laughs basically occur because they come from pain, comedy's actual twin. There is a both sad and happy ending (or is it happy and sad?) from this film, but its never forced because Ramis, Franken, Vincent D'Onofrio, Juila Sweeny, and Laura San Giacomo know how to play the tightrope between pain and humor. It's not perfect, but its easily one of the best SNL character movies ever made, and one of the best about family alcoholism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This in a sweet, under rated movie....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bill04250
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movies inspired by SNL characters seem to have a consistently bad reputation. But that reputation is usually based on the fact that the films failed at the box office. The truth is, they are good solid comedies that were never meant to be blockbusters. 'Stuart Saves His Family' is just such a film. This film has a cast of excellent actors who portray tragedy and comedy with sublime skill. The script is heartfelt and funny. There is no mockery of recovery programs or the self-help movement. Instead, 'Stuart Saves His Family' evokes the all too real humor amid the tragedy that comes from being part of a dysfunctional family (and world). AL Franken's deadpan deliver of Stuart's ridiculous, but charming self is the the heart of the movie. But equally good are Piper Laurie, Vincent D'Onofrio, Lesley Boone & Harris Yulin. All four play characters who could easily descend into shrill, two-dimensional background support to the wacky lead character. Thankfully, the actors all bring out the human beings inside their characters. The message about finding your own definition of happiness and family is another of the movie's strong points. I also recommend "Superstar", another SNL character driven movie, starring Molly Shannon. She's an excellent actress with a wicked, silly streak.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    alba500
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of best comedies of all times. The psychology of the main character is very incisive and realistic. However it is put in a grotesque context. Other characters are also very true to life or rather caricatures of certain types of people. The brother and the father of the main character seem to bring up the politically correct goofiness and dorkines of Al Franken. The Mother cuts also a very real and yet exaggerated person. The plot flows well and the whole dysfunctional family is funny and sad at the same time. The friends of Al Franken are also funny in their pseudo psychological babble and pretense. I find this film to be so good that I have bought the DVD.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not quite good enough or smart enough, but kind of likable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Stuart Saves His Family" came out before I had heard of Al Franken, so I took no notice. After I read Franken's book "Rush Limbaugh is a Big, Fat Idiot and Other Observations", I decided to check it out. It turns out that there's not really very much here. Franken plays Stuart Smalley, a character from "Saturday Night Live", and the movie portrays him having a crazy family. Why do movies and TV shows always seem to portray families as nearly mental? I actually giggled when he resorts to name-calling ("You are a big...!), but it seemed like the movie didn't have much of a point beyond that. Then again, few "SNL" skits make good movies. Of course, I might just be too tough on Al Franken; having read his political satires, I expect the highest quality from him. So I don't recommend it. I do think that Al Franken would make a really good senator (in case you haven't heard, he's running for senate in Minnesota), but for entertainment, he should stick to mocking the Bush administration and right-wing commentators.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    not what I expected yet loved it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    skydvr38
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    surprisingly, what I thought would be a farce had some interesting depth. What's starts off as lampooning 12 step programs becomes a touching and somewhat tragic ride through recovery. Laced with humor, this is a dry, yet poignant study in recovery from 'our family of origin'. I watched this with several friends and we were stunned at the ending, namely,Stauart did not save all his family because it was their choice not to be saved. As Stuart says, he needed to move on with his life.Its easier to wear slippers than to carpet the whole world. True enough,you cannot fix others, particularly those who do not want to be fixed. Some revel in their misery or are so addicted to it some real peace would be disturbing. D'on't expect a major laugh riot here in this movie, expect the subtleties of humanity and conditions to give you a smirk, a grin,an 'aha' here and there. The real humor comes in Stuarts' journey. I salute the filmmakers for adding some really 'teary' moments.Alcoholism isn't fun. Perhapsthose touched by this disease,particularly those children (grown or not) who still ache from the hurts. You'll cheer Stauart for his own personal choices, not because he couldn't get his father into rehab.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A kind of serious comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bloewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a fan of Al Frankin and had wanted to see this movie for quite a while. As it turns out, that was 12 years, but I finally saw Stuart Saves His Family on HBO. The short answer is that I liked it a lot, but not for the reasons that I was expecting to like it for. The movie was funny, but not really laugh out loud funny. The characters were too well developed for "laugh out loud". It would have felt mean to laugh at the alcoholic father who has no clue that he has a problem. The stoner brother who eventually figures out he's wasted his life. The enabler mother. The obese sister who deals with her stress by eating pound cake. I found myself rooting for these people, and not really wanting to laugh at them. There are certainly funny parts of the movie, and Al Frankin is a funny guy, but I think that the problem with Stuart Saves His Family is that it is too well done for an audience who want Wayne's World (One of my favorites, BTW) and instead got a serious movie about dysfunctional people with very real problems where you laugh with them and not at them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Save yourself from this movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tamimarie228
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stuart is a whiny spoiled man who looks in the mirror and talks to himself. It is seriously annoying and people do NOT like him because his cable access show gets canceled. You would that is the end of the movie but it goes on and on. Stuart is in every 12 step program that there is but still cannot deal with his fat mom or drunk dad. When you see this you will want to take a billion steps and runaway. The acting is terrible and throughout the whole movie I could not stand the guy with the sweater. That's okay because I could only watch about half of this movie before watching something else. This movie isn't good enough or smart enough. A better SNL movie is "Tommy Boy" so watch that instead and save yourself!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
