<filme>
 <id>
  998
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109361
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Um Gaiato no Navio
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A foul-mouthed finishing school graduate mistakenly winds up on an ill-fated fishing boat, and faces the wrath of a crew that considers him bad luck.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Snobby school boy goes left, and mistakes the "Filthy Whore" for his millionaire dad's yacht. He joins four filthy fishermen for hijinx on the high seas.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   sea
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   boat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   shark man
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   giant
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cupcake
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Adam Resnick
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Chris Elliott
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Adam Resnick
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Chris Elliott
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ritch Brinkley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   James Gammon
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanna buy a monkey?......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Elliott plays a spoilt little rich kid who after finishing Fancy Boy school, will go on to run his fathers business. After being thrown out by his Limo driver, Elliott takes a wrong turn and ends up on a boat with a bunch of sea dogs who cannot stand rich people. And things go pretty crazy, and almost too Tim Burton.... Its a random movie, full of plot holes, quite a bad script, a bad performance from Elliott, but never ever boring, Cabin Boy wreaked of Burton, and he may as well had directed it, because despite being involved in the production, the director doesn't seem to have an original idea in his head. The sets are fantastic, cheap looking, but so bonkers that they just seem to fit in, and the crew of the boat are great too. But that's where all the good stuff ends. Despite it being totally bonkers, its fairly predictable stuff, and you can see how its going to end from a mile off. But its never boring, and its worth watching the once, even to remind you of the disastrous year Letterman hosted the Oscars, and featuring his scene from this movie in it heavily...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siavash_khavarnejad
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am really shocked by this movie's super low rating of not even five out of ten, I figured it probably would be kind of low since it was not as good as Chris Elliott's TV show Get a Life and a lot of people didn't like his humour or this movie, but it was pretty good. It's obviously not for everyone with a really "out there" sense of humour but for what it was it was really funny, with a lot of laugh out loud gut busting moments. David Letterman's "wanna buy a monkey?" cameo is fantastic and Chris Elliott is great as the full of himself, super annoying rich kid turned cabin boy. I really recommend it if you like any of his other work or Get A Life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stink or Swim
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Proudly wearing his "Fancy Lad" description, over-cultured and prissy prep school graduate Chris Elliott (as Nathanial Mayweather) goes to board a ship bound for Hawaii. He expects to join his wealthy father, but mistakenly gets on "The Filthy Whore" and is unable to get the crew of four salty and soused fishermen to change direction. After becoming a replacement for dim-witted "Cabin Boy" Andy Richter (as Kenny), Mr. Elliott befriends shapely swimmer Melora Walters (as Trina) and shark-man Russ Tamblyn (as Chocki). David Letterman has an amusing cameo during the early running, before this comic ship sinks. Too bad for Mr. Elliott, who once had a good persona going with his "Get a Life" TV series. *** Cabin Boy (1/7/94) Adam Resnick ~ Chris Elliott, Melora Walters, Russ Tamblyn, Ritch Brinkley
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott's allegorical autobiography.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like his character Nathanial Mayweather, Chris Elliott was born to a very talented father (Bob Elliott) and into a lucrative family business (showbiz). Also like Nathanial, the elder's talent casts an especially harsh light on the younger's near complete lack thereof. Chris takes us as Nathanial on a metaphorical journey starting from privileged upbringing complete with shots at televisions shows, both his own and David Letterman's, based on the respect others have for his father. And like Nathanial eventually that life of ease ebbs away as Chris/Nathanial have to make it on their own talents either making a comedy or surviving on a ship called "The Filthy Whore." Neither fares well and Elliott deserves credit for taking an unflinching look at his situation and filming what he see even if only in metaphor. Like his career, little about the movie works. As a character, Nathanial grates and a lack of more attractive protagonists means little that happens provokes any empathy from the audience - The Filthy Whore could have pulled "A Perfect Storm" sinking about the 35 minute mark and no tears would have been shed. As a story, Nathanial's being thrown out of an anachronistically modern limousine only to mistake The Filthy Whore for his father's "Queen Anne" yacht works less well than your average "Two Close for Comfort" episode setup. As a comedy, even Letterman himself finds himself in a disjointed, seemingly improvised, unfunny exchange with his one-time television foil. In short, while a small, vociferous group of Elliott fans consider this a cult classic, it is only their hero-worship that makes it watchable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It might have been good as a 3 minute skit on Late Night with David Letterman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine one of those weird little skits you used to see on Late Night with either David Letterman or Conan O'Brian. You know, one of those where some surreal character comes out and does some silly stuff for a minute or so and then goes away. Now imagine one of those skits without a host there to play straight man, no studio audience to draw energy from and it goes on for almost an hour and a half. Congratulations! You've now seen Cabin Boy. Nathanial Mayweather (Chris Elliott) is a prissy, fussy, arrogant, dimwitted son of a rich man. After graduating from finishing school is all his bewigged glory, Nathanial gets misdirected and instead of winding up on a luxury cruiser taking him home to Hawaii, he winds up a cabin boy on a fishing boat named The Filthy Whore. After a whole bunch of lame inanity with 4 grubby and overacting fishermen, Nathanial falls in love at first sight with a girl swimming around the world and must prove his manhood to her by having sex with the slutty 2nd cousin of the Hindu goddess Shiva. And that's not as funny as it may sound. After teaming up with a shark man to battle a giant appliance salesman (that's a giant salesman who sells appliances, not a regular size salesman who sells giant appliances), Nathanial realizes he no longer wants a life of aimless wealth and rides his new girlfriend out to sea. Again, not as funny as it may sound. This film is like a primer on why Letterman has gotten his ass kicked in the ratings by Jay Leno for years, why Conan bombed at The Tonight Show and hasn't set the world on fire at TBS and why there are so many comics beloved of other comics who never manage to achieve much mainstream success. There's a certain breed of comedian who are mainly focused on entertaining themselves. They're usually very bright and clever, oftentimes dark or subversive or edgy, but their humor is disconnected from or perpendicular to what other people find funny. They just make themselves laugh and if it amuses anyone else, that's a bonus. Such inwardly directed, almost defiant comedy can be hilarious to the general public in small bursts. It's essentially impossible to sustain it for a long period of time, something Cabin Boy makes agonizingly clear. I suppose disaffected, supercilious hipsters might find some laughs in this movie, or at least convince themselves to laugh at what they think only they are "with it" enough to appreciate. Normal folk will only stare at the screen in slackjawed amazement at how pitiful it all is. There's no narrative standard by which anything in this motion picture works. The attempts at humor are so fractured and esoteric that even stoned slackers would be hard pressed to summon up a giggle in response. Let me give you an example. Even back in 1994, goofy looking Chris Elliott was too balding and too bearded to play a kid fresh out of finishing school. We first see Nathanial when he's singing in a choir with his schoolmates. Now, a traditional attempt at comedy would fill the choir with fresh-faced teens and leave Elliott sticking out like a sore thumb. Cabin Boy fills the choir with guys who, just like Elliott, are far too old and too hirsute to pass for a student body. You see, you're supposed to anticipate the joke that would normally be told and instead appreciate them doing the complete opposite. This isn't smart humor. It's humor that wants to be applauded for being smart, which isn't the same at all. I quite enjoyed seeing Chris Elliott show up on the old Letterman show, not that I'm dating myself or anything. I didn't laugh or smile even once at this film. That pretty much says it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice Jest !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about this movie is that it doesn't allege some things it doesn't have, or bigger than it already owns. I loved it, and it's crazy since I'm not a Chris Elliott's fan at all. It's solid simple fun. The naive atmosphere worked perfectly. The idiot gags looked smart. Sometimes it's the most cynical kids' fantasy. Sometimes it's a close spoof of (Jason and The Argonauts - 1963) ! and all the time it's some fine comics. Surprisingly (Melora Walters) looked super cute and for the first time sexy. The sailors' team delivered so right performance. Nothing was over the top, or goofy in a bad way. All the elements harmonized to make the jest good. It even managed to be a story about a boy turning into a man. This kind of comedies used to be twisted, disgusting, poor, or easy, whatever. But Cabin Boy isn't any of that. It's joyful, yet in loyally childish way; which could be the secret of it indeed. Unlike so many jests, this will live long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What is wrong with you people?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I fully maintain that this movie is the worst of all time...right up there with Battlefield: Earth and The Star Wars Holiday Special. There's virtually no plot, stupid songs, and humor that tries and nearly always misses. The sad part is that I watched it to the end, believing that Elliot and Co. would be able to redeem themselves, but it never happened. I mean, they melt the giant snowman with coffee?! You must have to be high to get it. But maybe that was the point all along...I seriously don't understand how anybody could give this movie beyond a D-, even less how so many of you on this board gave it ten stars!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott is just plain funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    caa821
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those who gained their initial fame on television -- even at the highest level and with top popularity -- have often found their feature films finishing at the other end of the scale. Bill Cosby and Ray Romano are two examples of this -- Bill Murray one of the few exceptions. Chevy Chase has had some sporadic success, and even Martin Short -- one of the comedic geniuses of all-time -- has found his big-screen offerings sporadic. I think one of the reasons is that we are just too used to seeing them on the small screen, and/or in the characters/personas with which we have become accustomed. It also seems that their films often seem to be stories which would lend them to 10- or 12-minute skits, or the 22 minutes or so contained within a half hour program. Chris Elliott avoids this completely in this funny presentation. He succeeds in taking this character over-the-top, with the same quirky skill we've seen him employ on television so often. At 80 minutes, he also avoids making it overlong, and the supporting cast and Letterman's cameo are all well-presented, too. It's "quirkiness" is likely the reason this film didn't receive a higher overall rating in this site, and among professional reviewers. However, for me it's a thoroughly entertaining and engaging movie, and best of all, funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    God, I love this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rich56
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No, not in the 'it's so bad it's good' way. I truly think it's one of the funnier comedies of the last 20 years or so. Perhaps a lot of it depends on how you feel about Chris Elliot to begin with. I think he's priceless. Used to love his old show Get A Life and have followed him ever since. The plot of this, kind of a twisted version of Captains Courageous, really doesn't matter. What's fun are the numerous sight gags, Elliot's constant barrage of sarcastic one-liners and the generally anything goes attitude of the whole enterprise. The ship's crew, filled with a number of character actors we're not used to seeing in this kind of thing, are a wonderfully sleazy bunch. David Letterman's hysterically amateurish cameo at the beginning is the stuff of legend. "Wanna buy a bunny?" Ha! OK Citizen Kane it ain't. I own that on DVD btw. Right next to it is Cabin Boy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Comedic Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers ahead. Rarely is a comedy such a masterpiece! Cabin Boy succeeds because it is gonzo and really, really funny. It is a dead-on parody of the Rudyard Kipling morality play "Captains Courageous," as well as a fitting homage to the cheesy stop-motion special effects from master Ray Harryhausen. Chris Elliot, a master of the bizarre, is excellent as the spoiled brat Nathaniel Mayweather, who undergoes a profound transformation into the child-like cabin boy of the "Filthy Whore." The whole cast are devoted to their roles as grungy, cruel fishermen. this is a wonderful dark comedy with no pleasant moralizing, where the fishermen are Kipling's noble souls. This morally ambiguous film turns "Courageous's" pat duality of morals and noble fishermen on its it as a savage parody. The cast, crew, and directors knew this had to be a weird film, and all put in exemplary efforts to make this film as bizarre and as wonderful as possible. The cheesy special effects work perfectly. Elliot should have won an Oscar for his masterful performance. Fans of performance art will also relish the lovely Ann Magnuson's role as Kali, a parody of the monsters from Harryhausen's "Sinbad" movies. Lovers of comedy will adore this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanna buy a monkey?......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Elliott plays a spoilt little rich kid who after finishing Fancy Boy school, will go on to run his fathers business. After being thrown out by his Limo driver, Elliott takes a wrong turn and ends up on a boat with a bunch of sea dogs who cannot stand rich people. And things go pretty crazy, and almost too Tim Burton.... Its a random movie, full of plot holes, quite a bad script, a bad performance from Elliott, but never ever boring, Cabin Boy wreaked of Burton, and he may as well had directed it, because despite being involved in the production, the director doesn't seem to have an original idea in his head. The sets are fantastic, cheap looking, but so bonkers that they just seem to fit in, and the crew of the boat are great too. But that's where all the good stuff ends. Despite it being totally bonkers, its fairly predictable stuff, and you can see how its going to end from a mile off. But its never boring, and its worth watching the once, even to remind you of the disastrous year Letterman hosted the Oscars, and featuring his scene from this movie in it heavily...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siavash_khavarnejad
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am really shocked by this movie's super low rating of not even five out of ten, I figured it probably would be kind of low since it was not as good as Chris Elliott's TV show Get a Life and a lot of people didn't like his humour or this movie, but it was pretty good. It's obviously not for everyone with a really "out there" sense of humour but for what it was it was really funny, with a lot of laugh out loud gut busting moments. David Letterman's "wanna buy a monkey?" cameo is fantastic and Chris Elliott is great as the full of himself, super annoying rich kid turned cabin boy. I really recommend it if you like any of his other work or Get A Life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stink or Swim
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Proudly wearing his "Fancy Lad" description, over-cultured and prissy prep school graduate Chris Elliott (as Nathanial Mayweather) goes to board a ship bound for Hawaii. He expects to join his wealthy father, but mistakenly gets on "The Filthy Whore" and is unable to get the crew of four salty and soused fishermen to change direction. After becoming a replacement for dim-witted "Cabin Boy" Andy Richter (as Kenny), Mr. Elliott befriends shapely swimmer Melora Walters (as Trina) and shark-man Russ Tamblyn (as Chocki). David Letterman has an amusing cameo during the early running, before this comic ship sinks. Too bad for Mr. Elliott, who once had a good persona going with his "Get a Life" TV series. *** Cabin Boy (1/7/94) Adam Resnick ~ Chris Elliott, Melora Walters, Russ Tamblyn, Ritch Brinkley
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott's allegorical autobiography.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like his character Nathanial Mayweather, Chris Elliott was born to a very talented father (Bob Elliott) and into a lucrative family business (showbiz). Also like Nathanial, the elder's talent casts an especially harsh light on the younger's near complete lack thereof. Chris takes us as Nathanial on a metaphorical journey starting from privileged upbringing complete with shots at televisions shows, both his own and David Letterman's, based on the respect others have for his father. And like Nathanial eventually that life of ease ebbs away as Chris/Nathanial have to make it on their own talents either making a comedy or surviving on a ship called "The Filthy Whore." Neither fares well and Elliott deserves credit for taking an unflinching look at his situation and filming what he see even if only in metaphor. Like his career, little about the movie works. As a character, Nathanial grates and a lack of more attractive protagonists means little that happens provokes any empathy from the audience - The Filthy Whore could have pulled "A Perfect Storm" sinking about the 35 minute mark and no tears would have been shed. As a story, Nathanial's being thrown out of an anachronistically modern limousine only to mistake The Filthy Whore for his father's "Queen Anne" yacht works less well than your average "Two Close for Comfort" episode setup. As a comedy, even Letterman himself finds himself in a disjointed, seemingly improvised, unfunny exchange with his one-time television foil. In short, while a small, vociferous group of Elliott fans consider this a cult classic, it is only their hero-worship that makes it watchable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It might have been good as a 3 minute skit on Late Night with David Letterman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine one of those weird little skits you used to see on Late Night with either David Letterman or Conan O'Brian. You know, one of those where some surreal character comes out and does some silly stuff for a minute or so and then goes away. Now imagine one of those skits without a host there to play straight man, no studio audience to draw energy from and it goes on for almost an hour and a half. Congratulations! You've now seen Cabin Boy. Nathanial Mayweather (Chris Elliott) is a prissy, fussy, arrogant, dimwitted son of a rich man. After graduating from finishing school is all his bewigged glory, Nathanial gets misdirected and instead of winding up on a luxury cruiser taking him home to Hawaii, he winds up a cabin boy on a fishing boat named The Filthy Whore. After a whole bunch of lame inanity with 4 grubby and overacting fishermen, Nathanial falls in love at first sight with a girl swimming around the world and must prove his manhood to her by having sex with the slutty 2nd cousin of the Hindu goddess Shiva. And that's not as funny as it may sound. After teaming up with a shark man to battle a giant appliance salesman (that's a giant salesman who sells appliances, not a regular size salesman who sells giant appliances), Nathanial realizes he no longer wants a life of aimless wealth and rides his new girlfriend out to sea. Again, not as funny as it may sound. This film is like a primer on why Letterman has gotten his ass kicked in the ratings by Jay Leno for years, why Conan bombed at The Tonight Show and hasn't set the world on fire at TBS and why there are so many comics beloved of other comics who never manage to achieve much mainstream success. There's a certain breed of comedian who are mainly focused on entertaining themselves. They're usually very bright and clever, oftentimes dark or subversive or edgy, but their humor is disconnected from or perpendicular to what other people find funny. They just make themselves laugh and if it amuses anyone else, that's a bonus. Such inwardly directed, almost defiant comedy can be hilarious to the general public in small bursts. It's essentially impossible to sustain it for a long period of time, something Cabin Boy makes agonizingly clear. I suppose disaffected, supercilious hipsters might find some laughs in this movie, or at least convince themselves to laugh at what they think only they are "with it" enough to appreciate. Normal folk will only stare at the screen in slackjawed amazement at how pitiful it all is. There's no narrative standard by which anything in this motion picture works. The attempts at humor are so fractured and esoteric that even stoned slackers would be hard pressed to summon up a giggle in response. Let me give you an example. Even back in 1994, goofy looking Chris Elliott was too balding and too bearded to play a kid fresh out of finishing school. We first see Nathanial when he's singing in a choir with his schoolmates. Now, a traditional attempt at comedy would fill the choir with fresh-faced teens and leave Elliott sticking out like a sore thumb. Cabin Boy fills the choir with guys who, just like Elliott, are far too old and too hirsute to pass for a student body. You see, you're supposed to anticipate the joke that would normally be told and instead appreciate them doing the complete opposite. This isn't smart humor. It's humor that wants to be applauded for being smart, which isn't the same at all. I quite enjoyed seeing Chris Elliott show up on the old Letterman show, not that I'm dating myself or anything. I didn't laugh or smile even once at this film. That pretty much says it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice Jest !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about this movie is that it doesn't allege some things it doesn't have, or bigger than it already owns. I loved it, and it's crazy since I'm not a Chris Elliott's fan at all. It's solid simple fun. The naive atmosphere worked perfectly. The idiot gags looked smart. Sometimes it's the most cynical kids' fantasy. Sometimes it's a close spoof of (Jason and The Argonauts - 1963) ! and all the time it's some fine comics. Surprisingly (Melora Walters) looked super cute and for the first time sexy. The sailors' team delivered so right performance. Nothing was over the top, or goofy in a bad way. All the elements harmonized to make the jest good. It even managed to be a story about a boy turning into a man. This kind of comedies used to be twisted, disgusting, poor, or easy, whatever. But Cabin Boy isn't any of that. It's joyful, yet in loyally childish way; which could be the secret of it indeed. Unlike so many jests, this will live long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What is wrong with you people?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I fully maintain that this movie is the worst of all time...right up there with Battlefield: Earth and The Star Wars Holiday Special. There's virtually no plot, stupid songs, and humor that tries and nearly always misses. The sad part is that I watched it to the end, believing that Elliot and Co. would be able to redeem themselves, but it never happened. I mean, they melt the giant snowman with coffee?! You must have to be high to get it. But maybe that was the point all along...I seriously don't understand how anybody could give this movie beyond a D-, even less how so many of you on this board gave it ten stars!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott is just plain funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    caa821
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those who gained their initial fame on television -- even at the highest level and with top popularity -- have often found their feature films finishing at the other end of the scale. Bill Cosby and Ray Romano are two examples of this -- Bill Murray one of the few exceptions. Chevy Chase has had some sporadic success, and even Martin Short -- one of the comedic geniuses of all-time -- has found his big-screen offerings sporadic. I think one of the reasons is that we are just too used to seeing them on the small screen, and/or in the characters/personas with which we have become accustomed. It also seems that their films often seem to be stories which would lend them to 10- or 12-minute skits, or the 22 minutes or so contained within a half hour program. Chris Elliott avoids this completely in this funny presentation. He succeeds in taking this character over-the-top, with the same quirky skill we've seen him employ on television so often. At 80 minutes, he also avoids making it overlong, and the supporting cast and Letterman's cameo are all well-presented, too. It's "quirkiness" is likely the reason this film didn't receive a higher overall rating in this site, and among professional reviewers. However, for me it's a thoroughly entertaining and engaging movie, and best of all, funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    God, I love this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rich56
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No, not in the 'it's so bad it's good' way. I truly think it's one of the funnier comedies of the last 20 years or so. Perhaps a lot of it depends on how you feel about Chris Elliot to begin with. I think he's priceless. Used to love his old show Get A Life and have followed him ever since. The plot of this, kind of a twisted version of Captains Courageous, really doesn't matter. What's fun are the numerous sight gags, Elliot's constant barrage of sarcastic one-liners and the generally anything goes attitude of the whole enterprise. The ship's crew, filled with a number of character actors we're not used to seeing in this kind of thing, are a wonderfully sleazy bunch. David Letterman's hysterically amateurish cameo at the beginning is the stuff of legend. "Wanna buy a bunny?" Ha! OK Citizen Kane it ain't. I own that on DVD btw. Right next to it is Cabin Boy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Comedic Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers ahead. Rarely is a comedy such a masterpiece! Cabin Boy succeeds because it is gonzo and really, really funny. It is a dead-on parody of the Rudyard Kipling morality play "Captains Courageous," as well as a fitting homage to the cheesy stop-motion special effects from master Ray Harryhausen. Chris Elliot, a master of the bizarre, is excellent as the spoiled brat Nathaniel Mayweather, who undergoes a profound transformation into the child-like cabin boy of the "Filthy Whore." The whole cast are devoted to their roles as grungy, cruel fishermen. this is a wonderful dark comedy with no pleasant moralizing, where the fishermen are Kipling's noble souls. This morally ambiguous film turns "Courageous's" pat duality of morals and noble fishermen on its it as a savage parody. The cast, crew, and directors knew this had to be a weird film, and all put in exemplary efforts to make this film as bizarre and as wonderful as possible. The cheesy special effects work perfectly. Elliot should have won an Oscar for his masterful performance. Fans of performance art will also relish the lovely Ann Magnuson's role as Kali, a parody of the monsters from Harryhausen's "Sinbad" movies. Lovers of comedy will adore this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanna buy a monkey?......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Elliott plays a spoilt little rich kid who after finishing Fancy Boy school, will go on to run his fathers business. After being thrown out by his Limo driver, Elliott takes a wrong turn and ends up on a boat with a bunch of sea dogs who cannot stand rich people. And things go pretty crazy, and almost too Tim Burton.... Its a random movie, full of plot holes, quite a bad script, a bad performance from Elliott, but never ever boring, Cabin Boy wreaked of Burton, and he may as well had directed it, because despite being involved in the production, the director doesn't seem to have an original idea in his head. The sets are fantastic, cheap looking, but so bonkers that they just seem to fit in, and the crew of the boat are great too. But that's where all the good stuff ends. Despite it being totally bonkers, its fairly predictable stuff, and you can see how its going to end from a mile off. But its never boring, and its worth watching the once, even to remind you of the disastrous year Letterman hosted the Oscars, and featuring his scene from this movie in it heavily...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siavash_khavarnejad
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am really shocked by this movie's super low rating of not even five out of ten, I figured it probably would be kind of low since it was not as good as Chris Elliott's TV show Get a Life and a lot of people didn't like his humour or this movie, but it was pretty good. It's obviously not for everyone with a really "out there" sense of humour but for what it was it was really funny, with a lot of laugh out loud gut busting moments. David Letterman's "wanna buy a monkey?" cameo is fantastic and Chris Elliott is great as the full of himself, super annoying rich kid turned cabin boy. I really recommend it if you like any of his other work or Get A Life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stink or Swim
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Proudly wearing his "Fancy Lad" description, over-cultured and prissy prep school graduate Chris Elliott (as Nathanial Mayweather) goes to board a ship bound for Hawaii. He expects to join his wealthy father, but mistakenly gets on "The Filthy Whore" and is unable to get the crew of four salty and soused fishermen to change direction. After becoming a replacement for dim-witted "Cabin Boy" Andy Richter (as Kenny), Mr. Elliott befriends shapely swimmer Melora Walters (as Trina) and shark-man Russ Tamblyn (as Chocki). David Letterman has an amusing cameo during the early running, before this comic ship sinks. Too bad for Mr. Elliott, who once had a good persona going with his "Get a Life" TV series. *** Cabin Boy (1/7/94) Adam Resnick ~ Chris Elliott, Melora Walters, Russ Tamblyn, Ritch Brinkley
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott's allegorical autobiography.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like his character Nathanial Mayweather, Chris Elliott was born to a very talented father (Bob Elliott) and into a lucrative family business (showbiz). Also like Nathanial, the elder's talent casts an especially harsh light on the younger's near complete lack thereof. Chris takes us as Nathanial on a metaphorical journey starting from privileged upbringing complete with shots at televisions shows, both his own and David Letterman's, based on the respect others have for his father. And like Nathanial eventually that life of ease ebbs away as Chris/Nathanial have to make it on their own talents either making a comedy or surviving on a ship called "The Filthy Whore." Neither fares well and Elliott deserves credit for taking an unflinching look at his situation and filming what he see even if only in metaphor. Like his career, little about the movie works. As a character, Nathanial grates and a lack of more attractive protagonists means little that happens provokes any empathy from the audience - The Filthy Whore could have pulled "A Perfect Storm" sinking about the 35 minute mark and no tears would have been shed. As a story, Nathanial's being thrown out of an anachronistically modern limousine only to mistake The Filthy Whore for his father's "Queen Anne" yacht works less well than your average "Two Close for Comfort" episode setup. As a comedy, even Letterman himself finds himself in a disjointed, seemingly improvised, unfunny exchange with his one-time television foil. In short, while a small, vociferous group of Elliott fans consider this a cult classic, it is only their hero-worship that makes it watchable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It might have been good as a 3 minute skit on Late Night with David Letterman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine one of those weird little skits you used to see on Late Night with either David Letterman or Conan O'Brian. You know, one of those where some surreal character comes out and does some silly stuff for a minute or so and then goes away. Now imagine one of those skits without a host there to play straight man, no studio audience to draw energy from and it goes on for almost an hour and a half. Congratulations! You've now seen Cabin Boy. Nathanial Mayweather (Chris Elliott) is a prissy, fussy, arrogant, dimwitted son of a rich man. After graduating from finishing school is all his bewigged glory, Nathanial gets misdirected and instead of winding up on a luxury cruiser taking him home to Hawaii, he winds up a cabin boy on a fishing boat named The Filthy Whore. After a whole bunch of lame inanity with 4 grubby and overacting fishermen, Nathanial falls in love at first sight with a girl swimming around the world and must prove his manhood to her by having sex with the slutty 2nd cousin of the Hindu goddess Shiva. And that's not as funny as it may sound. After teaming up with a shark man to battle a giant appliance salesman (that's a giant salesman who sells appliances, not a regular size salesman who sells giant appliances), Nathanial realizes he no longer wants a life of aimless wealth and rides his new girlfriend out to sea. Again, not as funny as it may sound. This film is like a primer on why Letterman has gotten his ass kicked in the ratings by Jay Leno for years, why Conan bombed at The Tonight Show and hasn't set the world on fire at TBS and why there are so many comics beloved of other comics who never manage to achieve much mainstream success. There's a certain breed of comedian who are mainly focused on entertaining themselves. They're usually very bright and clever, oftentimes dark or subversive or edgy, but their humor is disconnected from or perpendicular to what other people find funny. They just make themselves laugh and if it amuses anyone else, that's a bonus. Such inwardly directed, almost defiant comedy can be hilarious to the general public in small bursts. It's essentially impossible to sustain it for a long period of time, something Cabin Boy makes agonizingly clear. I suppose disaffected, supercilious hipsters might find some laughs in this movie, or at least convince themselves to laugh at what they think only they are "with it" enough to appreciate. Normal folk will only stare at the screen in slackjawed amazement at how pitiful it all is. There's no narrative standard by which anything in this motion picture works. The attempts at humor are so fractured and esoteric that even stoned slackers would be hard pressed to summon up a giggle in response. Let me give you an example. Even back in 1994, goofy looking Chris Elliott was too balding and too bearded to play a kid fresh out of finishing school. We first see Nathanial when he's singing in a choir with his schoolmates. Now, a traditional attempt at comedy would fill the choir with fresh-faced teens and leave Elliott sticking out like a sore thumb. Cabin Boy fills the choir with guys who, just like Elliott, are far too old and too hirsute to pass for a student body. You see, you're supposed to anticipate the joke that would normally be told and instead appreciate them doing the complete opposite. This isn't smart humor. It's humor that wants to be applauded for being smart, which isn't the same at all. I quite enjoyed seeing Chris Elliott show up on the old Letterman show, not that I'm dating myself or anything. I didn't laugh or smile even once at this film. That pretty much says it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice Jest !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about this movie is that it doesn't allege some things it doesn't have, or bigger than it already owns. I loved it, and it's crazy since I'm not a Chris Elliott's fan at all. It's solid simple fun. The naive atmosphere worked perfectly. The idiot gags looked smart. Sometimes it's the most cynical kids' fantasy. Sometimes it's a close spoof of (Jason and The Argonauts - 1963) ! and all the time it's some fine comics. Surprisingly (Melora Walters) looked super cute and for the first time sexy. The sailors' team delivered so right performance. Nothing was over the top, or goofy in a bad way. All the elements harmonized to make the jest good. It even managed to be a story about a boy turning into a man. This kind of comedies used to be twisted, disgusting, poor, or easy, whatever. But Cabin Boy isn't any of that. It's joyful, yet in loyally childish way; which could be the secret of it indeed. Unlike so many jests, this will live long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What is wrong with you people?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I fully maintain that this movie is the worst of all time...right up there with Battlefield: Earth and The Star Wars Holiday Special. There's virtually no plot, stupid songs, and humor that tries and nearly always misses. The sad part is that I watched it to the end, believing that Elliot and Co. would be able to redeem themselves, but it never happened. I mean, they melt the giant snowman with coffee?! You must have to be high to get it. But maybe that was the point all along...I seriously don't understand how anybody could give this movie beyond a D-, even less how so many of you on this board gave it ten stars!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott is just plain funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    caa821
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those who gained their initial fame on television -- even at the highest level and with top popularity -- have often found their feature films finishing at the other end of the scale. Bill Cosby and Ray Romano are two examples of this -- Bill Murray one of the few exceptions. Chevy Chase has had some sporadic success, and even Martin Short -- one of the comedic geniuses of all-time -- has found his big-screen offerings sporadic. I think one of the reasons is that we are just too used to seeing them on the small screen, and/or in the characters/personas with which we have become accustomed. It also seems that their films often seem to be stories which would lend them to 10- or 12-minute skits, or the 22 minutes or so contained within a half hour program. Chris Elliott avoids this completely in this funny presentation. He succeeds in taking this character over-the-top, with the same quirky skill we've seen him employ on television so often. At 80 minutes, he also avoids making it overlong, and the supporting cast and Letterman's cameo are all well-presented, too. It's "quirkiness" is likely the reason this film didn't receive a higher overall rating in this site, and among professional reviewers. However, for me it's a thoroughly entertaining and engaging movie, and best of all, funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    God, I love this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rich56
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No, not in the 'it's so bad it's good' way. I truly think it's one of the funnier comedies of the last 20 years or so. Perhaps a lot of it depends on how you feel about Chris Elliot to begin with. I think he's priceless. Used to love his old show Get A Life and have followed him ever since. The plot of this, kind of a twisted version of Captains Courageous, really doesn't matter. What's fun are the numerous sight gags, Elliot's constant barrage of sarcastic one-liners and the generally anything goes attitude of the whole enterprise. The ship's crew, filled with a number of character actors we're not used to seeing in this kind of thing, are a wonderfully sleazy bunch. David Letterman's hysterically amateurish cameo at the beginning is the stuff of legend. "Wanna buy a bunny?" Ha! OK Citizen Kane it ain't. I own that on DVD btw. Right next to it is Cabin Boy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Comedic Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers ahead. Rarely is a comedy such a masterpiece! Cabin Boy succeeds because it is gonzo and really, really funny. It is a dead-on parody of the Rudyard Kipling morality play "Captains Courageous," as well as a fitting homage to the cheesy stop-motion special effects from master Ray Harryhausen. Chris Elliot, a master of the bizarre, is excellent as the spoiled brat Nathaniel Mayweather, who undergoes a profound transformation into the child-like cabin boy of the "Filthy Whore." The whole cast are devoted to their roles as grungy, cruel fishermen. this is a wonderful dark comedy with no pleasant moralizing, where the fishermen are Kipling's noble souls. This morally ambiguous film turns "Courageous's" pat duality of morals and noble fishermen on its it as a savage parody. The cast, crew, and directors knew this had to be a weird film, and all put in exemplary efforts to make this film as bizarre and as wonderful as possible. The cheesy special effects work perfectly. Elliot should have won an Oscar for his masterful performance. Fans of performance art will also relish the lovely Ann Magnuson's role as Kali, a parody of the monsters from Harryhausen's "Sinbad" movies. Lovers of comedy will adore this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanna buy a monkey?......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Elliott plays a spoilt little rich kid who after finishing Fancy Boy school, will go on to run his fathers business. After being thrown out by his Limo driver, Elliott takes a wrong turn and ends up on a boat with a bunch of sea dogs who cannot stand rich people. And things go pretty crazy, and almost too Tim Burton.... Its a random movie, full of plot holes, quite a bad script, a bad performance from Elliott, but never ever boring, Cabin Boy wreaked of Burton, and he may as well had directed it, because despite being involved in the production, the director doesn't seem to have an original idea in his head. The sets are fantastic, cheap looking, but so bonkers that they just seem to fit in, and the crew of the boat are great too. But that's where all the good stuff ends. Despite it being totally bonkers, its fairly predictable stuff, and you can see how its going to end from a mile off. But its never boring, and its worth watching the once, even to remind you of the disastrous year Letterman hosted the Oscars, and featuring his scene from this movie in it heavily...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siavash_khavarnejad
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am really shocked by this movie's super low rating of not even five out of ten, I figured it probably would be kind of low since it was not as good as Chris Elliott's TV show Get a Life and a lot of people didn't like his humour or this movie, but it was pretty good. It's obviously not for everyone with a really "out there" sense of humour but for what it was it was really funny, with a lot of laugh out loud gut busting moments. David Letterman's "wanna buy a monkey?" cameo is fantastic and Chris Elliott is great as the full of himself, super annoying rich kid turned cabin boy. I really recommend it if you like any of his other work or Get A Life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stink or Swim
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Proudly wearing his "Fancy Lad" description, over-cultured and prissy prep school graduate Chris Elliott (as Nathanial Mayweather) goes to board a ship bound for Hawaii. He expects to join his wealthy father, but mistakenly gets on "The Filthy Whore" and is unable to get the crew of four salty and soused fishermen to change direction. After becoming a replacement for dim-witted "Cabin Boy" Andy Richter (as Kenny), Mr. Elliott befriends shapely swimmer Melora Walters (as Trina) and shark-man Russ Tamblyn (as Chocki). David Letterman has an amusing cameo during the early running, before this comic ship sinks. Too bad for Mr. Elliott, who once had a good persona going with his "Get a Life" TV series. *** Cabin Boy (1/7/94) Adam Resnick ~ Chris Elliott, Melora Walters, Russ Tamblyn, Ritch Brinkley
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott's allegorical autobiography.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like his character Nathanial Mayweather, Chris Elliott was born to a very talented father (Bob Elliott) and into a lucrative family business (showbiz). Also like Nathanial, the elder's talent casts an especially harsh light on the younger's near complete lack thereof. Chris takes us as Nathanial on a metaphorical journey starting from privileged upbringing complete with shots at televisions shows, both his own and David Letterman's, based on the respect others have for his father. And like Nathanial eventually that life of ease ebbs away as Chris/Nathanial have to make it on their own talents either making a comedy or surviving on a ship called "The Filthy Whore." Neither fares well and Elliott deserves credit for taking an unflinching look at his situation and filming what he see even if only in metaphor. Like his career, little about the movie works. As a character, Nathanial grates and a lack of more attractive protagonists means little that happens provokes any empathy from the audience - The Filthy Whore could have pulled "A Perfect Storm" sinking about the 35 minute mark and no tears would have been shed. As a story, Nathanial's being thrown out of an anachronistically modern limousine only to mistake The Filthy Whore for his father's "Queen Anne" yacht works less well than your average "Two Close for Comfort" episode setup. As a comedy, even Letterman himself finds himself in a disjointed, seemingly improvised, unfunny exchange with his one-time television foil. In short, while a small, vociferous group of Elliott fans consider this a cult classic, it is only their hero-worship that makes it watchable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It might have been good as a 3 minute skit on Late Night with David Letterman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine one of those weird little skits you used to see on Late Night with either David Letterman or Conan O'Brian. You know, one of those where some surreal character comes out and does some silly stuff for a minute or so and then goes away. Now imagine one of those skits without a host there to play straight man, no studio audience to draw energy from and it goes on for almost an hour and a half. Congratulations! You've now seen Cabin Boy. Nathanial Mayweather (Chris Elliott) is a prissy, fussy, arrogant, dimwitted son of a rich man. After graduating from finishing school is all his bewigged glory, Nathanial gets misdirected and instead of winding up on a luxury cruiser taking him home to Hawaii, he winds up a cabin boy on a fishing boat named The Filthy Whore. After a whole bunch of lame inanity with 4 grubby and overacting fishermen, Nathanial falls in love at first sight with a girl swimming around the world and must prove his manhood to her by having sex with the slutty 2nd cousin of the Hindu goddess Shiva. And that's not as funny as it may sound. After teaming up with a shark man to battle a giant appliance salesman (that's a giant salesman who sells appliances, not a regular size salesman who sells giant appliances), Nathanial realizes he no longer wants a life of aimless wealth and rides his new girlfriend out to sea. Again, not as funny as it may sound. This film is like a primer on why Letterman has gotten his ass kicked in the ratings by Jay Leno for years, why Conan bombed at The Tonight Show and hasn't set the world on fire at TBS and why there are so many comics beloved of other comics who never manage to achieve much mainstream success. There's a certain breed of comedian who are mainly focused on entertaining themselves. They're usually very bright and clever, oftentimes dark or subversive or edgy, but their humor is disconnected from or perpendicular to what other people find funny. They just make themselves laugh and if it amuses anyone else, that's a bonus. Such inwardly directed, almost defiant comedy can be hilarious to the general public in small bursts. It's essentially impossible to sustain it for a long period of time, something Cabin Boy makes agonizingly clear. I suppose disaffected, supercilious hipsters might find some laughs in this movie, or at least convince themselves to laugh at what they think only they are "with it" enough to appreciate. Normal folk will only stare at the screen in slackjawed amazement at how pitiful it all is. There's no narrative standard by which anything in this motion picture works. The attempts at humor are so fractured and esoteric that even stoned slackers would be hard pressed to summon up a giggle in response. Let me give you an example. Even back in 1994, goofy looking Chris Elliott was too balding and too bearded to play a kid fresh out of finishing school. We first see Nathanial when he's singing in a choir with his schoolmates. Now, a traditional attempt at comedy would fill the choir with fresh-faced teens and leave Elliott sticking out like a sore thumb. Cabin Boy fills the choir with guys who, just like Elliott, are far too old and too hirsute to pass for a student body. You see, you're supposed to anticipate the joke that would normally be told and instead appreciate them doing the complete opposite. This isn't smart humor. It's humor that wants to be applauded for being smart, which isn't the same at all. I quite enjoyed seeing Chris Elliott show up on the old Letterman show, not that I'm dating myself or anything. I didn't laugh or smile even once at this film. That pretty much says it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice Jest !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about this movie is that it doesn't allege some things it doesn't have, or bigger than it already owns. I loved it, and it's crazy since I'm not a Chris Elliott's fan at all. It's solid simple fun. The naive atmosphere worked perfectly. The idiot gags looked smart. Sometimes it's the most cynical kids' fantasy. Sometimes it's a close spoof of (Jason and The Argonauts - 1963) ! and all the time it's some fine comics. Surprisingly (Melora Walters) looked super cute and for the first time sexy. The sailors' team delivered so right performance. Nothing was over the top, or goofy in a bad way. All the elements harmonized to make the jest good. It even managed to be a story about a boy turning into a man. This kind of comedies used to be twisted, disgusting, poor, or easy, whatever. But Cabin Boy isn't any of that. It's joyful, yet in loyally childish way; which could be the secret of it indeed. Unlike so many jests, this will live long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What is wrong with you people?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I fully maintain that this movie is the worst of all time...right up there with Battlefield: Earth and The Star Wars Holiday Special. There's virtually no plot, stupid songs, and humor that tries and nearly always misses. The sad part is that I watched it to the end, believing that Elliot and Co. would be able to redeem themselves, but it never happened. I mean, they melt the giant snowman with coffee?! You must have to be high to get it. But maybe that was the point all along...I seriously don't understand how anybody could give this movie beyond a D-, even less how so many of you on this board gave it ten stars!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott is just plain funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    caa821
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those who gained their initial fame on television -- even at the highest level and with top popularity -- have often found their feature films finishing at the other end of the scale. Bill Cosby and Ray Romano are two examples of this -- Bill Murray one of the few exceptions. Chevy Chase has had some sporadic success, and even Martin Short -- one of the comedic geniuses of all-time -- has found his big-screen offerings sporadic. I think one of the reasons is that we are just too used to seeing them on the small screen, and/or in the characters/personas with which we have become accustomed. It also seems that their films often seem to be stories which would lend them to 10- or 12-minute skits, or the 22 minutes or so contained within a half hour program. Chris Elliott avoids this completely in this funny presentation. He succeeds in taking this character over-the-top, with the same quirky skill we've seen him employ on television so often. At 80 minutes, he also avoids making it overlong, and the supporting cast and Letterman's cameo are all well-presented, too. It's "quirkiness" is likely the reason this film didn't receive a higher overall rating in this site, and among professional reviewers. However, for me it's a thoroughly entertaining and engaging movie, and best of all, funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    God, I love this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rich56
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No, not in the 'it's so bad it's good' way. I truly think it's one of the funnier comedies of the last 20 years or so. Perhaps a lot of it depends on how you feel about Chris Elliot to begin with. I think he's priceless. Used to love his old show Get A Life and have followed him ever since. The plot of this, kind of a twisted version of Captains Courageous, really doesn't matter. What's fun are the numerous sight gags, Elliot's constant barrage of sarcastic one-liners and the generally anything goes attitude of the whole enterprise. The ship's crew, filled with a number of character actors we're not used to seeing in this kind of thing, are a wonderfully sleazy bunch. David Letterman's hysterically amateurish cameo at the beginning is the stuff of legend. "Wanna buy a bunny?" Ha! OK Citizen Kane it ain't. I own that on DVD btw. Right next to it is Cabin Boy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Comedic Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers ahead. Rarely is a comedy such a masterpiece! Cabin Boy succeeds because it is gonzo and really, really funny. It is a dead-on parody of the Rudyard Kipling morality play "Captains Courageous," as well as a fitting homage to the cheesy stop-motion special effects from master Ray Harryhausen. Chris Elliot, a master of the bizarre, is excellent as the spoiled brat Nathaniel Mayweather, who undergoes a profound transformation into the child-like cabin boy of the "Filthy Whore." The whole cast are devoted to their roles as grungy, cruel fishermen. this is a wonderful dark comedy with no pleasant moralizing, where the fishermen are Kipling's noble souls. This morally ambiguous film turns "Courageous's" pat duality of morals and noble fishermen on its it as a savage parody. The cast, crew, and directors knew this had to be a weird film, and all put in exemplary efforts to make this film as bizarre and as wonderful as possible. The cheesy special effects work perfectly. Elliot should have won an Oscar for his masterful performance. Fans of performance art will also relish the lovely Ann Magnuson's role as Kali, a parody of the monsters from Harryhausen's "Sinbad" movies. Lovers of comedy will adore this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanna buy a monkey?......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Elliott plays a spoilt little rich kid who after finishing Fancy Boy school, will go on to run his fathers business. After being thrown out by his Limo driver, Elliott takes a wrong turn and ends up on a boat with a bunch of sea dogs who cannot stand rich people. And things go pretty crazy, and almost too Tim Burton.... Its a random movie, full of plot holes, quite a bad script, a bad performance from Elliott, but never ever boring, Cabin Boy wreaked of Burton, and he may as well had directed it, because despite being involved in the production, the director doesn't seem to have an original idea in his head. The sets are fantastic, cheap looking, but so bonkers that they just seem to fit in, and the crew of the boat are great too. But that's where all the good stuff ends. Despite it being totally bonkers, its fairly predictable stuff, and you can see how its going to end from a mile off. But its never boring, and its worth watching the once, even to remind you of the disastrous year Letterman hosted the Oscars, and featuring his scene from this movie in it heavily...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siavash_khavarnejad
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am really shocked by this movie's super low rating of not even five out of ten, I figured it probably would be kind of low since it was not as good as Chris Elliott's TV show Get a Life and a lot of people didn't like his humour or this movie, but it was pretty good. It's obviously not for everyone with a really "out there" sense of humour but for what it was it was really funny, with a lot of laugh out loud gut busting moments. David Letterman's "wanna buy a monkey?" cameo is fantastic and Chris Elliott is great as the full of himself, super annoying rich kid turned cabin boy. I really recommend it if you like any of his other work or Get A Life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stink or Swim
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Proudly wearing his "Fancy Lad" description, over-cultured and prissy prep school graduate Chris Elliott (as Nathanial Mayweather) goes to board a ship bound for Hawaii. He expects to join his wealthy father, but mistakenly gets on "The Filthy Whore" and is unable to get the crew of four salty and soused fishermen to change direction. After becoming a replacement for dim-witted "Cabin Boy" Andy Richter (as Kenny), Mr. Elliott befriends shapely swimmer Melora Walters (as Trina) and shark-man Russ Tamblyn (as Chocki). David Letterman has an amusing cameo during the early running, before this comic ship sinks. Too bad for Mr. Elliott, who once had a good persona going with his "Get a Life" TV series. *** Cabin Boy (1/7/94) Adam Resnick ~ Chris Elliott, Melora Walters, Russ Tamblyn, Ritch Brinkley
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott's allegorical autobiography.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like his character Nathanial Mayweather, Chris Elliott was born to a very talented father (Bob Elliott) and into a lucrative family business (showbiz). Also like Nathanial, the elder's talent casts an especially harsh light on the younger's near complete lack thereof. Chris takes us as Nathanial on a metaphorical journey starting from privileged upbringing complete with shots at televisions shows, both his own and David Letterman's, based on the respect others have for his father. And like Nathanial eventually that life of ease ebbs away as Chris/Nathanial have to make it on their own talents either making a comedy or surviving on a ship called "The Filthy Whore." Neither fares well and Elliott deserves credit for taking an unflinching look at his situation and filming what he see even if only in metaphor. Like his career, little about the movie works. As a character, Nathanial grates and a lack of more attractive protagonists means little that happens provokes any empathy from the audience - The Filthy Whore could have pulled "A Perfect Storm" sinking about the 35 minute mark and no tears would have been shed. As a story, Nathanial's being thrown out of an anachronistically modern limousine only to mistake The Filthy Whore for his father's "Queen Anne" yacht works less well than your average "Two Close for Comfort" episode setup. As a comedy, even Letterman himself finds himself in a disjointed, seemingly improvised, unfunny exchange with his one-time television foil. In short, while a small, vociferous group of Elliott fans consider this a cult classic, it is only their hero-worship that makes it watchable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It might have been good as a 3 minute skit on Late Night with David Letterman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine one of those weird little skits you used to see on Late Night with either David Letterman or Conan O'Brian. You know, one of those where some surreal character comes out and does some silly stuff for a minute or so and then goes away. Now imagine one of those skits without a host there to play straight man, no studio audience to draw energy from and it goes on for almost an hour and a half. Congratulations! You've now seen Cabin Boy. Nathanial Mayweather (Chris Elliott) is a prissy, fussy, arrogant, dimwitted son of a rich man. After graduating from finishing school is all his bewigged glory, Nathanial gets misdirected and instead of winding up on a luxury cruiser taking him home to Hawaii, he winds up a cabin boy on a fishing boat named The Filthy Whore. After a whole bunch of lame inanity with 4 grubby and overacting fishermen, Nathanial falls in love at first sight with a girl swimming around the world and must prove his manhood to her by having sex with the slutty 2nd cousin of the Hindu goddess Shiva. And that's not as funny as it may sound. After teaming up with a shark man to battle a giant appliance salesman (that's a giant salesman who sells appliances, not a regular size salesman who sells giant appliances), Nathanial realizes he no longer wants a life of aimless wealth and rides his new girlfriend out to sea. Again, not as funny as it may sound. This film is like a primer on why Letterman has gotten his ass kicked in the ratings by Jay Leno for years, why Conan bombed at The Tonight Show and hasn't set the world on fire at TBS and why there are so many comics beloved of other comics who never manage to achieve much mainstream success. There's a certain breed of comedian who are mainly focused on entertaining themselves. They're usually very bright and clever, oftentimes dark or subversive or edgy, but their humor is disconnected from or perpendicular to what other people find funny. They just make themselves laugh and if it amuses anyone else, that's a bonus. Such inwardly directed, almost defiant comedy can be hilarious to the general public in small bursts. It's essentially impossible to sustain it for a long period of time, something Cabin Boy makes agonizingly clear. I suppose disaffected, supercilious hipsters might find some laughs in this movie, or at least convince themselves to laugh at what they think only they are "with it" enough to appreciate. Normal folk will only stare at the screen in slackjawed amazement at how pitiful it all is. There's no narrative standard by which anything in this motion picture works. The attempts at humor are so fractured and esoteric that even stoned slackers would be hard pressed to summon up a giggle in response. Let me give you an example. Even back in 1994, goofy looking Chris Elliott was too balding and too bearded to play a kid fresh out of finishing school. We first see Nathanial when he's singing in a choir with his schoolmates. Now, a traditional attempt at comedy would fill the choir with fresh-faced teens and leave Elliott sticking out like a sore thumb. Cabin Boy fills the choir with guys who, just like Elliott, are far too old and too hirsute to pass for a student body. You see, you're supposed to anticipate the joke that would normally be told and instead appreciate them doing the complete opposite. This isn't smart humor. It's humor that wants to be applauded for being smart, which isn't the same at all. I quite enjoyed seeing Chris Elliott show up on the old Letterman show, not that I'm dating myself or anything. I didn't laugh or smile even once at this film. That pretty much says it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice Jest !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about this movie is that it doesn't allege some things it doesn't have, or bigger than it already owns. I loved it, and it's crazy since I'm not a Chris Elliott's fan at all. It's solid simple fun. The naive atmosphere worked perfectly. The idiot gags looked smart. Sometimes it's the most cynical kids' fantasy. Sometimes it's a close spoof of (Jason and The Argonauts - 1963) ! and all the time it's some fine comics. Surprisingly (Melora Walters) looked super cute and for the first time sexy. The sailors' team delivered so right performance. Nothing was over the top, or goofy in a bad way. All the elements harmonized to make the jest good. It even managed to be a story about a boy turning into a man. This kind of comedies used to be twisted, disgusting, poor, or easy, whatever. But Cabin Boy isn't any of that. It's joyful, yet in loyally childish way; which could be the secret of it indeed. Unlike so many jests, this will live long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What is wrong with you people?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I fully maintain that this movie is the worst of all time...right up there with Battlefield: Earth and The Star Wars Holiday Special. There's virtually no plot, stupid songs, and humor that tries and nearly always misses. The sad part is that I watched it to the end, believing that Elliot and Co. would be able to redeem themselves, but it never happened. I mean, they melt the giant snowman with coffee?! You must have to be high to get it. But maybe that was the point all along...I seriously don't understand how anybody could give this movie beyond a D-, even less how so many of you on this board gave it ten stars!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott is just plain funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    caa821
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those who gained their initial fame on television -- even at the highest level and with top popularity -- have often found their feature films finishing at the other end of the scale. Bill Cosby and Ray Romano are two examples of this -- Bill Murray one of the few exceptions. Chevy Chase has had some sporadic success, and even Martin Short -- one of the comedic geniuses of all-time -- has found his big-screen offerings sporadic. I think one of the reasons is that we are just too used to seeing them on the small screen, and/or in the characters/personas with which we have become accustomed. It also seems that their films often seem to be stories which would lend them to 10- or 12-minute skits, or the 22 minutes or so contained within a half hour program. Chris Elliott avoids this completely in this funny presentation. He succeeds in taking this character over-the-top, with the same quirky skill we've seen him employ on television so often. At 80 minutes, he also avoids making it overlong, and the supporting cast and Letterman's cameo are all well-presented, too. It's "quirkiness" is likely the reason this film didn't receive a higher overall rating in this site, and among professional reviewers. However, for me it's a thoroughly entertaining and engaging movie, and best of all, funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    God, I love this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rich56
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No, not in the 'it's so bad it's good' way. I truly think it's one of the funnier comedies of the last 20 years or so. Perhaps a lot of it depends on how you feel about Chris Elliot to begin with. I think he's priceless. Used to love his old show Get A Life and have followed him ever since. The plot of this, kind of a twisted version of Captains Courageous, really doesn't matter. What's fun are the numerous sight gags, Elliot's constant barrage of sarcastic one-liners and the generally anything goes attitude of the whole enterprise. The ship's crew, filled with a number of character actors we're not used to seeing in this kind of thing, are a wonderfully sleazy bunch. David Letterman's hysterically amateurish cameo at the beginning is the stuff of legend. "Wanna buy a bunny?" Ha! OK Citizen Kane it ain't. I own that on DVD btw. Right next to it is Cabin Boy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Comedic Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers ahead. Rarely is a comedy such a masterpiece! Cabin Boy succeeds because it is gonzo and really, really funny. It is a dead-on parody of the Rudyard Kipling morality play "Captains Courageous," as well as a fitting homage to the cheesy stop-motion special effects from master Ray Harryhausen. Chris Elliot, a master of the bizarre, is excellent as the spoiled brat Nathaniel Mayweather, who undergoes a profound transformation into the child-like cabin boy of the "Filthy Whore." The whole cast are devoted to their roles as grungy, cruel fishermen. this is a wonderful dark comedy with no pleasant moralizing, where the fishermen are Kipling's noble souls. This morally ambiguous film turns "Courageous's" pat duality of morals and noble fishermen on its it as a savage parody. The cast, crew, and directors knew this had to be a weird film, and all put in exemplary efforts to make this film as bizarre and as wonderful as possible. The cheesy special effects work perfectly. Elliot should have won an Oscar for his masterful performance. Fans of performance art will also relish the lovely Ann Magnuson's role as Kali, a parody of the monsters from Harryhausen's "Sinbad" movies. Lovers of comedy will adore this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanna buy a monkey?......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Elliott plays a spoilt little rich kid who after finishing Fancy Boy school, will go on to run his fathers business. After being thrown out by his Limo driver, Elliott takes a wrong turn and ends up on a boat with a bunch of sea dogs who cannot stand rich people. And things go pretty crazy, and almost too Tim Burton.... Its a random movie, full of plot holes, quite a bad script, a bad performance from Elliott, but never ever boring, Cabin Boy wreaked of Burton, and he may as well had directed it, because despite being involved in the production, the director doesn't seem to have an original idea in his head. The sets are fantastic, cheap looking, but so bonkers that they just seem to fit in, and the crew of the boat are great too. But that's where all the good stuff ends. Despite it being totally bonkers, its fairly predictable stuff, and you can see how its going to end from a mile off. But its never boring, and its worth watching the once, even to remind you of the disastrous year Letterman hosted the Oscars, and featuring his scene from this movie in it heavily...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siavash_khavarnejad
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am really shocked by this movie's super low rating of not even five out of ten, I figured it probably would be kind of low since it was not as good as Chris Elliott's TV show Get a Life and a lot of people didn't like his humour or this movie, but it was pretty good. It's obviously not for everyone with a really "out there" sense of humour but for what it was it was really funny, with a lot of laugh out loud gut busting moments. David Letterman's "wanna buy a monkey?" cameo is fantastic and Chris Elliott is great as the full of himself, super annoying rich kid turned cabin boy. I really recommend it if you like any of his other work or Get A Life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stink or Swim
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Proudly wearing his "Fancy Lad" description, over-cultured and prissy prep school graduate Chris Elliott (as Nathanial Mayweather) goes to board a ship bound for Hawaii. He expects to join his wealthy father, but mistakenly gets on "The Filthy Whore" and is unable to get the crew of four salty and soused fishermen to change direction. After becoming a replacement for dim-witted "Cabin Boy" Andy Richter (as Kenny), Mr. Elliott befriends shapely swimmer Melora Walters (as Trina) and shark-man Russ Tamblyn (as Chocki). David Letterman has an amusing cameo during the early running, before this comic ship sinks. Too bad for Mr. Elliott, who once had a good persona going with his "Get a Life" TV series. *** Cabin Boy (1/7/94) Adam Resnick ~ Chris Elliott, Melora Walters, Russ Tamblyn, Ritch Brinkley
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott's allegorical autobiography.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like his character Nathanial Mayweather, Chris Elliott was born to a very talented father (Bob Elliott) and into a lucrative family business (showbiz). Also like Nathanial, the elder's talent casts an especially harsh light on the younger's near complete lack thereof. Chris takes us as Nathanial on a metaphorical journey starting from privileged upbringing complete with shots at televisions shows, both his own and David Letterman's, based on the respect others have for his father. And like Nathanial eventually that life of ease ebbs away as Chris/Nathanial have to make it on their own talents either making a comedy or surviving on a ship called "The Filthy Whore." Neither fares well and Elliott deserves credit for taking an unflinching look at his situation and filming what he see even if only in metaphor. Like his career, little about the movie works. As a character, Nathanial grates and a lack of more attractive protagonists means little that happens provokes any empathy from the audience - The Filthy Whore could have pulled "A Perfect Storm" sinking about the 35 minute mark and no tears would have been shed. As a story, Nathanial's being thrown out of an anachronistically modern limousine only to mistake The Filthy Whore for his father's "Queen Anne" yacht works less well than your average "Two Close for Comfort" episode setup. As a comedy, even Letterman himself finds himself in a disjointed, seemingly improvised, unfunny exchange with his one-time television foil. In short, while a small, vociferous group of Elliott fans consider this a cult classic, it is only their hero-worship that makes it watchable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It might have been good as a 3 minute skit on Late Night with David Letterman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine one of those weird little skits you used to see on Late Night with either David Letterman or Conan O'Brian. You know, one of those where some surreal character comes out and does some silly stuff for a minute or so and then goes away. Now imagine one of those skits without a host there to play straight man, no studio audience to draw energy from and it goes on for almost an hour and a half. Congratulations! You've now seen Cabin Boy. Nathanial Mayweather (Chris Elliott) is a prissy, fussy, arrogant, dimwitted son of a rich man. After graduating from finishing school is all his bewigged glory, Nathanial gets misdirected and instead of winding up on a luxury cruiser taking him home to Hawaii, he winds up a cabin boy on a fishing boat named The Filthy Whore. After a whole bunch of lame inanity with 4 grubby and overacting fishermen, Nathanial falls in love at first sight with a girl swimming around the world and must prove his manhood to her by having sex with the slutty 2nd cousin of the Hindu goddess Shiva. And that's not as funny as it may sound. After teaming up with a shark man to battle a giant appliance salesman (that's a giant salesman who sells appliances, not a regular size salesman who sells giant appliances), Nathanial realizes he no longer wants a life of aimless wealth and rides his new girlfriend out to sea. Again, not as funny as it may sound. This film is like a primer on why Letterman has gotten his ass kicked in the ratings by Jay Leno for years, why Conan bombed at The Tonight Show and hasn't set the world on fire at TBS and why there are so many comics beloved of other comics who never manage to achieve much mainstream success. There's a certain breed of comedian who are mainly focused on entertaining themselves. They're usually very bright and clever, oftentimes dark or subversive or edgy, but their humor is disconnected from or perpendicular to what other people find funny. They just make themselves laugh and if it amuses anyone else, that's a bonus. Such inwardly directed, almost defiant comedy can be hilarious to the general public in small bursts. It's essentially impossible to sustain it for a long period of time, something Cabin Boy makes agonizingly clear. I suppose disaffected, supercilious hipsters might find some laughs in this movie, or at least convince themselves to laugh at what they think only they are "with it" enough to appreciate. Normal folk will only stare at the screen in slackjawed amazement at how pitiful it all is. There's no narrative standard by which anything in this motion picture works. The attempts at humor are so fractured and esoteric that even stoned slackers would be hard pressed to summon up a giggle in response. Let me give you an example. Even back in 1994, goofy looking Chris Elliott was too balding and too bearded to play a kid fresh out of finishing school. We first see Nathanial when he's singing in a choir with his schoolmates. Now, a traditional attempt at comedy would fill the choir with fresh-faced teens and leave Elliott sticking out like a sore thumb. Cabin Boy fills the choir with guys who, just like Elliott, are far too old and too hirsute to pass for a student body. You see, you're supposed to anticipate the joke that would normally be told and instead appreciate them doing the complete opposite. This isn't smart humor. It's humor that wants to be applauded for being smart, which isn't the same at all. I quite enjoyed seeing Chris Elliott show up on the old Letterman show, not that I'm dating myself or anything. I didn't laugh or smile even once at this film. That pretty much says it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice Jest !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about this movie is that it doesn't allege some things it doesn't have, or bigger than it already owns. I loved it, and it's crazy since I'm not a Chris Elliott's fan at all. It's solid simple fun. The naive atmosphere worked perfectly. The idiot gags looked smart. Sometimes it's the most cynical kids' fantasy. Sometimes it's a close spoof of (Jason and The Argonauts - 1963) ! and all the time it's some fine comics. Surprisingly (Melora Walters) looked super cute and for the first time sexy. The sailors' team delivered so right performance. Nothing was over the top, or goofy in a bad way. All the elements harmonized to make the jest good. It even managed to be a story about a boy turning into a man. This kind of comedies used to be twisted, disgusting, poor, or easy, whatever. But Cabin Boy isn't any of that. It's joyful, yet in loyally childish way; which could be the secret of it indeed. Unlike so many jests, this will live long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What is wrong with you people?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I fully maintain that this movie is the worst of all time...right up there with Battlefield: Earth and The Star Wars Holiday Special. There's virtually no plot, stupid songs, and humor that tries and nearly always misses. The sad part is that I watched it to the end, believing that Elliot and Co. would be able to redeem themselves, but it never happened. I mean, they melt the giant snowman with coffee?! You must have to be high to get it. But maybe that was the point all along...I seriously don't understand how anybody could give this movie beyond a D-, even less how so many of you on this board gave it ten stars!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott is just plain funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    caa821
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those who gained their initial fame on television -- even at the highest level and with top popularity -- have often found their feature films finishing at the other end of the scale. Bill Cosby and Ray Romano are two examples of this -- Bill Murray one of the few exceptions. Chevy Chase has had some sporadic success, and even Martin Short -- one of the comedic geniuses of all-time -- has found his big-screen offerings sporadic. I think one of the reasons is that we are just too used to seeing them on the small screen, and/or in the characters/personas with which we have become accustomed. It also seems that their films often seem to be stories which would lend them to 10- or 12-minute skits, or the 22 minutes or so contained within a half hour program. Chris Elliott avoids this completely in this funny presentation. He succeeds in taking this character over-the-top, with the same quirky skill we've seen him employ on television so often. At 80 minutes, he also avoids making it overlong, and the supporting cast and Letterman's cameo are all well-presented, too. It's "quirkiness" is likely the reason this film didn't receive a higher overall rating in this site, and among professional reviewers. However, for me it's a thoroughly entertaining and engaging movie, and best of all, funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    God, I love this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rich56
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No, not in the 'it's so bad it's good' way. I truly think it's one of the funnier comedies of the last 20 years or so. Perhaps a lot of it depends on how you feel about Chris Elliot to begin with. I think he's priceless. Used to love his old show Get A Life and have followed him ever since. The plot of this, kind of a twisted version of Captains Courageous, really doesn't matter. What's fun are the numerous sight gags, Elliot's constant barrage of sarcastic one-liners and the generally anything goes attitude of the whole enterprise. The ship's crew, filled with a number of character actors we're not used to seeing in this kind of thing, are a wonderfully sleazy bunch. David Letterman's hysterically amateurish cameo at the beginning is the stuff of legend. "Wanna buy a bunny?" Ha! OK Citizen Kane it ain't. I own that on DVD btw. Right next to it is Cabin Boy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Comedic Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers ahead. Rarely is a comedy such a masterpiece! Cabin Boy succeeds because it is gonzo and really, really funny. It is a dead-on parody of the Rudyard Kipling morality play "Captains Courageous," as well as a fitting homage to the cheesy stop-motion special effects from master Ray Harryhausen. Chris Elliot, a master of the bizarre, is excellent as the spoiled brat Nathaniel Mayweather, who undergoes a profound transformation into the child-like cabin boy of the "Filthy Whore." The whole cast are devoted to their roles as grungy, cruel fishermen. this is a wonderful dark comedy with no pleasant moralizing, where the fishermen are Kipling's noble souls. This morally ambiguous film turns "Courageous's" pat duality of morals and noble fishermen on its it as a savage parody. The cast, crew, and directors knew this had to be a weird film, and all put in exemplary efforts to make this film as bizarre and as wonderful as possible. The cheesy special effects work perfectly. Elliot should have won an Oscar for his masterful performance. Fans of performance art will also relish the lovely Ann Magnuson's role as Kali, a parody of the monsters from Harryhausen's "Sinbad" movies. Lovers of comedy will adore this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanna buy a monkey?......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Elliott plays a spoilt little rich kid who after finishing Fancy Boy school, will go on to run his fathers business. After being thrown out by his Limo driver, Elliott takes a wrong turn and ends up on a boat with a bunch of sea dogs who cannot stand rich people. And things go pretty crazy, and almost too Tim Burton.... Its a random movie, full of plot holes, quite a bad script, a bad performance from Elliott, but never ever boring, Cabin Boy wreaked of Burton, and he may as well had directed it, because despite being involved in the production, the director doesn't seem to have an original idea in his head. The sets are fantastic, cheap looking, but so bonkers that they just seem to fit in, and the crew of the boat are great too. But that's where all the good stuff ends. Despite it being totally bonkers, its fairly predictable stuff, and you can see how its going to end from a mile off. But its never boring, and its worth watching the once, even to remind you of the disastrous year Letterman hosted the Oscars, and featuring his scene from this movie in it heavily...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siavash_khavarnejad
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am really shocked by this movie's super low rating of not even five out of ten, I figured it probably would be kind of low since it was not as good as Chris Elliott's TV show Get a Life and a lot of people didn't like his humour or this movie, but it was pretty good. It's obviously not for everyone with a really "out there" sense of humour but for what it was it was really funny, with a lot of laugh out loud gut busting moments. David Letterman's "wanna buy a monkey?" cameo is fantastic and Chris Elliott is great as the full of himself, super annoying rich kid turned cabin boy. I really recommend it if you like any of his other work or Get A Life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stink or Swim
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Proudly wearing his "Fancy Lad" description, over-cultured and prissy prep school graduate Chris Elliott (as Nathanial Mayweather) goes to board a ship bound for Hawaii. He expects to join his wealthy father, but mistakenly gets on "The Filthy Whore" and is unable to get the crew of four salty and soused fishermen to change direction. After becoming a replacement for dim-witted "Cabin Boy" Andy Richter (as Kenny), Mr. Elliott befriends shapely swimmer Melora Walters (as Trina) and shark-man Russ Tamblyn (as Chocki). David Letterman has an amusing cameo during the early running, before this comic ship sinks. Too bad for Mr. Elliott, who once had a good persona going with his "Get a Life" TV series. *** Cabin Boy (1/7/94) Adam Resnick ~ Chris Elliott, Melora Walters, Russ Tamblyn, Ritch Brinkley
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott's allegorical autobiography.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like his character Nathanial Mayweather, Chris Elliott was born to a very talented father (Bob Elliott) and into a lucrative family business (showbiz). Also like Nathanial, the elder's talent casts an especially harsh light on the younger's near complete lack thereof. Chris takes us as Nathanial on a metaphorical journey starting from privileged upbringing complete with shots at televisions shows, both his own and David Letterman's, based on the respect others have for his father. And like Nathanial eventually that life of ease ebbs away as Chris/Nathanial have to make it on their own talents either making a comedy or surviving on a ship called "The Filthy Whore." Neither fares well and Elliott deserves credit for taking an unflinching look at his situation and filming what he see even if only in metaphor. Like his career, little about the movie works. As a character, Nathanial grates and a lack of more attractive protagonists means little that happens provokes any empathy from the audience - The Filthy Whore could have pulled "A Perfect Storm" sinking about the 35 minute mark and no tears would have been shed. As a story, Nathanial's being thrown out of an anachronistically modern limousine only to mistake The Filthy Whore for his father's "Queen Anne" yacht works less well than your average "Two Close for Comfort" episode setup. As a comedy, even Letterman himself finds himself in a disjointed, seemingly improvised, unfunny exchange with his one-time television foil. In short, while a small, vociferous group of Elliott fans consider this a cult classic, it is only their hero-worship that makes it watchable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It might have been good as a 3 minute skit on Late Night with David Letterman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine one of those weird little skits you used to see on Late Night with either David Letterman or Conan O'Brian. You know, one of those where some surreal character comes out and does some silly stuff for a minute or so and then goes away. Now imagine one of those skits without a host there to play straight man, no studio audience to draw energy from and it goes on for almost an hour and a half. Congratulations! You've now seen Cabin Boy. Nathanial Mayweather (Chris Elliott) is a prissy, fussy, arrogant, dimwitted son of a rich man. After graduating from finishing school is all his bewigged glory, Nathanial gets misdirected and instead of winding up on a luxury cruiser taking him home to Hawaii, he winds up a cabin boy on a fishing boat named The Filthy Whore. After a whole bunch of lame inanity with 4 grubby and overacting fishermen, Nathanial falls in love at first sight with a girl swimming around the world and must prove his manhood to her by having sex with the slutty 2nd cousin of the Hindu goddess Shiva. And that's not as funny as it may sound. After teaming up with a shark man to battle a giant appliance salesman (that's a giant salesman who sells appliances, not a regular size salesman who sells giant appliances), Nathanial realizes he no longer wants a life of aimless wealth and rides his new girlfriend out to sea. Again, not as funny as it may sound. This film is like a primer on why Letterman has gotten his ass kicked in the ratings by Jay Leno for years, why Conan bombed at The Tonight Show and hasn't set the world on fire at TBS and why there are so many comics beloved of other comics who never manage to achieve much mainstream success. There's a certain breed of comedian who are mainly focused on entertaining themselves. They're usually very bright and clever, oftentimes dark or subversive or edgy, but their humor is disconnected from or perpendicular to what other people find funny. They just make themselves laugh and if it amuses anyone else, that's a bonus. Such inwardly directed, almost defiant comedy can be hilarious to the general public in small bursts. It's essentially impossible to sustain it for a long period of time, something Cabin Boy makes agonizingly clear. I suppose disaffected, supercilious hipsters might find some laughs in this movie, or at least convince themselves to laugh at what they think only they are "with it" enough to appreciate. Normal folk will only stare at the screen in slackjawed amazement at how pitiful it all is. There's no narrative standard by which anything in this motion picture works. The attempts at humor are so fractured and esoteric that even stoned slackers would be hard pressed to summon up a giggle in response. Let me give you an example. Even back in 1994, goofy looking Chris Elliott was too balding and too bearded to play a kid fresh out of finishing school. We first see Nathanial when he's singing in a choir with his schoolmates. Now, a traditional attempt at comedy would fill the choir with fresh-faced teens and leave Elliott sticking out like a sore thumb. Cabin Boy fills the choir with guys who, just like Elliott, are far too old and too hirsute to pass for a student body. You see, you're supposed to anticipate the joke that would normally be told and instead appreciate them doing the complete opposite. This isn't smart humor. It's humor that wants to be applauded for being smart, which isn't the same at all. I quite enjoyed seeing Chris Elliott show up on the old Letterman show, not that I'm dating myself or anything. I didn't laugh or smile even once at this film. That pretty much says it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice Jest !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about this movie is that it doesn't allege some things it doesn't have, or bigger than it already owns. I loved it, and it's crazy since I'm not a Chris Elliott's fan at all. It's solid simple fun. The naive atmosphere worked perfectly. The idiot gags looked smart. Sometimes it's the most cynical kids' fantasy. Sometimes it's a close spoof of (Jason and The Argonauts - 1963) ! and all the time it's some fine comics. Surprisingly (Melora Walters) looked super cute and for the first time sexy. The sailors' team delivered so right performance. Nothing was over the top, or goofy in a bad way. All the elements harmonized to make the jest good. It even managed to be a story about a boy turning into a man. This kind of comedies used to be twisted, disgusting, poor, or easy, whatever. But Cabin Boy isn't any of that. It's joyful, yet in loyally childish way; which could be the secret of it indeed. Unlike so many jests, this will live long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What is wrong with you people?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I fully maintain that this movie is the worst of all time...right up there with Battlefield: Earth and The Star Wars Holiday Special. There's virtually no plot, stupid songs, and humor that tries and nearly always misses. The sad part is that I watched it to the end, believing that Elliot and Co. would be able to redeem themselves, but it never happened. I mean, they melt the giant snowman with coffee?! You must have to be high to get it. But maybe that was the point all along...I seriously don't understand how anybody could give this movie beyond a D-, even less how so many of you on this board gave it ten stars!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott is just plain funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    caa821
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those who gained their initial fame on television -- even at the highest level and with top popularity -- have often found their feature films finishing at the other end of the scale. Bill Cosby and Ray Romano are two examples of this -- Bill Murray one of the few exceptions. Chevy Chase has had some sporadic success, and even Martin Short -- one of the comedic geniuses of all-time -- has found his big-screen offerings sporadic. I think one of the reasons is that we are just too used to seeing them on the small screen, and/or in the characters/personas with which we have become accustomed. It also seems that their films often seem to be stories which would lend them to 10- or 12-minute skits, or the 22 minutes or so contained within a half hour program. Chris Elliott avoids this completely in this funny presentation. He succeeds in taking this character over-the-top, with the same quirky skill we've seen him employ on television so often. At 80 minutes, he also avoids making it overlong, and the supporting cast and Letterman's cameo are all well-presented, too. It's "quirkiness" is likely the reason this film didn't receive a higher overall rating in this site, and among professional reviewers. However, for me it's a thoroughly entertaining and engaging movie, and best of all, funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    God, I love this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rich56
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No, not in the 'it's so bad it's good' way. I truly think it's one of the funnier comedies of the last 20 years or so. Perhaps a lot of it depends on how you feel about Chris Elliot to begin with. I think he's priceless. Used to love his old show Get A Life and have followed him ever since. The plot of this, kind of a twisted version of Captains Courageous, really doesn't matter. What's fun are the numerous sight gags, Elliot's constant barrage of sarcastic one-liners and the generally anything goes attitude of the whole enterprise. The ship's crew, filled with a number of character actors we're not used to seeing in this kind of thing, are a wonderfully sleazy bunch. David Letterman's hysterically amateurish cameo at the beginning is the stuff of legend. "Wanna buy a bunny?" Ha! OK Citizen Kane it ain't. I own that on DVD btw. Right next to it is Cabin Boy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Comedic Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers ahead. Rarely is a comedy such a masterpiece! Cabin Boy succeeds because it is gonzo and really, really funny. It is a dead-on parody of the Rudyard Kipling morality play "Captains Courageous," as well as a fitting homage to the cheesy stop-motion special effects from master Ray Harryhausen. Chris Elliot, a master of the bizarre, is excellent as the spoiled brat Nathaniel Mayweather, who undergoes a profound transformation into the child-like cabin boy of the "Filthy Whore." The whole cast are devoted to their roles as grungy, cruel fishermen. this is a wonderful dark comedy with no pleasant moralizing, where the fishermen are Kipling's noble souls. This morally ambiguous film turns "Courageous's" pat duality of morals and noble fishermen on its it as a savage parody. The cast, crew, and directors knew this had to be a weird film, and all put in exemplary efforts to make this film as bizarre and as wonderful as possible. The cheesy special effects work perfectly. Elliot should have won an Oscar for his masterful performance. Fans of performance art will also relish the lovely Ann Magnuson's role as Kali, a parody of the monsters from Harryhausen's "Sinbad" movies. Lovers of comedy will adore this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanna buy a monkey?......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Elliott plays a spoilt little rich kid who after finishing Fancy Boy school, will go on to run his fathers business. After being thrown out by his Limo driver, Elliott takes a wrong turn and ends up on a boat with a bunch of sea dogs who cannot stand rich people. And things go pretty crazy, and almost too Tim Burton.... Its a random movie, full of plot holes, quite a bad script, a bad performance from Elliott, but never ever boring, Cabin Boy wreaked of Burton, and he may as well had directed it, because despite being involved in the production, the director doesn't seem to have an original idea in his head. The sets are fantastic, cheap looking, but so bonkers that they just seem to fit in, and the crew of the boat are great too. But that's where all the good stuff ends. Despite it being totally bonkers, its fairly predictable stuff, and you can see how its going to end from a mile off. But its never boring, and its worth watching the once, even to remind you of the disastrous year Letterman hosted the Oscars, and featuring his scene from this movie in it heavily...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siavash_khavarnejad
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am really shocked by this movie's super low rating of not even five out of ten, I figured it probably would be kind of low since it was not as good as Chris Elliott's TV show Get a Life and a lot of people didn't like his humour or this movie, but it was pretty good. It's obviously not for everyone with a really "out there" sense of humour but for what it was it was really funny, with a lot of laugh out loud gut busting moments. David Letterman's "wanna buy a monkey?" cameo is fantastic and Chris Elliott is great as the full of himself, super annoying rich kid turned cabin boy. I really recommend it if you like any of his other work or Get A Life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stink or Swim
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Proudly wearing his "Fancy Lad" description, over-cultured and prissy prep school graduate Chris Elliott (as Nathanial Mayweather) goes to board a ship bound for Hawaii. He expects to join his wealthy father, but mistakenly gets on "The Filthy Whore" and is unable to get the crew of four salty and soused fishermen to change direction. After becoming a replacement for dim-witted "Cabin Boy" Andy Richter (as Kenny), Mr. Elliott befriends shapely swimmer Melora Walters (as Trina) and shark-man Russ Tamblyn (as Chocki). David Letterman has an amusing cameo during the early running, before this comic ship sinks. Too bad for Mr. Elliott, who once had a good persona going with his "Get a Life" TV series. *** Cabin Boy (1/7/94) Adam Resnick ~ Chris Elliott, Melora Walters, Russ Tamblyn, Ritch Brinkley
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott's allegorical autobiography.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like his character Nathanial Mayweather, Chris Elliott was born to a very talented father (Bob Elliott) and into a lucrative family business (showbiz). Also like Nathanial, the elder's talent casts an especially harsh light on the younger's near complete lack thereof. Chris takes us as Nathanial on a metaphorical journey starting from privileged upbringing complete with shots at televisions shows, both his own and David Letterman's, based on the respect others have for his father. And like Nathanial eventually that life of ease ebbs away as Chris/Nathanial have to make it on their own talents either making a comedy or surviving on a ship called "The Filthy Whore." Neither fares well and Elliott deserves credit for taking an unflinching look at his situation and filming what he see even if only in metaphor. Like his career, little about the movie works. As a character, Nathanial grates and a lack of more attractive protagonists means little that happens provokes any empathy from the audience - The Filthy Whore could have pulled "A Perfect Storm" sinking about the 35 minute mark and no tears would have been shed. As a story, Nathanial's being thrown out of an anachronistically modern limousine only to mistake The Filthy Whore for his father's "Queen Anne" yacht works less well than your average "Two Close for Comfort" episode setup. As a comedy, even Letterman himself finds himself in a disjointed, seemingly improvised, unfunny exchange with his one-time television foil. In short, while a small, vociferous group of Elliott fans consider this a cult classic, it is only their hero-worship that makes it watchable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It might have been good as a 3 minute skit on Late Night with David Letterman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine one of those weird little skits you used to see on Late Night with either David Letterman or Conan O'Brian. You know, one of those where some surreal character comes out and does some silly stuff for a minute or so and then goes away. Now imagine one of those skits without a host there to play straight man, no studio audience to draw energy from and it goes on for almost an hour and a half. Congratulations! You've now seen Cabin Boy. Nathanial Mayweather (Chris Elliott) is a prissy, fussy, arrogant, dimwitted son of a rich man. After graduating from finishing school is all his bewigged glory, Nathanial gets misdirected and instead of winding up on a luxury cruiser taking him home to Hawaii, he winds up a cabin boy on a fishing boat named The Filthy Whore. After a whole bunch of lame inanity with 4 grubby and overacting fishermen, Nathanial falls in love at first sight with a girl swimming around the world and must prove his manhood to her by having sex with the slutty 2nd cousin of the Hindu goddess Shiva. And that's not as funny as it may sound. After teaming up with a shark man to battle a giant appliance salesman (that's a giant salesman who sells appliances, not a regular size salesman who sells giant appliances), Nathanial realizes he no longer wants a life of aimless wealth and rides his new girlfriend out to sea. Again, not as funny as it may sound. This film is like a primer on why Letterman has gotten his ass kicked in the ratings by Jay Leno for years, why Conan bombed at The Tonight Show and hasn't set the world on fire at TBS and why there are so many comics beloved of other comics who never manage to achieve much mainstream success. There's a certain breed of comedian who are mainly focused on entertaining themselves. They're usually very bright and clever, oftentimes dark or subversive or edgy, but their humor is disconnected from or perpendicular to what other people find funny. They just make themselves laugh and if it amuses anyone else, that's a bonus. Such inwardly directed, almost defiant comedy can be hilarious to the general public in small bursts. It's essentially impossible to sustain it for a long period of time, something Cabin Boy makes agonizingly clear. I suppose disaffected, supercilious hipsters might find some laughs in this movie, or at least convince themselves to laugh at what they think only they are "with it" enough to appreciate. Normal folk will only stare at the screen in slackjawed amazement at how pitiful it all is. There's no narrative standard by which anything in this motion picture works. The attempts at humor are so fractured and esoteric that even stoned slackers would be hard pressed to summon up a giggle in response. Let me give you an example. Even back in 1994, goofy looking Chris Elliott was too balding and too bearded to play a kid fresh out of finishing school. We first see Nathanial when he's singing in a choir with his schoolmates. Now, a traditional attempt at comedy would fill the choir with fresh-faced teens and leave Elliott sticking out like a sore thumb. Cabin Boy fills the choir with guys who, just like Elliott, are far too old and too hirsute to pass for a student body. You see, you're supposed to anticipate the joke that would normally be told and instead appreciate them doing the complete opposite. This isn't smart humor. It's humor that wants to be applauded for being smart, which isn't the same at all. I quite enjoyed seeing Chris Elliott show up on the old Letterman show, not that I'm dating myself or anything. I didn't laugh or smile even once at this film. That pretty much says it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice Jest !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about this movie is that it doesn't allege some things it doesn't have, or bigger than it already owns. I loved it, and it's crazy since I'm not a Chris Elliott's fan at all. It's solid simple fun. The naive atmosphere worked perfectly. The idiot gags looked smart. Sometimes it's the most cynical kids' fantasy. Sometimes it's a close spoof of (Jason and The Argonauts - 1963) ! and all the time it's some fine comics. Surprisingly (Melora Walters) looked super cute and for the first time sexy. The sailors' team delivered so right performance. Nothing was over the top, or goofy in a bad way. All the elements harmonized to make the jest good. It even managed to be a story about a boy turning into a man. This kind of comedies used to be twisted, disgusting, poor, or easy, whatever. But Cabin Boy isn't any of that. It's joyful, yet in loyally childish way; which could be the secret of it indeed. Unlike so many jests, this will live long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What is wrong with you people?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I fully maintain that this movie is the worst of all time...right up there with Battlefield: Earth and The Star Wars Holiday Special. There's virtually no plot, stupid songs, and humor that tries and nearly always misses. The sad part is that I watched it to the end, believing that Elliot and Co. would be able to redeem themselves, but it never happened. I mean, they melt the giant snowman with coffee?! You must have to be high to get it. But maybe that was the point all along...I seriously don't understand how anybody could give this movie beyond a D-, even less how so many of you on this board gave it ten stars!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott is just plain funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    caa821
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those who gained their initial fame on television -- even at the highest level and with top popularity -- have often found their feature films finishing at the other end of the scale. Bill Cosby and Ray Romano are two examples of this -- Bill Murray one of the few exceptions. Chevy Chase has had some sporadic success, and even Martin Short -- one of the comedic geniuses of all-time -- has found his big-screen offerings sporadic. I think one of the reasons is that we are just too used to seeing them on the small screen, and/or in the characters/personas with which we have become accustomed. It also seems that their films often seem to be stories which would lend them to 10- or 12-minute skits, or the 22 minutes or so contained within a half hour program. Chris Elliott avoids this completely in this funny presentation. He succeeds in taking this character over-the-top, with the same quirky skill we've seen him employ on television so often. At 80 minutes, he also avoids making it overlong, and the supporting cast and Letterman's cameo are all well-presented, too. It's "quirkiness" is likely the reason this film didn't receive a higher overall rating in this site, and among professional reviewers. However, for me it's a thoroughly entertaining and engaging movie, and best of all, funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    God, I love this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rich56
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No, not in the 'it's so bad it's good' way. I truly think it's one of the funnier comedies of the last 20 years or so. Perhaps a lot of it depends on how you feel about Chris Elliot to begin with. I think he's priceless. Used to love his old show Get A Life and have followed him ever since. The plot of this, kind of a twisted version of Captains Courageous, really doesn't matter. What's fun are the numerous sight gags, Elliot's constant barrage of sarcastic one-liners and the generally anything goes attitude of the whole enterprise. The ship's crew, filled with a number of character actors we're not used to seeing in this kind of thing, are a wonderfully sleazy bunch. David Letterman's hysterically amateurish cameo at the beginning is the stuff of legend. "Wanna buy a bunny?" Ha! OK Citizen Kane it ain't. I own that on DVD btw. Right next to it is Cabin Boy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Comedic Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers ahead. Rarely is a comedy such a masterpiece! Cabin Boy succeeds because it is gonzo and really, really funny. It is a dead-on parody of the Rudyard Kipling morality play "Captains Courageous," as well as a fitting homage to the cheesy stop-motion special effects from master Ray Harryhausen. Chris Elliot, a master of the bizarre, is excellent as the spoiled brat Nathaniel Mayweather, who undergoes a profound transformation into the child-like cabin boy of the "Filthy Whore." The whole cast are devoted to their roles as grungy, cruel fishermen. this is a wonderful dark comedy with no pleasant moralizing, where the fishermen are Kipling's noble souls. This morally ambiguous film turns "Courageous's" pat duality of morals and noble fishermen on its it as a savage parody. The cast, crew, and directors knew this had to be a weird film, and all put in exemplary efforts to make this film as bizarre and as wonderful as possible. The cheesy special effects work perfectly. Elliot should have won an Oscar for his masterful performance. Fans of performance art will also relish the lovely Ann Magnuson's role as Kali, a parody of the monsters from Harryhausen's "Sinbad" movies. Lovers of comedy will adore this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wanna buy a monkey?......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chris Elliott plays a spoilt little rich kid who after finishing Fancy Boy school, will go on to run his fathers business. After being thrown out by his Limo driver, Elliott takes a wrong turn and ends up on a boat with a bunch of sea dogs who cannot stand rich people. And things go pretty crazy, and almost too Tim Burton.... Its a random movie, full of plot holes, quite a bad script, a bad performance from Elliott, but never ever boring, Cabin Boy wreaked of Burton, and he may as well had directed it, because despite being involved in the production, the director doesn't seem to have an original idea in his head. The sets are fantastic, cheap looking, but so bonkers that they just seem to fit in, and the crew of the boat are great too. But that's where all the good stuff ends. Despite it being totally bonkers, its fairly predictable stuff, and you can see how its going to end from a mile off. But its never boring, and its worth watching the once, even to remind you of the disastrous year Letterman hosted the Oscars, and featuring his scene from this movie in it heavily...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siavash_khavarnejad
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am really shocked by this movie's super low rating of not even five out of ten, I figured it probably would be kind of low since it was not as good as Chris Elliott's TV show Get a Life and a lot of people didn't like his humour or this movie, but it was pretty good. It's obviously not for everyone with a really "out there" sense of humour but for what it was it was really funny, with a lot of laugh out loud gut busting moments. David Letterman's "wanna buy a monkey?" cameo is fantastic and Chris Elliott is great as the full of himself, super annoying rich kid turned cabin boy. I really recommend it if you like any of his other work or Get A Life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stink or Swim
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wes-connors
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Proudly wearing his "Fancy Lad" description, over-cultured and prissy prep school graduate Chris Elliott (as Nathanial Mayweather) goes to board a ship bound for Hawaii. He expects to join his wealthy father, but mistakenly gets on "The Filthy Whore" and is unable to get the crew of four salty and soused fishermen to change direction. After becoming a replacement for dim-witted "Cabin Boy" Andy Richter (as Kenny), Mr. Elliott befriends shapely swimmer Melora Walters (as Trina) and shark-man Russ Tamblyn (as Chocki). David Letterman has an amusing cameo during the early running, before this comic ship sinks. Too bad for Mr. Elliott, who once had a good persona going with his "Get a Life" TV series. *** Cabin Boy (1/7/94) Adam Resnick ~ Chris Elliott, Melora Walters, Russ Tamblyn, Ritch Brinkley
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott's allegorical autobiography.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jonny 99
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Like his character Nathanial Mayweather, Chris Elliott was born to a very talented father (Bob Elliott) and into a lucrative family business (showbiz). Also like Nathanial, the elder's talent casts an especially harsh light on the younger's near complete lack thereof. Chris takes us as Nathanial on a metaphorical journey starting from privileged upbringing complete with shots at televisions shows, both his own and David Letterman's, based on the respect others have for his father. And like Nathanial eventually that life of ease ebbs away as Chris/Nathanial have to make it on their own talents either making a comedy or surviving on a ship called "The Filthy Whore." Neither fares well and Elliott deserves credit for taking an unflinching look at his situation and filming what he see even if only in metaphor. Like his career, little about the movie works. As a character, Nathanial grates and a lack of more attractive protagonists means little that happens provokes any empathy from the audience - The Filthy Whore could have pulled "A Perfect Storm" sinking about the 35 minute mark and no tears would have been shed. As a story, Nathanial's being thrown out of an anachronistically modern limousine only to mistake The Filthy Whore for his father's "Queen Anne" yacht works less well than your average "Two Close for Comfort" episode setup. As a comedy, even Letterman himself finds himself in a disjointed, seemingly improvised, unfunny exchange with his one-time television foil. In short, while a small, vociferous group of Elliott fans consider this a cult classic, it is only their hero-worship that makes it watchable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It might have been good as a 3 minute skit on Late Night with David Letterman
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MBunge
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Imagine one of those weird little skits you used to see on Late Night with either David Letterman or Conan O'Brian. You know, one of those where some surreal character comes out and does some silly stuff for a minute or so and then goes away. Now imagine one of those skits without a host there to play straight man, no studio audience to draw energy from and it goes on for almost an hour and a half. Congratulations! You've now seen Cabin Boy. Nathanial Mayweather (Chris Elliott) is a prissy, fussy, arrogant, dimwitted son of a rich man. After graduating from finishing school is all his bewigged glory, Nathanial gets misdirected and instead of winding up on a luxury cruiser taking him home to Hawaii, he winds up a cabin boy on a fishing boat named The Filthy Whore. After a whole bunch of lame inanity with 4 grubby and overacting fishermen, Nathanial falls in love at first sight with a girl swimming around the world and must prove his manhood to her by having sex with the slutty 2nd cousin of the Hindu goddess Shiva. And that's not as funny as it may sound. After teaming up with a shark man to battle a giant appliance salesman (that's a giant salesman who sells appliances, not a regular size salesman who sells giant appliances), Nathanial realizes he no longer wants a life of aimless wealth and rides his new girlfriend out to sea. Again, not as funny as it may sound. This film is like a primer on why Letterman has gotten his ass kicked in the ratings by Jay Leno for years, why Conan bombed at The Tonight Show and hasn't set the world on fire at TBS and why there are so many comics beloved of other comics who never manage to achieve much mainstream success. There's a certain breed of comedian who are mainly focused on entertaining themselves. They're usually very bright and clever, oftentimes dark or subversive or edgy, but their humor is disconnected from or perpendicular to what other people find funny. They just make themselves laugh and if it amuses anyone else, that's a bonus. Such inwardly directed, almost defiant comedy can be hilarious to the general public in small bursts. It's essentially impossible to sustain it for a long period of time, something Cabin Boy makes agonizingly clear. I suppose disaffected, supercilious hipsters might find some laughs in this movie, or at least convince themselves to laugh at what they think only they are "with it" enough to appreciate. Normal folk will only stare at the screen in slackjawed amazement at how pitiful it all is. There's no narrative standard by which anything in this motion picture works. The attempts at humor are so fractured and esoteric that even stoned slackers would be hard pressed to summon up a giggle in response. Let me give you an example. Even back in 1994, goofy looking Chris Elliott was too balding and too bearded to play a kid fresh out of finishing school. We first see Nathanial when he's singing in a choir with his schoolmates. Now, a traditional attempt at comedy would fill the choir with fresh-faced teens and leave Elliott sticking out like a sore thumb. Cabin Boy fills the choir with guys who, just like Elliott, are far too old and too hirsute to pass for a student body. You see, you're supposed to anticipate the joke that would normally be told and instead appreciate them doing the complete opposite. This isn't smart humor. It's humor that wants to be applauded for being smart, which isn't the same at all. I quite enjoyed seeing Chris Elliott show up on the old Letterman show, not that I'm dating myself or anything. I didn't laugh or smile even once at this film. That pretty much says it all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice Jest !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best thing about this movie is that it doesn't allege some things it doesn't have, or bigger than it already owns. I loved it, and it's crazy since I'm not a Chris Elliott's fan at all. It's solid simple fun. The naive atmosphere worked perfectly. The idiot gags looked smart. Sometimes it's the most cynical kids' fantasy. Sometimes it's a close spoof of (Jason and The Argonauts - 1963) ! and all the time it's some fine comics. Surprisingly (Melora Walters) looked super cute and for the first time sexy. The sailors' team delivered so right performance. Nothing was over the top, or goofy in a bad way. All the elements harmonized to make the jest good. It even managed to be a story about a boy turning into a man. This kind of comedies used to be twisted, disgusting, poor, or easy, whatever. But Cabin Boy isn't any of that. It's joyful, yet in loyally childish way; which could be the secret of it indeed. Unlike so many jests, this will live long.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What is wrong with you people?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I fully maintain that this movie is the worst of all time...right up there with Battlefield: Earth and The Star Wars Holiday Special. There's virtually no plot, stupid songs, and humor that tries and nearly always misses. The sad part is that I watched it to the end, believing that Elliot and Co. would be able to redeem themselves, but it never happened. I mean, they melt the giant snowman with coffee?! You must have to be high to get it. But maybe that was the point all along...I seriously don't understand how anybody could give this movie beyond a D-, even less how so many of you on this board gave it ten stars!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Chris Elliott is just plain funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    caa821
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/4/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Those who gained their initial fame on television -- even at the highest level and with top popularity -- have often found their feature films finishing at the other end of the scale. Bill Cosby and Ray Romano are two examples of this -- Bill Murray one of the few exceptions. Chevy Chase has had some sporadic success, and even Martin Short -- one of the comedic geniuses of all-time -- has found his big-screen offerings sporadic. I think one of the reasons is that we are just too used to seeing them on the small screen, and/or in the characters/personas with which we have become accustomed. It also seems that their films often seem to be stories which would lend them to 10- or 12-minute skits, or the 22 minutes or so contained within a half hour program. Chris Elliott avoids this completely in this funny presentation. He succeeds in taking this character over-the-top, with the same quirky skill we've seen him employ on television so often. At 80 minutes, he also avoids making it overlong, and the supporting cast and Letterman's cameo are all well-presented, too. It's "quirkiness" is likely the reason this film didn't receive a higher overall rating in this site, and among professional reviewers. However, for me it's a thoroughly entertaining and engaging movie, and best of all, funny as hell.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    God, I love this movie...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rich56
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    No, not in the 'it's so bad it's good' way. I truly think it's one of the funnier comedies of the last 20 years or so. Perhaps a lot of it depends on how you feel about Chris Elliot to begin with. I think he's priceless. Used to love his old show Get A Life and have followed him ever since. The plot of this, kind of a twisted version of Captains Courageous, really doesn't matter. What's fun are the numerous sight gags, Elliot's constant barrage of sarcastic one-liners and the generally anything goes attitude of the whole enterprise. The ship's crew, filled with a number of character actors we're not used to seeing in this kind of thing, are a wonderfully sleazy bunch. David Letterman's hysterically amateurish cameo at the beginning is the stuff of legend. "Wanna buy a bunny?" Ha! OK Citizen Kane it ain't. I own that on DVD btw. Right next to it is Cabin Boy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Comedic Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael_the_nermal
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Spoilers ahead. Rarely is a comedy such a masterpiece! Cabin Boy succeeds because it is gonzo and really, really funny. It is a dead-on parody of the Rudyard Kipling morality play "Captains Courageous," as well as a fitting homage to the cheesy stop-motion special effects from master Ray Harryhausen. Chris Elliot, a master of the bizarre, is excellent as the spoiled brat Nathaniel Mayweather, who undergoes a profound transformation into the child-like cabin boy of the "Filthy Whore." The whole cast are devoted to their roles as grungy, cruel fishermen. this is a wonderful dark comedy with no pleasant moralizing, where the fishermen are Kipling's noble souls. This morally ambiguous film turns "Courageous's" pat duality of morals and noble fishermen on its it as a savage parody. The cast, crew, and directors knew this had to be a weird film, and all put in exemplary efforts to make this film as bizarre and as wonderful as possible. The cheesy special effects work perfectly. Elliot should have won an Oscar for his masterful performance. Fans of performance art will also relish the lovely Ann Magnuson's role as Kali, a parody of the monsters from Harryhausen's "Sinbad" movies. Lovers of comedy will adore this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
